<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-08-29T14:29:01.123484+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/i-want-to-color-the-sac-input-controls-according-to-the-situation/qaa-p/14199328#M4924524</id>
    <title>Re: I want to color the SAC input controls according to t...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T12:50:40.893000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi @ tsuuuu,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You are correct. CSS lets you style the input control widget globally. To go further (e.g., colour different states: selected, unselected, disabled), you need to combine SAC Analytic Application scripting with CSS class manipulation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. In SAC Analytic Applications, each input control is a widget with scripting APIs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From this you can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Compare against all available members → determine which are unselected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Compare against a filter or a condition → determine which are disabled/unselectable.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Once you’ve evaluated the state, you can apply CSS classes dynamically to the DOM elements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Here are some Best Practices to provide some details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use Analytic Applications, not Stories à only applications support this scripting + CSS manipulation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keep lists like disabled values in a model or script variable, so business logic is centralised.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test across browsers; SAC updates can sometimes alter DOM class names, so pin CSS to unique selectors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consider usability: always provide a legend explaining your colours.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To summarise, you need to combine getSelectedMembers scripting with dynamic CSS injection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use scripting to evaluate selected, not selected, or disabled/unselectable.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Apply CSS classes conditionally to each checkbox option.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This way you can achieve green (selected), grey (disabled), none (unselected) colouring for SAC input controls.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/i-want-to-color-the-sac-input-controls-according-to-the-situation/qaa-p/14199328#M4924524"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T12:50:40.893000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/position-to-job-sync-through-data-loader-api-creating-blank-job/qaq-p/14199330</id>
    <title>Position To Job Sync through Data Loader API creating blank Job Relationship record</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T12:50:56.902000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rigjit_banerjee</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2246182</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I am currently facing a setback in SuccessFactors Employee Central with an API transaction in Job Information.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Scenario:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;DATA Loader is being used to update Job Information for employees. While doing a Job information update for an employee (let's say we create a blank data change record in the Job Information with today's date).&amp;nbsp; After uploading, a blank record gets created in Job Information with Data Change as event reason (AS EXPECTED), but a blank Job relationship record is also getting created with the same effective date.&lt;BR /&gt;As per rule trace, the Position to Job Sync rule is getting triggered and e due to the different "Set" Job Relationship Matrix rules, Job Relationship portlet is getting affected and creating blank records even if there no change in Position Matrix relationships.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Is there any workaround where the API profile can be made to identify that this data loader update will only trigger Job Information and not Job Relationship if there is no change in Matrix relationships?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Rigjit Banerjee&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/position-to-job-sync-through-data-loader-api-creating-blank-job/qaq-p/14199330"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T12:50:56.902000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sql-anywhere-problem-with-json-data-with-german-umlauts-wrongly-decoded/qaa-p/14199331#M4924525</id>
    <title>Re: SQL Anywhere: Problem with JSON data with German umla...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T12:52:29.746000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>johnsmirnios</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/398035</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I looked at our JSON parser and it does accept 6-character hex sequences. It should not be doing so and it's a quick fix.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, I would also recommend that you consider using a CHAR collation based on UTF8 rather than windows-1252. If I recall correctly, sp_parse_json returns its string values as CHAR datatype; however, although our parser internally converts the bare text in strings from NCHAR to CHAR, it explicitly generates UTF8 encoding for escape sequences.&amp;nbsp;The result can be strings that are in a mix of CHAR and UTF8 encoding. It's an old bug but changing our JSON support to use NCHAR everywhere had backward compatibility issues and some other complications that meant it never got implemented. Using a UTF8-based CHAR collation is an easy workaround. Unfortunately, it means a database unload/reload would be required.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sql-anywhere-problem-with-json-data-with-german-umlauts-wrongly-decoded/qaa-p/14199331#M4924525"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T12:52:29.746000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/saw-17-question-on-the-system-load-of-file-handling-functions-xp-write-file/qaa-p/14199332#M4924526</id>
    <title>Re: SAW 17: Question on the system load of file handling functions (xp_write_file, xp_read_file) ?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T12:53:54.254000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stalker4</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1750830</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Files of various sizes, ranging from 500 KB to 20-40 MB, are stored in the database. The average size of a file stored in the database is about 3 MB.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a document management database, and document cards are stored in the database (a card consists of a number of fields that are stored in linked tables - master-detail).&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;These document texts are stored in a separate table located in a separate table space in the BLOB field.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simply put, some users save these document texts to the database, while other users download these document texts from the database to the client's computer for viewing, if necessary.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this situation, I am interested in the load on the database server in the context of writing/reading these files from (to) BLOB by a large number of users (100-400 simultaneous connections, although not all of these users necessarily view these document texts).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Which is less resource-intensive for the database server: loading these files from the table from the BLOB field or reading them from the file system via xp_read_file and then returning them to the user ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/saw-17-question-on-the-system-load-of-file-handling-functions-xp-write-file/qaa-p/14199332#M4924526"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T12:53:54.254000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/partially-committed-webservice-transactions-in-sql-anywhere/qaa-p/14199333#M4924527</id>
    <title>Re: partially committed webservice-transactions in SQL Anywhere</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T12:56:44.308000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>johnsmirnios</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/398035</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/127571"&gt;@Volker&lt;/a&gt;: TEMPORARY NON TRANSACTIONAL tables have not rollback information at all. That's what the "NON TRANSACTIONAL" part is all about. It has nothing to do with LOAD. If you want a LOAD to be all-or-nothing, you cannot use a non-transactional table.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/partially-committed-webservice-transactions-in-sql-anywhere/qaa-p/14199333#M4924527"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T12:56:44.308000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fms-in-good-issue/qaa-p/14199335#M4225355</id>
    <title>Re: FMS In Good Issue</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T12:57:37.376000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe_Lima</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2127356"&gt;@user2001&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This happens because cost centres are bound to the GL in the setting "relevant for cost accounting". BS accounts ideally won't be cost-relevant, so CC fields are "nulled" by SAP. P&amp;amp;L GLs tend to be cost-relevant, so SAP will try to pick the CC from there. If it is null, SAP does the same as the BS, if not, the CC will be pulled from there.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A workaround would be creating another FMS, assigned to the CC field, so they are cross-dependent:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keep the Account Code's FMS as is, but change the refresh option to "When Column Value Changes"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new FMS and assign it to your CC field (keep the refresh option to "When Column Value Changes"). It would be something like the below:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT CASE 
    WHEN IFNULL($[$13.59.0], '') = '5001014' THEN 'IDC-1027'
    WHEN IFNULL($[$13.59.0], '') = '5001015' THEN 'IDC-1028'
    ELSE 'XXX-XXXX'
END​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;It should do the job.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope it helps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR,&lt;BR /&gt;Felipe&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fms-in-good-issue/qaa-p/14199335#M4225355"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T12:57:37.376000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/dms-query-on-limiting-attachment-file-upload-size-and-formats-in-s-4hana-on/qaq-p/14199338</id>
    <title>DMS: Query on Limiting Attachment File Upload Size and Formats in S/4HANA on RISE (PCE Edition)CV01N</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T12:59:39.984000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nilesh62</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/155544</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The customer has requested to restrict users from uploading large image or PDF files and would like to enforce a maximum file size limit — for example, 500 KB or 1 MB — for attachments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you please confirm the following for S/4HANA on RISE (PCE Edition):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is it possible to restrict the file upload size for attachments?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can this restriction be applied based on file formats (e.g., allow only specific types and limit their size individually)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are there any inherent limitations or configurable options regarding supported file formats for attachment uploads?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/dms-query-on-limiting-attachment-file-upload-size-and-formats-in-s-4hana-on/qaq-p/14199338"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T12:59:39.984000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-prepare-for-sap-s-4-hana-private-edition-certification-with-sample/ba-p/14197612</id>
    <title>How to Prepare for SAP S/4 HANA Private Edition Certification (with Sample Questions)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:00:00.038000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Amin_Omidy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog, I’ll share practical tips to help you to prepare and be able to pass the SAP S/4 HANA Cloud Private Edition certification (&lt;STRONG&gt;E_S4CPE_2405&lt;/STRONG&gt;). While the post is especially helpful for those aiming to get certified, it also provides useful insights for SAP developers, Basis Admin, SAP Architects, Project Managers, and anyone who works daily in SAP ERP projects or operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You often start preparing for a certification and end up confused or lost, what are the right resources, and how deep should you go through different materials and references?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a Microsoft and SAP Certified , I always tell new learners: preparing for a certification is like learning English as a second language—you want to be able to use it effectively in your day-to-day work, not become Shakespeare!&lt;BR /&gt;Here, I share the exact resources I use in my day-to-day role as an SAP Architect—drawing on over 20 years of hands-on experience in the SAP space. I’ve also included the key materials that can help you confidently prepare for the SAP S/4 HANA Private Edition. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I’ll be updating this post from time to time, since SAP technology and S/4HANA continue to evolve at a fast pace!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Being a successful SAP&amp;nbsp;Solution consultant or&amp;nbsp;SAP Expert&amp;nbsp;requires a deep understanding of both on-premises and hyperscaler technologies, combined with hands-on experience from real customer projects. On top of that, strong expertise in SAP solutions is essential. Earning the SAP S/4 HANA certification is just the beginning of this journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is the second blog of series, I’m going to share practical insights to help you prepare and succeed to achieve this as a goal.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Amin_Omidy_0-1756397272505.png" style="width: 34px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306062i6F355585F0BECABB/image-dimensions/34x34/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="34" height="34" role="button" title="Amin_Omidy_0-1756397272505.png" alt="Amin_Omidy_0-1756397272505.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Get SAP Certified? Real-World Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Being certified earns immediate credibility customers, partners, and hiring managers are more likely to trust your knowledge and decisions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP certification improves your chances of landing your desired role.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Certified professionals often qualify for higher rates, promotions, and leadership roles in SAP projects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In some cases (e.g., security reviews, migration, SOC 2 documentation), certification adds weight to your approval or sign-off.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The annual certification renewal process ensures your knowledge stays current, especially with cloud solutions and SAP's evolving product roadmap.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Certification validates your hands-on skills and prepares you to deliver better results in real SAP implementations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Certified professionals are more likely to be chosen for challenging or high-impact projects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Certification gives you recognition within the broader SAP ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exam Topics and Focus Areas&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To pass the certification you’ll need a score of 72% or higher, SAP outlines the following key areas:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction to Cloud Computing and SAP Cloud ERP Deployment Options (11% - 20%)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Migration and Business Process Testing (11% - 20%)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Implementing with a Cloud Mindset, Building the Team, and Conducting Fit-to-Standard Workshops (11% - 20%)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System Landscapes and Identity Access Management (11% - 20%)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configuration and the SAP Fiori Launchpad (11% - 20%)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extensibility, Integration, and Clean Core (11% - 20%)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Areas of Study&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To gain the knowledge required, focus on the following areas:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Characteristics of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;RISE with SAP Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer transition paths to SAP S/4 HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New Implementation (Greenfield)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System Conversion (Brownfield)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Selective Data Transition (Bluefield)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Stockholders and their role &amp;amp; responsibilities &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System landscapes used to implement SAP S/4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;S/4 HANA Cloud Private Edition release upgrade&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cloud ALM Implementation Project setup for S/4 HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System Preparation Activities for conversion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analyse customer’s exiting business process (Signavio)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Run and review SAP Readiness check report&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Identity Access Management in S/4 HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Creating users in S/4 HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Role vs System Admin Role&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiori Launchpad UI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Fiori Launchpad &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Applications and users&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Content Manager&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;App Manager&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fit-to-Standard analysis workshops (mostly for greenfield customers)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business processes configuration, evaluation , improvement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Working with SAP Fiori Launchpad&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My Home, Spaces and Pages Layout&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Embedded help support and Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ange Team and Responsibilities app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Situation Handling&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extensibility tools for S/4 HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean core tiers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key user In-App Extensibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Developer In-App Extensibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Side by Side Extensibility with BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Setting up integration in S/4 HANA &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration Solution Advisory Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Setting up integrations with various recourses &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration Monitoring with Cloud ALM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data migration methods to S/4 HANA &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Testing types and strategy &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cloud ALM for test case and test plan&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cloud ALM test Automation (Tricentis)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All the resources listed below are free. You may only need to create a Universal ID to track your progress if the resource is from SAP Learning Hub.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommended (Free) Learning Courses:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/explore-sap-cloud-erp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exploring SAP Cloud ERP &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/implementing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implementing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important Reference Links:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Amin_Omidy_0-1756415642612.png" style="width: 36px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306093i95F2B10E98790B60/image-dimensions/36x26/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="36" height="26" role="button" title="Amin_Omidy_0-1756415642612.png" alt="Amin_Omidy_0-1756415642612.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://youtu.be/qojVtJaSGOA" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;F&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://youtu.be/qojVtJaSGOA" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;rom Classic ABAP to Clean Corse&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Amin_Omidy_1-1756415749858.png" style="width: 32px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306094iD31B458C6431174B/image-dimensions/32x30/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="32" height="30" role="button" title="Amin_Omidy_1-1756415749858.png" alt="Amin_Omidy_1-1756415749858.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;A href="https://notebooklm.google.com/notebook/5bc88475-c941-41e9-8677-e0c1e63efaec?artifactId=03abe305-c5d9-4768-9be1-ae710948243d" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP Cloud, Wrappers, and ATC for Stable S/4HANA Upgrades&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/introducing-the-rise-with-sap-methodology-for-sap-partners-and-customers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing the RISE with SAP Methodology for SAP Partners and Customers (&lt;/STRONG&gt;Learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jFOLaXvTNxI&amp;amp;list=PLPn1cKhthG5VZLw-c14QhWn9aAqfEiEeO&amp;amp;index=11" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Executing Your Cloud ERP Project&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;(Video)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jDuZfvdivOs" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Specifics of transformation to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Video)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wjLDN4Gj54s&amp;amp;list=PLPn1cKhthG5XO-qz_2KMBiSfbywY3PpmU" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clean Core - a holistic concept I Move to Cloud ERP &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/managing-clean-core-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Managing Clean Core for SAP S/4HANA Cloud &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/practicing-clean-core-extensibility-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud/explaining-extensibility-model-best-practices_e290f382-800e-40ef-a203-85a13115f487" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explaining Extensibility Model Best Practices&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xqCKxFfytiQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clean core extensibility in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Video)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/key-technical-topics-in-a-system-conversion-to-sap-s-4hana/extensibility-overview-and-guidance_LE_ad29947a-ad44-430b-87ff-32e470367acb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility Overview and Guidance &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advance Learning and Practice&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/implementing-sap-s-4-hana-cloud-public-edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implementing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/sap-s-4hana-conversion-and-sap-system-upgrade?userlogin=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Conversion and SAP System Upgrade &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Learning course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/system-conversion-to-sap-s-4hana" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System Conversion to SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VlQxjhUoWfo" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streamline Your SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Upgrade &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Video)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/learn-the-basics-of-sap-fiori" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning the Basics of SAP Fiori &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/get-started-with-in-app-extensibility-in-sap-s-4hana" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Getting Started with In-App Extensibility in SAP S/4HANA &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="http://Practicing%20Clean Core Extensibility for SAP S/4HANA Cloud" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practicing Clean Core Extensibility for SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Learning Course)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/build-side-by-side-extensions-on-sap-btp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building side-by-side extensions on SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt; (learning Course)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/3248/3277/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Develop extensions for SAP S/4HANA with SAP BTP, ABAP Environment, runtime&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Mission)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/s4hana-private-edition/trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4 HANA Fully-Activated Appliance on Hyperscalers &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(30 days trail)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/s4hana/trial.html?campaigncode=crm-ya22-int-1517075&amp;amp;source=ppc-1na-googleads-search-71700000111982626-58700008462002968-clouderpgrow_s4s-x-x-x&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds&amp;amp;gad_source=1&amp;amp;gad_campaignid=20315499480&amp;amp;gbraid=0AAAAAp1XE4_82rp5IfFTLwZmTvE4AZO7G&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjw8KrFBhDUARIsAMvIApafY9jPy1eWEfQMUDvo7iuF15Rr-KkDEbJE4gCYQuoN7tcM-5kwDhEaAuIGEALw_wcB" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4 HANA Cloud Public Edition free &lt;/STRONG&gt;(14 days trail&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before we start the sample questions , let me explain different types of SAP ERP provisioning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP ECC was traditionally deployed in on-premises environments or customer data centres. With the introduction of &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;, cloud provisioning options became available alongside traditional deployments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current Types of SAP ERP Deployment Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Editions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA Cloud, public edition&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Multi-tenant SaaS, fully managed by SAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA Cloud, private edition&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Single-tenant, SAP-managed infrastructure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: Although it runs on cloud infrastructure, &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA Cloud, private edition&lt;/STRONG&gt; shares more operational and management characteristics with on-premises deployments (greater customer control, customization, and lifecycle management).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On-Premises Editions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA On-Premises in customer data centre&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Fully customer-managed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA On-Premises managed by SAP (HEC – HANA Enterprise Cloud or ECS-Enterprise Cloud Service)&lt;/STRONG&gt; – SAP hosts and operates the system in hyperscalers &amp;nbsp;on behalf of the customer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA On-Premises at hyperscalers&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Hosted by AWS, Azure, or Google Cloud but managed by the customer or a systems integrator.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA On-Premises via SAP certified partners&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Deployed using appliances in a customer data centre.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA for Government (National security Service -&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/Energir%20IAM%20Non%20Prod%20Landscape.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;NS2&lt;/A&gt; )&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Specialized U.S. &amp;nbsp;deployment for government and defense, meeting the highest national security certifications in U.S and Canada .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Legacy Options&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ECC in customer data centre (on-premises)&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Classic model, customer-managed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ECC at hyperscalers&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Often a transitional step (Unicode migration, system prep) before moving to S/4HANA in cloud environment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I've put together 15 sample questions to help you prepare for the exam. These questions are a bit more challenging than the ones you'll typically see on the actual test:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sample Questions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Which choice is the main used of Launchpad Content Manager? There are 2 correct answers to this question&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage technical catalogs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create custom business catalogs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Perform mass changes on business catalogs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add or remove catalogs content references&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In an S/4HANA Private Edition implementation, which type of testing focuses on verifying that the overall system still works as expected after applying changes such as upgrades, patches, or configuration updates?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unit Test&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Process Test&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;User Acceptance Test&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regression Test&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;During an SAP S/4HANA Private Edition project using the SAP Integration Solution Advisory Methodology (ISA-M), which activity would you expect to complete &lt;EM&gt;before&lt;/EM&gt; selecting integration technologies or designing detailed interfaces?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Defining target integration domains and aligning them with business priorities&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Establishing governance guidelines for integration domains and setting decision-making processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Executing end-to-end interface tests with all involved applications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configuring middleware connections between S/4HANA and third-party systems&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A customer is moving from SAP ECC to the latest release of SAP S/4HANA, which will be hosted and managed by the ECS team. Their requirement is to migrate both master data and full historical transactional data into the new environment. Which transition approach would best meet their needs?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System conversion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select data transition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lift &amp;amp; shift&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Greenfield&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How are SAP Best Practices initially deploy in S/4 HANA Cloud Private Edition system?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Through SAP Transport Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Through SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Through SAP Activate Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Through SAP Solution Builder&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A customer running ECC plans to move to SAP S/4HANA Private Edition through a system conversion. They want to follow SAP’s recommended preparation steps to confirm technical readiness, understand functional impacts, and plan for custom code remediation.&lt;BR /&gt;Which of the following sequences reflects SAP’s best practice?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Run the SAP Readiness Check → Review the Simplification Item List → Perform ATC custom code analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Perform ATC custom code analysis → Run the SAP Readiness Check → Review the Simplification Item List&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Review the Simplification Item List → Run the SAP Readiness Check → Perform ATC custom code analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Run the SAP Readiness Check → Perform ATC custom code analysis → Update the Simplification Item List&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You are on an SAP S/4HANA Private Edition project where the customer needs to deliver advanced custom business logic that must:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-roman"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reuse internal ABAP application objects (e.g., BAPIs, CDS views) without exposing them via remote APIs first.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Participate in the same LUW as standard S/4 transactions when required.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Remain upgrade-safe and fully compliant with the “clean core” principle.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Avoid the performance overhead of cross-system remote calls.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Which approach best meets &lt;STRONG&gt;all&lt;/STRONG&gt; of these constraints for a Tier-3 developer extension?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build the logic in the ABAP environment on SAP BTP (standalone Steampunk) using side-by-side extensions, avoiding any in-stack custom code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Modify standard ABAP code directly inside S/4HANA to embed the logic within existing processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use SAP Build Apps to deliver the functionality as a low-code/no-code side-by-side extension on SAP BTP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Develop in the embedded Steampunk ABAP environment inside the S/4HANA system, following in-app extension guidelines and ensuring upgrade safety.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;8.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;During the Realize phase of an SAP S/4HANA Private Edition project using SAP Activate, the team encounters multiple fit-to-standard gaps that require custom extensions. At the same time, performance issues are found during integration testing, and the customer insists on adding new scope items not originally in the signed backlog.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Which of the following actions are&lt;STRONG&gt; fully aligned with the Activate methodology’s Realize phase best practices? &lt;EM&gt;(Select TWO)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Perform configuration in the Quality system based on the backlog items confirmed in the Explore phase and manage any new scope through formal change control.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Re-open Fit-to-Standard workshops to capture and approve all new requirements before continuing configuration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conduct performance tuning and regression testing as part of iterative configuration cycles before the formal User Acceptance Test.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Postpone addressing integration performance issues until after cutover, since Realize focuses on functional build.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Implement all new customer scope immediately to avoid delays, updating the backlog informally.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;9.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;You are in the preparation phase for an SAP S/4HANA Private Edition project and need a platform that provides &lt;/STRONG&gt;mission-based guidance&lt;STRONG&gt;, best practices, and ready-to-use service configurations for deploying and extending solutions on SAP BTP. The customer also wants visibility into estimated service costs and technical prerequisites before starting.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Which SAP platform best meets this need?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Store&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Discovery Centre &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;10&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;You are implementing the latest DMOVE2S4 conversion method (available since SUM 2.0 SP17) for migrating your SAP ECC system from on-premises to hyperscaler cloud. Considering the technical architecture and SUM execution flow, which statements are correct? (Select TWO)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You execute SUM from a newly installed AAS in the target cloud environment, and during the ASCS_ASK phase, SUM automatically detects the remote ASCS instance and offers an "ASCS instance move" dialog to relocate central services to the same target host&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You must manually pre-install both AAS and ASCS instances in the target cloud before initiating SUM, ensuring network latency remains below 20ms with minimum 400 MB bandwidth between environments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SUM execution begins from the source PAS while simultaneously creating a shadow AAS instance in the target cloud, with ASCS migration occurring during the EU_CLONE_MNG phase through automated system move protocols&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;T&lt;SPAN&gt;he conversion utilizes standard DMO functionality rather than "DMO with system move," requiring manual post-processing of shared filesystems (/sapmnt/ and /usr/sap/trans) and RFC adjustments after SUM completion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;11.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In your SAP S/4HANA Private Edition system, you need to manage role maintenance efficiently. Which methods are correct for role management? (Select TWO)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use transaction PFCG to create roles, assign transactions to menu tree, then generate authorization profiles and perform user master record comparison&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use transaction SU01 to directly assign authorization profiles to users without generating profiles through role maintenance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use transaction SU01 to assign users to roles, maintain validity periods, then perform user comparison to activate authorization profiles in user master records&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use Business Role Maintenance Fiori app to create business roles with business catalogs for S/4HANA Private Edition&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;12&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Which of the following statements correctly describes the Migration Cockpit capabilities and requirements for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition implementations?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Migration Cockpit is a recommended SAP tool that requires separate licensing with dedicated infrastructure setup, exclusively supporting master data migration through manual staging table creation with limited connectivity options&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Migration Cockpit is an embedded data migration tool included in S/4HANA licenses that supports both staging tables and direct transfer methods, with value mapping capabilities, simulation features, and comprehensive project management for data migration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Migration Cockpit must be installed and run from the source system with specific add-on requirements, designed exclusively for cloud-to-cloud migrations and cannot support on-premise to private cloud migration scenarios&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Migration Cockpit is limited to transactional data migration only and requires mandatory third-party ETL tools for all master data migration scenarios&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;13.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition, when implementing business workflows that require extensive customization capabilities, which of the following statements best describes the workflow development approach available compared to the Public Edition?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Private Edition only supports standard flexible workflows through Central Business Configuration (CBC) similar to Public Edition, with no access to classical workflow development tools.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Private Edition allows full classical ABAP workflow development using SPRO-IMG transactions and Workbench tools, providing the same customization flexibility as S/4HANA On-Premise systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Private Edition requires all custom workflows to be developed exclusively on SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) with no on-system development capabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Private Edition uses the same starter system approach as Public Edition, where workflows are pre-configured and cannot be modified beyond standard parameters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;14.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;In SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition, when implementing SAP Best Practices with multiple country solutions in a greenfield environment, which of the following represents the most critical constraint that must be adhered to during the activation process to avoid configuration conflicts and system errors?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Best Practices can only be activated in client 000 as it serves as the reference client, and all country solutions must be activated sequentially starting with the home country before adding international localizations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Demo data must be activated for all country solutions simultaneously during the initial activation cycle, as it cannot be transported between development, quality, and production systems via standard transport mechanisms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once you activate additional scope items or country solutions, you cannot perform any technical upgrade to the next Feature Package Stack (FPS) or new release, and you must not change the SAP Best Practices configuration for already activated countries/regions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The group currency can be changed at any time during the activation process, and each country solution can maintain its own local currency independent of the global group currency setting.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;15.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You are modernizing your ECC system by migrating to S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition. What would be the most cost-effective and secure approach to enable external users (who do not exist in your corporate Identity Provider) to access S/4HANA applications?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure their external IdP as a Corporate Identity Provider in SAP IAS and use SAP RISE external Load Balancer to access S/4HANA embedded Fiori applications&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure their external IdP as a Corporate Identity Provider in SAP IAS and use SAP Build Work Zone to provide Fiori access to S/4HANA via federation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create individual VPN connections for each external user to access the corporate network, then leverage RISE internal Load Balancer to connect to S/4HANA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create individual user accounts in IAS and configure conditional authentication in the S/4HANA application within IAS to direct users to S/4HANA embedded Fiori&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;Answers:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answer: b, d&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The Launchpad Content Manager is specifically designed to manage business catalogs, not technical catalogs&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;. Its primary functions include:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Creating custom business catalogs&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Adding/removing catalog content (references to tiles and target mappings)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Copying catalogs (e.g., copy SAP standard catalog to customize)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Searching for launchpad content&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Transporting catalogs&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/implementing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/managing-content-on-the-sap-fiori-launchpad_fee1a412-019b-4b6f-9d31-65b63e896453" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;[1]&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.Answer: d&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unit Test&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – Verifies that an individual program, function, or configuration element works as expected in isolation.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Process Test&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – Checks that complete end-to-end business workflows operate correctly across integrated modules.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;User Acceptance Test (UAT)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – Confirms, by end users, that the system meets business requirements before go-live.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regression Test&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – Ensures that recent changes (e.g., upgrades, patches) haven’t broken existing functionality.&lt;EM&gt; specifically&lt;/EM&gt; about re-testing to detect unintended impacts from changes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.Answer: b&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4.Answer: a&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The key points are migrating master data and a full historical data which will be possible only in brownfield or conversion approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5.Answer: d&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The initial deployment starts by SAP Solution builder in Dev tier then you can use the Transport Management to move that to the higher tier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6.Answer: a&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answer: d&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;a&lt;SPAN&gt; is tempting because it keeps the core untouched — but it can’t directly call unreleased ABAP objects or share LUW without APIs.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;b&lt;SPAN&gt; delivers all technical needs but breaks “clean core” and upgrade safety — an instant long-term maintenance risk.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;c&lt;SPAN&gt; satisfies low-code/no-code but fails the “deep ABAP integration” requirement.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;d&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is the only one that ticks all boxes: same LUW, direct ABAP object reuse, upgrade-safe, and compliant with clean core via embedded Steampunk in-app extensions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answer: a, c&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;a&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is correct — Realize phase configuration is based on the signed backlog, and scope changes go through governance.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;c&lt;/STRONG&gt; is correct — performance tuning and regression testing are part of iterative cycles in Realize.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;b is wrong — you don’t re-open full Fit-to-Standard in Realize, you handle gaps via change requests.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;d is wrong — delaying performance issue resolution violates Activate’s iterative build/test principle.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;e is wrong — skipping governance for new scope breaks methodology discipline.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answer: b&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Store&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;– to purchase SAP and partner solutions with licensing and pricing &lt;/SPAN&gt;options.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Discovery Centre &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– to access guided missions, service setup details, and&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;cost estimations for SAP BTP services.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; – &lt;SPAN&gt;to browse and test APIs, integration content, and event definitions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;– to manage the application lifecycle with monitoring and documentation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10.Answer: a, d&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;a&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;correctly describes the SUM execution from target AAS and the automatic ASCS move dialog offering&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/homogeneous-dmo-and-dmove2s4/ba-p/13551478/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/homogeneous-dmo-and-dmove2s4/ba-p/13551478" target="_blank"&gt;[1]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;d&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;accurately reflects that DMOVE2S4 uses standard DMO (not DMO with system move) and requires manual post-processing of filesystems and configurations&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;b is incorrect because ASCS is NOT pre-installed; it's created during SUM execution&lt;BR /&gt;c&amp;nbsp;is incorrect because SUM runs entirely from the target AAS, not from source PAS&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This enhanced version tests deeper understanding of the technical architecture, timing of component installations, and post-migration considerations specific to DMOVE2S4 methodology.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;11.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answer: a, c&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;a&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;correctly describes the traditional PFCG approach with proper profile generation and user master record comparison&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;c&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;accurately reflects using SU01 for user-to-role assignments with validity period management and user comparison process&lt;BR /&gt;b is incorrect - profiles should never be directly assigned to user master records without proper generation&lt;BR /&gt;d&amp;nbsp;describes S/4HANA Cloud functionality, not Private Edition capabilities&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;12.Answer: b&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A&lt;SPAN&gt; is incorrect: Migration Cockpit is included in S/4HANA licenses and supports comprehensive data migration beyond just manual staging table creation [&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/implementing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/migrating-data-to-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition_a200507c-9d05-4e05-bc27-34b594a90acf?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;1&lt;/A&gt;]&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;b&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is correct: Migration Cockpit is an integrated tool within S/4HANA that provides multiple migration approaches including staging tables and direct transfer methods, with built-in project management, simulation, validation, and execution capabilities for both master and transactional data [&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3588725" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2&lt;/A&gt;]&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;c&lt;SPAN&gt; is incorrect: While source system add-ons may be required for specific scenarios (particularly for direct transfer from SAP ERP systems), Migration Cockpit supports various deployment options including Private Edition implementations and on-premise to private cloud migrations&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;d&lt;SPAN&gt; is incorrect: Migration Cockpit supports comprehensive migration of both master data and transactional data with built-in capabilities, though third-party ETL tools can optionally be used to populate staging tables [&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/29193bf0ebdd4583930b2176cb993268/a4d4119a2cc9448a98e5d17e6dd0eac4.html?version=2021.000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3&lt;/A&gt;]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Migration Cockpit provides integrated capabilities including migration object modeler (LTMOM), project management features, data validation, simulation modes, and flexible migration approaches specifically designed for S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition implementations&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;13.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answer: b&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;a is incorrect because Private Edition does not use CBC (Central Business Configuration) - that's specific to Public Edition&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/questions-by-partners-on-sap-activate-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/13563290/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/questions-by-partners-on-sap-activate-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/13563290" target="_blank"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;b&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is correct - Private Edition allows full classical ABAP development and uses SPRO-IMG transactions for configuration, providing extensive customization capabilities similar to On-Premise&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s-4-hana-cloud-private-edition-vs-public-edition-vs-sap-hcm-in-rise-vs/qaq-p/12751138/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s-4-hana-cloud-private-edition-vs-public-edition-vs-sap-hcm-in-rise-vs/qaq-p/12751138" target="_blank"&gt;[1]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;c is incorrect because Private Edition supports on-system development, unlike Public Edition which has more restrictions&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/questions-by-partners-on-sap-activate-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/13563290/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/questions-by-partners-on-sap-activate-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/13563290" target="_blank"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;d is incorrect because Private Edition does not use the starter system approach - that's specific to Public Edition&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/questions-by-partners-on-sap-activate-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/13536217/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/questions-by-partners-on-sap-activate-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/13536217" target="_blank"&gt;[3]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;14.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answer: c&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;A is incorrect because SAP Best Practices should never be activated in client 000, which is only a reference client&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3039705" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;[1]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3140618" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;c&lt;/STRONG&gt; is correct as it reflects the critical boundary conditions that must be followed when activating additional scope items or countries in SAP Best Practices&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3140618" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;b is incorrect because demo data activation is optional and can be added later, and demo data cannot be transported via standard mechanisms&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;d is incorrect because the group currency cannot be changed once Best Practices activation starts and must be decided upfront&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3140618" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3268525" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;[3]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Key Learning Points:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP Best Practices activation has strict boundary conditions for additional activations&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3140618" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;System upgrades and configuration changes to already activated countries can cause activation errors&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3140618" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Group currency decisions are permanent once activation begins&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3268525" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;[3]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Best Practices should only be used in greenfield implementations&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3268525" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;[3]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;15.Answer: a&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To purchase exam attempts if you don’t have SAP Learning Hub license, you can check the link below:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/content/purchase-certification-attempts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://training.sap.com/content/purchase-certification-attempts&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-specialist-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-implementation-with-sap-activate" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Schedule exam for SAP S/4 HANA Cloud Private Edition certificate&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Share with others and Connect with us!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please leave your comment if you have anything to add!&lt;BR /&gt;If you would like to ask questions, please use the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://answers.sap.com/questions/ask.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;community Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Give us a like and share on social media if you feel it was useful!&lt;BR /&gt;You can check my &lt;A href="https://profile.sap.com/u/Amin_Omidy" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;posts&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;or follow me&amp;nbsp;in People SAP&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40654" target="_blank"&gt;@Amin_Omidy&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks and wish you a happy reading !&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-prepare-for-sap-s-4-hana-private-edition-certification-with-sample/ba-p/14197612"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:00:00.038000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-deploy-a-mcp-server-on-cloud-foundry-with-non-public-access/qaq-p/14199347</id>
    <title>How to deploy a  mcp server on cloud foundry with non public access</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:03:22.911000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marcus_schiffer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/195686</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we try to deploy a mcp server with python FASTMCP on cloud foundry for use in an agentic ai setting. It works well in the default settings with a public route.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, we would like to secure the access to the mcp server and remove it from the public access. We understand that the apps.internal option is not available in SAP BTP.&amp;nbsp; Trying to route the &lt;A href="https://mcp-server.ourdomain.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://mcp-server.ourdomain.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;through an approuter did not work either since we always get unauthorized ( get token from destinations clientid / pw as well as xsuaa service clientid /pw did not work with the&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;client &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;=&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; MultiServerMCPClient(&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; { &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"simplemcp"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"url"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"https:/approuterurl"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"transport"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"streamable_http"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"headers"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Authorization"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;f&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Bearer &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;{&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;access_token&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;}&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;},&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; }&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; }&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Is there any trick to get this done ? Help is very much appreciated.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Marcsu&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-deploy-a-mcp-server-on-cloud-foundry-with-non-public-access/qaq-p/14199347"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:03:22.911000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/responsibility-management-create-your-rules-5-5/bc-p/14199349#M61657</id>
    <title>Re: Responsibility Management: Create Your Rules (5/5)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:05:12.287000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AshishShahSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1894660</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1438963"&gt;@Gaayathri&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Thanks for your comment - I just double checked the standard responsibility context exists for the workflow template&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;WS0080303&lt;/SPAN&gt; as mentioned by my colleague in this thread&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-no-agents-determined-after-execution-of-responsibility-determination/qaa-p/14197368#M4924448" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-no-agents-determined-after-execution-of-responsibility-determination/qaa-p/14197368#M4924448&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AshishShahSAP_0-1756465158720.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306563i24E851AEB8B1E359/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AshishShahSAP_0-1756465158720.png" alt="AshishShahSAP_0-1756465158720.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have added a custom agent rule in this context as well &amp;amp; linked it to a custom field too.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AshishShahSAP_1-1756465298588.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306566i14AD7340F1DE8883/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AshishShahSAP_1-1756465298588.png" alt="AshishShahSAP_1-1756465298588.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However the workflow is not able to determine the agent from the custom team that we have maintained and rather giving this error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AshishShahSAP_2-1756465357331.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306570i08D6F37C9389C94D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AshishShahSAP_2-1756465357331.png" alt="AshishShahSAP_2-1756465357331.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this because there is no option to &lt;STRONG&gt;add custom "team category" in standard responsibility context&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;amp; there is no standard team category for workflow scenario&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;WS0080303&lt;/SPAN&gt;?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AshishShahSAP_0-1756470788286.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306593i1370371E5CF9CC32/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AshishShahSAP_0-1756470788286.png" alt="AshishShahSAP_0-1756470788286.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ashish Shah&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/responsibility-management-create-your-rules-5-5/bc-p/14199349#M61657"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:05:12.287000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/configuring-time-based-auto-assembly-tbaa-in-sap-digital-manufacturing/bc-p/14199352#M7642</id>
    <title>Re: Configuring Time Based Auto-Assembly (TBAA) in SAP Digital Manufacturing</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:08:49.927000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sunita_sarkar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/411297</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Manoel,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;as of now facing issue to populate sfc&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sunita_sarkar_0-1756465631601.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306571i0936DF7D66F824CD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sunita_sarkar_0-1756465631601.png" alt="sunita_sarkar_0-1756465631601.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/configuring-time-based-auto-assembly-tbaa-in-sap-digital-manufacturing/bc-p/14199352#M7642"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:08:49.927000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/migration-of-an-html-application-from-neo-to-cloud-foundry-environment/qaq-p/14199354</id>
    <title>Migration of an HTML application from neo to cloud foundry environment</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:10:41.339000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abhishek73</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1496760</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;I have a problem to solve. Recently, I migrated an HTML5 application from BTP neo to cloud foundry with the process guided on sap help portal. the application got migrated successfully and also, I migrated my destination from my BTP neo to cloud foundry environment in order to connect my application to backend. But when I preview my application, it shows the error in my ui5.yaml file.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Attached pictures are the screenshots of my ui5.yaml file.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Here's the detailed log of the error in my terminal when I'm using command "npm run start":&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;backend: [{"path":"/sap","url":"&lt;A href="http://pvlhe4decc1.lthe.com:8101" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;http://pvlhe4decc1.lthe.com:8101&lt;/A&gt;","client":"110","destination":"S4HANA_DEV"},{"path":"/api/UploadDocumentToSP","destination":"SharePoint","url":""},{"path":"/api/DownloadDocumentFromSP","destination":"SharePoint","url":""}]&lt;BR /&gt;info fiori-tools-proxy ui5: [{"path":"/resources","url":"&lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://ui5.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;","version":"1.108.45"},{"path":"/test-resources","url":"&lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://ui5.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;","version":"1.108.45"}]&lt;BR /&gt;info fiori-tools-proxy debug: 'false'&lt;BR /&gt;info backend-proxy-middleware Using destination: S4HANA_DEV&lt;BR /&gt;info backend-proxy-middleware Backend proxy created for &lt;A href="https://S4HANA_DEV.dest" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://S4HANA_DEV.dest&lt;/A&gt; /sap&lt;BR /&gt;error fiori-tools-proxy Failed to register backend for /api/UploadDocumentToSP. Check configuration in yaml file.&lt;BR /&gt;error fiori-tools-proxy Error&lt;BR /&gt;error fiori-tools-proxy Failed to register backend for /api/UploadDocumentToSP. Check configuration in yaml file.&lt;BR /&gt;error fiori-tools-proxy Error&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt; Process Failed With Error&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Error Message:&lt;BR /&gt;Failed to register backend for /api/UploadDocumentToSP. Check configuration in yaml file.&lt;BR /&gt;Error&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone help me with this error?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Abhishek73_0-1756465303067.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306567i1B6D88DEB4D8E763/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Abhishek73_0-1756465303067.png" alt="Abhishek73_0-1756465303067.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Abhishek73_2-1756465340886.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306569iF73DA351845C7E19/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Abhishek73_2-1756465340886.png" alt="Abhishek73_2-1756465340886.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Abhishek&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/migration-of-an-html-application-from-neo-to-cloud-foundry-environment/qaq-p/14199354"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:10:41.339000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-can-i-change-sh-in-delivery-public-cloud/qaa-p/14199355#M206657</id>
    <title>Re: How can i change SH in delivery Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:14:25.665000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;It is strictly &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; recommended to change the Ship-To in delivery. You can change in the sale order and create a delivery which is straight forward approach. On the other hand, if your business scenario requires alternate delivery addresses, consider using:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Partner function ZH (Alternate Ship-To) in the sales order&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Customer-specific enhancements via In-App Extensibility (e.g., custom logic to validate or propose alternate addresses)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Delivery split logic based on Ship-To if multiple addresses are involved&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;For more details, SAP’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/configuring-supply-chain-business-processes-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/setting-up-deliveries_d8c8642e-d590-4052-8598-80607a0b3f00?form=MG0AV3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Delivery Setup Guide&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for Public Cloud explains the constraints and best practices.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-can-i-change-sh-in-delivery-public-cloud/qaa-p/14199355#M206657"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:14:25.665000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/supplier-and-purchasing-group-email-not-picked-in-po-output-message/qaa-p/14199356#M206658</id>
    <title>Re: Supplier and Purchasing group email not picked in PO...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:14:37.631000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sudharmv</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1424185</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks a lot Lakshmipathi for your reply, We went with enhancement solution for determination of emails.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/supplier-and-purchasing-group-email-not-picked-in-po-output-message/qaa-p/14199356#M206658"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:14:37.631000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/hard-currency-values-as-realtime-posting-in-asset-depreciation-area-turkey/qaq-p/14199358</id>
    <title>Hard currency values as realtime posting in asset depreciation area - Turkey POC</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:16:28.167000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ronaldo_meza</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/893312</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear sir/madam,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have added hard currency as parallel currency for ledger postings&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Local currency/Company code currency- USD&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Global currency - USD&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hard Currency - TRY&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we have created new chart of depreciation and created multiple depreciation areas for different ledger postings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;0L - Leading ledger&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;L1- Local ledger&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;T1- Tax ledger&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For L1 ledger for asset postings, we want to have hard currency values as real time posting&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So for ledger L1, we need system to take Hard currency valuess to be posted to GL instead of deriving from company code currency. is there any affect to other ledgers if we make hard currency values as real time posting. Please let us know.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/hard-currency-values-as-realtime-posting-in-asset-depreciation-area-turkey/qaq-p/14199358"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:16:28.167000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/why-community-moderator-is-not-willing-to-moderate-a-spam-what-is-spam-what/qaa-p/14199361#M62031</id>
    <title>Re: Why Community moderator is not willing to moderate a...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:17:13.975000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks. Indeed, lastly I was reporting the individual posts. So, from now on, I'll report only the users.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/why-community-moderator-is-not-willing-to-moderate-a-spam-what-is-spam-what/qaa-p/14199361#M62031"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:17:13.975000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-send-email-notification-to-multiple-supplier-contacts-for-purchase/qaq-p/14199363</id>
    <title>How to Send Email Notification to Multiple Supplier Contacts For Purchase Order</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:18:25.854000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For Created/Changed/Canceled purchase order, email notification should be sent to multiple contacts from supplier, how to achieve this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-send-email-notification-to-multiple-supplier-contacts-for-purchase/qaq-p/14199363"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:18:25.854000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-send-email-notification-to-multiple-supplier-contacts-for-purchase/qaa-p/14199364#M4225359</id>
    <title>Re: How to Send Email Notification to Multiple Supplier C...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:18:33.955000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Customer,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are two ways to achieve this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) When creating/changing/canceling a specific purchase order, click button You Can Also, select the option of edit output setting, in the pop-up window, in the section Email Settings, click Add Row to add email address. This output change only applies to this specific purchase order.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) In the master data of supplier, select tab Communication, select sub tab Collaboration, select business document Purchase Order, in the below, select Add Row to add email address. This output change applies to all purchase order related to this supplier.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Henry&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Support&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-send-email-notification-to-multiple-supplier-contacts-for-purchase/qaa-p/14199364#M4225359"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:18:33.955000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/why-community-moderator-is-not-willing-to-moderate-a-spam-what-is-spam-what/qaa-p/14199366#M62032</id>
    <title>Re: Why Community moderator is not willing to moderate a...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:19:14.207000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Nice, the spam is gone!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/why-community-moderator-is-not-willing-to-moderate-a-spam-what-is-spam-what/qaa-p/14199366#M62032"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:19:14.207000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/ecc-ehp4-to-ehp8-upgrade-phase-prep-install-submod-prep-install-shdinst-db/qaa-p/14199367#M83948</id>
    <title>Re: ECC EHP4 to EHP8 upgrade phase PREP_INSTALL/SUBMOD_PR...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:19:25.275000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rsnit</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7496</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;mh there was misunderstanding, you should not create the user again on your own (because this is the error message of the sum "user already exist") either this was the solution in the mentioned other thread. delete the user again before you repeat sum&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;the privileges for unlimited and resource for OPS$ User should bring you the solution&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/ecc-ehp4-to-ehp8-upgrade-phase-prep-install-submod-prep-install-shdinst-db/qaa-p/14199367#M83948"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:19:25.275000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/to-close-old-stos-with-open-archived-obds-that-have-been-archived/qaq-p/14199368</id>
    <title>To close old STOs with open archived OBDs that have been Archived</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:20:12.088000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ARPITGUPTA09</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1929165</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Can someone tell a standard way to close old STOs with open archived OBDs without unarchiving OBDs.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/to-close-old-stos-with-open-archived-obds-that-have-been-archived/qaq-p/14199368"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:20:12.088000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-can-i-map-by-seeing-the-fields-in-mapping-sheet/qaq-p/14199373</id>
    <title>how can I map by seeing the fields in mapping sheet</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:24:52.662000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>navyamunjam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2129874</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="navyamunjam_0-1756466485136.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306575i1DB33934E1ADB45A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="navyamunjam_0-1756466485136.png" alt="navyamunjam_0-1756466485136.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;first how can I prepare an XSLT file for mapping&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-can-i-map-by-seeing-the-fields-in-mapping-sheet/qaq-p/14199373"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:24:52.662000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/ecc-ehp4-to-ehp8-upgrade-phase-prep-install-submod-prep-install-shdinst-db/qaa-p/14199375#M83949</id>
    <title>Re: ECC EHP4 to EHP8 upgrade phase PREP_INSTALL/SUBMOD_PR...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:25:16.246000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>raheelqaiser</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/626233</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I have tried it several times (Del the user and Repeat the SUM) but no success!!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/ecc-ehp4-to-ehp8-upgrade-phase-prep-install-submod-prep-install-shdinst-db/qaa-p/14199375#M83949"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:25:16.246000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap%E3%81%A7%E5%AE%9F%E7%8F%BE%E3%81%99%E3%82%8B%E3%82%B5%E3%83%96%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%97%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E7%AE%A1%E7%90%86-2%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B5%E3%83%96%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%97%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E3%83%93%E3%82%B8%E3%83%8D%E3%82%B9%E6%88%90%E5%8A%9F%E3%81%AE%E9%8D%B5-q2c%E3%82%BD%E3%83%AA%E3%83%A5%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E3%81%A8%E3%81%AF/ba-p/14199377</id>
    <title>SAPで実現するサブスクリプション管理#2ーサブスクリプションビジネス成功の鍵：Q2Cソリューションとは</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:25:32.101000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryutaro_Koizumi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1387811</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="SAPで実現するサブスクリプション管理#1―あらゆる業界で進む「所有から利用」への大転換 - SAP Community" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap%E3%81%A7%E5%AE%9F%E7%8F%BE%E3%81%99%E3%82%8B%E3%82%B5%E3%83%96%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%97%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E7%AE%A1%E7%90%86-1-%E3%81%82%E3%82%89%E3%82%86%E3%82%8B%E6%A5%AD%E7%95%8C%E3%81%A7%E9%80%B2%E3%82%80-%E6%89%80%E6%9C%89%E3%81%8B%E3%82%89%E5%88%A9%E7%94%A8-%E3%81%B8%E3%81%AE%E5%A4%A7%E8%BB%A2%E6%8F%9B/ba-p/14182714" target="_self"&gt;前回の記事&lt;/A&gt;では、サブスクリプションが今後のビジネス成長に欠かせないモデルである一方、多くの企業がIT&lt;SPAN&gt;システム面での課題に直面していることをお伝えしました。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;では、こうした課題をどう解決し、サブスクリプションビジネスを軌道に乗せればよいのでしょうか。その答えとなるのが &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q2C&lt;SPAN&gt;（&lt;/SPAN&gt;Quote-to-Cash&lt;SPAN&gt;）ソリューション&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; です。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;今回は、サブスクリプションビジネスを支えるQ2C&lt;SPAN&gt;ソリューションの役割と、その中核を担う &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Subscription Billing&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;および &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;の機能について解説します。（その他のソリューションについては、後日紹介します。）&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q2C&lt;SPAN&gt;（&lt;/SPAN&gt;Quote-to-Cash&lt;SPAN&gt;）とは？&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Q2Cと&lt;SPAN&gt;は「見積もり（&lt;/SPAN&gt;Quote&lt;SPAN&gt;）」から「入金・収益化（&lt;/SPAN&gt;Cash&lt;SPAN&gt;）」まで、顧客取引の一連の流れを統合的に管理する仕組みです。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;従来の「モノ売り」モデルでは比較的シンプルでしたが、サブスクリプションモデルでは次のように複雑なプロセスをシームレスにつなぐ必要があります。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;見積・案件管理&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;SPAN&gt;顧客ごとに異なる料金プランや割引を適用し、見積を作成・管理&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ソリューション販売&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;SPAN&gt;受注・サービス・サブスクリプションを柔軟に組み合わせて提供&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;請求&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;SPAN&gt;定額・従量・使用量ベースを含む正確な請求書の発行&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;入金・収益認識&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;SPAN&gt;会計基準に基づいた売上計上を自動処理&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;改善・拡張&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;SPAN&gt;市場の変化に合わせて、バンドル構成や料金モデルを迅速に見直し&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;サブスクリプションビジネスの成功は、この複雑な一連の流れをいかに効率化・自動化できるかにかかっています。Q2C&lt;SPAN&gt;ソリューションは、その基盤を提供するものです&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryutaro_Koizumi_0-1756466198815.png" style="width: 896px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306573i577FE75104DE6A74/image-dimensions/896x504/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="896" height="504" role="button" title="Ryutaro_Koizumi_0-1756466198815.png" alt="Ryutaro_Koizumi_0-1756466198815.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;複雑なサブスクモデルを支える「&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Subscription Billing&lt;SPAN&gt;＋&lt;/SPAN&gt;S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;SPAN&gt;」&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Subscription Billing&lt;SPAN&gt;は、多様なサブスクリプションモデルに対応した&lt;/SPAN&gt;Q2C&lt;SPAN&gt;プロセスを支援するソリューションです。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;特に&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;SPAN&gt;と連携することで、フロントからバックエンドまで一貫した業務プロセスを構築し、前回の記事で挙げた課題を包括的に解決します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryutaro_Koizumi_1-1756466198818.png" style="width: 921px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306572i9B96D8048A83A1DD/image-dimensions/921x518/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="921" height="518" role="button" title="Ryutaro_Koizumi_1-1756466198818.png" alt="Ryutaro_Koizumi_1-1756466198818.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;課題&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1&lt;SPAN&gt;：複雑な料金モデルの管理&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;解決策&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Web&lt;SPAN&gt;ベースの直感的な&lt;/SPAN&gt;UI&lt;SPAN&gt;で、定額制・従量制・階層制などの複雑な料金体系を柔軟に設定可能。特別なプログラミングは不要で、セールス担当者自身が新しい料金プランを作成できます。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;課題&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2&lt;SPAN&gt;：契約ライフサイクル管理の煩雑さ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;解決策&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;SPAN&gt;契約開始・一時停止・変更・解約までを自動管理。顧客リクエストに応じて契約を変更しても、新料金が自動適用されるため、手作業の負担やミスを削減します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;課題&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3&lt;SPAN&gt;：正確かつ迅速な請求処理&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;解決策&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;SPAN&gt;契約情報と利用データをリアルタイムで連携し、自動で料金計算。月末の煩雑な処理を省き、正確な請求書をタイムリーに発行できます。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;課題&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4&lt;SPAN&gt;：システム間連携の難しさ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;解決策&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Subscription Billing&lt;SPAN&gt;は&lt;/SPAN&gt;S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;SPAN&gt;と標準シナリオでシームレスに統合可能です。受注処理から会計処理・収益認識・決済までデータを一元管理でき、プロセス全体をリアルタイムで可視化可能。さらに、顧客や製品のマスタデータも容易に統合できるため、全社的なデータ整合性を確保できます。&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;【実際の画面イメージ】&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ryutaro_Koizumi_0-1756466531532.png" style="width: 913px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306576i1820B3D541044622/image-dimensions/913x356/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="913" height="356" role="button" title="Ryutaro_Koizumi_0-1756466531532.png" alt="Ryutaro_Koizumi_0-1756466531532.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;まとめ&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;サブスクリプションビジネスの成功は、顧客に提供する価値だけでなく、それを支える堅牢な業務基盤にかかっています。&lt;BR /&gt;Q2C&lt;SPAN&gt;ソリューション、とりわけ &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Subscription Billing&lt;SPAN&gt;と&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;SPAN&gt;の連携&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; は、複雑なサブスクモデルを効率的に運用し、ビジネスをスケールさせるための強力な手段です。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;次回は、実際にこれらのソリューションを導入した企業事例を通じて、具体的な効果やメリットを紹介します。&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;サブスクリプションモデルの導入・拡大をご検討中の方は、ぜひご期待ください。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;共同著者：&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/166724"&gt;@masanobu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap%E3%81%A7%E5%AE%9F%E7%8F%BE%E3%81%99%E3%82%8B%E3%82%B5%E3%83%96%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%97%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E7%AE%A1%E7%90%86-2%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B5%E3%83%96%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%97%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E3%83%93%E3%82%B8%E3%83%8D%E3%82%B9%E6%88%90%E5%8A%9F%E3%81%AE%E9%8D%B5-q2c%E3%82%BD%E3%83%AA%E3%83%A5%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E3%81%A8%E3%81%AF/ba-p/14199377"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:25:32.101000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/include-a-field-to-fiori-app-mass-change-of-purchase-order/qaq-p/14199376</id>
    <title>Include a field to FIORI app Mass change of purchase order</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:25:32.170000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sudharmv</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1424185</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I need to add a PO item field to the FIORI app MASS CHANGES TO PURCHASE ORDER in SAP S/4HANA PUBLIC CLOUD.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I tried&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Adapt UI feature available in the "Mass changes to Purchase Orders" Fiori app. I am not able to add the field Requistioner. it only shows the header fields. Not able to select the item tab for selecting item fields.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kindly advice on the steps to add the item field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/include-a-field-to-fiori-app-mass-change-of-purchase-order/qaq-p/14199376"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:25:32.170000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/release-navigator-for-sap-btp-what-s-new-in-q3-2025/ba-p/14199379</id>
    <title>Release Navigator for SAP BTP - What's New in Q3 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:29:29.609000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chriskollhed</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6181</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Blog Header.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306539i8232E2E073389790/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog Header.png" alt="Blog Header.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Release Navigator for SAP BTP continues to evolve and expand, offering our customers improved resources and streamlined access to product updates. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the Q3 2025 update, we ensured all content is up-to-date and we are excited to announce the addition of a new product page for SAP Customer Data Solutions as well as some cosmetic UI updates. Read more about the details in this blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Check out the release navigator for SAP BTP" href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=book!BO_EC8330B09B97CDBE#slide!SL_120BDFE08096029D" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="What is the RN.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265537i23AA8349B1EA28DE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="What is the RN.png" alt="What is the RN.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="01_New Products.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265540iD87D0E02D3327B78/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01_New Products.png" alt="01_New Products.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Collaborating closely with SAP BTP experts, we've expanded the release coverage by introducing 11 new product pages. These pages compile links to all available release information, such as schedules, pre- and post-release communications, blogs, and more:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Customer Data Solutions, including&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Customer Data Cloud / SAP Customer Identity and Access Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Customer Data Platform&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read on to see what you can find on this new page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1868020934"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Customer Data Solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This page contains specific resources for SAP Customer Identity and Access Management, SAP Customer Data Platform, as well as release resources relevant across different SAP Customer Data Solutions. Here’s a list of all you can find on this page:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Customer Identity and Access Management (CDC)&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Roadmap Explorer: Upcoming Innovations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What’s New Viewer: Release Notes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer Influence Campaign&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Community Tag&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Customer Data Platform&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Roadmap Explorer: Upcoming Innovations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What’s New Viewer: Release Notes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer Influence Campaign&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Community Tag&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;General Customer Data Solutions Resources&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP Newsletter&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enablement Webcasts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Subscription link to Cloud Availability Center&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This page has previously been available via the &lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=book!BO_B3B4A4BF7E057D99#slide!SL_B62D843C1DD43A9A" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Release Navigator for Customer Experience&lt;/A&gt;. Adding this page to the Release Navigator for SAP BTP reflects the move of SAP Customer Data Solutions from the Customer Experience area to SAP BTP. The page in the Release Navigator for Customer Experience will stay online until the beginning of Q4 2025 for everyone to take note and switch out their potential bookmarks or saved links. After that, only the page within the Release Navigator for SAP BTP will remain available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Check out the new page for SAP Customer Data Solutions" href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=book!BO_EC8330B09B97CDBE#SL_CAAC3ED5C2293A81" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="chriskollhed_0-1756462658463.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306540iF2536BB5FBCAFAB9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="chriskollhed_0-1756462658463.png" alt="chriskollhed_0-1756462658463.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=book!BO_EC8330B09B97CDBE#SL_CAAC3ED5C2293A81" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Check it out.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="03_New UX Features.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/163275i474DE9BAA1B6321B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="03_New UX Features.png" alt="03_New UX Features.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this last round of updates, we added new visual elements to all release navigators. The UI updates in the Release Navigator for SAP BTP do not affect functionality or performance and are strictly cosmetical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the home page also known as the Product Specific page, you will notice that our &lt;STRONG&gt;Welcome&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Release Calendar&lt;/STRONG&gt; cards have received a facelift for a fresher look and feel.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Check out the changes in the Release Navigator for SAP BTP" href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=book!BO_EC8330B09B97CDBE#SL_120BDFE08096029D" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="chriskollhed_1-1756463442291.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306544i434F3B481F5CC574/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="chriskollhed_1-1756463442291.png" alt="chriskollhed_1-1756463442291.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="20240827_06_UI Elements_Lightbulb.png" style="width: 28px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/163285i9270D26ED228EC1F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20240827_06_UI Elements_Lightbulb.png" alt="20240827_06_UI Elements_Lightbulb.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;On all pages where you can open informational text boxes by hovering over the lightbulb icon, you will see a slight update to the design of these boxes. Content and functionality remain the same.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="graphic UX changes bubbles.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306564i043B23259402D475/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="graphic UX changes bubbles.png" alt="graphic UX changes bubbles.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;As a reminder&lt;/STRONG&gt;: These pop-up boxes show up on every page with a lightbulb icon at the top and may be moved around on the page or closed once you are done reading them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="02_Update Plan.png" style="width: 906px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266396i7419E65D422332B0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="02_Update Plan.png" alt="02_Update Plan.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For centralized information regarding the release of new features for SAP BTP products and services, consult the &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3430170" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Consolidated Release Schedule for SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding the Release Navigator updates, refer to this update plan:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Content Plan.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306561iD6767BBF155595CC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Content Plan.png" alt="Content Plan.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;*Disclaimer: The schedule is subject to alterations without notice, including potential delays or the integration of changes in subsequent update windows. It doesn't establish a commitment, promise, or legal duty to deliver any material, code, or functionality. Looking into the remaining quarters of 2025, updates will focus on quarterly content maintenance and a steady extension of product coverage. No substantial UI updates are planned for the time being.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="03_Connect.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266399i2FA2535DDFAC6F87/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="03_Connect.png" alt="03_Connect.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Readiness@Scale team within SAP Enterprise Support is driven to ensure release readiness across the SAP Enterprise Support portfolio. Our mission is to empower SAP customers to effectively adopt and utilize innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have feedback or specific requests for content within the release navigator, feel free to contact us.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapinsights.eu.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_egtCPhgGOuO4Iwm?SolutionArea=SAPBTP" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="button provide feedback.png" style="width: 271px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266400i8AA2658279669BCB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="button provide feedback.png" alt="button provide feedback.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don't forget to explore our team’s blogs tagged under &lt;A href="mailto:Readiness@Scale." target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Readiness@Scale. &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy navigating!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Readiness@Scale &amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Enterprise Support&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/release-navigator-for-sap-btp-what-s-new-in-q3-2025/ba-p/14199379"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:29:29.609000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/avalara-configuration-in-sap-business-bydesign/bc-p/14199384#M61658</id>
    <title>Re: Avalara Configuration in SAP Business ByDesign</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:39:15.882000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SLA</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1511033</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have integrated SAP Byd with Avalara and my understanding is taxes now will come from Avalara in the following documents : Contracts, Sales order and Customer invoice. Please confirm if this understanding is right ?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/avalara-configuration-in-sap-business-bydesign/bc-p/14199384#M61658"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:39:15.882000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/activity-rate-planning-amp-activity-rate-calculation-opex-planning-amp-ifp/qaq-p/14199386</id>
    <title>Activity Rate Planning &amp; Activity Rate Calculation OPEX Planning &amp; IFP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:42:40.355000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SANA11</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1696282</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hello all,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can anyone please help me understand the purpose and difference between &lt;EM&gt;Cost Center Activity Cost Rate Planning&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;Cost Center Activity Cost Rate Calculation&lt;/EM&gt; in IFP OPEX? I’m unable to grasp this point. I can clearly understand expense planning, project expense planning, and even activity cost rate planning — but I don’t quite see the need for incorporating &lt;EM&gt;Cost Center Activity Cost Rate Calculation&lt;/EM&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/activity-rate-planning-amp-activity-rate-calculation-opex-planning-amp-ifp/qaq-p/14199386"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:42:40.355000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/abap-7-4-what-is-the-new-program-to-change-released-task-to-unreleased/m-p/14199388#M2042394</id>
    <title>Re: [ABAP 7.4] : What is the new program to change released task to unreleased ?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:45:11.626000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tva</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/522579</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The note mentioned 3132029 cannot be accessed via OSS anymore.... But:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On SolMan it should be possible to delete the ChaRM there (leaving an orhpaned TR in the connected SAP system with a released task). Via SE16, debug to EDIT or DELETE mode change of E070 it should be possible to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Delete the Transport of Copies task&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Change the status of the released task from R (released) to D (changes possible)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;After that, SE01 or SE10 should be sufficient to delete the request/task as per usual if the task would not have been released before.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/abap-7-4-what-is-the-new-program-to-change-released-task-to-unreleased/m-p/14199388#M2042394"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:45:11.626000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/user-id-for-ias-users/qaa-p/14199393#M4225363</id>
    <title>Re: User ID for IAS users</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:47:19.498000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dyaryura</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/103697</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi The EmployeeID only makes sense if you only use employees in your BTP solutions. Most companies have External users or even scenarios with B2B cases. The UUID is inteneded to be the long term solution and has a specific format. mapping the EmployeeID there is incorrect because it won't respect the intended format. Agree with Mathias that some solutions still don't support it but there you can use some additional IAS attribute as of now.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/user-id-for-ias-users/qaa-p/14199393#M4225363"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:47:19.498000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/not-able-to-post-data-to-odata-v4-api-in-s4/qaq-p/14199394</id>
    <title>Not able to post data to OData V4 API in S4</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:47:50.309000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lisin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2071818</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are not able to post data to OData V4 API in S4. We are using Post Query from the query builder and mapped our data to the xsd structure we got. However we are getting error as "XML is malformed".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have already applied note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003266527" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/0003266527&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;, but still no luck.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone please guide.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/not-able-to-post-data-to-odata-v4-api-in-s4/qaq-p/14199394"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:47:50.309000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/webinar-ce-amp-pe-2025h2-regional-pet-session-s-4hana-public-cloud-china/ev-p/14199395</id>
    <title>‌🇨🇳‌ Webinar: CE&amp;PE: 2025H2 Regional PET session — S/4HANA Public Cloud China Localization</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:47:59.071000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OxanaSidorkina</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170162</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Join SAP for an exclusive webinar exploring key aspects of localization in China. Discover the latest updates and innovations — straight from the experts. Don’t miss this opportunity to stay ahead and gain insights!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agenda&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Morning sessions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CE2508 &lt;SPAN&gt;中国本地化财务过账增强 &lt;/SPAN&gt;Huang Suki&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CE2508 &lt;SPAN&gt;中国本地化支付管理增强 &lt;/SPAN&gt;Hu Fiona&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;年大中国区新增业务流程&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scope Item&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;概览 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ying Diao&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Afternoon Session:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;2025&lt;SPAN&gt;年中国本地化增值税管理直连方案功能增强 &lt;/SPAN&gt;Jiang Tia, Ni Raymond&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Registration&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for morning session:&lt;STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/48dbe80f-91c0-4a43-be25-92cad4df8f37@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LINK&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for afternoon session: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/d74da1a9-1461-45d0-8a15-b364265312e0@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LINK&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you want to get more information about the localization topics in China provided by SAP experts, join the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://workzone.one.int.sap/site#workzone-home&amp;amp;/groups/GdjAqeAahGgnmsJdoUZsnv/workpage_tabs/7wtnk2jOOZopM8p8Ru8Dps" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Greater China - Human Capital Management Localization WorkZone group.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/webinar-ce-amp-pe-2025h2-regional-pet-session-s-4hana-public-cloud-china/ev-p/14199395"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:47:59.071000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/import-sales-orders-part-9-creation-with-reference/bc-p/14199396#M184134</id>
    <title>Re: Import Sales Orders (Part 9):  Creation with Reference</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:48:19.006000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lea77</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/133257</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/726252"&gt;@frank_xie&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, correct. But my system is behaving like that:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Sales Quote in SAP created (10 PC TG11)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Sales Order upload with reference to that quote with exact 10 PC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Sales Quote is showing the link in the process flow but the status is "not referenced" = a new sales order can reference the same quote even though it should already be fully referenced.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maybe it is a timing topic and the status will only be updated after some time? Could that be the case?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In your system, does the status of the quote change to "Fully referenced" right after the import?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR, Lea&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/import-sales-orders-part-9-creation-with-reference/bc-p/14199396#M184134"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:48:19.006000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/bc-p/14199399#M184135</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP test cockpit (ATC) recommendations for governance of clean core ABAP development</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:49:48.538000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tom_Major</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1750203</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Very informative, thank you Olga!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/bc-p/14199399#M184135"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:49:48.538000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/i-would-like-to-understand-where-the-tax-information-comes-from-when/qaq-p/14199401</id>
    <title>I would like to understand where the tax information comes from when avalara is integrated with SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:51:32.545000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We have integrated SAP with Avalara&amp;nbsp;.&lt;BR /&gt;I would like to understand where the tax information comes from when PERSON_NAME is integrated with SAP. My understanding is that once we integrate SAP with PERSON_NAME, taxi information or Tax data (or Tax determiantion) in documents like Contracts , Sales orders and Customer Inovoices comes from Avalara. Please confirm if my understanding is correct here?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/i-would-like-to-understand-where-the-tax-information-comes-from-when/qaq-p/14199401"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:51:32.545000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/i-would-like-to-understand-where-the-tax-information-comes-from-when/qaa-p/14199402#M4225365</id>
    <title>Re: I would like to understand where the tax information...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:51:40.148000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Customer,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Avalara AvaTax(Tax Rate Determination Service Provider), maintain tax rates, applicable on sale or purchase of goods and services across the jurisdictions in the US in their side.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you integrate SAP with Avalara, taxi information or Tax data (or Tax determination) in documents like Contracts , Sales orders and Customer Invoices comes from Avalara.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Arjun T H&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Product Support&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/i-would-like-to-understand-where-the-tax-information-comes-from-when/qaa-p/14199402#M4225365"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:51:40.148000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/user-status-without-status-number-box-is-greyed-out-in-webui-change-pm/qaa-p/14199417#M83950</id>
    <title>Re: User status without status number box is greyed out i...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:56:49.804000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KArist</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1966655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your input, memen&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is odd though is that we are already using User Status with status number without any issues in Fiori.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The issue only appears on the User Status without Status number.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/user-status-without-status-number-box-is-greyed-out-in-webui-change-pm/qaa-p/14199417#M83950"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:56:49.804000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ias-notification-for-migrated-users-from-external-sites-learning-only-user/qaa-p/14199422#M47100</id>
    <title>Re: IAS- Notification for Migrated users from External Si...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:58:12.129000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dyaryura</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/103697</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Agree. You'll also have a condition probably in the transformation if you don't want an activation email for everyone. Some users might access using SSO so no local password would be needed.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ias-notification-for-migrated-users-from-external-sites-learning-only-user/qaa-p/14199422#M47100"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:58:12.129000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/reconciliation-account-selection-in-quot-create-supplier-invoice-quot-app/qaa-p/14199424#M254551</id>
    <title>Re: Reconciliation Account selection in "Create Supplier...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:59:32.996000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1469394"&gt;@Kazuhiro_F&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for sharing the screenshots. I understand why there was confusion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud, the reconciliation account for supplier invoices is typically derived from the supplier master data and cannot be modified during the invoice posting process. The behaviour you noticed in one system, where you can select the reconciliation account manually, usually happens under these circumstances&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The supplier is set up as a one-time vendor account group that permits reconciliation account entry.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The reconciliation account is not kept in the supplier master, leaving the field blank when posting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Field status configuration through &lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/2861561" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SSCUI 150001&lt;/A&gt; or related settings permits optional entry.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For standard suppliers, it is best practice to assign a fixed reconciliation account in the master data to ensure accurate reconciliation between the subledger and general ledger. Editable reconciliation accounts should be used only in one-time vendor situations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I recommend examining the supplier account group and reconciliation account configurations in both systems to understand why editing is allowed in one but not the other.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Help Portal – &lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/2700132" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create Supplier Invoice (F0859)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Help Portal – &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/implementing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-sourcing-and-procurement/maintaining-business-partner-master-data_b4f2836d-945e-4ee9-a1b4-312f32d42c6f" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supplier Master Data and Reconciliation Accounts&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/reconciliation-account-selection-in-quot-create-supplier-invoice-quot-app/qaa-p/14199424#M254551"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:59:32.996000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/to-close-old-stos-with-open-archived-obds-that-have-been-archived/qaa-p/14199426#M4225366</id>
    <title>Re: To close old STOs with open archived OBDs that have b...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:00:01.947000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Some of the workarounds when OBDs are archived&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;1. Unarchive Temporarily (if policy allows). &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If your organization permits it, you can temporarily reload the archived delivery using transaction SARI or via Archive Information System. Once restored, you can reverse PGI using VL09, adjust the STO accordingly. After corrections, the delivery can be re-archived. This requires coordination with your BASIS team and may not be feasible in tightly controlled environments.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;2. Manual Closure via ME22N&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If reversal isn’t possible, you can manually set the “Delivery Completed” indicator in ME22N for the STO line item. This tells the system that no further deliveries or GRs are expected. You may also need to adjust the open quantity to match the delivered quantity if the system blocks the flag due to mismatch.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;3. Custom Program or BAPI&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Some companies develop a custom report or BAPI-based tool to mass-close STOs with archived deliveries. These tools bypass standard checks and update the delivery completion flag or final delivery status directly in the backend.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;4. Accounting Adjustments&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If the goods were never received and cannot be reversed, consider posting a manual write-off to a loss account or cost center. This is often done via MB1A with movement type 551 (scrapping) or similar.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/to-close-old-stos-with-open-archived-obds-that-have-been-archived/qaa-p/14199426#M4225366"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:00:01.947000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/budget-excededing-issue/qaq-p/14199439</id>
    <title>Budget excededing issue</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:03:19.325000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MaruthiS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1384053</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Project Creation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;WBS , budget allocation, material Procurement. Production order creation and stock transfer to consume in Production order and final product consumed by other wbs&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/budget-excededing-issue/qaq-p/14199439"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:03:19.325000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/massive-update-the-atp-rule-in-ede/qaq-p/14199442</id>
    <title>Massive update the ATP rule in EDE?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:04:53.451000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ana_Brrios</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2185904</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi. Is there any way we can massive update the ATP rule in EDE and then request the TR to GDE?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/massive-update-the-atp-rule-in-ede/qaq-p/14199442"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:04:53.451000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/import-sales-orders-part-9-creation-with-reference/bc-p/14199444#M184136</id>
    <title>Re: Import Sales Orders (Part 9):  Creation with Reference</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:05:49.521000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lea77</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/133257</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/726252"&gt;@frank_xie&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;there are two more things I would like to ask:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) special price: when referencing a quote during sales order upload, the price from the quote is not taken into account. Instead in the sales order, the usual list price (PPR0) will be used. Whereas with manual Sales Order creation with reference to Quote, the changed or manual price from the quote is used.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) referenced quantity too high: when referencing a quote during sales order upload there will be no warning if the quantity of the sales order exceeds the quantity from the references sales quote. Is that the usual system behaviour?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/import-sales-orders-part-9-creation-with-reference/bc-p/14199444#M184136"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:05:49.521000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-rap-custom-action-print-pdf/qaq-p/14199448</id>
    <title>SAP public cloud RAP Custom action Print pdf</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:08:34.389000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JamesG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1281</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I added a Print button in the RAP BDEF, and within the logic of that button, I called an Adobe Form template. It has already been sent to the print queue. How can I trigger a direct download from the front end?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks advance&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-rap-custom-action-print-pdf/qaq-p/14199448"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:08:34.389000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/sap-cis-sap-ariba-user-provisioning-issue-scim-schema-mismatch/qaa-p/14199449#M180674</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CIS ↔ SAP Ariba User Provisioning Issue (SCIM Sch...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:12:05.084000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dyaryura</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/103697</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Said&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We're using this scenario but to provision UUID as of now and works fine without the need to create an schema, but the attribute we're provisioning is not part of the schema you mentioned. I checked in the documentation and the transformations are using the "...&lt;SPAN&gt;sap&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;ariba:...."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;schema. Did you get an error with the standard provided transformation and then you decided to create a custom schema?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/identity-provisioning/identity-provisioning/target-sap-ariba-applications" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/identity-provisioning/identity-provisioning/target-sap-ariba-applications&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/sap-cis-sap-ariba-user-provisioning-issue-scim-schema-mismatch/qaa-p/14199449#M180674"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:12:05.084000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/calculate-date-diff-formula-on-emp-history-variable-pay/qaa-p/14199452#M47110</id>
    <title>Re: Calculate Date Diff Formula on Emp History - Variable Pay</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:15:19.005000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1779513"&gt;@MuhammadFaizan&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Can you make an example with actual time slices in writing ? Like this :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is what the system retrieves :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;7/1/2022 - 9/1/2022&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;9/2/2022 - 11/3/2022&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is what I want:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;7/1/2022 - 11/3/2022&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Or if the issue isn't in the employee history use screenshots of the worksheet or your bonus plans with the current config and what you are trying to get to.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/calculate-date-diff-formula-on-emp-history-variable-pay/qaa-p/14199452#M47110"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:15:19.005000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/ecc-ehp4-to-ehp8-upgrade-phase-prep-install-submod-prep-install-shdinst-db/qaa-p/14199456#M83951</id>
    <title>Re: ECC EHP4 to EHP8 upgrade phase PREP_INSTALL/SUBMOD_PR...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:22:18.982000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rsnit</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7496</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;if the sap note does not work for you, there is probably something wrong in your underlying layer (database or os environment). what oracle version are you running? are you running multiple ora instances on your sandbox? or is this dedicated machine for only one sap system?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;also check your oracle tracefile/alertfiles of your oracle db&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/ecc-ehp4-to-ehp8-upgrade-phase-prep-install-submod-prep-install-shdinst-db/qaa-p/14199456#M83951"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:22:18.982000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sql-anywhere-problem-with-json-data-with-german-umlauts-wrongly-decoded/qaa-p/14199458#M4924539</id>
    <title>Re: SQL Anywhere: Problem with JSON data with German umla...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:22:52.702000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VolkerBarth</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/352</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the quick response, John - and the hint to a different collation. I cannot currently change the database collation but will be careful in that respect.&lt;BR /&gt;As a workaround I will replace the possibly misinterpreted \uxxxx escape sequences with the actual characters (typically umlauts) when they are followed by two hex digits - and do that before sp_parse_json() is called. This should work as long as they are available in our charset.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sql-anywhere-problem-with-json-data-with-german-umlauts-wrongly-decoded/qaa-p/14199458#M4924539"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:22:52.702000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/service-contract-determination-on-service-orders/qaq-p/14199459</id>
    <title>Service contract determination on service orders</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:27:12.226000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm using the API Service Order A2X (API_SERVICE_ORDER_SRV) to migrate service orders from external systems to S/4HANA Public Cloud. There are some orders which I don't want to link to service contracts, but if I don't, there'll be errors on the UI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a way to select if I don't want service contract determination in a specific order?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you, best regards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/service-contract-determination-on-service-orders/qaq-p/14199459"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:27:12.226000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/service-contract-determination-on-service-orders/qaa-p/14199460#M4225373</id>
    <title>Re: Service contract determination on service orders</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:27:19.976000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the payload for the service order, on item level, you can include the field &lt;SPAN&gt;SrvcContrDetnIsSpprsd, it indicates that the service contract determination is &lt;STRONG&gt;suppressed&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the service order item. Check the documentation &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/6d57d4ab71e5408581e2018320a0ce49/17ee23b18d464e83b473e4416c5e003c.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Service Order Items | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's also possible to configure the service contract determination through this configuration activity: 'Specify Contract Determination Option for Trans. Types' (ID: 103686).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/service-contract-determination-on-service-orders/qaa-p/14199460#M4225373"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:27:19.976000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/badi-is-internal-sap-implementation-in-customer-namespace-not-allowed/m-p/14199461#M2042395</id>
    <title>Re: BAdI is internal SAP; implementation in customer namespace not allowed</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:27:20.165000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>David_mT</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1568992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;You cannot&lt;/STRONG&gt; implement &lt;STRONG&gt;BADI&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;in Z: it is blocked by design.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommended solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: find a &lt;STRONG&gt;released BAdI&lt;/STRONG&gt; for Batch Management via SE18.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If not available: use an &lt;STRONG&gt;enhancement point&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the standard (with caution).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/badi-is-internal-sap-implementation-in-customer-namespace-not-allowed/m-p/14199461#M2042395"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:27:20.165000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/hard-currency-values-as-realtime-posting-in-asset-depreciation-area-turkey/qaa-p/14199463#M4225374</id>
    <title>Re: Hard currency values as realtime posting in asset dep...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:29:18.133000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ndubuisi_PALMER</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2164375</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Ronaldo&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No, activating hard currency real-time posting for ledger L1 only will not affect other ledgers (0L, T1) as long as depreciation areas are carefully mapped per ledger group. The only effect is in ACDOCA entries and reporting, where you will see explicit TRY postings for L1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have you tried the following?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In FI-AA IMG:&lt;BR /&gt;SPRO → Financial Accounting → Asset Accounting → Valuation → Currencies → Specify Depreciation Areas for Foreign Currencies&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a depreciation area linked to Hard Currency (40).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Set it as real-time posting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assign it to ledger group L1 only.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Depreciation Area → Ledger Assignment:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure hard currency depreciation area is not assigned to 0L and T1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/hard-currency-values-as-realtime-posting-in-asset-depreciation-area-turkey/qaa-p/14199463#M4225374"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:29:18.133000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/assertion-faileure-201503/qaa-p/14199464#M4924540</id>
    <title>Re: Assertion Faileure 201503</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:30:39.353000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>johnsmirnios</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/398035</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you are using '-f', you must also move the TEST.log file out of the way. '-f' means it's okay not to apply the redo log during recover if the redo log cannot be found.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/assertion-faileure-201503/qaa-p/14199464#M4924540"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:30:39.353000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/the-salesarrangement-element-is-missing-in-soap-message-despite-the-bp/qaa-p/14199465#M4924541</id>
    <title>Re: The SalesArrangement element is missing in SOAP messa...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:32:52.507000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>milan_10</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150158</uri>
    </author>
    <content>So emberrasing, The Sales Area, where this customer was created is not more active in the system...</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/the-salesarrangement-element-is-missing-in-soap-message-despite-the-bp/qaa-p/14199465#M4924541"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:32:52.507000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/assertion-faileure-201503/qaa-p/14199467#M4924542</id>
    <title>Re: Assertion Faileure 201503</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:35:52.343000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>johnsmirnios</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/398035</uri>
    </author>
    <content>If you can get the database started (see my comment about -f and renaming the .log file), try an unordered unload (dbunload -u) which will prevent the usages of key indexes. Failing that, we have been able to recover some databases if you send it to support.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/assertion-faileure-201503/qaa-p/14199467#M4924542"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:35:52.343000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/cim-master-data-file-upload-error/qaq-p/14199469</id>
    <title>CIM: Master Data File Upload Error</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:38:33.783000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joebe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1457185</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;i wanted to test the new app "Master Data File Upload" to upload payment informations to CIM, but i get the error message "500 Internal Server Error" (see screenshot).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joebe_0-1756471087858.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306594iC56B9B637F85E85F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Joebe_0-1756471087858.png" alt="Joebe_0-1756471087858.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I already added the roles CAP Editor/CAP Admin in IAS to my User and CIM_Replication_Admin on the BTP. Did somebody experience the same error, if yes how did you fix it?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you,&lt;BR /&gt;Benjamin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/cim-master-data-file-upload-error/qaq-p/14199469"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:38:33.783000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/how-to-create-a-user-group-with-limited-permissions-in-sap-customer-data/qaa-p/14199476#M457444</id>
    <title>Re: How to create a user group with limited permissions i...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:39:52.765000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stefaniaZ</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/141529</uri>
    </author>
    <content>hi, I noticed that the problem was resolved, I probably had to wait for the information to spread. Thank you</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/how-to-create-a-user-group-with-limited-permissions-in-sap-customer-data/qaa-p/14199476#M457444"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:39:52.765000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/automatic-clarifications-adjusting-selw1-and-selt1-fields/qaa-p/14199478#M254553</id>
    <title>Re: Automatic Clarifications – Adjusting SELW1 and SELT1...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:41:03.047000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>william_eastman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/196891</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Maybe you could do this differently.&amp;nbsp; when the receivable is posted you could update a field in the receivable which references the payment document.&amp;nbsp; And in the clearing variant you could compare these values to determine if a match exists.&amp;nbsp; Then you could run clarification in mass where if the match is found then it would clear automatically.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/automatic-clarifications-adjusting-selw1-and-selt1-fields/qaa-p/14199478#M254553"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:41:03.047000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/dblog-and-dfs-share/qaa-p/14199479#M4924543</id>
    <title>Re: dblog and DFS share</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:42:54.629000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>johnsmirnios</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/398035</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Did you ever get at response to this issue -- possibly via a support ticket? I know we looked at a DFS issue internally in early March of this year. I doubt it is coincidence.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/dblog-and-dfs-share/qaa-p/14199479#M4924543"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:42:54.629000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/to-close-old-stos-with-open-archived-obds-that-have-been-archived/qaa-p/14199480#M4225375</id>
    <title>Re: To close old STOs with open archived OBDs that have b...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:48:55.915000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ARPITGUPTA09</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1929165</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Lakshmipati&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;1) Organization doesn't allow to unarchive documents.&lt;BR /&gt;2) Since OBDs are showing open in STOs, we are not able to mark them as "Delivery Completed".&lt;BR /&gt;3) We can try, if client agree to this.&lt;BR /&gt;4) POs are 8-9 yrs old.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Note - OBD got created but there was no further processing.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/to-close-old-stos-with-open-archived-obds-that-have-been-archived/qaa-p/14199480#M4225375"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:48:55.915000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/s-4-hana-extensibility-service-instance/qaa-p/14199481#M4924544</id>
    <title>Re: S/4 Hana Extensibility Service Instance</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:50:23.124000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2134306"&gt;@Dipto_Arafat&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The S/4HANA Public Cloud service binding is necessary, as it provides your BTP app with trusted endpoints and credentials for a secure connection to SAP S/4HANA Cloud. While the XSUAA binding secures your app's users, the S4-HANA Public Cloud binding facilitates system-to-system integration through API calls and events. The Destination service stores the runtime connection details used by your code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For side-by-side extension using TypeScript and SAP Cloud SDK, the process is as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a communication arrangement in S/4HANA Cloud.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create and bind S4 HANA Cloud, XSUAA, and Destination services in BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure a Destination to the S/4HANA API.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Download the EDMX from SAP Business Accelerator Hub.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use Cloud SDK to generate TypeScript client code.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your app, call the API via the generated client — the SDK reads the Destination at runtime.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Brief&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;XSUAA → secures the app (users).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;s4-hana-cloud → secures the S/4HANA Cloud link.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Destination → holds API endpoint/auth for runtime use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check below SAP documentation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/da8edbe97a2842c08127474858c90436/1.0/en-US/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud SDK for JavaScript/TypeScript&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-advanced-extensions-with-sap-cloud-sdk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learning Journey – Develop Extensions with SAP Cloud SDK&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/s-4-hana-extensibility-service-instance/qaa-p/14199481#M4924544"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:50:23.124000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-blog-posts/bem-vindos-%C3%A0-comunidade-sap-de-belo-horizonte-e-regi%C3%A3o/bc-p/14199484#M40</id>
    <title>Re: 🌟 Bem-Vindos à Comunidade SAP de Belo Horizonte e Região!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:57:24.793000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rafael_Teixeira88</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2165051</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Bom dia a todos, sou de Minas e atualmente estou em um projeto de implementação do S4 em Divinópolis,&amp;nbsp; é um prazer fazer parte desta comunidade, poder aprender um poquinho com os "mestres" e poder contribuir&amp;nbsp; um pouco também. Sou SD e pretendo me certificar este ano, mas também estou me aventurando em ABAP, CDS e BTP. O SAP entrou na minha vida a mais ou menos 3 anos quando implantamos na empresa que eu era analista de TI e posso dizer que foi amor a primeira vista, simplesmente mudou a minha vida e a minha forma de pensar. Um forte abraço a todos.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-blog-posts/bem-vindos-%C3%A0-comunidade-sap-de-belo-horizonte-e-regi%C3%A3o/bc-p/14199484#M40"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:57:24.793000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fms-in-good-issue/qaa-p/14199485#M4225376</id>
    <title>Re: FMS In Good Issue</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T14:59:45.795000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>user2001</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2127356</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476992"&gt;@Felipe_Lima&lt;/a&gt; but the problem is it would mean updating the FMS query everytime I add new expense accounts.Can you explain this statement in maybe simple way.'This happens because cost centres are bound to the GL in the setting "relevant for cost accounting". BS accounts ideally won't be cost-relevant, so CC fields are "nulled" by SAP. P&amp;amp;L GLs tend to be cost-relevant, so SAP will try to pick the CC from there. If it is null, SAP does the same as the BS, if not, the CC will be pulled from there. ".i am confused as a beginner. Thanks</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fms-in-good-issue/qaa-p/14199485#M4225376"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T14:59:45.795000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/missing-document-generation-option-in-profile/qaa-p/14199486#M47111</id>
    <title>Re: Missing Document Generation Option in Profile</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:00:19.904000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>M_Anzer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1424105</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Kindly refer to this article:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0002310843" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2310843 - Document Generation: Unable to 'Generate Document' as Self Service (MSS/ESS)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/missing-document-generation-option-in-profile/qaa-p/14199486#M47111"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:00:19.904000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fms-in-good-issue/qaa-p/14199488#M4225377</id>
    <title>Re: FMS In Good Issue</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:04:10.076000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe_Lima</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2127356"&gt;@user2001&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I understand your pain. The hardcoded value FMS is not a dynamic choice, indeed. I've used user-defined tables for such purposes many times, and I think it is the best approach without going further with coding. So you would have a table where all GL to CC mapping is kept, and your FMS would look up values on this table, which streamlines maintenance a lot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding SAP's behaviour, have a look at how GLs are set up in the Chart of Accounts. When an account is of the type "other", it's understood as a Balance Sheet GL (BS), where typically there is no cost assignment, although you may keep a GL in the BS structure of your CoA and set it up as "Expense" or "Sales", which basically tells SAP you want to enable cost assignment. This is a business decision and must be studied to understand the impacts.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Felipe_Lima_1-1756473692091.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306612iE1010AC314EE4B21/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Felipe_Lima_1-1756473692091.png" alt="Felipe_Lima_1-1756473692091.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Either way, when you call an GL in the document, SAP will try to get the CC from the CoA setup. For example, if in your case,&amp;nbsp;5001014 GL has ABC-1234 defaulted to one cost dimension, selecting this account will make SAP enforce this default value and fetch&amp;nbsp;ABC-1234. If there is no CC default, it will enforce NULL (no value), that's why your field gets emptied after the FMS is triggered, as the GL gets populated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I hope it makes sense.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;BR,&lt;BR /&gt;Felipe&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fms-in-good-issue/qaa-p/14199488#M4225377"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:04:10.076000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-site-improvements-new-badges-and-hot-content/ba-p/14197399</id>
    <title>SAP Community Voice: Site Improvements, New Badges, and Hot Content</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:04:54.073000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jerryjanda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/23</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you’re a What’s New regular, you know we’ve been busy since our last newsletter edition on August 15. We’ve launched new progression badge sets (with more coming in September), made several site improvements, and announced a redesign pilot for blog posts.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you missed those updates, we summarize them for your convenience below. We also highlight popular blog posts from SAP and non-SAP members, introduce new groups and topic pages, and cover upcoming events.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Read on to learn more!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1738878695"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Featured Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1800530628"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1604017123"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP Extensibility Guide – Clean Core for SAP S/4HANA Cloud &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;SAP’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6638"&gt;@OlgaDolinskaja&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;gives a breakdown of new clean-core extensibility guidance and explains how the ABAP extensibility guide has been updated with guidelines that align with and support the clean-core level concept for the classification of custom extensions. You won’t want to miss this post and its lively thread!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-extensibility-guide-clean-core-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-august-2025/ba-p/14175399" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1407503618"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1210990113"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing the New AI Adapter for SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148179"&gt;@Punith_Oswal&lt;/a&gt;, one of our &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/sap-champions/ba-p/13988156" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Champions&lt;/A&gt;, has a question for you: Have you ever wished that your iFlow could talk to ChatGPT? If you answered yes, you’ll want to take some time out of your day to read this post. And if you answered no, I still feel pretty positive you’ll enjoy this contribution.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ci-just-started-talking-to-ai-introducing-the-new-ai-adapter-for-sap/ba-p/14170748" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1014476608"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-817963103"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Series: SAP UX Q3/2025 Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;A new series from SAP’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149639"&gt;@ThomasReiss&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;provides an overview of user experience innovations in the cloud from the last six months, covering the whole portfolio, such as AI and Joule, SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508, and SAP SuccessFactors, as well as detailing innovations in SAP’s UI technologies for building great UX.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-ux-q3-2025-update-part-1-ai-joule-sap-build-work-zone-sap-mobile-start/ba-p/14161847" target="_blank"&gt;Start with the first post, which contains links to the entire series&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-621449598"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model with Local App Previews &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I’m happy to see our &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/sap-champions/ba-p/13988156" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Champions&lt;/A&gt; have been so active with their blogging this month!&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/789"&gt;@MioYasutake&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;has written a short blog post detailing experiences while trying out virtual endpoints with SAP Cloud Application Programming Model with Node.js. The post covers findings while testing local previews.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/cap-with-local-app-previews-tips-for-smooth-development/ba-p/14182208" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-166770655"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Community News&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-228422588"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badges, Badges, and More Badges!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Long-time SAP Community members may remember the days when they could earn sets of badges for ongoing positive contributions. Well, we’ve brought these progression badges back! This week, we rolled out four new badges based on the number of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/thumbs-up-for-the-new-kudos-received-progression-badges/ba-p/14193157" target="_blank"&gt;kudos received&lt;/A&gt;. Last week we assigned badges for providing &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bringing-back-badges-to-reward-q-amp-a-experts/ba-p/14182870" target="_blank"&gt;solutions to questions&lt;/A&gt;. And there are more badges coming in the weeks ahead. With these badges, we’re once again recognizing active members and encouraging everyone to make our community a better place by participating more frequently. Make sure to subscribe to &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bg-p/whats-new" target="_blank"&gt;What’s New&lt;/A&gt; so you won’t miss more badge announcements next month!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--465808012"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Features: Dark Mode (Beta) and Events Listings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;A beta version of dark mode is available for SAP Community, and our events listings now include additional filtering options that make it easier for you to find activities of interest to you. You can learn more about these two new features in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-features-dark-mode-beta-and-events-listings/ba-p/14191070" target="_blank"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt;. Experiment with dark mode/light mode to see which presentation works best for you, and try out the various new event filters to find educational and social get-togethers in your area that appeal to you.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--662321517"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your Feedback Wanted for New Design Pilot &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We’re currently running a pilot to test a new layout for blog posts that removes widgets and white space from the right column – based on a &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-feedback-list/change-post-reading-view-to-one-column-layout/idi-p/14101534" target="_blank"&gt;feature request&lt;/A&gt; from members who asked us to improve the readability of these pages. You can learn more about this pilot in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/white-space-begone-new-pilot-removes-widgets-column-from-blog-posts/ba-p/14191534" target="_blank"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt;, and we’re inviting members to share their opinions in the comments there. The pilot concludes on Tuesday, September 23, so please leave your input there before then.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--858835022"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Location Groups Now Available&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We’ve launched (or renamed) three location groups. Our Brazilian members continue to expand our groups in the Americas – with the recent addition of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville/gh-p/joinville" target="_blank"&gt;Joinville&lt;/A&gt;. Over in the Europe section, the former ’s-Hertogenbosch group has switched its name to &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/the-netherlands/gh-p/the-netherlands" target="_blank"&gt;The Netherlands&lt;/A&gt; to accommodate more members in that country. Elsewhere in Europe, we’ve introduced the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/d%C3%BCsseldorf-k%C3%B6ln/gh-p/duesseldorfkoeln" target="_blank"&gt;Düsseldorf-Köln&lt;/A&gt; group to bring together members from those cities. If you’re from one of these areas, you’ll want to join the corresponding group so you can connect with members close to you.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--468542513"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Upcoming Events&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1251862032"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet SAP TechEd Community Speaker Marla Alschweiki&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/82"&gt;@TammyPowlas&lt;/a&gt;, part of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/sap-mentors/ba-p/13988201" target="_self"&gt;our SAP Mentors program&lt;/A&gt;, has referred to the upcoming SAP TechEd event as a family reunion, and so it’s no surprise she’s showing familial-type support for another SAP Mentor,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7391"&gt;@Marla-Schwaiki&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(whom we mentioned in the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-popular-posts-blog-it-forward-site-updates-and-more/ba-p/14181784" target="_blank"&gt;last edition of SAP Community Voice&lt;/A&gt;). In &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/meet-sap-teched-community-speaker-marla-alschweiki/ba-p/14182264" target="_blank"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt;, Tammy explains why you should attend Marla’s community talk in Berlin. We love seeing members supporting members, so if you’re planning to attend SAP TechEd, please make sure to include Marla’s session in your schedule.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1448375537"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find Meetup Events in Your Region&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bg-p/whats-new/label-name/sap%20community%20voice" target="_self"&gt;last two SAP Community Voice newsletters&lt;/A&gt;, we’ve focused on &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/eb-p/codejam-events" target="_blank"&gt;SAP CodeJam events&lt;/A&gt;, but as explained earlier in this edition, our events listings have been expanded to include filters for finding a variety of local activities. Therefore, I’d like to use this edition to draw attention to meetups (also known as SAP Stammtisch events in Germany) in September. Next month, you can socialize with members in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/wien-events/sap-stammtisch-wien-04-09-2025/ev-p/14192248" target="_blank"&gt;Wien&lt;/A&gt; (Austria), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/gurugram-events/sap-tech-night-in-gurgaon/ev-p/14185685" target="_blank"&gt;Gurugram&lt;/A&gt; (India), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/sap-community-meetup-casablanca/ev-p/14192768" target="_blank"&gt;Casablanca&lt;/A&gt; (Morocco), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/dortmund-events/sap-stammtisch-sap-community-meetup-dortmund-10-09-2025/ev-p/14180075" target="_blank"&gt;Dortmund&lt;/A&gt; (Germany), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/cyprus-events/sap-meetup-cyprus-networking-amp-insights/ev-p/14195156" target="_blank"&gt;Cyprus&lt;/A&gt; (Greece), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/brussels-events/sap-inside-track-belgium-september-20th-2025/ev-p/14093107" target="_blank"&gt;Brussels&lt;/A&gt; (Belgium), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/warsaw-events/sap-inside-track-warsaw-2025/ev-p/14177160" target="_blank"&gt;Warsaw&lt;/A&gt; (Poland), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/lingen-events/golf-member-amp-friendsturnier/ev-p/14182945" target="_blank"&gt;Lingen&lt;/A&gt; (Germany), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/bamberg-events/sap-stammtisch-bamberg-09-2025/ev-p/14145466" target="_blank"&gt;Bamberg&lt;/A&gt; (Germany), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/hamburg-events/sap-inside-track-hamburg-2025-registration-open/ev-p/14164575" target="_blank"&gt;Hamburg&lt;/A&gt; (Germany), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/porto-events/sap-inside-track-porto-2025/ev-p/13899698" target="_blank"&gt;Porto&lt;/A&gt; (Portugal), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/rio-grande-do-sul-events/eb-p/rio-grande-do-suloccasion-board" target="_blank"&gt;Rio Grande do Sul&lt;/A&gt; (Brazil), and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/luzern-events/sap-stammtisch-plus-luzern-30-september-2025/ev-p/14142453" target="_blank"&gt;Luzern&lt;/A&gt; (Switzerland). You can find a full list of events &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/events/ct-p/events" target="_self"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;. Make sure to register for an event near you!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-site-improvements-new-badges-and-hot-content/ba-p/14197399"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:04:54.073000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/sap-community-meetup-casablanca/ec-p/14199493#M789</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community Meetup Casablanca</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:05:53.387000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bajadda1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2018609</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;interesting !!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/sap-community-meetup-casablanca/ec-p/14199493#M789"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:05:53.387000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/ukm000-bp-role-assigned-automatically-during-shcm-bupa-sync-s-how-to/qaa-p/14199494#M206660</id>
    <title>Re: UKM000 BP Role Assigned Automatically During /SHCM/BU...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:06:18.445000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GitteGreibe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/173623</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&lt;BR /&gt;You can check whether you have a job running which adds the Credit Management role to your business partners.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;It might have been scheduled in the "Schedule Credit Management Jobs"&lt;BR /&gt;BR Gitte&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/ukm000-bp-role-assigned-automatically-during-shcm-bupa-sync-s-how-to/qaa-p/14199494#M206660"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:06:18.445000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/browser-content-area-in-enable-now-is-capturing-entire-browser/qaq-p/14199495</id>
    <title>Browser Content Area in Enable Now is capturing entire browser</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:08:48.962000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lben</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/119127</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For the past week or so, we've been experiencing an issue where selecting Browser Content Area (as we always have) is capturing the entire browser (similar to Active Window) and not just the content. This happens in both Chrome and Edge...I've tried uninstalling and reinstalling the extensions, clearing the browser cache and cookies, but nothing has worked...I'd guess this was due to a browser update, but for it to happen in both browsers makes it seem unlikely. For the time being, we are using the Region option and manually sizing the capture area to fit the content. This is causing much frustration in our projects and we are desperately trying to find a solution for this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="lben_0-1756472569248.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306602i0C522B1906A13841/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="lben_0-1756472569248.png" alt="lben_0-1756472569248.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/browser-content-area-in-enable-now-is-capturing-entire-browser/qaq-p/14199495"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:08:48.962000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/why-community-moderator-is-not-willing-to-moderate-a-spam-what-is-spam-what/qaa-p/14199497#M62033</id>
    <title>Re: Why Community moderator is not willing to moderate a...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:10:22.729000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnePetteroe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36</uri>
    </author>
    <content>We were literally just a bit behind because the amount of abuse reports we received! And, we are, of course, in parallell also working on other measurements to prevent spam. More to follow soon.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/why-community-moderator-is-not-willing-to-moderate-a-spam-what-is-spam-what/qaa-p/14199497#M62033"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:10:22.729000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/budget-excededing-issue/qaa-p/14199499#M4225378</id>
    <title>Re: Budget excededing issue</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:12:09.107000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Please describe your requirement in detail and what is the error message you were getting. Share that screen shot, so that, it will be easy to assist you.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/budget-excededing-issue/qaa-p/14199499#M4225378"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:12:09.107000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/why-community-moderator-is-not-willing-to-moderate-a-spam-what-is-spam-what/qaa-p/14199500#M62034</id>
    <title>Re: Why Community moderator is not willing to moderate a...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:12:15.877000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnePetteroe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36</uri>
    </author>
    <content>And thank you for only reporting the user, that will save us time &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/why-community-moderator-is-not-willing-to-moderate-a-spam-what-is-spam-what/qaa-p/14199500#M62034"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:12:15.877000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/to-close-old-stos-with-open-archived-obds-that-have-been-archived/qaa-p/14199503#M4225379</id>
    <title>Re: To close old STOs with open archived OBDs that have b...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:17:57.833000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;That is what I also suggested.&amp;nbsp; If PO does not allow to set Delivery Completed, then, you need to go with custom validation to set the PO status closed bypassing the standard validations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/to-close-old-stos-with-open-archived-obds-that-have-been-archived/qaa-p/14199503#M4225379"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:17:57.833000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-note-for-create-xml-transformation-logbr-nf-to-xml-download/qaa-p/14199506#M4225380</id>
    <title>Re: SAP NOTE FOR CREATE XML TRANSFORMATION LOGBR_NF_TO_XM...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:20:39.982000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sptf</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1761838</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;3642384 - Guia de solução de problemas da reforma tributária do Brasil - SAP for Me&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;E4. No código de transação STRANS, não é possível encontrar a transformação "LOGBR_NF_TO_XML_DOWNLOAD" ao executar a etapa manual descrita na nota SAP&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;3618181 - Campos de nota fiscal de pré-requisito para situação fiscal CBS e IBS&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: o &lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;LOGBR_NF_TO_XML_DOWNLOAD só existe no release do sistema S4&lt;/FONT&gt;. Se o seu release do sistema for SAP_APPL, você irá observar que existe outro conjunto de processamentos posteriores manuais, que estão relacionados ao report NOTE_3618181.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-note-for-create-xml-transformation-logbr-nf-to-xml-download/qaa-p/14199506#M4225380"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:20:39.982000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/making-sense-of-sales-org-structures-in-sap-sales-sales-org-sales-office/ba-p/14199508</id>
    <title>Making Sense of Sales Org Structures in SAP: Sales, Sales Org, Sales Office, and Sales Group</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:20:58.138000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogesh__Vijay</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/227756</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When you first look at sales structures in SAP, the terms can feel like they’re all saying the same thing. Sales Org, Sales Office, Sales Group, Sales Unit—it’s easy to get lost. Let’s break it down in a way that actually makes sense.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Sales Org, Sales Office, Sales Group – the classics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Think of these as the traditional building blocks. They’ve been around in ERP and S/4 forever, and they have specific meanings:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Organization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The top level. Usually tied to a country or a large region, like “Germany Sales Org.” It’s also important in transactions (pricing, master data, sales orders, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Office&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A sub-level, often representing a physical office, like “Berlin Sales Office.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Group&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Even more granular, like “North Berlin Sales Group” inside that office.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These units are embedded into the system. They show up in transactions, master data, and user assignments. If a sales rep is tied to a Sales Group, that info automatically flows into quotes, orders, and reporting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Sales Unit – the flexible layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Now here’s the modern twist: &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Unit&lt;/STRONG&gt; is like a flexible overlay that lets you model your structure more creatively. It’s not bound by the strict definitions of Org, Office, or Group.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why use it?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;You want reporting across multiple orgs (e.g., “Europe Sales” across five countries).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;You want to add dimensions that aren’t in your backend (e.g., splitting one office into “Internet Sales” vs. “Direct Sales”).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;You want to restructure without touching the ERP backbone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short: &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Units let you go beyond the rigid ERP structure.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. How they work together&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Here’s the simplest way to think of it:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Org / Office / Group = specific, traditional sales units&lt;/STRONG&gt; that matter for master and transaction data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Unit = the superset&lt;/STRONG&gt; that gives you finer granularity and flexibility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you assign a user to a Sales Unit and they create a sales document (like a quote), the system knows the hierarchy. It pulls in the related Sales Group, Office, and Org automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;So what’s the takeaway?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re defining &lt;STRONG&gt;legal and transactional structures&lt;/STRONG&gt;, stick to Sales Org, Office, and Group.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re defining &lt;STRONG&gt;reporting and flexible structures&lt;/STRONG&gt;, use Sales Units.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s it. No need to overcomplicate. Think of Sales Units as your way to model the real-world sales structure without being trapped by backend constraints.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/making-sense-of-sales-org-structures-in-sap-sales-sales-org-sales-office/ba-p/14199508"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:20:58.138000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/use-table-order-endpoints-from-sap-customer-checkout-manager-api/qaa-p/14199512#M457445</id>
    <title>Re: Use Table Order endpoints from SAP Customer Checkout...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:24:38.442000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RicardoRenteria</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/248336</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you Robin, could you please share some screens to be sure which are those configurations?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/use-table-order-endpoints-from-sap-customer-checkout-manager-api/qaa-p/14199512#M457445"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:24:38.442000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/pgi-and-pgr-in-advanced-returns-management-arm/qaa-p/14199515#M4225381</id>
    <title>Re: PGI and PGR in Advanced Returns Management (ARM)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:25:55.087000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Why PGI works differently in ARM is because, in classic returns, the system treats the SD-FC (Subsequent Delivery Free of Charge) order as a standalone replenishment. You can upload stock directly to the SD-FC sales order item and execute PGI without issue.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;But in &lt;STRONG&gt;ARM&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the SD-FC order is &lt;STRONG&gt;logistically and financially linked to the original return order.&lt;/STRONG&gt; This linkage is managed through the follow-up activity and returns document flow, which changes how inventory is tracked and consumed.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What is happening behind the scenes is when you create a return order in ARM, the returned goods are received into blocked stock (typically via movement type 653). The system &lt;STRONG&gt;tracks this blocked stock against the return sales order and item&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;not&lt;/FONT&gt; the SD-FC order. When you create the SD-FC order, it inherits the reference to the return order. But the system expects the PGI to consume stock from the return order, not from a fresh upload to the SD-FC order. So when you upload stock against the SD-FC order directly, the system doesn’t recognize it as valid for PGI—because it’s not part of the ARM-managed return flow.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What you can do is if you want PGI to work smoothly in ARM:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Always upload or adjust stock against the return order and item.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Ensure the follow-up activity in the ARM return order is correctly set to “Subsequent Delivery Free of Charge.”&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Use transaction MSR_INSPWH if inspection is involved, to release stock from blocked to unrestricted before PGI.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/pgi-and-pgr-in-advanced-returns-management-arm/qaa-p/14199515#M4225381"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:25:55.087000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/qa33-displays-an-inspection-lot-without-usage-decision-but-qvm3-does-not/qaa-p/14199527#M83952</id>
    <title>Re: QA33 Displays an Inspection Lot without Usage Decisio...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:38:42.224000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mark_perkins</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/480681</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks Lakshmipathi. The Dara Source Logic feature that QVM3 only includes REL status was the key as to why this lot with statuses "CRTD PASG SPRQ" was not included in QVM3.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/qa33-displays-an-inspection-lot-without-usage-decision-but-qvm3-does-not/qaa-p/14199527#M83952"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:38:42.224000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-note-for-create-xml-transformation-logbr-nf-to-xml-download/qaa-p/14199539#M4225382</id>
    <title>Re: SAP NOTE FOR CREATE XML TRANSFORMATION LOGBR_NF_TO_XM...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:43:50.752000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cesar_cardoso1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/384049</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Muito obrigado pela ajuda! nossa release do sistema é mesmo SAP_APPL</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-note-for-create-xml-transformation-logbr-nf-to-xml-download/qaa-p/14199539#M4225382"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:43:50.752000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/ui5-routing-issue-in-multi-page-custom-plugin-for-sap-digital-manufacturing/qaq-p/14199541</id>
    <title>UI5 Routing Issue in Multi-Page Custom Plugin for SAP Digital Manufacturing</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:45:18.292000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PhH66</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1661122</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m experiencing an issue when using a custom plugin with multiple pages in&amp;nbsp;SAP Digital Manufacturing. When I route between pages, the&amp;nbsp;“The requested page is not available”&amp;nbsp;bypass page briefly appears before the correct page is loaded. This only happens when navigating between subpages. However, when I route&amp;nbsp;back from the Detail view to the MainView, the navigation works correctly&amp;nbsp;without&amp;nbsp;showing the bypass page. The plugin was uploaded properly as an extension in the&amp;nbsp;POD Designer&amp;nbsp;and was created using the&amp;nbsp;Yeoman Generator.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are the most important code snippets:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;manifest.json (1,2)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Routing in DetailController.js (3)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;MainView.view (4)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Component.json (5)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Structure:&amp;nbsp; MainView.view -&amp;gt; Detail.view -&amp;gt; Over.view.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would appreciate any help or suggestions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PhH66_0-1756474940757.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306627i9E9982F5E1A81EF2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="PhH66_0-1756474940757.png" alt="PhH66_0-1756474940757.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PhH66_1-1756474955988.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306628i2F7132035805A24F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="PhH66_1-1756474955988.png" alt="PhH66_1-1756474955988.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PhH66_2-1756474965038.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306629i6ED9A4081D132612/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="PhH66_2-1756474965038.png" alt="PhH66_2-1756474965038.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PhH66_3-1756474972083.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306630i8673595F1C3F7272/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="PhH66_3-1756474972083.png" alt="PhH66_3-1756474972083.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PhH66_4-1756474979950.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306631i3F9668C17A6529B5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="PhH66_4-1756474979950.png" alt="PhH66_4-1756474979950.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/175657"&gt;@ManoelCosta&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/197200"&gt;@Kevin_Hunter1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/ui5-routing-issue-in-multi-page-custom-plugin-for-sap-digital-manufacturing/qaq-p/14199541"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:45:18.292000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/garden-update-the-raised-bed-went-wild/m-p/14199544#M3258</id>
    <title>Re: Garden Update: the raised bed went wild</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:46:28.639000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vitaliy-R</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Very well done! Unfortunately, the soil in our backyard isn’t suitable for growing fruits or vegetables. We were told that a car parts warehouse used to be located here, and oil would often drip when they emptied the parts. So, we’re considering raised beds as an alternative.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Meanwhile, my wife just bought 15 kg of tomatoes for canning for the winter. When I just hoped to relax after returning from our family holiday &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/garden-update-the-raised-bed-went-wild/m-p/14199544#M3258"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:46:28.639000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/remove-suppress-groovy-script-for-cpi-message-mapping/qaq-p/14199548</id>
    <title>Remove Suppress Groovy script for CPI Message Mapping</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:48:43.093000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Karthik_ramadurai</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1482449</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-java"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import com.sap.it.api.mapping.*

def void removeSuppress(String[] values, Output output, MappingContext context) {
def filtered = values.findAll { v -&amp;gt; v != null &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !output.isSuppress(v) }
filtered.each { v -&amp;gt; output.addValue(v) }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/remove-suppress-groovy-script-for-cpi-message-mapping/qaq-p/14199548"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:48:43.093000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-do-background-scheduling-with-clean-core-including-fiori-apps/bc-p/14199550#M184139</id>
    <title>Re: How to do background scheduling with clean core, including Fiori apps, replacing se38 reports</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:49:01.884000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shashank_Gupta_BTP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2168043</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157846"&gt;@mlauber&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for the blog and explaining steps to create the background job. I can see we can create application logs using 'cl_bali_log' class but in some standard jobs I can see results are generated which are downloadable and are in pdf format. How can we generate those?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shashank_Gupta_BTP_0-1756475312808.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306634i6098117CE82FE070/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shashank_Gupta_BTP_0-1756475312808.png" alt="Shashank_Gupta_BTP_0-1756475312808.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shashank_Gupta_BTP_1-1756475333247.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306635iF7E50A219A446359/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shashank_Gupta_BTP_1-1756475333247.png" alt="Shashank_Gupta_BTP_1-1756475333247.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-do-background-scheduling-with-clean-core-including-fiori-apps/bc-p/14199550#M184139"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:49:01.884000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fms-in-good-issue/qaa-p/14199555#M4225386</id>
    <title>Re: FMS In Good Issue</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:52:42.874000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>user2001</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2127356</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476992"&gt;@Felipe_Lima&lt;/a&gt; Can you please help me with user defined tables.I have not used it before</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fms-in-good-issue/qaa-p/14199555#M4225386"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:52:42.874000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-rap-custom-action-print-pdf/qaa-p/14199557#M4924546</id>
    <title>Re: SAP public cloud RAP Custom action Print pdf</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:55:54.249000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1281"&gt;@JamesG&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To trigger a direct download of a printed Adobe Form (PDF) from the front-end in a RAP (RESTful ABAP Programming Model) Fiori app, instead of just sending it to the print queue, you need to expose the PDF as a stream from your backend action and trigger it from the custom button on your Fiori UI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is the approach I recommend&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your RAP behaviour definition (BDEF), ensure the Print action calls the Adobe Form rendering and returns the PDF file content as&amp;nbsp;RAWSTRING&amp;nbsp;(XSTRING).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use Base64 or binary format to transfer the PDF from the ABAP backend to the Fiori front-end.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Update your Fiori UI logic so that when the print action is executed, the app receives the file content and opens a browser download using Blob/URL.createObjectURL for binary data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following technical steps should support you in that process:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Backend ABAP (RAP) Action:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After rendering the Adobe Form, encode the PDF output as Base64 or provide the XSTRING/RAWSTRING in the response payload. An example is to add the file content to an entity or as an action return parameter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fiori UI (Front-end):&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On Print button press, trigger the RAP action and receive the PDF content.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Convert Base64/RAWSTRING to blob and use JavaScript to prompt file download or open the PDF directly in a new tab.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are some useful References&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-rap-action-to-generate-a-file-to-download/qaq-p/13658358" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Q&amp;amp;A: How to create RAP Action to generate a file to download?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/downloading-excel-or-pdf-file-on-click-of-a-custom-button-using-rap-in-btp/qaq-p/12792200" target="_blank"&gt;Sample workaround for similar download logic.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This process will enable end users to directly download or view the generated PDF from the RAP service without needing to access the print queue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the necessary details. I am happy to help if you have further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-rap-custom-action-print-pdf/qaa-p/14199557#M4924546"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:55:54.249000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/massive-update-the-atp-rule-in-ede/qaa-p/14199570#M4225387</id>
    <title>Re: Massive update the ATP rule in EDE?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:00:02.130000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ndubuisi_PALMER</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2164375</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;please read SAP Help Wiki: "How to setup an APO‑ATP example"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, you can massively update ATP rules in EDE via LSMW/FM or custom program, and then request a Master Data Transport TR from /SAPAPO/AC42 (Extras → Transport) to move them into GDE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do the massive update in EDE via either:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;LSMW (using BDC in /SAPAPO/AC42) Or a Z-report using /SAPAPO/RRP_ATP_RULE_SAVE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After update, go to /SAPAPO/AC42 → Extras → Transport, select updated ATP Rules.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will create a transport request which you can release and move to GDE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/massive-update-the-atp-rule-in-ede/qaa-p/14199570#M4225387"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:00:02.130000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/quot-access-to-path-is-denied-quot-cannot-open-the-solution-in-the-new-sap/qaa-p/14199572#M4924547</id>
    <title>Re: "Access to path is denied", cannot open the solution...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:03:35.088000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AdemFidan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1461885</uri>
    </author>
    <content>hi planteksz, actualy there are some reason for the occured problem "... path denied"</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/quot-access-to-path-is-denied-quot-cannot-open-the-solution-in-the-new-sap/qaa-p/14199572#M4924547"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:03:35.088000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/multiple-ways-to-give-feedback-on-cap-documentation/ba-p/14199559</id>
    <title>Multiple Ways to Give Feedback on CAP Documentation</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:06:20.583000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ren</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13759</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;At CAP, we believe great documentation is a collaborative effort. That's why we've built multiple channels for you to share feedback, report issues, and contribute improvements. Whether you spot a typo, need clarification, or want to suggest new content, we've got you covered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1738940075"&gt;Quick Feedback: "Was This Page Helpful?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The fastest way to give feedback is right at the bottom of every documentation page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ren_0-1756475138757.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306632i4C198466E0AC59CC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ren_0-1756475138757.png" alt="Ren_0-1756475138757.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our "Was This Page Helpful?" widget lets you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Give a quick &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_up:"&gt;👍&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_down:"&gt;👎&lt;/span&gt; rating.&lt;BR /&gt;• Add optional comments (up to 140 characters, dialog opens after you gave a rating).&lt;BR /&gt;• Track sentiment without leaving the page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feedback is collected anonymously through Matomo analytics and helps us identify which pages need attention. It's perfect for quick reactions and brief improvement suggestions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1542426570"&gt;Targeted Survey Feedback&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more structured feedback, click the survey icon in the top navigation bar.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ren_1-1756475306967.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306633iEF5559457CFCF34D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ren_1-1756475306967.png" alt="Ren_1-1756475306967.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This links to our comprehensive SAP Insights survey where you can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Rate different aspects of the documentation.&lt;BR /&gt;• Suggest specific improvements.&lt;BR /&gt;• Share your overall experience with CAP.&lt;BR /&gt;• Provide demographic information to help us understand our audience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The survey typically takes 5-10 minutes and gives us deeper insights into what's working and what needs improvement. Not only for capire but also for CAP overall.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1345913065"&gt;Issues &amp;amp; Bug Reports: GitHub Issues&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Found a problem? Have a feature request? Head to our &lt;A href="https://github.com/capire/docs/issues" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub Issues&lt;/A&gt; page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ren_2-1756475432584.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306638iA1B9A311CE4C759D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ren_2-1756475432584.png" alt="Ren_2-1756475432584.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is ideal for:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Bug reports: Broken links, incorrect code examples, outdated information&lt;BR /&gt;• Content requests: Missing documentation, unclear explanations&lt;BR /&gt;• Technical issues: Problems with the website functionality&lt;BR /&gt;• Enhancement suggestions: Ideas for improving existing content&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;GitHub Issues provide full transparency - you can see what others have reported and track progress on fixes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1149399560"&gt;Direct Contributions: Edit This Page&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;See something that needs a quick fix? At the bottom of every page is an "Edit this page" link that takes you directly to GitHub.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ren_3-1756475486227.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306639i719294297F34DAE2/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Ren_3-1756475486227.png" alt="Ren_3-1756475486227.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There you can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Fix typos and formatting issues.&lt;BR /&gt;• Update code examples.&lt;BR /&gt;• Add clarifications.&lt;BR /&gt;• Improve explanations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This leverages GitHub's collaborative features. The process is as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Fork the repository&lt;BR /&gt;2. Make your changes&lt;BR /&gt;3. Submit a pull request&lt;BR /&gt;4. Get your improvements reviewed and merged&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-952886055"&gt;Learning Resources &amp;amp; Community Contributions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We maintain a curated collection of community learning resources. You can nominate blog posts, tutorials, and other content that helped you learn CAP through &lt;A href="https://github.com/capire/docs/issues/new" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub Issues&lt;/A&gt;. Tag your issue with suggestions for the learning resources page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-756372550"&gt;Contributing to Open Source Projects&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many CAP components are open source with their own feedback channels:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• &lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-js/cds-dbs" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CDS Database Services&lt;/A&gt;: Feature requests and bug reports for database connectors&lt;BR /&gt;• &lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-js/cds-types" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CDS Types&lt;/A&gt;: TypeScript declaration improvements&lt;BR /&gt;• &lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-js/cds-intellij" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;IntelliJ Plugin&lt;/A&gt;: IDE integration feedback&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-559859045"&gt;Which Channel Should You Use?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use the page widget when:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• You want to quickly rate a page.&lt;BR /&gt;• You have brief suggestions (under 140 characters).&lt;BR /&gt;• You don't need to track the response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use the survey when:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• You want to provide comprehensive feedback.&lt;BR /&gt;• You have time for a detailed questionnaire.&lt;BR /&gt;• You want to influence our documentation strategy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use GitHub Issues when:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• You found a bug or technical problem.&lt;BR /&gt;• You need to include screenshots or code examples.&lt;BR /&gt;• You want to track progress on your request.&lt;BR /&gt;• You're suggesting new content or major changes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use "Edit this page" when:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• You can fix the issue yourself.&lt;BR /&gt;• The change is straightforward (typos, small clarifications).&lt;BR /&gt;• You want to contribute directly to the codebase.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-363345540"&gt;What Happens Next?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your feedback doesn't go into a black hole! Here's how we process it:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Page ratings are monitored weekly to identify problematic content.&lt;BR /&gt;2. Survey responses inform our quarterly documentation roadmap.&lt;BR /&gt;3. GitHub Issues are triaged and assigned to subject matter experts if needed.&lt;BR /&gt;4. Pull requests are reviewed by maintainers and merged when appropriate.&lt;BR /&gt;5. Community contributions are highlighted in our release notes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-166832035"&gt;Get Involved!&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The CAP documentation is a community effort. Whether you're fixing a typo or contributing a comprehensive guide, every improvement helps thousands of developers worldwide.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ready to contribute? Start with something small - maybe rate this blog post or leave us a comment. Every&lt;BR /&gt;contribution makes CAP better for everyone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have ideas for improving our feedback mechanisms? We'd love to hear them! Use any of the channels above to let us know.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/multiple-ways-to-give-feedback-on-cap-documentation/ba-p/14199559"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:06:20.583000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-feature-for-the-pipeline-for-cloud-integration-custom-preprocessing/ba-p/14199571</id>
    <title>New feature for the Pipeline for Cloud Integration: custom preprocessing exit</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:07:46.101000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alex_bundschuh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45178</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As mentioned in my last blog post &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-integration-packages-for-the-pipeline-for-cloud-integration/ba-p/14175339" target="_blank"&gt;New integration packages for the Pipeline for Cloud Integration&lt;/A&gt;, we have deprecated the previous package&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/PIPipelineGenericIntegrationFlows/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Process Integration Pipeline - Generic Integration Flows &amp;amp; Templates&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and have shipped four new packages replacing the deprecated package for supporting the Pipeline for Cloud Integration. You will notice that the previous package has the label [DEPRECATED] in its name now. No worries, you can still run the old package in a transition phase, if you run the latest update you will notice that just the name has been changed. But we encourage you to switch to the new packages, see &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/migration-guide-po/migration-guide-for-sap-process-orchestration/pipelines" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Pipelines&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;about how to proceed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One more reason for switching to the new packages, besides the higher flexibility for setting up different pipelines, is that from now on we ship new features in the new packages only. One of the new features that we have lately shipped is the &lt;STRONG&gt;support for custom preprocessing&lt;/STRONG&gt;. You have the option to&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;call a custom exit integration flow without having to edit the provided generic flows. To do so, you must implement a separate integration flow that can be called at the very beginning of each generic integration flow. See &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/migration-guide-po/migration-guide-for-sap-process-orchestration/customizing-pipeline-concept#custom-preprocessing-exit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Custom Preprocessing Exit&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let me show you how to configure the custom preprocessing. You have two options, either configure it globally, which means that the custom exit integration flow is called for all of your integration scenarios, or configure it scenario-specific. You can even combine both options, having one global custom exit which is applied across all scenarios and in addition calling scenario-specific exit flows for particular scenarios only.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1738940129"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Global setting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To enable custom preprocessing globally, you need to configure each generic integration flow that should call the custom preprocessing flow as follows:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the configuration, change the value of the parameter &lt;STRONG&gt;CustomXPreGlobal_Enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt; from &lt;EM&gt;false&lt;/EM&gt; (which is the default) to &lt;EM&gt;true&lt;/EM&gt;. Furthermore, maintain the ProcessDirect endpoint of your custom exit integration flow in the parameter &lt;STRONG&gt;CustomXPreGlobal_Endpoint&lt;/STRONG&gt;, by default the value is&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;/pip/custom/preProcessing/global&lt;/EM&gt;. You can keep it or change it to your preference. You may then create one custom integration flow for each generic integration flow of the pipeline or use one single&amp;nbsp;custom integration flow across all pipeline steps depending on your requirements. See also below.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Exit Global Setting.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306607i0772911C94656545/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Exit Global Setting.png" alt="Exit Global Setting.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1542426624"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scenario-specific setting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For scenario-specific configuration, you can define for which pipeline steps the custom exit integration flow should be called. For this, you need to add the corresponding string parameters to the scenario in the Partner Directory&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;for which the custom preprocessing should be enabled.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a string parameter&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CustomXPreEnabled&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;where &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;you define the list of pipeline steps which should call the exit flow separated by pipe.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In our example in the screenshot below, we enable custom preprocessing for all pipeline steps:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;01 stands for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;either the generic XI inbound processing or the generic IDoc inbound processing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;02 corresponds to either the generic inbound processing flow or the generic integrated messaging runtime&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;04 corresponds to the generic receiver determination flow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;05 corresponds to the generic interface determination flow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;06 corresponds to the generic outbound processing flow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you run through the integrated messaging runtime, which is our recommended pipeline anyway, only step numbers 01, 02, and 06 are relevant. If you only like to run the custom exit flow for the&amp;nbsp;integrated messaging runtime and the&amp;nbsp;generic outbound processing flow for instance, then set the value to 02|06. I think you get the point.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Furthermore, create a string parameter&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;CustomXPreEndpoint&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which points to the ProcessDirect endpoint of your custom exit integration flow. Other than for the global setting, here we only support one custom integration flow across all pipeline steps to minimize the configuration effort, but you can have a separate&amp;nbsp;custom integration flow for each scenario. See how we are able to implement pipeline step specific logic below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Exit Scenario-specific Setting.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306610i10FD7B30905DC99C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Exit Scenario-specific Setting.png" alt="Exit Scenario-specific Setting.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Because we only have one&amp;nbsp;custom integration flow for each scenario, we pass the header &lt;STRONG&gt;customXPipelineStep&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the generic flows to the custom flow. With this, you have the option to implement pipeline step specific logic based on this very header. You can use a copy of the template &lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/integrationflow/com.sap.integration.cloud.pipeline.v2.template.custom.exit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Pipeline v2 Template - Custom Exit&lt;/A&gt; to model your custom flow. It contains a router with routes for all pipeline steps including corresponding router conditions. To ensure that the header value is present in the custom flow, the header is part of the allowed headers settings. Furthermore, the template adds the pipeline step number to the custom header properties so that you have full transparency in the message monitor about which pipeline step called the exit flow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Exit Scenario-specific flow.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306611iCDCD9D819B47CD55/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Exit Scenario-specific flow.png" alt="Exit Scenario-specific flow.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From what we heard from customers, potential use cases could be to implement additional external or internal logging capabilities or to stop certain messages from sending to the receiver systems based on some conditions, e.g. maintained in the Partner Directory. So, regardless of your use case, I think with this we have increased the flexibility of the pipeline for Cloud Integration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-feature-for-the-pipeline-for-cloud-integration-custom-preprocessing/ba-p/14199571"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:07:46.101000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/sap-community-meetup-casablanca/ec-p/14199575#M790</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community Meetup Casablanca</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:09:23.479000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chafikrazouk17</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/105034</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Looks a great opportunity to meet in person with you the Moroccan SAPiers, I'm convinced that it will be an awesome opportunity to all participants.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/sap-community-meetup-casablanca/ec-p/14199575#M790"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:09:23.479000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/quot-access-to-path-is-denied-quot-cannot-open-the-solution-in-the-new-sap/qaa-p/14199577#M4924548</id>
    <title>Re: "Access to path is denied", cannot open the solution...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:09:45.344000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AdemFidan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1461885</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;hi planteksz, actualy there are some reason for the occured problem "... path denied" , step by step check please: 1 Pc Language and Region Settings (EN_US must have additionaly your setup) 2 Clean setup(you need only for Vs22 insatallation(Extension+vsupdate3 +vshell2015)) 3, Permission(I chose different path for C4C like "C:/C4C/..." ; I hope it will be solve your problem))))&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/quot-access-to-path-is-denied-quot-cannot-open-the-solution-in-the-new-sap/qaa-p/14199577#M4924548"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:09:45.344000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-central-business-configuration-blog-collection/bc-p/14199580#M61659</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Central Business Configuration – Blog Collection</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:11:59.402000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FabianAckermann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131646</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New blog alert − Check out our latest blog post: "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Q3 2025: Customer Influence Results for SAP Central Business Configuration" href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3693" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3 2025: Customer Influence Results for SAP Central Business Configuration&lt;/A&gt;"&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-central-business-configuration-blog-collection/bc-p/14199580#M61659"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:11:59.402000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fms-in-good-issue/qaa-p/14199583#M4225388</id>
    <title>Re: FMS In Good Issue</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:13:29.427000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe_Lima</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2127356"&gt;@user2001&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please refer to the SAP's official guide:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_BUSINESS_ONE/134d110d7c9e4d108cdeb3ba3f6fbeb0/1e562cc1cc9240f4beeac48bc2ad3f51.html?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;User-Defined Tables | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR,&lt;BR /&gt;Felipe&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fms-in-good-issue/qaa-p/14199583#M4225388"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:13:29.427000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/is-there-anything-equivalent-to-scwm-cancpick-on-the-cloud-public-edition/qaa-p/14199587#M206661</id>
    <title>Re: Is there anything equivalent to /SCWM/CANCPICK on the...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:13:56.293000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VictorVillarpando</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1453858</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Chuma&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/is-there-anything-equivalent-to-scwm-cancpick-on-the-cloud-public-edition/qaa-p/14199587#M206661"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:13:56.293000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enable-microsoft-copilot-and-teams-to-pass-requests-to-joule/bc-p/14199597#M184141</id>
    <title>Re: Enable Microsoft Copilot and Teams to Pass Requests to Joule</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:16:29.612000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rajmadhavanms79</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6845</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In Step #5 under&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Teams-Bot Application&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;section, it would be good to update the screenshot that says UNVERIFIED.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enable-microsoft-copilot-and-teams-to-pass-requests-to-joule/bc-p/14199597#M184141"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:16:29.612000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/multiple-values-into-the-variable-in-the-sac-script/qaq-p/14199601</id>
    <title>multiple values into the variable in the SAC script.</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:17:16.411000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jakub19</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1840952</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to input multiple values into the variable in SAC script. Something like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Table_xxx.getDataSource().setVariableValue("COUNTRY", ["BRAZIL","PERU"]);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I get the error message saying:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Cannot convert from convert from array of string into Array of VariableValues "&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you help me?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/multiple-values-into-the-variable-in-the-sac-script/qaq-p/14199601"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:17:16.411000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/massive-update-the-atp-rule-in-ede/qaa-p/14199602#M4225391</id>
    <title>Re: Massive update the ATP rule in EDE?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:17:40.059000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ana_Brrios</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2185904</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you very much. This helps!!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/massive-update-the-atp-rule-in-ede/qaa-p/14199602#M4225391"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:17:40.059000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/new-employee-inactive-profile-but-job-information-is-active/qaa-p/14199612#M47117</id>
    <title>Re: New Employee Inactive Profile but Job Information is Active</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:23:07.696000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lucasbizarro58</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/34879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Has anyone found a solution for this issue? it seems the user still has Active_External_Suite even though their Process is Completed.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/new-employee-inactive-profile-but-job-information-is-active/qaa-p/14199612#M47117"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:23:07.696000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/validate-json-message-in-api-management/bc-p/14199613#M175191</id>
    <title>Re: Validate JSON message in API Management</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:23:09.129000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yashpull</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1527562</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;stephen_xue,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Thank you for the wonderful blog!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The policy template works perfectly for handling single exceptions. However, I’ve found it challenging to extend this approach to capture multiple exceptions and return them as an array in the response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do you have any suggestions or best practices to achieve this, so that multiple errors can be collected and returned as an array?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/validate-json-message-in-api-management/bc-p/14199613#M175191"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:23:09.129000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/activity-rate-planning-amp-activity-rate-calculation-opex-planning-amp-ifp/qaa-p/14199617#M4924550</id>
    <title>Re: Activity Rate Planning &amp; Activity Rate Calculation OP...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:24:43.920000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Susanne_Helbig</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46410</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1696282"&gt;@SANA11&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we offer a very detailed documentation for the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrated Financial Planning&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;business content in SAC.&lt;BR /&gt;Please have a look into the topic&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/1cbcff7ccd35405ab445b223c1ab1588/6ac4819142c142cf9fa2d70c8e632d38.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cost Center Activity Cost Rate Calculation&lt;/A&gt;, this should help you to understand the purpose of this story.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additionally, we offer a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/fAWb5ht?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;demo script&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for the content, which is also linked in our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/1cbcff7ccd35405ab445b223c1ab1588/54dde1ad476e4ce984cf1d57949c4dbe.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and is updated on a quarterly basis.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let me know if you're missing any information and we'll update the documentation accordingly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;BR /&gt;Susanne&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/activity-rate-planning-amp-activity-rate-calculation-opex-planning-amp-ifp/qaa-p/14199617#M4924550"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:24:43.920000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
