<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-09-23T11:14:01.887015+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/deployed-objects-not-getting-saved-in-sap-bods/qaa-p/14225208#M4927131</id>
    <title>Re: Deployed Objects not getting saved in SAP BODS</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:23:34.482000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jmuiruri</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1499</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Adding -D flag to the end of the command should display the debug logs which can also be very helpful.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/deployed-objects-not-getting-saved-in-sap-bods/qaa-p/14225208#M4927131"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:23:34.482000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/test-data-conversion-the-accelerator-scaling-smart/ba-p/14225192</id>
    <title>Test Data Conversion, the accelerator: scaling smart</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:23:48.356000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>guruL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125249</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/data-migration-for-test-environment-validation-in-3-system-landscape/ba-p/14220999" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Migration for Test Environment Validation in ... - SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Blog, we explored Test Data Conversion (TDC) and Test Data Refresh (TDR), the potential pathways for test system readiness as part of the 3 SL post-conversion activity. We have also seen the unique value added by both the services. If you're seeking deeper insight into Test Data Conversion (TDC), you're in the right place. In this blog we will see a comprehensive overview of TDC, purpose, and value added by TDC.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer satisfaction is the cornerstone of any business. To ensure a seamless transition into 3 SL conversion, TDC is being offered as a one-time complimentary service to all the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 3 SL conversion customers by SAP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before we delve into the full scope and benefits of TDC, Let’s have an understanding on the key prerequisites for TDC implementation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TDC Pre-requisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To ensure a seamless and efficient data transfer during the TDC enablement process, below key prerequisites must be fulfilled at the system level:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Uniform Software Release Across all tenants:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All Tenants must operate on the same software release configuration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This consistency helps eliminate system discrepancies and ensures reliable data flow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System Configuration Maintenance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A well-maintained System configuration is essential for seamless TDC execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It supports system stability there by reduces integration friction.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Content Version Alignment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All tenants should be in the same content version release.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Version mismatches can lead to errors during data transfer and could lead to incomplete data mapping.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extension Readiness&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ensure all relevant extensions are active and configured with the latest updates.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Handle Your Extensions app will come handy to verify and manage extensions efficiently.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean Development Transport Queue&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Confirm that there are no open transports in the development queue.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The transport queue should be clean to avoid data inconsistency or conflicts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; if you need help with the first three prerequisites, The conversion team will help you to validate and maintain the necessary configurations across tenants. This simplifies the process and ensures readiness for TDC onboarding.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TDC: Enabling Seamless Data Transition for tenant post-conversion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The TDC service offers a powerful solution for transferring reliable data from the development tenant to the test tenant. It supports the migration of:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Master Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="TDC_data.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318592iD75516B7583F6F81/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="TDC_data.jpg" alt="TDC_data.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transactional Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Historical Test Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System Configurations (e.g., Output Management and others)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By this, TDC will not only take care of data, but also help in setting up certain configurations thereby reduces manual setup efforts and accelerate system readiness process. One of the critical components in system setup is the Output Management Configuration. TDC streamlines this process by automatically transferring output management configuration data from the development tenant to the new test tenant. In addition to configuration data, TDC also migrates all available test automation assets, ensuring that testing frameworks and scripts are ready to resume at the earliest.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One of the key concerns during data migration is data privacy. TDC service offers depersonalization as an optional feature, which ensures sensitive information (Workforce data is out of scope) is anonymized during the transfer process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Depersonalization is a broad and critical topic. While this blog focuses on understanding TDC, reference links will be provided below for those who wish to explore depersonalization in detail.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once the data migration via TDC is complete, the system reaches a near-ready state, as a next step initiate Rewiring of Applications as a Post migration step to ensure the alignment of applications with the new test tenant. This step ensures seamless integration with applications and functionality across the system landscape.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Rewiring of apps is beyond the scope of this blog. Kindly refer to SAP help page for those who wish to explore Rewiring of apps in more detail.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With consistent and complete data in place and successful rewiring of apps, the test tenant becomes fully operational. This marks the transition of test tenant from setup to active usage. All available test automation scripts from the development tenant can now be resumed. This helps to validate system integrity, confirm readiness, and ensure smooth performance post conversion.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this Blog, we’ve explored the pre-requisite, scope of TDC. We've also seen how TDC significantly reducing manual effort and saving time during the 3 SL post conversion process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We hope this has provided you with a comprehensive and clear understanding of TDC, its benefits, and its role in enabling a smoother transition to the new Test tenant.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reference:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/data-migration-for-test-environment-validation-in-3-system-landscape/ba-p/14220999" target="_blank"&gt;Data Migration for Test Environment Validation in ... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/3sl-conversion-for-two-system-landscape-customers-managed-by-sap-central/ba-p/13758268" target="_self"&gt;3SL Conversion for two-system landscape customers managed by SAP Central Business Configuration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/s-4hana-cloud-3sl-onboarding-and-initial-system-set-up-series/ba-p/13579789" target="_self"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud 3SL onboarding and initial system set-up series&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/streamlining-3sl-post-conversion-steps-introducing-cias-and-tdc-services/ba-p/14096288" target="_self"&gt;Streamlining 3SL Post Conversion Steps: Introducing CIAS and TDC Services&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/test-data-refresh-service-request-on-sap-for-me/ba-p/14171893" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/test-data-refresh-service-request-on-sap-for-me/ba-p/14171893" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/test-data-refresh-service-request-on-sap-f...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more details about the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Handle Your Extensions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;app and its use, refer to the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/01/25/handle-your-extensions-test-data-refresh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Blog - Handle Your Extensions - test data refresh&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/test-data-conversion-the-accelerator-scaling-smart/ba-p/14225192"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:23:48.356000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/starting-process-chains-in-bw-bridge-from-datasphere-taskchains-csrf-issue/qaa-p/14225211#M4927132</id>
    <title>Re: Starting Process chains in BW Bridge from Datasphere...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:27:10.056000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NauwelaertA</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1418661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40140"&gt;@Dominik_Graus&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, mentioned playing around with the user mapping claim solved the above issue.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank u!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/starting-process-chains-in-bw-bridge-from-datasphere-taskchains-csrf-issue/qaa-p/14225211#M4927132"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:27:10.056000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enabling-agent-interoperability-a-practical-path-from-api-to-mcp-server/ba-p/14203372</id>
    <title>Enabling Agent Interoperability: A Practical Path from API to MCP Server</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:28:10.147000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yarloy_Wang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1879819</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The future of enterprise AI will be driven by the deep and seamless integration of LLMs into existing enterprise products and workflows. To stay competitive, companies must make their vast landscape of existing capabilities directly accessible and usable by AI, empowering a new generation of intelligent ecosystems. This requires a clear strategy for enabling agent interoperability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this article,&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;we will &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;establish that the journey to agent interoperability begins with a foundational pillar: enabling agents to reliably connect with tools (Agent-to-Tool). We'll start by defining the foundational challenge that prevents agents and tools from communicating effectively. We will then introduce the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/docs/getting-started/intro" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Model Context Protocol&lt;/A&gt; (MCP) as a standardized solution and walk through a step-by-step tutorial on how to transform a standard REST API into a fully compliant MCP Server using a cloud-native gateway.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1629994205"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is Agent Interoperability and Why Does It Matter?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agent Interoperability is a comprehensive framework for a complete AI ecosystem, which relies on two fundamental pillars: Agent-to-Agent (A2A) interaction and Agent-to-Tool (A2T) interaction.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While A2A interaction—how agents collaborate and delegate tasks—represents a sophisticated, multi-agent system's goal, A2T interaction is the foundational prerequisite. The ability of agents to collaborate is contingent upon their individual capacity to connect to tools.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Therefore, solving the Agent-to-Tool challenge is the most critical first step towards the broader goal of agent interoperability. While not an Agent-to-Agent protocol itself, solving the Agent-to-Tool challenge is the most critical first step towards the broader goal of agent interoperability: how to let any agent discover and use any external capability in a standardized way.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1433480700"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Foundational Challenge: Connecting Agents to Enterprise Tools&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In an enterprise environment like SAP,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;this challenge presents distinct engineering considerations on both sides of the connection:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On the agent side&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: The challenge is building agents with the autonomy to dynamically discover and utilize a diverse set of capabilities, moving beyond static tool integrations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On the capability side&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;The engineering task is to adapt SAP's vast landscape of powerful APIs for a new type of consumer: the autonomous AI agent.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;The goal is to create AI-consumable interfaces for these existing capabilities, which involves adding the necessary semantic context and standardized formats that agents require for dynamic interaction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This difference in design paradigms creates a natural "Interoperability Gap”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bridging this gap requires a foundational layer for communication: a standardized protocol that enables dynamic discovery and standardized interaction between agents and established enterprise APIs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1236967195"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Solution: MCP as a Standardized Protocol Bridge&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, how do we bridge this "Interoperability Gap"? The solution lies in a shared standard—a common language that both agents and tools can speak. This is where the Model Context Protocol (MCP)&amp;nbsp; comes in.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;MCP is an open protocol that standardizes how applications provide context to large language models (LLMs). MCP provides a standardized way to connect AI models to different data sources and tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We use MCP to build agents and complex workflows on top of LLMs. The key participants in the MCP architecture are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MCP Host&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The AI application that coordinates and manages one or multiple MCP clients&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MCP Client&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A component that maintains a connection to an MCP server and obtains context from an MCP server for the MCP host to use&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MCP Server&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A program that provides context to MCP clients&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-02 at 18.23.05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307786i34101443A9040C2B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-02 at 18.23.05.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-02 at 18.23.05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As for enterprise like SAP, the best practice will be:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757496429561.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312186iAC4A61BEC1A4FF81/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757496429561.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757496429561.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, a protocol is only useful if capabilities adopt it. The enterprise landscape is filled with valuable, pre-existing REST APIs that were not built for this new paradigm. Therefore, a critical first step toward achieving agent interoperability is to bridge these legacy APIs to the MCP standard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The act of transforming a standard API into a discoverable MCP Server is the foundational process for unlocking existing enterprise value for AI agents.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1169536409"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MCP Adoption Strategy in Enterprise Ecosystems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When adopting a new standard like MCP within a large enterprise ecosystem like SAP, there are typically two primary strategic paths to consider for implementation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. The Standard Path:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Platform-Managed Solutions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For most common use cases, the standard approach is to leverage platform-integrated, centrally managed solutions. This path involves using automated services, often provided by the enterprise platform (e.g., SAP BTP), to convert existing APIs into standardized tools. By using unified method for transformation, this approach ensures consistency and manageability across the entire ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. The&amp;nbsp;Flexible Path: Custom or "Native" Implementations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For scenario demanding greater flexibility or more complex business logic, a more custom approach is required. This involves building what can be considered "native" MCP servers. This approach allows teams to build custom implementations using a variety of technologies, such as open-source libraries or different programming languages, giving them full control over the implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This Guide's Focus: A Hands-on Example of the Flexible Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following guide, we will focus on the flexible, native server approach. &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;We will demonstrate a powerful and practical pattern for this by using a cloud-native gateway, Higress, to wrap an existing API. This method is ideal for teams who require full control over the transformation logic and deployment environment, providing a valuable, hands-on example of building a native-style MCP server.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-843940185"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step-by-Step Guide: Transforming API into MCP Server&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To see how this concept works in the real world, let's take a standard REST API and use a gateway to transform it into a fully-compliant MCP server.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our Goal&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Wrap a simple HTTP API as an MCP Server and invoke it from an agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Simple API:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A REST API that returns&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;real-time currency exchange data&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Gateway:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://higress.cn/en/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Higress&lt;/A&gt;, an open-source, cloud-native gateway with a powerful plugin architecture.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Standard:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The Model Context Protocol (MCP), which we'll implement using the Higress MCP Plugin.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Environment:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;A Kubernetes environment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-776509399"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-579995894"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A Modern Transport Protocol: Streamable HTTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before we begin, it's important to understand transport mechanisms for client-server communication we'll be using. This guide utilizes a modern and powerful approach defined by the MCP standard: &lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/specification/2025-03-26/basic/transports#streamable-http%20" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Streamable HTTP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We chose this approach for several key advantages that make it superior for modern AI systems:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified Architecture:&lt;/STRONG&gt; In the Streamable HTTP transport, the server operates as an independent process that can handle multiple client connections. Because the session context is maintained within this single, stateful connection, the need for an external session manager like Redis is often eliminated.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bidirectional and Flexible Communication:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The protocol handles simple request-response patterns efficiently but also enables true bidirectional communication. Server can optionally make use of Server-Sent Events (SSE) to stream multiple server messages. This permits basic MCP servers, as well as more feature-rich servers supporting streaming and server-to-client notifications and requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-383482389"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 1: The Starting Point - A Simple REST API&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the requirement of Streamable HTTP, The server MUST provide a single HTTP endpoint path (hereafter referred to as the MCP endpoint) that supports both POST and GET methods.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To demonstrate the transformation process, this guide will use the ExchangeRate-API, a professional service that provides real-time currency exchange data. We'll use its lasted&amp;nbsp;endpoint, which returns up-to-date global rates based on the US Dollar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;API Endpoint:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://open.er-api.com/v6/latest/USD" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://open.er-api.com/v6/latest/USD&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;A successful request to this endpoint returns a JSON object with a structure similar to this, containing metadata and a nested rates object:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "result": "success",
  "time_last_update_utc": "Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:02:31 +0000",
  "base_code": "USD",
  "rates": {
    "USD": 1,
    "EUR": 0.925,
    "GBP": 0.789,
    ...
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This represents a typical "legacy" capability—useful, but not inherently agent-friendly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-186968884"&gt;Step 2: Preparing the Gateway with Higress&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of modifying the API's code, we'll use a gateway to act as a transformation layer. Higress is an ideal choice because its plugin architecture is designed to extend gateway capabilities, including native support for AI scenarios through protocols like MCP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-119538098"&gt;2.1 Higress Deployment&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First, install Higress into your cluster environment (To simplify, we use k3s as an example).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check your console's node port:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;kubectl get svc higress-console -n higress-system&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once the installation succeeds, you can access the Higress Console in browser by &lt;A target="_self"&gt;http://&amp;lt;your-cluster-external-ip&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;console-port&amp;gt;&lt;/A&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757496799751.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312202i2AEEFF7078F6613E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757496799751.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757496799751.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--152206776"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--348720281"&gt;2.2 Config MCP Server&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once deployed, we need to enable the MCP Server functionality globally by editing the higress-config ConfigMap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;kubectl edit configmap higress-config -n higress-system&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the ConfigMap data, we'll add the MCP Server configuration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;apiVersion: v1
data:
  higress: |-
    mcpServer:
      sse_path_suffix: /sse  # Suffix for the Server-Sent Events connection path
      enable: true           # Enable the MCP Server
      servers: []
  downstream:
    # ... (rest of the config)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--545233786"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--448344284"&gt;Step 3: Transforming the API with the MCP Plugin&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--938260796"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.1 Add a Service Source&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Higress Console, navigate to&amp;nbsp;Service Source page&lt;A target="_self"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A target="_self"&gt;http://&amp;lt;your-cluster-external-ip&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;console-port&amp;gt;/service-source&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and add a new source pointing to our API's address (&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://open.er-api.com/v6/latest/USD" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://open.er-api.com/v6/latest/USD&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757931121414.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314428i214A6174BD4262C4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757931121414.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757931121414.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1134774301"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1331287806"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3.2 Create a Route&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, go to the&amp;nbsp;Route&amp;nbsp;page&amp;nbsp;and create a new route.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click "Route Config" on the left sidebar&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click "Create Route" button&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fill in the form with the following details:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Route Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: exchange-rate-route&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Select&amp;nbsp;Exact&amp;nbsp;and enter&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;/exchange-rates&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Select the service source you just created&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_1-1757931163528.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314430i005F91659DF6F9D8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_1-1757931163528.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_1-1757931163528.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will create a route that matches the path &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;/exchange-rates&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and forwards requests to the service source you created. Now you can see the new route in the list.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this point, Higress will simply proxy requests from&lt;EM&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;/exchange-rates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;to our API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1821204318"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1724314816"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Configure the MCP Server Plugin&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click the&amp;nbsp;Strategy&amp;nbsp;link on your new route and find the&amp;nbsp;MCP Server&amp;nbsp;plugin.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Route Config3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307673i3B89CFE60DE8E011/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Route Config3.png" alt="Route Config3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After enabling the plugin, click "Configure" and switch to the YAML view. This is where we define the metadata that makes our API discoverable and understandable to agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_2-1757931258146.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314431i2976D125D06884AC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_2-1757931258146.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_2-1757931258146.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Paste the following configuration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;server:
  name: "exchange-rate-server"
tools:
  - name: "get-latest-usd-rates"
    description: "Fetches the latest currency exchange rates based on the US Dollar."
    requestTemplate:
      method: "GET"
      url: "https://open.er-api.com/v6/latest/USD"
    responseTemplate:
      body: |-
        **Latest Exchange Rates (Base: {{.base_code}})**
        *Updated at: {{.time_last_update_utc}}*
        
        - **Euro (EUR):** {{.rates.EUR}}
        - **Japanese Yen (JPY):** {{.rates.JPY}}
        - **British Pound (GBP):** {{.rates.GBP}}
        - **Chinese Yuan (CNY):** {{.rates.CNY}}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's break this down:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;server.name: A human-readable name for our new MCP server.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;tools: A list of capabilities this server provides.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;name &amp;amp; description: The crucial metadata for agent to intelligently discover and select this tool when a user asks about exchange rates.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;requestTemplate &amp;amp; responseTemplate: These define how Higress calls the backend API and formats the response. Here, the requestTemplate specifies a simple GET request, and the responseTemplate transforms the JSON output into a clean, agent-friendly format.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Save the plugin configuration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our standard REST API is now exposed as a fully functional and discoverable MCP Server, ready for any compliant AI agent to use.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1627425314"&gt;Step 4: Connecting and Invoking from an Agent with Streamable HTTP&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, any MCP-compliant agent or client can connect to our gateway and use this new tool. To test our new MCP server, we can use any compliant MCP Host app, such as Cline, Cursor, Trae, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For this guide, we'll use &lt;A href="https://cline.bot%20" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cline&lt;/A&gt; as example. It's &lt;SPAN&gt;an autonomous coding agent&lt;/SPAN&gt; that can be&lt;SPAN&gt; installed&lt;/SPAN&gt; as a VS Code extension&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;Configure Cline with the following setting to establish a connection to our new server:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "mcpServers": {
    "exchange-rate-server": {
      "url": "http://&amp;lt;your-cluster-external-ip&amp;gt;/exchange-rates",
      "type": "streamableHttp"
    }
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now you can test the server in Cline:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757931306012.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314432iA494F5F67F1D73A3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757931306012.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757931306012.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1655755128"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this post, we've navigated a practical path toward the broader vision of agent interoperability. We established that the most critical first step is solving the Agent-to-Tool (A2T) challenge: making existing enterprise APIs discoverable and usable by AI agents. We then demonstrated a powerful pattern to achieve this, using a cloud-native gateway, Higress, to transform a standard REST API into a fully compliant MCP Server. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The most powerful takeaway is demonstrating a flexible path to a native server: You've learned how a gateway-centric pattern can be used to build a "native" MCP server, offering full control to teams that require flexibility and customization in their MCP adoption strategy. It means existing, valuable enterprise services can be rapidly integrated into the agent ecosystem, making them dynamically discoverable and usable by any MCP-compliant agent.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solving the Agent-to-Tool problem building the foundation for agent interoperability. With a robust A2T layer in place, the path is cleared for more advanced Agent-to-Agent collaboration, paves the way for a future where countless enterprise services can be seamlessly integrated with agent ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enabling-agent-interoperability-a-practical-path-from-api-to-mcp-server/ba-p/14203372"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:28:10.147000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/dates-and-roundings-in-compensation/bc-p/14225213#M9214</id>
    <title>Re: Dates and Roundings in Compensation</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:29:51.593000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Oltion_Rrumbullaku57</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2225805</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879"&gt;@xavierlegarrec&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your thorough examples on dates. I used the same concept to calculate another variant of proration through dates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyhow, I have to present a column which gets only the dates if the hiring is on this year. I have tried hundredths of variants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I cannot used STRINGs, because I needs the dates in the European format and the system uses US formats. I am basically left in this last option, which shows the date, but the date disappears when the adjacent column is changed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 092854.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318600i3F4B63A63E96DA9F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 092854.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 092854.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/dates-and-roundings-in-compensation/bc-p/14225213#M9214"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:29:51.593000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/tour-processing-in-sap-s-4hana-for-manufacturing-logistics-a-simple/bc-p/14225217#M7719</id>
    <title>Re: Tour processing in SAP S/4HANA for Manufacturing Logistics: a simple introduction</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:39:19.947000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Prashant9316</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2029188</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Even though i have maintained the condition record for Route and PSA bins and WPT, my Route ID is not getting determined at JIT item level.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do you have any idea where to look further ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/tour-processing-in-sap-s-4hana-for-manufacturing-logistics-a-simple/bc-p/14225217#M7719"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:39:19.947000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-setup-authentication-in-external-fiori-app-for-communication-user-of/qaq-p/14225219</id>
    <title>How to setup authentication in External FIORI APP for Communication User of OData in SAP Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:41:54.231000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>G_Sachin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1918343</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have created a new communication arrangement with new user for an Inbound OData Service in SAP PUBLIC CLOUD. I created destination in BTP with SAML Assertion. I created fiori app and deployed on to ABAP CLOUD. Everything is fine. The challenge is end user is already logged into PUBLIC CLOUD and when trying t open app for the first time before loading fiori app Communication User credentials popup is coming. In production there might be N no. of users who use this app. We are struck at a point how to make this authentication happens automatically using End User Credentials or how to setup a streamline for this authentication so that only Cloud Login is enough to load Application automatically. Everything is need to be done in SAP PUBLIC CLOUD not in on-premise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+BTP+cockpit/pd-p/e6ab964e-18d4-49a1-b26b-46827aa6ca66" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1245-1"&gt;SAP BTP cockpit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+BTP+Security/pd-p/842ea649-eeef-464c-b80c-a64b03e40158" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="99-1"&gt;SAP BTP Security&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Fiori+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800000375" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="20-1"&gt;SAP Fiori Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-setup-authentication-in-external-fiori-app-for-communication-user-of/qaq-p/14225219"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:41:54.231000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/fi-document-rounding-problem/qaq-p/14225222</id>
    <title>FI Document Rounding Problem</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:44:51.838000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>volkansen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/882824</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Below I have a FI doc. The selected line is the calculated VAT. Which is EUR 139,49&lt;BR /&gt;If I convert it to TRY by multiplying it with the exchange rate: 139,49 * 47,0414 = 6.561,804886 which is 6.561,8 rounded.&lt;BR /&gt;Why does SAP calculate it 6.561,81 ?&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="volkansen_0-1758611655852.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318596i153AF5FED42A2763/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="volkansen_0-1758611655852.png" alt="volkansen_0-1758611655852.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The sales document consists 4 items. The values can be seen below. Does SAP calculate each line separately, round them and then take a sum? Because if I do that I get TRY 6.561,81&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="volkansen_1-1758612199604.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318597i31B7479D5EF6172E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="volkansen_1-1758612199604.png" alt="volkansen_1-1758612199604.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;P.S. VAT Rate is 10% on these items.&lt;BR /&gt;P.P.S For colleagues in UK&amp;amp;US decimal separator is "," in Turkey &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Private+Edition+Finance/pd-p/caf0b1cb-b985-4cd0-84dd-50b7cf919288" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1259-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Finance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks in advance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/fi-document-rounding-problem/qaq-p/14225222"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:44:51.838000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-record-technical-object-in-change-sales-order-va02/qaa-p/14225226#M4927134</id>
    <title>Re: How to create record Technical Object in Change Sales...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:48:22.220000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alex_frank</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1396482</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;Phuhs,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can set up automatic serial number creation for sales orders in the serial number profile customizing. You have to set procedure SDAU (Serial numbers in SD order) to 04 (Automatic) for your serial number profile.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to influence the automatic numbering via BAdI, you can use BAdI&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;LOSN_SER_NUM_INT_CREATE for developer extensibility (Eclipse ADT) or&amp;nbsp;LOSN_CBO_SERIAL_NUMBER_INT for key user extensibility (Custom Logic app).&lt;BR /&gt;The corresponding help document:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/32da8359c8ee4e8b8e8c5e15cacba5aa/20f4d8b2420544f7a5e41471c5bf5dac.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/32da8359c8ee4e8b8e8c5e15cacba5aa/20f4d8b2420544f7a5e41471c5bf5dac.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;BR,&lt;BR /&gt;Alex&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-record-technical-object-in-change-sales-order-va02/qaa-p/14225226#M4927134"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:48:22.220000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-odata-to-mcp-server-running-on-btp/bc-p/14225228#M175602</id>
    <title>Re: SAP OData to MCP Server running on BTP</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:49:54.017000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Averi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/166101</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9863"&gt;@WouterLemaire&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;I am getting the below error in my trial account, any idea/suggestion how we can make this work? The API endpoint is: &lt;A href="https://api.cf.us10-001.hana.ondemand.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.cf.us10-001.hana.ondemand.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Averi_0-1758613689645.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318606i16B943F314FDF33D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Averi_0-1758613689645.png" alt="Averi_0-1758613689645.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-odata-to-mcp-server-running-on-btp/bc-p/14225228#M175602"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:49:54.017000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/webi-filtre-conserv%C3%A9/qaa-p/14225229#M4927135</id>
    <title>Re: WEBI : filtre conservé</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:52:11.703000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>benasirennes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348531</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Bonjour,&lt;BR /&gt;C'est normal puisque TOUTES les valeurs pour le nom sont sélectionnées : la sélection du prénom reste donc valide.&lt;BR /&gt;Essaye en prenant un prénom qui n'existe que pour 1 seul nom que tu as sélectionné : change de nom de famille et tous les prénoms seront sélectionnés.&lt;BR /&gt;4.3 SP05&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Benoît&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/webi-filtre-conserv%C3%A9/qaa-p/14225229#M4927135"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:52:11.703000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-deployment-in-2025-embedded-vs-work-zone-standard-vs-advanced/bc-p/14225231#M184774</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Fiori Deployment in 2025: Embedded vs. Work Zone Standard vs. Advanced Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:57:05.997000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DWeicht</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1429494</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7118" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Abhishekmodi,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for the detailed blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I have a question regarding the Fiori architectures. You mentioned only two types of architectures: embedded and hybrid in the cloud, utilizing the advanced/standard SAP Build Work Zone editions. My question is: Is the &lt;STRONG&gt;HUB&lt;/STRONG&gt; architecture still supported in SAP S/4HANA 2025?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to SAP, I have not come across any article indicating that the hub architecture is no longer supported from the S/4HANA 2025 version.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Could you please clarify this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you very much in advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-deployment-in-2025-embedded-vs-work-zone-standard-vs-advanced/bc-p/14225231#M184774"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:57:05.997000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-table-title-mirrored-to-the-next-cell/qaa-p/14225233#M4927136</id>
    <title>Re: SAC - table title mirrored to the next cell</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:59:27.881000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sateixeira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2042267</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370"&gt;@N1kh1l&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've tried it before and it doesn't work:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sateixeira_0-1758614423166.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318611i2DB931A1DF81BB01/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sateixeira_0-1758614423166.png" alt="sateixeira_0-1758614423166.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If I remove "Table Title" option as well, the "mirror" line stays, although I don't have the title anymore:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sateixeira_1-1758614495014.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318613i9BFC86460B18F3B0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sateixeira_1-1758614495014.png" alt="sateixeira_1-1758614495014.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Appreciate your help in any case!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-table-title-mirrored-to-the-next-cell/qaa-p/14225233#M4927136"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:59:27.881000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/bi-4-3-report-universe-metadata-missing-for-unchanged-migrated-reports/qaa-p/14225237#M4927137</id>
    <title>Re: BI 4.3 Report / Universe Metadata missing for unchanged migrated reports</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:01:18.980000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>benasirennes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348531</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;BR /&gt;Did you try BIClever's tool name "&lt;A title="BI Clever - CMS Query Builder" href="https://biclever.com/products/cms-query-builder/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;CMS Query Builder&lt;/A&gt;" (free) to extract these data ?&lt;BR /&gt;Else, if you want to repoint your webi documents to new unx universes effortless, have a look to Seenovate's new tool &lt;A title="Seenovate's BOostShift" href="https://www.seenovate.com/blog/boost-propulsez-sap-bo-dans-une-nouvelle-dimension/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;BOost Shift&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Hope this help.&lt;BR /&gt;Benoît&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/bi-4-3-report-universe-metadata-missing-for-unchanged-migrated-reports/qaa-p/14225237#M4927137"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:01:18.980000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/smart-filter-bar-not-visible-after-smart-table-personalisation-in-sap-fiori/qaa-p/14225242#M4927138</id>
    <title>Re: smart filter bar not visible after smart table person...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:03:31.625000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>s_chunduru</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/717777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1921350"&gt;@Anjan_3331&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A few things you might &lt;STRONG&gt;try&lt;/STRONG&gt; to see if they help with the Smart Filter Bar disappearing when a custom default variant is used:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bind to SmartVariantManagement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Try wrapping the SmartFilterBar with a SmartVariantManagement and give both controls stable persistencyKey values. This &lt;EM&gt;may&lt;/EM&gt; ensure the default variant (and visibility) persists across sessions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Try to Recreate the default variant with “Show Filter Bar” on&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;When saving the variant, ensure the filter bar isn’t hidden. Sometimes a hidden flag gets persisted and might be the bar won’t show after re-login cause of a wrongly saved variant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reset personalization and retest&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;In FLP, reset user settings/personalization and rebuild the variant to rule out stale metadata.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Minimal repro&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Try the same in a fresh Fiori Elements template (SmartFilterBar + SmartVariantManagement) to see if the behavior reproduces. If it does, it’s likely config/persistence rather than app logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Collect hints&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;After login, open DevTools and check console/network for variant‐load messages or errors related to SmartVariantManagement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If any of these help, you can narrow it down further; otherwise, sharing a small XML snippet of the filter bar/variant setup might help the community suggest next steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sudheer&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/smart-filter-bar-not-visible-after-smart-table-personalisation-in-sap-fiori/qaa-p/14225242#M4927138"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:03:31.625000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/base-quantity-fixed-lot-size-not-updating-using-bapi-material-savedata/m-p/14225243#M2042493</id>
    <title>Re: Base quantity, fixed lot size not updating using BAPI_MATERIAL_SAVEDATA?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:04:29+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>manfred_fettinger3</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/626372</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;You have to choose cost_view in headdata, then it works!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    DATA:
      ls_headdata   TYPE bapimathead,
      ls_client     TYPE bapi_mara,
      ls_clientx    TYPE bapi_marax,
      ls_plantdata  TYPE bapi_marc,
      ls_plantdatax TYPE bapi_marcx,
      lt_return     TYPE TABLE OF bapiret2.


    "Headerinfos
    ls_headdata-material  = iv_matnr.
    ls_headdata-cost_view = 'X'. 

    "Plantdata
    ls_plantdata-plant    = iv_werks.
    ls_plantdata-lot_size = iv_losgr. 

    ls_plantdatax-plant    = iv_werks.
    ls_plantdatax-lot_size = 'X'. 

    CALL FUNCTION 'BAPI_MATERIAL_SAVEDATA'
      EXPORTING
        headdata       = ls_headdata
        plantdata      = ls_plantdata
        plantdatax     = ls_plantdatax
      IMPORTING
        return         = rs_return
      TABLES
        returnmessages = et_return.

    IF rs_return-type CA 'EAX'.
      IF if_commit = abap_true.
        CALL FUNCTION 'BAPI_TRANSACTION_ROLLBACK'.
      ENDIF.
    ELSE.
      IF if_commit = abap_true.
        CALL FUNCTION 'BAPI_TRANSACTION_COMMIT'
          EXPORTING
            wait = 'X'.
      ENDIF.
      CLEAR rs_return.
    ENDIF.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/base-quantity-fixed-lot-size-not-updating-using-bapi-material-savedata/m-p/14225243#M2042493"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:04:29+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/gl-accounts-missing-in-test-and-production-for-new-company-code/qaq-p/14225244</id>
    <title>GL Accounts Missing in Test and Production for New Company Code</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:04:32.430000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Wayne10</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1649552</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we’re currently setting up a new company code XY. According to our configuration, this company code should have the same GL accounts assigned as company code XX.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, we’ve encountered a strange situation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Test, none of the GL accounts are available for company code XY.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Production, only a few GL accounts appear — most are missing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From what I understand, all GL accounts should have been assigned automatically to XY (mirroring XX).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone experienced something similar? What could cause such discrepancies between Test and Production, or between the two company codes? Any tips on how to troubleshoot or verify the configuration would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there way to mass update the the company code assignments to G/L accounts? How is it possible that in the customizing system all of the G/L accounts are there for company code XY,&amp;nbsp; in Test 0, and in the production only a few appear?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Wayne10_0-1758614362403.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318609i343CC99E654F8855/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Wayne10_0-1758614362403.png" alt="Wayne10_0-1758614362403.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Wayne10_1-1758614395928.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318610iEE95643BC8921137/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Wayne10_1-1758614395928.png" alt="Wayne10_1-1758614395928.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Wayne10_2-1758614516624.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318615i6132EAEBE4C2E1B0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Wayne10_2-1758614516624.png" alt="Wayne10_2-1758614516624.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Images attached of customizing, test, prod.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/gl-accounts-missing-in-test-and-production-for-new-company-code/qaq-p/14225244"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:04:32.430000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/data-not-archiving-from-bsas-bsak-and-bsad/qaa-p/14225246#M4227814</id>
    <title>Re: data not archiving from BSAS, BSAK and BSAD</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:05:21.591000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ibrahim_kourah58</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/835224</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It seems you didnt execute "PostProc" step in TCode SARA for the object FI_DOCUMNT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This step is responsible for deleting those tables contents (BSID, BSAD, BSAK, ...)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will be asked to create a new variant for "PostProc" step (as it is a different program not the same as Write program). Use the same values you used for Write program variant.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/data-not-archiving-from-bsas-bsak-and-bsad/qaa-p/14225246#M4227814"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:05:21.591000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/can-you-add-url-position-links-to-be-pulled-in-a-job-requisition-report-in/qaa-p/14225248#M48158</id>
    <title>Re: Can you add URL Position links to be pulled in a job...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:06:31.256000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CSrivatsav</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2127727</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1460635"&gt;@RdubsDuke&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We can write a business rule to generate a URL but the value is not rendering in hyperlink format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have to use the Concatenate functionality in the business rule while using the substring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CSrivatsav_0-1758614681486.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318617i879E58B02D3C698A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="CSrivatsav_0-1758614681486.png" alt="CSrivatsav_0-1758614681486.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CSrivatsav_1-1758614754894.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318618i4112FD59FF9D523D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="CSrivatsav_1-1758614754894.png" alt="CSrivatsav_1-1758614754894.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/can-you-add-url-position-links-to-be-pulled-in-a-job-requisition-report-in/qaa-p/14225248#M48158"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:06:31.256000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/synchronization-of-serial-no-and-equipment-no/qaq-p/14225249</id>
    <title>Synchronization of Serial no and Equipment no</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:11:55.251000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mohammedrahman4</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1179520</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All ,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can anyone please explain the impact&amp;nbsp; if serial no and equipment no is not synchronized . Please note that we are using Refurbishment Process for serialized and non-serialized material .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanking you&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mohammed&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/synchronization-of-serial-no-and-equipment-no/qaq-p/14225249"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:11:55.251000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extract-selected-data-from-very-large-hana-table-using-sap-data-services/qaa-p/14225252#M4927139</id>
    <title>Re: Extract selected data from very large Hana table usin...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:15:33.303000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ugjust</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/717189</uri>
    </author>
    <content>We originally had the Dataflow, with only the Query (with where) but after 4hrs, the job failed.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extract-selected-data-from-very-large-hana-table-using-sap-data-services/qaa-p/14225252#M4927139"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:15:33.303000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-rap-functions-managed-scenario-not-triggering/qaa-p/14225256#M4927140</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP RAP Functions - Managed Scenario not triggering</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:18:35.896000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vishnucta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6604</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="vishnucta_0-1758615430211.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318621i9FEE93C7A462F2CF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="vishnucta_0-1758615430211.png" alt="vishnucta_0-1758615430211.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="vishnucta_0-1758615622992.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318624i15B72BCEE2E49869/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="vishnucta_0-1758615622992.png" alt="vishnucta_0-1758615622992.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="vishnucta_1-1758615484096.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318622iA56D7B0170F3CE4C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="vishnucta_1-1758615484096.png" alt="vishnucta_1-1758615484096.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="vishnucta_2-1758615505939.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318623iD7ED792DEA8D05DC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="vishnucta_2-1758615505939.png" alt="vishnucta_2-1758615505939.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-rap-functions-managed-scenario-not-triggering/qaa-p/14225256#M4927140"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:18:35.896000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-setup-authentication-in-external-fiori-app-for-communication-user-of/qaa-p/14225257#M4927141</id>
    <title>Re: How to setup authentication in External FIORI APP for...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:18:52.715000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>s_chunduru</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/717777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1918343"&gt;@G_Sachin&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From what you describe it sounds like the app is still using a communication user directly, which is why you’re seeing the credentials popup. In SAP Public Cloud the usual way to avoid that popup is to switch from a technical user login to an end-user SSO / principal propagation type of setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’d recommend working with your SAP BTP architect or Basis/Integration team to set up the trust and destination settings needed for your external Fiori app. With their help you can configure the app and its destination so that once the user is logged in to the Cloud Identity Service, the OData calls run automatically without another login prompt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps point you in the right direction.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-setup-authentication-in-external-fiori-app-for-communication-user-of/qaa-p/14225257#M4927141"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:18:52.715000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extract-selected-data-from-very-large-hana-table-using-sap-data-services/qaa-p/14225258#M4927142</id>
    <title>Re: Extract selected data from very large Hana table usin...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:18:59.359000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ugjust</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/717189</uri>
    </author>
    <content>We originally had the Dataflow, with only the Query (with where) but after 4hrs, the job failed. We then added the Data_Transform and it was successful. We could also see with the Log Monitor in the original job that it was selecting all the data in the table and then applying the where.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extract-selected-data-from-very-large-hana-table-using-sap-data-services/qaa-p/14225258#M4927142"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:18:59.359000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-rap-functions-managed-scenario-not-triggering/qaa-p/14225259#M4927143</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP RAP Functions - Managed Scenario not triggering</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:19:43.982000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vishnucta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6604</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10276"&gt;@Ramjee_korada&lt;/a&gt;any suggestions??&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-rap-functions-managed-scenario-not-triggering/qaa-p/14225259#M4927143"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:19:43.982000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/setting-up-open-payment-framework-in-sap-commerce-cloud-video-series/ba-p/14224652</id>
    <title>Setting up Open Payment Framework in SAP Commerce Cloud - Video Series Walkthrough</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:19:53.023000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cuikenjian</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/41892</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Are you looking to streamline your payment processes within SAP Commerce Cloud? Wondering how to seamlessly integrate payment gateways like Stripe and manage transactions efficiently? Let me introduce you a comprehensive playlist of step-by-step videos designed to guide you through the entire journey of integrating payment services using the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/OPEN_PAYMENT_FRAMEWORK" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Commerce Cloud, Open Payment Framework (OPF)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This curated series covers everything from initial setup to advanced management techniques, ensuring you have all the tools and knowledge needed to build a reliable and secure payment ecosystem with the Open Payment Framework and SAP Commerce Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890039297"&gt;1. Start with Setting Up Your Payment Gateway&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The journey begins with setting up your &lt;STRONG&gt;payment service provider account&lt;/STRONG&gt; - in this case, Stripe (as an application example), a widely used and essential payment processing platform for integrating payments with SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;. The first video walks you through the account creation process:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/creating-a-stripe-account-for-open-payment-framework-and-sap-commerce-cloud-integration" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating a Stripe Account for Open Payment Framework and SAP Commerce Cloud Integration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once your Stripe account is ready, the next step is to connect it to SAP Commerce Cloud through the Open Payment Framework by creating a &lt;STRONG&gt;payment integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/creating-a-payment-integration-with-open-payment-framework-workbench" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating a Payment Integration with Open Payment Framework Workbench&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693525792"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;Configuring Payment Authorization &amp;amp; Testing&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the integration in place, you’ll want to configure how payments are &lt;STRONG&gt;authorized&lt;/STRONG&gt; within SAP Commerce Cloud. This involves &lt;STRONG&gt;initializing&lt;/STRONG&gt; a payment form:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/configuring-payment-authorization-by-initializing-a-payment-form-within-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring Payment Authorization By Initializing A Payment Form within Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To ensure everything works smoothly, you'll learn how to &lt;STRONG&gt;test and troubleshoot&lt;/STRONG&gt; the checkout page, verifying that the integration correctly processes transactions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/testing-and-troubleshooting-the-checkout-page-in-payment-integration-with-the-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Testing and Troubleshooting the Checkout Page in Payment Integration with the Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497012287"&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;Setting Up Verification &amp;amp; Managing Payment References&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following the basic authorization setup, there's a critical step to set up &lt;STRONG&gt;payment authorization verification&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which confirms the legitimacy of each transaction before proceeding:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/setting-up-payment-authorization-verification-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Setting Up Payment Authorization Verification in Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, it's important to ensure accurate tracking of transactions. This is where the necessary &lt;STRONG&gt;PSP mapping&lt;/STRONG&gt; comes into play, allowing you to capture payment identifiers and traceability:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/testing-and-mapping-psp-references-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mapping PSP References in Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1300498782"&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;Optimizing Notifications for Reliable Transactions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the authorization and reference mapping established, the next step is to set up &lt;STRONG&gt;notifications&lt;/STRONG&gt; to maintain transparency and responsiveness in the transaction process. Begin by configuring webhooks to receive real-time updates on payment events:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/configuring-notifications-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring Notifications in Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Building on that, please delve into &lt;STRONG&gt;additional notification mappings&lt;/STRONG&gt;, handling custom fields such as card expiry dates and customer order links, to enhance tracking accuracy:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/configuring-additional-notification-mappings-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring Additional Notification Mappings in Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Last but not least, to secure the notification process, you''ll need to set up &lt;STRONG&gt;notification authentication&lt;/STRONG&gt; with Stripe's HMAC signatures, safeguarding your payment data:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/configuring-notification-authentication-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring Notification Authentication in Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1103985277"&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;Building Dynamic and Secure Payment Configurations&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before proceeding to the capture configuration, it's important to understand that effective management of dynamic data in OPF is achieved through &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;variables&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, which allow for flexible and secure configurations:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/managing-variables-in-open-payment-framework-for-sap-commerce-cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Managing Variables in Open Payment Framework for SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next, we will focus on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;capture settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, guiding you through the API call configurations necessary to finalize payments via Stripe's Payment Intent, ensuring a seamless transition from authorization to capture:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/configuring-capture-settings-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring Capture Settings in Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-907471772"&gt;6.&amp;nbsp;Handling Refunds and Reversals&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A robust payment system needs to support refunds and reversals. You will learn how to map &lt;STRONG&gt;refund&lt;/STRONG&gt; requests for seamless customer service:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/mapping-a-refund-request-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mapping a Refund Request in Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the setup is complete, you'll see how to &lt;STRONG&gt;test payment authorization, capture, and refund&lt;/STRONG&gt; processes to ensure full-cycle transaction handling:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/testing-payment-authorization-capture-and-refund-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Testing Payment Authorization, Capture and Refund in Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition,&amp;nbsp;you'll learn to map and test authorization &lt;STRONG&gt;reversals&lt;/STRONG&gt;, crucial for handling order cancellations and funds releases:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/mapping-a-payment-authorization-reversal-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mapping a Payment Authorization Reversal in Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-710958267"&gt;7. Advanced Payment Management:&amp;nbsp;Reauthorization &amp;amp; API Enhancements&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;For ongoing transactions, you should also learn how to &lt;STRONG&gt;configure reauthorization&lt;/STRONG&gt;, allowing for future payments on the same session:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/configuring-reauthorization-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring Reauthorization in Open Payment Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And you'd learn how to &lt;STRONG&gt;test the reauthorization&lt;/STRONG&gt; configuration to ensure it functions correctly within your environment:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/testing-reauthorization-in-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Testing Reauthorization in Open Payment Framework for SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To extend the API capabilities, you can enhance the payment workflows by integrating adjacent API calls with custom fields,&amp;nbsp;such as attaching customer data to checkout sessions for more personalized and efficient processes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/using-adjacent-api-calls-with-custom-fields-in-open-payment-framework-in-sap-commerce-cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using Adjacent API Calls with Custom Fields in Open Payment Framework in SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Should issues arise, you'll find guidance in &lt;STRONG&gt;resolving reauthorization problems&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring minimal disruption:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/resolving-reauthorization-issues-in-open-payment-framework-for-sap-commerce-cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Resolving Reauthorization Issues in Open Payment Framework for SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And when necessary, &lt;STRONG&gt;manually adjust transaction statuses&lt;/STRONG&gt; to maintain accurate records:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/manually-adjusting-transaction-statuses-in-open-payment-framework-for-sap-commerce-cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manually Adjusting Transaction Statuses in Open Payment Framework for SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-514444762"&gt;8.&amp;nbsp;Broaden Payment Options&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, you can expand your payment options by &lt;STRONG&gt;configuring additional payment methods&lt;/STRONG&gt; like PayPal and Link, providing your customers more flexibility at checkout:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos/configuring-alternative-payment-methods-in-open-payment-framework-for-sap-commerce-cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring Alternative Payment Methods in Open Payment Framework for SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-317931257"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This concludes the quick overview of each video in the video series:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/video-playlists/integrating-payment-services-into-sap-commerce-cloud-with-open-payment-framework" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrating Payment Services into SAP Commerce Cloud with Open Payment Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(You can also access the playlist directly to watch the videos one by one.)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This series serves as your comprehensive resource for mastering payment integration in SAP Commerce Cloud. Follow the step-by-step instructions to enable your business with reliable, flexible, and secure payment solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy learning!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/setting-up-open-payment-framework-in-sap-commerce-cloud-video-series/ba-p/14224652"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:19:53.023000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-extensibility-guide-clean-core-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-august-2025/bc-p/14225266#M184775</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP Extensibility Guide – Clean Core for SAP S/4HANA Cloud - August 2025 Update</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:23:31.471000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OlgaDolinskaja</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6638</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/336735"&gt;@ragupta&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;yes, for the usage of not released SAP APIs custom wrappers can be created. Your custom code of Level A using the released parts of the wrapper will be Level A. The parts of the wrapper calling directly not released SAP API will be Level B (if this not released SAP API is a nominated classic SAP API).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Olga.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-extensibility-guide-clean-core-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-august-2025/bc-p/14225266#M184775"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:23:31.471000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/deploy-sca-in-multiple-as-java-telnet/qaa-p/14225267#M4927144</id>
    <title>Re: Deploy SCA in multiple AS JAVA telnet</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:24:24.990000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S_Sriram</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/816</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Lee, It depends on the deployment SCA file; if it is required, it will perform the restart. You can deploy the SCA file using the SUM tool. BR SS</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/deploy-sca-in-multiple-as-java-telnet/qaa-p/14225267#M4927144"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:24:24.990000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/implementation-of-a-taxable-entity-across-system-boundaries-public-cloud/qaa-p/14225269#M255356</id>
    <title>Re: Implementation of a taxable entity across system boun...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:27:09.371000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Janina,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you very much for your question!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you please check whether the following information (&lt;SPAN&gt;GenAI was used to help generate this content)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;is helpful?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631899844"&gt;Implementation of DRC in Hybrid SAP Environments&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1564469058"&gt;Licensing Models&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The licensing for Document and Reporting Compliance (DRC) in a hybrid setup involving both public and private cloud systems can vary. Typically, licensing may be based on the number of documents processed, such as blocks of 10,000 invoices, rather than the number of company codes or users. It is advisable to consult with your SAP sales representative to get precise details tailored to your specific setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367955553"&gt;Technical Functionality&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;DRC is designed to handle complex scenarios, including the integration of company codes from different SAP systems. However, the automatic merging of company codes for a taxable entity across public and private clouds might require additional configuration or middleware solutions. While DRC can facilitate data processing and reporting, manual steps like using the FOTV app might still be necessary depending on the specific requirements and setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1171442048"&gt;Lobster Integration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrating Lobster as middleware between public cloud, private cloud, and DRC is feasible, but it requires careful planning. Lobster can be used to map interfaces and facilitate data transfer between systems. Ensure that Lobster is configured to handle the data formats and communication protocols required by DRC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974928543"&gt;Requirements for DRC Processing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To process data from the public cloud system using DRC, ensure that the necessary communication arrangements and data mappings are in place. This includes setting up the correct integration flows and ensuring that the data is compliant with the requirements of the DRC component for VAT returns in Germany (FI-LOC-VAT-DE).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-778415038"&gt;Additional Considerations&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;While there is a separate DRC scenario for processing external data sources for electronic invoicing, reporting might not have the same flexibility. It is crucial to explore all available options and consult with SAP experts to find the best solution for your specific needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-members/tips-to-assess-and-plan-global-e-invoicing-solution-implementation-based-on/ba-p/13567185" target="_blank"&gt;[1] Tips to assess and plan global e-invoicing solution implementation based on SAP Document and Report Compliance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/implementation-of-a-taxable-entity-across-system-boundaries-public-cloud/qaa-p/14225269#M255356"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:27:09.371000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/create-z-program-to-update-edpar-entries/qaa-p/14225270#M207238</id>
    <title>Re: Create Z program to update EDPAR entries</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:29:15.150000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>abap_learner1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1398911</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Dominik thank you for your answer, but our problem is in Quality not production. that's why we want to create a Zprogram that should be promoted till Quality system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/create-z-program-to-update-edpar-entries/qaa-p/14225270#M207238"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:29:15.150000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-create-stories-in-sap-public-cloud-3sl/qaa-p/14225272#M4927145</id>
    <title>Re: unable to create Stories in sap public cloud(3SL)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:31:06.328000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dawid90</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172309</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235643"&gt;@Thanushree1999&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'll describe step by step what you should do to solve the problem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&amp;nbsp;open the Maintain Business Roles application and add the SAP_BR_ANALYTICS_SPECIALIST role&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To the role above add the catalog: SAP_CORE_BC_SSB_PC and Save&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ask your administrator or, if you have access, log in to Cloud Identity Services (screen)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dawid90_0-1758615698665.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318626i75753D2FC7194BDE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dawid90_0-1758615698665.png" alt="dawid90_0-1758615698665.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose Identity Provisioning and Source Systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dawid90_1-1758615698666.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318625iB3BFB1F1D9DAA634/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dawid90_1-1758615698666.png" alt="dawid90_1-1758615698666.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the left panel, select your system, next Jobs and Run Now like on screen&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dawid90_2-1758615698669.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318627iA9ACD8521BC851F7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dawid90_2-1758615698669.png" alt="dawid90_2-1758615698669.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Refresh SAP S/4 Hana Public Cloud system and try create Stories without error like on screen below&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dawid90_4-1758615946132.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318629iE79DC70A6ACE9538/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dawid90_4-1758615946132.png" alt="dawid90_4-1758615946132.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dawid&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-create-stories-in-sap-public-cloud-3sl/qaa-p/14225272#M4927145"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:31:06.328000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/live-part-1-a-hitchhiker-s-guide-to-sap-fiori-user-experience-and-its/ev-p/14225273</id>
    <title>LIVE -Part 1- A Hitchhiker's Guide to SAP Fiori User Experience and its Technologies – 2025 Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:33:00.927000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nadeemmohd</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1528070</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I’m sure you’ve heard of SAP Fiori, the design system for all SAP products. SAP Fiori covers the design itself, the SAP Fiori applications delivered by SAP, but also technologies and tools to run those apps, to extend standard SAP apps or even to develop your own custom apps.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;• Are you looking for a high-level understanding of SAP Fiori and its technologies and tools? &lt;BR /&gt;• Would you like to get an overview to see how all of this fits together? • Do you know which role SAP Build plays? &lt;BR /&gt;• You have an ABAP / on-prem background and want to learn about how SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) / cloud is used for SAP Fiori? &lt;BR /&gt;• Do you want to leverage entry points for your own practical learning, e.g. recommended tutorials?&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Look no further. This 2-part webinar helps and provides entry points for your hands-on learning&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Agenda Part 1 &lt;BR /&gt;SAP Fiori is the User Experience of SAP Business Suite that changes the way you work. In this overview you’ll get a first understanding of SAP Fiori: The SAP Fiori design system and how it is realized with the related UI technologies and tools, for business users, key users, and developers. This part covers the main environments like SAP S/4HANA and SAP Business Technology Platform. The overview extends to the actual productive usage of SAP Fiori business applications via an SAP Fiori launchpad, and the essential UI frameworks.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;• The SAP Fiori Design system &lt;BR /&gt;• An overview of Technologies and Tools for SAP Fiori &lt;BR /&gt;• The entry point to SAP Fiori: SAP Build Work Zone &lt;BR /&gt;• The strategic UI frameworks SAPUI5 and SAP Fiori elements&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;To see Part 2, please register here: &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-btp-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/sap-btp-2025/en_us/home.html&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;or join live on YouTube: &lt;A href="https://youtube.com/live/FU_mIbcYLpc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://youtube.com/live/FU_mIbcYLpc&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/live-part-1-a-hitchhiker-s-guide-to-sap-fiori-user-experience-and-its/ev-p/14225273"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:33:00.927000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/signavio-and-enable-now-integration/qaq-p/14225278</id>
    <title>Signavio and Enable Now integration</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:38:12.447000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PawelTK</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1978560</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am trying to integrate Signavio and Enable Now according to the instructions provided here: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-enable-now-and-sap-signavio-integration-overview/ba-p/13553928" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Enable Now and SAP Signavio Integration Overvi... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;, but I get stuck on the step of exporting SAP Signavio link. I get attached error massage. Pls support. (And no, it's not true, as the error message states, that any item is not published - all are published).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/signavio-and-enable-now-integration/qaq-p/14225278"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:38:12.447000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/live-part-2-a-hitchhiker-s-guide-to-sap-fiori-user-experience-and-its/ev-p/14225280</id>
    <title>LIVE-Part 2-A Hitchhiker's Guide to SAP Fiori User Experience and its Technologies –2025 Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:43:20.366000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nadeemmohd</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1528070</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In the second part we’ll cover SAP Build for AI–based application development and, of course, look at ABAP development tools. This leads us to the important scenario of extensibility and how you can easily add custom extension to standard SAP apps. Mobile technologies and a Q&amp;amp;A section close the second part.&lt;BR /&gt;• The SAP Build development environment and ABAP Development Tools in Eclipse&lt;BR /&gt;• Extending standard SAP applications with Clean Core principles&lt;BR /&gt;• Technologies for a mobile experience&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;To see Part 1, please register here: &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-btp-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/sap-btp-2025/en_us/home.html&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;or join live on YouTube:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_0Cc5dMvp7I" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_0Cc5dMvp7I&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/live-part-2-a-hitchhiker-s-guide-to-sap-fiori-user-experience-and-its/ev-p/14225280"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:43:20.366000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/replication-flow-with-abap-connection-and-odp-sapi-0fi-ar-4-handling-large/qaq-p/14225281</id>
    <title>Replication Flow with ABAP Connection and ODP/SAPI 0FI_AR_4 – Handling Large Volumes</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:45:24.081000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>A_Bracco</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1576708</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;we are planning to use in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere a Replication Flow based on an ABAP connection leveraging the ODP/SAPI extractor 0FI_AR_4.&lt;BR /&gt;The context is as follows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;The data volume is very large (&lt;STRONG&gt;over 2 billion records).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;We would like to &lt;STRONG&gt;retrieve historical data from an old BW system.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;The goal is to perform some kind of &lt;STRONG&gt;initialization without transferring data from S/4, and then manage only the deltas.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;We cannot use a &lt;STRONG&gt;Replication Flow init+delta directly from S/4HANA, because the 0FI_AR_4 extractor without filters is too slow (we estimated about 20 days of extraction) and, based on our tests, it runs into memory errors.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;We have also noticed that the &lt;STRONG&gt;“Delta Only” option in Replication Flow does not seem to be applicable to our scenario.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;thanks.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/replication-flow-with-abap-connection-and-odp-sapi-0fi-ar-4-handling-large/qaq-p/14225281"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:45:24.081000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/create-z-program-to-update-edpar-entries/qaa-p/14225282#M207239</id>
    <title>Re: Create Z program to update EDPAR entries</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:46:14.971000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dominik_Tylczynski</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/141029</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I guess you can use the same approach in quality.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/create-z-program-to-update-edpar-entries/qaa-p/14225282#M207239"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:46:14.971000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/traceability-log-validity-details/qaa-p/14225283#M4227816</id>
    <title>Re: Traceability Log validity details</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:47:49.529000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nishi13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2117834</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Jerry,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I updated my setting in define data mapping as you mentioned. This was done yesterday at 8 am PST. and since then we had 3 jobs that ran for the below job.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nishi13_0-1758617351992.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318634iBD7E42C67FA11B89/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nishi13_0-1758617351992.png" alt="nishi13_0-1758617351992.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yet I can only see the traceability log for the latest job. We select the option "with traceability log" for our every job.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nishi13_1-1758617516597.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318638i75C659A6F8B306BC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nishi13_1-1758617516597.png" alt="nishi13_1-1758617516597.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/traceability-log-validity-details/qaa-p/14225283#M4227816"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:47:49.529000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-extensibility-guide-clean-core-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-august-2025/bc-p/14225284#M184776</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP Extensibility Guide – Clean Core for SAP S/4HANA Cloud - August 2025 Update</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:48:29.857000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OlgaDolinskaja</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6638</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140546"&gt;@Apurv&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;it depends, what is your user-defined function module is doing: e.g. if it does not call any SAP internal APIs then it would be Level B.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Olga.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-extensibility-guide-clean-core-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-august-2025/bc-p/14225284#M184776"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:48:29.857000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sap-api-management-apikey-and-response-caching/bc-p/14225289#M72046</id>
    <title>Re: SAP API Management - APIKey and Response Caching</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:50:08.365000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LouisHuang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163052</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171723"&gt;@DenizZilyas&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Thanks for a nice blog.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; I add two response cache in my preflow`s in and out stream with below setting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; But it seems not working, all API call still reaches backend service ( CPI iflow).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Operation of my http request is post with basic authentication. Can you hint me where should I check?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Thanks a lot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;ResponseCache async="false" continueOnError="false" enabled="true" xmlns="&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/apimgmt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;http://www.sap.com/apimgmt&lt;/A&gt;"&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;CacheKey&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;KeyFragment ref="request.path"/&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;/CacheKey&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;Scope&amp;gt;Exclusive&amp;lt;/Scope&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;ExpirySettings&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;TimeoutInSec&amp;gt;3600&amp;lt;/TimeoutInSec&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;/ExpirySettings&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;/ResponseCache&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sap-api-management-apikey-and-response-caching/bc-p/14225289#M72046"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:50:08.365000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/new-fi-document-type-and-number-range-interval-in-s4hc/qaa-p/14225291#M255357</id>
    <title>Re: New FI document type and number range interval in S4HC</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:52:11.610000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, Thank you very much for your questions. I have forwarded them to the experts. Best regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/new-fi-document-type-and-number-range-interval-in-s4hc/qaa-p/14225291#M255357"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:52:11.610000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/traceability-log-validity-details/qaa-p/14225392#M4227817</id>
    <title>Re: Traceability Log validity details</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:56:15.676000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jerry_Jin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3200</uri>
    </author>
    <content>if so, Could you found the traceability log in the job details ? If you check data mapping job results page, could you found logs for each job? if not, please send the incidnet back to me or you can raise an new one. It seems an new questioins that we need to fix</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/traceability-log-validity-details/qaa-p/14225392#M4227817"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:56:15.676000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/sap-business-one/qaa-p/14225393#M19927</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Business One</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:57:05.877000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan15</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1478423</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I agree with Johan, it’s important to understand that B1 and S/4 are fundamentally different solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;B1 is typically suited to smaller organisations, with 'lighter' licensing, less add-ons and often deployed on-premise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4 is designed for larger, complex organisations. It has a wider range of functionality, extensive datasets, modern interface (Fiori) and a range of deployment options with additional licensing/complexity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you working within a specific vertical in B1? Or are you working as a generalist SAP functional support?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/sap-business-one/qaa-p/14225393#M19927"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:57:05.877000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/can-t-create-transport-request-for-my-new-abap-cloud-package/qaa-p/14225396#M19928</id>
    <title>Re: Can't create Transport Request for my new ABAP Cloud...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T10:58:52.271000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kaidehmann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14159</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks for bringing this up. The lesson of the learning journey will be updated.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/can-t-create-transport-request-for-my-new-abap-cloud-package/qaa-p/14225396#M19928"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T10:58:52.271000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extract-selected-data-from-very-large-hana-table-using-sap-data-services/qaa-p/14225398#M4927147</id>
    <title>Re: Extract selected data from very large Hana table usin...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:00:26.046000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>werner_daehn</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/182245</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Your question was, how to pushdown the where clause. That answers it.&lt;BR /&gt;Why it failed I cannot tell without more input, e.g. the error message.&lt;BR /&gt;Either way, reading bn of rows via a single stream (partition) is not a good idea anyhow - take too long. So how about the partitioning and parallel reader and loader?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extract-selected-data-from-very-large-hana-table-using-sap-data-services/qaa-p/14225398#M4927147"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:00:26.046000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-composable-storefront-problem-getting-current-user-with-asm/qaa-p/14225400#M457867</id>
    <title>Re: Sap Composable Storefront problem getting current use...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:01:56.814000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pvadla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1532094</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;Yasbet_Alvarez,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Could you check the below kba's which can be helpfull for your query.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3341122" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3341122&lt;/A&gt; :ASM Agent Cannot Emulate Customers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3514057" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3514057&lt;/A&gt; : ASM assistedservicefacades methods always return null/false using OCC&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;kindly check and let us know if you have further concerns.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-composable-storefront-problem-getting-current-user-with-asm/qaa-p/14225400#M457867"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:01:56.814000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/round-up-to-2-decimal-places-compensation-worksheets/qaa-p/14225401#M48160</id>
    <title>Re: Round up to 2 decimal places - Compensation Worksheets</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:03:41.927000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AJFelix</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/62583</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Xavier,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/round-up-to-2-decimal-places-compensation-worksheets/qaa-p/14225401#M48160"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:03:41.927000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sii-tip-for-spain-5-sii-adjustments-for-canary-islands-october-2025/bc-p/14225403#M184777</id>
    <title>Re: SII tip for Spain #5: SII Adjustments for Canary Islands October 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:06:13.937000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AH99</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1760893</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Buenos días, ¿se sabe cuándo estarán disponibles las notas que recogen los cambios en el SII de Canarias?&amp;nbsp; Gracias.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sii-tip-for-spain-5-sii-adjustments-for-canary-islands-october-2025/bc-p/14225403#M184777"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:06:13.937000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/fiori-message-iwfnd-med-170-in-slg1-when-starting-launchpad/qaa-p/14225404#M4927148</id>
    <title>Re: FIORI: Message /IWFND/MED 170 in SLG1 when starting Launchpad</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:06:41.654000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christian_Gaert</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/141511</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Found out a few things:</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/fiori-message-iwfnd-med-170-in-slg1-when-starting-launchpad/qaa-p/14225404#M4927148"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:06:41.654000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/build-a-new-connector-in-sap-cloud-platform-open-connectors/bc-p/14225406#M175604</id>
    <title>Re: Build a new connector in SAP Cloud Platform Open Connectors</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:07:14.572000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LaxmiAhujaPathak</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1528385</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Sir/All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying this open connector demo but unble to get correct api details , I am getting below errors due to which i cannot convert it to correct format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="LaxmiAhujaPathak_0-1758618325340.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318742i16EF87DC6F66588E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="LaxmiAhujaPathak_0-1758618325340.png" alt="LaxmiAhujaPathak_0-1758618325340.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyone who could help.......Kindly guide me how to get through this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warm Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Laxmi&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/build-a-new-connector-in-sap-cloud-platform-open-connectors/bc-p/14225406#M175604"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:07:14.572000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/fiori-message-iwfnd-med-170-in-slg1-when-starting-launchpad/qaa-p/14225407#M4927149</id>
    <title>Re: FIORI: Message /IWFND/MED 170 in SLG1 when starting Launchpad</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:08:13.425000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christian_Gaert</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/141511</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Found out a few things: Has to do with class CL_HCMFAB_MYREPORTING_DPC_EXT, Method "GET_ENTITY" and the Report BIRTHDAYLIST_CUSTOM (it is SAP-Standard).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/fiori-message-iwfnd-med-170-in-slg1-when-starting-launchpad/qaa-p/14225407#M4927149"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:08:13.425000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/traceability-log-validity-details/qaa-p/14225409#M4227818</id>
    <title>Re: Traceability Log validity details</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:08:47.073000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nishi13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2117834</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Jerry, I have added my comment on OSS - 1094785/2025</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/traceability-log-validity-details/qaa-p/14225409#M4227818"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:08:47.073000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/bc-p/14225410#M184778</id>
    <title>Re: Give Your AI Agent Some Tools: Introducing the UI5 MCP Server</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:09:02.224000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aashna_prakash</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/137393</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;getting this error with vscode -&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unable to write chat.mcp.access because it is configured in system policy. How to solve this?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/bc-p/14225410#M184778"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:09:02.224000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning/no-deployment-found-for-openai-embedding/m-p/14225412#M553</id>
    <title>Re: No deployment found for OpenAI Embedding</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:11:11.955000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DKK</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131035</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unfortunately, it is no supported today. Please choose either "&lt;SPAN&gt;Text Embedding 3 Large" or "Text Embedding 3 Small",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning/no-deployment-found-for-openai-embedding/m-p/14225412#M553"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:11:11.955000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/booking-of-material-issue-consumption-issue-in-custom-tcode-urgent-help/qaq-p/14225436</id>
    <title>Booking of material issue - Consumption issue in Custom tcode - Urgent help needed</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:22:00.826000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>umashankar301983</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255983</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need your help for the below issue, Please suggest as to move forward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We normally book the materials in one of the Custom tcode in the production system, it works perfectly when we book single material, when it comes to booking of multiple materials , the SAP booked qty in material movement 261 is different with the actual sap bom qty.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But this scenerio is working perfectly in &lt;STRONG&gt;quality system&lt;/STRONG&gt; as below, we have issue only in Prodcution system.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Quality system - Working fine.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318750i1E50D428D08F8330/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Quality system - Working fine.png" alt="Quality system - Working fine.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP BOOKED QTY and Actual qty is not matching in &lt;STRONG&gt;production system&lt;/STRONG&gt;, when we book multiple materials with Combination of Fruh (Early) and SPAT (Late) as below&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Production system - Error issue.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318763i967D896E8103EB3B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Production system - Error issue.png" alt="Production system - Error issue.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please help us to guide on this scenerio, we need a same qty in Production system&amp;nbsp;SAP BOOKED QTY and Actual qty should match.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;it is very much helpful , if you suggest, anything need to be changed in Master data level or program level for this issue?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Umashankar.A&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/booking-of-material-issue-consumption-issue-in-custom-tcode-urgent-help/qaq-p/14225436"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:22:00.826000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/event-mesh-activation-not-possible-in-integration-suite-free-plan/qaq-p/14225438</id>
    <title>Event Mesh activation not possible in Integration Suite - free plan</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:24:43.579000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FLang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2080419</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to set up the Manage Business Events Capability in Integration Suite - free plan&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am able to activate the capability, but when trying to activate Event Mesh (Configure -&amp;gt; Event Mesh) I get a message that it was set up ok but the Event Mesh shows the "failed" sign. In the queues it shows "Event mesh activation failed. Please try again."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I found note&amp;nbsp;0003527095 which references this error, but the suggested solution "To resolve this issue, the Event Mesh default plan must be removed from the subaccount." does not apply here, I have not added the Event Mesh default plan to the sub-account and still get the error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am wondering if the Event Mesh can even be used from the&amp;nbsp;Integration Suite - free plan (I am using a PAYG global account with only the Integration Suite - free added for the subaccount).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any help would be greatly appreciated, thanks!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/event-mesh-activation-not-possible-in-integration-suite-free-plan/qaq-p/14225438"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:24:43.579000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ownership-percentage-in-group-reporting/qaq-p/14225443</id>
    <title>ownership percentage in Group Reporting</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:28:50.055000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KHALEDKAMMOUN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2038559</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;when i maitain ownership if by mistake data uploaded 200% normally&amp;nbsp; CALC SHARE TASK&amp;nbsp; should show an error for this but not showing in my case&amp;nbsp; FYI also in Dev environment shows fail but in quality doesn't detect this error , i need to know what is the reason .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ownership-percentage-in-group-reporting/qaq-p/14225443"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:28:50.055000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/posting-supplier-invoice-through-ocr-process-in-sap-public-cloud/qaq-p/14225444</id>
    <title>Posting Supplier Invoice through OCR process in SAP Public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:29:00.851000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dinesh_RV10</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255989</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have an requirement to post the invoice in SAP by extracting the data from the PDF document which is sent by the supplier via OCR process in SAP Public Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly advice any process steps to be followed to suffice the requirement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dinesh&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/posting-supplier-invoice-through-ocr-process-in-sap-public-cloud/qaq-p/14225444"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:29:00.851000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/m7093-fld-selectn-for-mvmt-type-acct-differs-for/qaa-p/14225446#M4227821</id>
    <title>Re: M7093 Fld selectn for mvmt type &amp; / acct &amp; differs fo...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:32:35.600000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xujun</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;hi&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;try FS00 and put the **bleep** in it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;best regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/m7093-fld-selectn-for-mvmt-type-acct-differs-for/qaa-p/14225446#M4227821"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:32:35.600000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/idocs-are-still-safe-for-sap-s-4hana-sap-clean-core-extensibility-level-b/ba-p/14225439</id>
    <title>IDOCs are Still Safe for SAP S/4HANA - SAP Clean Core Extensibility Level B</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:35:28.820000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichalKrawczyk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45785</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760984392"&gt;Intro&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;IDOCs are safe to use in SAP S/4HANA programs—and if anyone tells you otherwise, point them to this blog to learn more. IDOCs are now officially part of &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Clean Core Extensibility!&lt;/STRONG&gt; That’s the big news from updated SAP Guidelines (OSS Note &lt;STRONG&gt;3578329 – Frameworks, Technologies and Development Patterns in Context of Clean Core Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This ends the myth that IDOCs are “dead.” They are not. They’re preserved as &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Clean Core Level B&amp;nbsp;Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which means your existing IDOC investments are safe.&amp;nbsp;Let’s explore four perspectives—&lt;STRONG&gt;integration, monitoring and error handling, performance, and testing&lt;/STRONG&gt;—to see where APIs are recommended first, and where IDOCs still bring value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1564470887"&gt;1. Integration Perspective&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s recommendation for new development in S/4HANA is clear: use &lt;STRONG&gt;modern integration technologies&lt;/STRONG&gt; such as APIs, events, or OData services. They are the strategic direction and best fit for greenfield or transformation projects. That said, not all projects require reinvention. If your business processes remain largely the same as in ECC, and the goal is to &lt;STRONG&gt;reduce cost and risk&lt;/STRONG&gt;, IDOCs can still be used. They are &lt;STRONG&gt;not prohibited&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and as long as an IDOC type is not listed as deprecated in the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Simplification List&lt;/STRONG&gt;, it is safe:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btc/lean-sdt-best-practices/sap-s-4hana-simplification-analysis?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/btc/lean-sdt-best-practices/sap-s-4hana-simplification-analysis?locale=en-US&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;Because IDOCs are now Clean Core Level B&amp;nbsp;Extensibility, continuing with them is fully supported in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA on-premise&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Private Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;. They offer a pragmatic path to de-risk projects and leverage existing know-how. &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="integration.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318770i4D4EF460ACC92791/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="integration.png" alt="integration.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367957382"&gt;2. Monitoring and Error Handling Perspective&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For new interfaces, SAP recommends using &lt;STRONG&gt;AIF (Application Interface Framework)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to handle monitoring, error management, and business validations. AIF provides a powerful, unified monitoring layer, and in many cases it comes &lt;STRONG&gt;license-free&lt;/STRONG&gt; (for standard SAP interfaces delivered in namespaces like /SDSLS or /LEEDI, or in CFIN, Document Compliance, or S/4HANA Public Cloud). Where APIs are deployed, AIF bridges the gap between technical payloads and business-friendly monitoring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IDOCs still have a strong card here: their monitoring capabilities are mature, well-known, and integrated into standard SAP transactions. Functional users know how to work with WE02, BD87, and standard reprocessing flows. This means less training, less overhead, and faster resolution in day-to-day operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In other words: &lt;STRONG&gt;AIF is recommended&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but IDOCs deliver proven stability in monitoring and error handling.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="monitoring.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318761i46911CE9A0AC3FD9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="monitoring.png" alt="monitoring.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1171443877"&gt;3. Performance Perspective&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;APIs are the recommended way forward, but they come with a structural tradeoff: their payloads are larger and typically handle transactions individually. This makes them more verbose and sometimes less efficient for high-volume use cases.&amp;nbsp;IDOCs, in contrast, have long supported &lt;STRONG&gt;bundling, batching, and parallel processing&lt;/STRONG&gt; at scale. They’ve been the backbone of high-volume EDI and SAP-to-SAP integrations for decades, and their ability to handle millions of documents daily is field-proven. So while APIs are the strategic choice for new designs, &lt;STRONG&gt;IDOCs remain a safe performance option for scenarios with heavy data throughput&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="performance.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318764i5B1281FABD0691EC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="performance.png" alt="performance.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974930372"&gt;4. Testing Perspective&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Testing support for APIs exists (for example, with &lt;STRONG&gt;SXI_MONITOR&lt;/STRONG&gt;), but it is more technical and often requires additional training for functional teams. For IDOCs, simulation and reprocessing are familiar to almost every SAP functional consultant. Tools like WE19 and BD87 make IDOC testing and troubleshooting accessible, reducing dependency on specialist skills.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="testing.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318765i9A532F171BFD6DE4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="testing.png" alt="testing.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For projects that need to &lt;STRONG&gt;standardize and automate testing across both APIs and IDOCs&lt;/STRONG&gt;, solutions like &lt;STRONG&gt;Int4 Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; provide simulation and test automation capabilities that unify all SAP integration scenarios. You can learn more on how to test and simulate SAP integrations in this SAP learning Course: &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/avoid-sap-s-4hana-project-delays-with-third-party-systems-service-virtualization?url_id=text-former-openSAP-course" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Avoid SAP S/4HANA Project Delays with Third-Party Systems Service Virtualization&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;So while &lt;STRONG&gt;APIs are recommended for new developments&lt;/STRONG&gt;, IDOCs still offer &lt;STRONG&gt;ease of testing and proven tooling&lt;/STRONG&gt;, especially in brownfield projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-778416867"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The strategic path forward in SAP S/4HANA is built on APIs, events, and frameworks like AIF. That’s &lt;STRONG&gt;the official recommendation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and it should guide greenfield and transformation projects. But IDOCs are far from obsolete. They are &lt;STRONG&gt;officially part of Clean Core extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;, safe to use in both on-premise and private cloud, and carry unique advantages in performance, monitoring, and ease of testing. That makes them not only supported, but still a pragmatic and safe choice when the situation calls for stability, cost reduction, and risk mitigation.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/idocs-are-still-safe-for-sap-s-4hana-sap-clean-core-extensibility-level-b/ba-p/14225439"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:35:28.820000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/requirement-webi-waterfall-report-gl-account-causing-multivalue-and-export/qaa-p/14225452#M4927152</id>
    <title>Re: Requirement: WebI Waterfall Report – GL Account Causing Multivalue and Export Issues</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:36:00.869000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>benasirennes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348531</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Bonjour,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/requirement-webi-waterfall-report-gl-account-causing-multivalue-and-export/qaa-p/14225452#M4927152"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:36:00.869000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fiori-app-extensibility/qaq-p/14225454</id>
    <title>FIORI APP extensibility</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:36:57.982000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LXBEL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1448775</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I need to extend a standard Fiori application with a custom field. Normally, the recommended approach would be to use the Custom Fields and Logic app, which automatically creates a new field (with the ZZ1_ prefix) in the relevant table and exposes it to Fiori.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, in my case, the situation is different:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The customer has already added a custom field ZCLASS in table MARD using an append structure and this field is already in use across multiple forms, reports (so it’s business critical)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If I use the Custom Fields and Logic app now, it will create a new field ZZ1_CLASS in MARD, which would lead to &lt;STRONG&gt;redundant fields for the same purpose&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My question is what is the correct approach to resolve this issue?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you In advance&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fiori-app-extensibility/qaq-p/14225454"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:36:57.982000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/requirement-webi-waterfall-report-gl-account-causing-multivalue-and-export/qaa-p/14225453#M4927153</id>
    <title>Re: Requirement: WebI Waterfall Report – GL Account Causing Multivalue and Export Issues</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:37:00.871000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>benasirennes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348531</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;BR /&gt;1. To avoid #MULTIVALUE, if you're sure that results are correct after that, you can add an aggregation operator such as SUM, MIN, MAX where detailed dimension object is not included in block or line.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. For Excel export, when the are too many lines, you sometimes get an error about max character limit exceeded.&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Resolution :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the CMC, go to&amp;nbsp;&lt;I&gt;Servers &amp;gt; Servers list &amp;gt; Properties&lt;/I&gt; of your &lt;STRONG&gt;WebIntelligenceProcessingServer &lt;/STRONG&gt;servers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under the "&lt;I&gt;Web Intelligence Common Services" &lt;/I&gt;section, increase the parameters below.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;I&gt;Maximum Character Stream Size (MB)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;I&gt;Binary Stream Maximum Size (MB)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/I&gt;Most of the time, 500MB for the Maximum Character Stream Size and 100MB for the Binary Stream Maximum Size is enough. If needed you can set an higher value but you will not be able to enter more than 4000.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Restart the updated servers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Hope this helps.&lt;BR /&gt;Benoît&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/requirement-webi-waterfall-report-gl-account-causing-multivalue-and-export/qaa-p/14225453#M4927153"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:37:00.871000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/lohnbearbeitung-auslaufsteuerung/qaq-p/14225456</id>
    <title>Lohnbearbeitung - Auslaufsteuerung</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:39:00.788000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abdulkadir_Senguen1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2199781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hallo zusammen, ich bin auf folgende SAP Note gestoßen:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/43636/D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/43636/D&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Die Note beschreibt folgendes:&amp;nbsp;Keine Umleitung der Bereitstellungsbedarfe für Lohnbearbeitung. Bereitstellungsbedarf wird nicht auf das Nachfolgematerial umgeleitet. Bedarf nach dem Auslaufdatum, der nicht gedeckt ist, wird in der Dispoliste mit der Ausnahmemeldung 58 'Ungedeckter Bedarf jenseits Auslaufdatum' gekennzeichnet. Eine Bedarfsdeckung durch neue Bestellvorschläge findet nicht statt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Grund:&amp;nbsp;Es wird nicht zwischen 'Lohnbearbeiter-Sekundärbedarf' (für Planauftrag, Bestellanforderung) und 'Lohnbearbeiter-Reservierung' (für LB-Bestellung) unterschieden.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hatte jemand schon das selbe Szenario in einem Projekt bzw. kennt eine Lösung wie man dies Elegant lösen kann?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/lohnbearbeitung-auslaufsteuerung/qaq-p/14225456"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:39:00.788000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-hashmap-magic-efficient-bulk-data-lookup-with-value-mapping-in/bc-p/14225457#M184779</id>
    <title>Re: Unlocking Hashmap Magic: Efficient Bulk Data Lookup with Value Mapping in SAP CI using Groovy/XS</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:40:29.902000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>anchurisanthi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/873308</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While working on this requirement, we faced an issue with the Groovy script. Please let us know what the problem is.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Error Details:-&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;com.sap.it.rt.adapter.http.api.exception.HttpResponseException: An internal server error occured: org.xml.sax.SAXParseException; lineNumber: 1; columnNumber: 1; Content is not allowed in prolog.@ line 8 in script1.groovy. The MPL ID for the failed message is : AGjSZ_tqgDpjmu3rAGwhsELj4okp&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Thanks &amp;amp; Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Anchuri Santhi&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-hashmap-magic-efficient-bulk-data-lookup-with-value-mapping-in/bc-p/14225457#M184779"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:40:29.902000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fiori-app-extensibility/qaa-p/14225463#M4227823</id>
    <title>Re: FIORI APP extensibility</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:47:03.712000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>s_chunduru</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/717777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Lxbel,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since the field already exists in MARD via an append structure, using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Fields and Logic app&lt;/STRONG&gt; will indeed generate a second field with a ZZ1_ prefix. To avoid redundant fields, a common approach is to &lt;STRONG&gt;bind the existing append field into your Fiori app directly&lt;/STRONG&gt; instead of creating a new one through CFL.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I recommend that you try to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;create an extension CDS view &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;that underlies the standard Fiori app, and include the existing &lt;/SPAN&gt;ZCLASS&lt;SPAN&gt; field. This lets you expose that field to the UI without creating a duplicate.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope that helps point you in the right direction.&lt;BR /&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Sudheer.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fiori-app-extensibility/qaa-p/14225463#M4227823"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:47:03.712000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/bc-p/14225466#M184780</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP test cockpit (ATC) recommendations for governance of clean core ABAP development</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:47:25.713000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mischarf</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/162177</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6638"&gt;@OlgaDolinskaja&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;thank you for the excellent blog post. &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179540"&gt;@wagener-mark&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and I&amp;nbsp;have implemented our ATC check accordingly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;No we are getting a lot of API Findings related to our Key User Extensions.&lt;BR /&gt;"Usage of DDIC database tables in CDS views is not recommended (successor available)". All of these Key user extensions were generated by the key user apps and don't use direct table access. How should we deal with this?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mischarf_0-1758620479106.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318774i11A3F2312776BA1C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="mischarf_0-1758620479106.png" alt="mischarf_0-1758620479106.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mischarf_1-1758620492778.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318775iFD8F875CEE0CD9C2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="mischarf_1-1758620492778.png" alt="mischarf_1-1758620492778.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your support!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Michael&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/bc-p/14225466#M184780"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:47:25.713000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/custom-analytical-queries-sap-cloud-erp-public-edition-sap-s-4hana-public/ba-p/14224990</id>
    <title>Custom Analytical Queries - SAP CLOUD ERP Public Edition ( SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud )</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:47:40.171000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vinu_Kurian</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1155</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Definition :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Custom Analytical Queries&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;app is a tool used for reporting and analysis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This tool transforms and organizes raw data delivered from business documents into a meaningful grid. It abstracts the process of writing structured queries so that you don’t have to understand the query language or the technical details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Custom Analytical Queries&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;provides the fields required to design a query. You select the required fields and set filters for your query. You can add restricted measures, calculated measures, and preview the query results. The various options in&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Custom Analytical Queries&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and the task that you can perform using the options are as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Search: Use to search an existing query.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;New: Use to create a query.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Copy: Use to create queries from predefined SAP queries or from packages that you do not have permissions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Adding Dimensions and Measures from the Data Source: Use to add a field from a data source to define a query or to remove a field from the query.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;( Definition referred From :&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Custom Analytical Queries - SAP Doc" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/33f3a229ecfe438ca6b2053c48b4e1bb.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Custom Analytical Queries - SAP Doc&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my words , &lt;STRONG&gt;Custom analytical queries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;are a tool for dynamic representation of data in rows and columns which provide meaningful insights , business intelligence and summarization of data in a higher to lower drilldown model with aggregations and segregations .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;( Literally I'm too bad in defining things in my own words )&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can consider the Custom analytical queries as a Key User extensible approach , but there are few scenarios where we might need the support of Developer extensions to meet our requirements .&amp;nbsp; Which will be explained below in the following portions .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;where to find the custom analytical queries ?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you are in your Public cloud Launchpad , use the search bar&amp;nbsp; .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 113018.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318574iDC1C347021529D10/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 113018.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 113018.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Or use the Left hamburger menu and scroll down till you find the &lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Section .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 113226.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318575i76619950F7C1F7C0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 113226.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 113226.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you click the &lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Section , You can find the Tile under the &lt;STRONG&gt;Query Design&lt;/STRONG&gt; part .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 113412.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318576iF28BCB3C8D97F966/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 113412.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 113412.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to Create an Analytical Query ?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate inside the tile , you can see the list of existing custom analytical queries and the&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;create&lt;/STRONG&gt; button&amp;nbsp; .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 114825.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318577i10DF3E009A6C44DF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 114825.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 114825.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has already provided us some&amp;nbsp; analytical queries and all the released queries will be available here , we can use the existing ones as well as create our own .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now click on the create button and following pop up will come .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 115057.png" style="width: 517px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318579i1E783B35160909A8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 115057.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 115057.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can give your Analytical query name and choose the Data source you need and click on &lt;STRONG&gt;OK&lt;/STRONG&gt; .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;click on the Data Source search help and you can see all your available data sources .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 115429.png" style="width: 406px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318581i0D858D9F38699D80/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 115429.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 115429.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;after choosing the data source of you need you can continue with the field selection , setting the Dimensions ,setting&amp;nbsp; Measures , setting the filters , calculations etc ...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before moving to the next segment or part of adjusting and setting query for our use , let me give you an idea about the data sources used in the Analytical queries or what are these data sources ?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The data sources shown here are of 3 types mainly :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. SAP created and Released Analytical Queries and Cube&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 115429.png" style="width: 406px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318582i9CEE087CD2681223/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 115429.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 115429.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Custom Analytical Cube created using the Custom CDS view APP .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 120425.png" style="width: 243px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318583i04359F2FD940EE3B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 120425.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 120425.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 120503.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318584iBDBEEDCB0FA5825E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 120503.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 120503.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Custom CDS views Created Using Developer extensibility and the C1 contract set for Use in key user apps . There are few other things to be careful as well , you can use the sample code added below for reference .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 121029.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318587iC4FA69395465C01F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 121029.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 121029.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Code Snippet for one of the Custom analytical cube created via eclipse :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt; @AbapCatalog.sqlViewName: 'ZI_FINSTATKEYFI'
@VDM.viewType: #COMPOSITE
@AccessControl.authorizationCheck: #CHECK
@EndUserText.label: 'Statistical Keyfigures per period'
@ObjectModel.representativeKey: 'StatisticalKeyFigureItem'
@ObjectModel.usageType.sizeCategory: #XXL
@ObjectModel.usageType.dataClass:  #MIXED
@ObjectModel.usageType.serviceQuality: #D
@Analytics: { dataCategory: #CUBE }
@Analytics.internalName: #LOCAL 
@Metadata.ignorePropagatedAnnotations: true
@Metadata.allowExtensions:true

@ObjectModel.modelingPattern: #ANALYTICAL_CUBE
@ObjectModel.supportedCapabilities: [#ANALYTICAL_PROVIDER, 
                                     #CDS_MODELING_DATA_SOURCE,
                                     #SQL_DATA_SOURCE]
                                     
define view  ZI_FINSTAT2
  as select from I_FinStatisticalKeyFigureItem

  
{
       @Consumption.filter: {selectionType: #SINGLE, multipleSelections: false, mandatory: true}
       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_Ledger'
  key  Ledger,


       @Consumption.filter: {selectionType: #SINGLE, multipleSelections: false, mandatory: true}
       //@Consumption.valueHelpDefinition: [{ entity: { name: 'I_LedgerCompanyCodeVH' , element: 'CompanyCode' },
       //                                     additionalBinding: [ { localElement: 'Ledger' , element: 'Ledger' } ]
       //                                  }]
       //@Consumption.valueHelp: '_LedgerCompanyCodeVH'
       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_CompanyCode'
  key  CompanyCode,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_StatisticalKeyFigure'
  key  StatisticalKeyFigure,

       ///////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
       // Attention !!!
       // The following field is the LedgerFiscalYear (depends on ledger + company code)
       // Unfortunately we have called it FiscalYear (because the semantic seems to be clear)
       // Because of compatibility reasons we can not change it anymore
       //
       // This view has no FiscalYear (depends on company code)
       //
       // if you use this view in your views on top please write:  FiscalYear as LedgerFiscalYear
       // then you can make a join or union with the field from ACDOCA: LedgerFiscalYear (please ignore in this case the FiscalYear from ACDOCA)
       /////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_FiscalYear'
  key  FiscalYear,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_FiscalPeriod'
  key  FiscalPeriod,

  key  StatisticalKeyFigureItem,


       FiscalYearPeriod,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_FiscalYearVariant'
       FiscalYearVariant,

       IsSpecialPeriod,


       //@ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_StatisticalKeyFigureCat'
       StatisticalKeyFigureCategory,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_UnitOfMeasure'
       StatisticalKeyFigQtyUnit,


       @Aggregation.default: #SUM
       @Semantics: { quantity : {unitOfMeasure: 'StatisticalKeyFigQtyUnit'} }
       StstclKeyFigIntmdPlanSumQty,



       GLRecordType,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_PlanningCategory'
       PlanningCategory,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_CostCenter'
       CostCenter,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_ProfitCenter'
       ProfitCenter,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_FunctionalArea'
       FunctionalArea,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_BusinessArea'
       BusinessArea,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_ControllingArea'
       ControllingArea,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_Segment'
       Segment,

       ControllingBusTransacType,

       AccountAssignmentType,



       ControllingObject,


       ControllingObjectClass,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_Order'
       OrderID,

       OrderCategory,

       @Semantics.quantity.unitOfMeasure: 'StatisticalKeyFigQtyUnit'
       @AnalyticsDetails: {
               exceptionAggregationSteps: [{ exceptionAggregationBehavior : #AVG, //LAST
                                             exceptionAggregationElements: ['FiscalPeriod']
                                          }]
           }
       @AnalyticsDetails.query.formula : 'StstclKeyFigIntmdActlFixedQty'
       @EndUserText.label: 'Fixed Quantity'
      
       cast(1 as abap.quan(15,3) )                        as Fixed_Quantity,
       @Consumption.hidden: true
       //@AnalyticsDetails.query.hidden: true  //  ==&amp;gt; is available but hidden at start of app
       @AnalyticsDetails.query.axis: #COLUMNS
       //@EndUserText.label: 'StatisticalKeyFigSumQty'
       //@DefaultAggregation: #FORMULA
       //@Semantics: { quantity : {unitOfMeasure: 'StatisticalKeyFigQtyUnit'} }
       @Semantics.quantity.unitOfMeasure: 'StatisticalKeyFigQtyUnit'
       @AnalyticsDetails: {
               exceptionAggregationSteps: [{ exceptionAggregationBehavior : #SUM,
                                             exceptionAggregationElements: ['FiscalPeriod']
                                          }]
           }
       @AnalyticsDetails.query.formula : 'StstclKeyFigIntmdActlSumQty'
       @EndUserText.label: 'Sum Quantity'
       //cast( cast(1 as abap.quan(15,3)) as fis_ui_sum_smexxx ) as StatisticalKeyFigSumQty,
       cast(1 as abap.quan(15,3) )                        as Sum_Quantity,
       @AnalyticsDetails.query.axis: #COLUMNS
       //@EndUserText.label: 'StatisticalKeyFigSumQty'
       //@DefaultAggregation: #FORMULA
       //@Semantics: { quantity : {unitOfMeasure: 'StatisticalKeyFigQtyUnit'} }
       @Semantics.quantity.unitOfMeasure: 'StatisticalKeyFigQtyUnit'
       @AnalyticsDetails.query.formula : 'StstclKeyFigIntmdActlSumQty'
       @EndUserText.label: 'Quantity'
       //cast( cast(1 as abap.quan(15,3)) as fis_ui_smexxx ) as StatisticalKeyFigureQuantity,
       cast(1 as abap.quan(15,3) )                        as Quantity,
     

       GrantID,

       //@ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_BudgetPeriod'
       BudgetPeriod,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_SalesDocument'
       SalesOrder,

       @ObjectModel.foreignKey.association: '_SalesDocumentItem'
       SalesOrderItem,

       CostCtrActivityType,

       ServiceDocumentType,

       ServiceDocument,

       ServiceDocumentItem,


       _ControllingArea,
       _Ledger,
       _CompanyCode,
       _LedgerCompanyCodeVH,
       _CostCenter,
       _ProfitCenter,
       _StatisticalKeyFigure,
       _StatisticalKeyFigureCat,
       _FiscalYear,
       _FiscalPeriod,
       _FiscalYearVariant,
       _UnitOfMeasure,
       _Segment,
       _FunctionalArea,
       _BusinessArea,
       _Order,
       _SalesDocument,
       _SalesDocumentItem,
       _ControllingObject,
       _BudgetPeriod,
       _PlanningCategory


}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now lets Fall back to our scenario , I am creating an Analytical query with the name&amp;nbsp;Analytical_Q2 and data source&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;I_ACCOUNTINGDOCUMENTJOURNAL , one of SAP released / Standard CDS views.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 130620.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318601i212C75E5DF24D174/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 130620.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 130620.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;and you will be on the next screen after clicking OK .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 131124.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318603i45110796994F4A93/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 131124.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 131124.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will be in the first tab &lt;STRONG&gt;General&lt;/STRONG&gt; ,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;in the General tab under properties , you can :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;add your Label&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Name and Data source will be displayed&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set the Zero suppression&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Under the Additional Properties , you can :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Processing effort for the query , Low / Medium / High&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set Run Time extensibility&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the top right corner you can see your status of the Query (Draft / Saved / published )&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the bottom right you can see buttons for , Saving Draft / Publishing / Previewing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moving to the Next Tab&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;Field selection&lt;/STRONG&gt; :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 132131.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318608i52C1B7AAE2BA7A5B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 132131.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 132131.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can see all your fields available in the Data source here . Check the selection check box for fields you will be needing in the query .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After selecting the check box you can see that most of the fields fell in to the Free axis position but some of them have automatically fallen to the Measure category . Mostly the fields with amount , quantity or marked as measure in the data source fall to this category.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you look closely to the field list , you can see the type of field .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;if a field is having&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 133016.png" style="width: 41px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318612iE829EA30D3E43BB5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 133016.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 133016.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;symbol , this is a dimension and could be placed in the ROW / Column axis of the report / Query.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;if a field is having&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 133133.png" style="width: 46px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318614iA052DDE609392777/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 133133.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 133133.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;symbol , this is a measure and could be placed in the COLUMN axis of the report / Query.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;if a field is having&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 133242.png" style="width: 71px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318616i4D27242625E9ED67/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 133242.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 133242.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;symbol , this is a date field and could be placed in&amp;nbsp;ROW / Column axis of the report / Query.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;In data analysis, dimensions are qualitative, descriptive fields (like names, dates, or categories) that provide context and "slice" data, answering "who," "what," "when," and "where".&amp;nbsp;Measures are quantitative, numerical fields (like sales, quantities, or profits) that you calculate or aggregate to answer "how much" or "how many".&amp;nbsp;The core difference is that&amp;nbsp;dimensions provide the descriptive context, while measures provide the numerical values to analyze within that context.&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dimensions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Purpose:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To provide context, segment, and describe data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Type:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Qualitative, categorical, or descriptive data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Examples:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Product names, customer IDs, region, date.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Information like "who," "what," "where," and "when".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Measures&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Purpose:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To be calculated and aggregated, such as sums or averages, to provide quantifiable insights.&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Type:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Quantitative, numerical, and measurable data.&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Examples:&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sales, profit, quantity, price, and temperature.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Information that answers "how much" or "how many".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Moving to the Next Tab&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Display&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 134508.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318620iA611BAB6C67079E0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 134508.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 134508.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Now you can move the fields to your desired axis , Row / Column. To do that you can either select the field and use the up , down button in the table to move the fields and place it in order . Or you can also use the Axis field in the options area and place the field in different Axis.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;I have adjusted the axis in the following order:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 134401.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318619iB26D6DC0BAC627B7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 134401.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 134401.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Now lets focus the main table with fields from left ,&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;you will see Remove column with x button to remove the field from the selection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Filter column to set the Filed as a filter ( We will look at the Filter in the next section or tab).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Display column to hide / show the field in output.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Name , label and Type as seen earlier and also a row wise hierarchy&amp;nbsp; separator to show the fields category or placement.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Now lets Save our Query and have a Preview :&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 140015.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318630iEB86F77EE5B11ABF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 140015.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 140015.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;We will consider this preview for comparing with changes we are going to next.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Now lets select a field in the row category and look at the available properties (Right Pane) .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 140446.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318633i75E61DB6D3097BC3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 140446.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 140446.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the Override Label to change the default Label :&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Display option to set field visible .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Display result Option to enable Total / Grand total row based on this field .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dimension format to display either the Key&amp;nbsp; / text / Key and text / text and Key&amp;nbsp; value of the Field , Applicable in case of fields with Key and value pair , eg : Country , currency , company code etc&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sorting to set the sorting for the Field , Ascending / descending .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Axis is to place the field at desired axis (Row / Column).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Include Unbooked data option to show values with this field as empty but others having data .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Now lets look at a Measure and its Properties :&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 141845.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318635iFE541788B6A89D5D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 141845.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 141845.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 141947.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318637i9B1651D8DC0CB2BB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 141947.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 141947.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the Override Label to change the default Label :&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Display option to set field visible .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Decimals option to define the number of decimal places needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scaling option to set the level of scaling .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reverse sign to reverse the sign of value .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use&amp;nbsp; the hierarchy&amp;nbsp; Part to set the Hierarchy of the field if needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collapsed to set the view to collapsed .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable hierarchy to enable hierarchy , Collapsed will only work if hierarchy is set .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Parent option to set the parent node of the current field in the hierarchy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Now after making some changes let me show the preview again :&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 142746.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318739i06B1C4062EA7AB3C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 142746.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 142746.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Moving to the Next Tab &lt;STRONG&gt;Filters&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 144629.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318755iC9108E35C05BBB8C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 144629.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 144629.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Here lets select a Row / Dimension and set the Filter values , Only dimensions are allowed as filters .&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 145625.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318767i051B25543A0929E7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 145625.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 145625.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can set No filter for a field , which will be default .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fixed Filter with values to&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;include and exclude.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User Input Values Filter with&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;selection type&amp;nbsp; Single / Interval&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Multiple selection&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mandatory Option&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Variable sequence&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Default value&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Derivation Functions with&amp;nbsp;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Lookup entity (Search help )&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hidden&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mandatory&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now after making some changes let me show the preview again :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 150521.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318771i862A0DE7FA3008BD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 150521.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 150521.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now we have covered almost all the options in all the tabs , but we haven't explored the ADD button in the Display tab .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 150632.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318773iE3364CCE0320D87F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-23 150632.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-23 150632.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This option lets you add :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Add Restricted Measure&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Add Calculated Measure&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Add Converted Measure&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Add Counter&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Add User Input Filter&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Add Characteristic Structure Element&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;I have also skipped the publishing process and adding the custom analytical query as a tile in this tile , I will try to write all the missing parts in the part 2 blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":beaming_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😁&lt;/span&gt; .&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;NB : This Blog is created based on my knowledge , experiments and experiences . If you have found any misleading information in the blog , please correct me in the comments . Happy Learning&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt; .&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/custom-analytical-queries-sap-cloud-erp-public-edition-sap-s-4hana-public/ba-p/14224990"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:47:40.171000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/smart-filter-bar-not-visible-after-smart-table-personalisation-in-sap-fiori/qaa-p/14225473#M4927154</id>
    <title>Re: smart filter bar not visible after smart table person...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:51:05.838000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anjan_3331</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1921350</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot for the reply sudheer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have tried to wrap the smart filterbar and smartvariant management and i am getting the below error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Anjan_3331_0-1758625238144.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318816i1FDEDA63151A763F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Anjan_3331_0-1758625238144.png" alt="Anjan_3331_0-1758625238144.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is the code of my View.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Anjan_3331_1-1758625305400.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318817iDAA91EDABCD1E2BD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Anjan_3331_1-1758625305400.png" alt="Anjan_3331_1-1758625305400.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please suggest&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/smart-filter-bar-not-visible-after-smart-table-personalisation-in-sap-fiori/qaa-p/14225473#M4927154"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:51:05.838000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/fileloadexception-could-not-load-file-or-assembly-crystaldecisions/qaq-p/14225474</id>
    <title>FileLoadException: Could not load file or assembly CrystalDecisions.ReportAppServer.CommLayer</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:53:21.881000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mcit</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255969</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I would like to call a crystal reports report in a .net application (C#) but even after installing "SAP Crystal Reports, version for Visual Studio" I am getting an error when executing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-csharp"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ReportDocument report = new ReportDocument();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the error:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;System.TypeInitializationException: 'The type initializer for 'CrystalDecisions.CrystalReports.Engine.ReportDocument' threw an exception.'&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inner Exception:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;FileLoadException: Could not load file or assembly 'CrystalDecisions.ReportAppServer.CommLayer, Version=13.0.3500.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=692fbea5521e1304' or one of its dependencies. The located assembly's manifest definition does not match the assembly reference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am using VS Pro 2022 64bit and .NET 4.8.09032. I included the following references in my application:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="refs" style="width: 383px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318783i58BCFF4278592600/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="references.png" alt="refs" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;refs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What do I have to do to get rid of the error? Actually I would like to call a predefined report like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-csharp"&gt;&lt;code&gt;string pathofrptfile=somepath + "\\Reports\\report1.rpt";
report.Load(pathofrptfile);
report.SetDataSource(dt);
report.ExportToDisk(CrystalDecisions.Shared.ExportFormatType.PortableDocFormat,Directory.GetParent(Path.GetDirectoryName(Application.ExecutablePath)) + FilePath);
report.Dispose();
GC.Collect();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/fileloadexception-could-not-load-file-or-assembly-crystaldecisions/qaq-p/14225474"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:53:21.881000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-get-date-filter-as-calendar-format/qaa-p/14225475#M4927156</id>
    <title>Re: How to get Date Filter as Calendar format</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:54:00.110000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vasu_Sac</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1394811</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370"&gt;@N1kh1l&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Generally "Add Input control" or "Create Custom Date" option will create a object in Page. Some times if we delete accidently how to get back the object in page. Is it require to create again new "Create Custom Date option"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards, Vasu&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-get-date-filter-as-calendar-format/qaa-p/14225475#M4927156"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:54:00.110000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/internal-error-quot-argument-cannot-be-null-error-rwi-00010-quot-while/qaa-p/14225476#M4927157</id>
    <title>Re: Internal error ("Argument cannot be null. (Error: RWI 00010)") while exporting the WEB</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:54:28.530000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>benasirennes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348531</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;BR /&gt;Do you know what happened since last time ?&lt;BR /&gt;- number of lines in result increased ? Try to add a filter to reduce them (for testing purpose) and try again&lt;BR /&gt;- changed in design of the report (charts, ...) ? If you have many reports in your document, suppress one after the other untill it works to determine if one of them is the cause of the error...&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Hope this helps,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Benoît&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/internal-error-quot-argument-cannot-be-null-error-rwi-00010-quot-while/qaa-p/14225476#M4927157"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:54:28.530000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-my-inbox-to-sap-task-center-a-customer-s-journey-to-unified-task/ba-p/14211167</id>
    <title>From My Inbox to SAP Task Center: A Customer’s Journey to Unified Task Management</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:58:38.874000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ferit_Hayrulov</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/151357</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In today’s enterprise landscape, employees often navigate multiple systems to complete everyday approvals - such as leave requests in SAP SuccessFactors, invoices in SAP Ariba, purchase orders in SAP S/4HANA, or workflows in SAP Build Process Automation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For many organizations, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Fiori My Inbox&lt;/STRONG&gt; has served as the go-to solution for managing workflow tasks. However, with the adoption of more SAP Cloud solutions, customers are looking for a &lt;STRONG&gt;central, scalable, and modern task hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; that goes beyond the capabilities of My Inbox.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Task Center&lt;/STRONG&gt; comes into play. And with the help of the official &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/task-center/transition-guide-to-stc/introducing-sap-task-center?locale=en-US&amp;amp;utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Transition Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, customers can make this shift with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why the Transition Guide Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of our customers, a global manufacturing company, recently began their journey from My Inbox to SAP Task Center. For their IT team, the &lt;STRONG&gt;Transition Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt; was an essential resource that addressed the most critical questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature Clarity:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A direct comparison of My Inbox and SAP Task Center capabilities helped them map existing functionality to the new experience.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migration Planning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Clear guidance on prerequisites, dependencies, and planning considerations made it easy to build a structured rollout plan.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implementation Steps:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Detailed instructions on setup, authentication, and connector configuration ensured the transition was straightforward and predictable.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“The guide made it feel less like a migration project and more like a natural upgrade path.”&lt;/EM&gt; — IT Manager, Customer Project&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits of Moving to SAP Task Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After adopting SAP Task Center, the customer quickly began to see measurable benefits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified Inbox:&lt;/STRONG&gt; All approvals and workflow items from multiple systems consolidated into a single, central inbox.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Time Savings:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reduced time spent switching between different applications for task approvals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resilience:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cached task storage ensured availability even if backend systems were temporarily unreachable.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Multiple service plan options allowed fine-tuning of task federation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mobile Enablement:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Seamless integration with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Mobile Start&lt;/STRONG&gt; provided executives with approvals on the go.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result: &lt;STRONG&gt;higher task completion rates&lt;/STRONG&gt;, reduced approval bottlenecks, and improved employee experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Unified Future for Task Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For organizations still relying on My Inbox, the transition to SAP Task Center is more than a technical migration—it’s a &lt;STRONG&gt;strategic opportunity to streamline work, empower employees, and prepare for future growth&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Transition Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt; ensures that this move is achievable and well-supported, regardless of IT landscape complexity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Get Started&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read the official &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/task-center/transition-guide-to-stc/introducing-sap-task-center?locale=en-US&amp;amp;utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Transition Guide to SAP Task Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Explore &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-task-center?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Task Center in SAP Discovery Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Join the conversation in the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/task-center/faq?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Community for Task Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Task Center represents the next generation of task management for SAP landscapes—bringing together approvals, workflows, and actions from multiple solutions into one unified experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the &lt;STRONG&gt;Transition Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt;, customers can move forward with clarity, confidence, and a proven roadmap for success.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-my-inbox-to-sap-task-center-a-customer-s-journey-to-unified-task/ba-p/14211167"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:58:38.874000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/not-able-to-update-issuing-storage-location-reslo-field-during-pr-creation/qaa-p/14225479#M4927158</id>
    <title>Re: Not able to update Issuing Storage Location - RESLO -...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T11:59:34.068000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Caterina_Bulgarelli</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/134087</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121" target="_blank"&gt;@Chris1973&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;are you able to give us any indication on this matter?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thank you in advance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Caterina&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/not-able-to-update-issuing-storage-location-reslo-field-during-pr-creation/qaa-p/14225479#M4927158"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:59:34.068000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/api-call-api-maintainanceorder-ends-with-http-rc-423-and-message-quot/qaq-p/14225480</id>
    <title>API Call API_MAINTAINANCEORDER ends with HTTP RC 423  and message "Billable Order 4001380 is not sup</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:01:41.401000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gregor_Graf1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1585086</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In SAP Note 3330419 (&lt;A href="https://deu01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fme.sap.com%2Fnotes%2F3330419&amp;amp;data=05%7C02%7CGregor-Hubert.Graf%40external.telekom.de%7Cd2b3a8d9fa4d4de6822208ddf7a37113%7Cbde4dffc4b604cf68b04a5eeb25f5c4f%7C0%7C0%7C638939003532278034%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJFbXB0eU1hcGkiOnRydWUsIlYiOiIwLjAuMDAwMCIsIlAiOiJXaW4zMiIsIkFOIjoiTWFpbCIsIldUIjoyfQ%3D%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=j%2FVW11Y3EyyrQ3bYuR03OByGsSOtEvuUxrVvRGm2Z8M%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;3330419 - Release-Informationen und -Einschränkungen in Bezug auf SAP S/4HANA Service - SAP for Me )&amp;nbsp; is described that for if you flag a maintenance order as billable&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;is described that ar least with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA Service 2023 FPS3&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;it is not possible to create or change a billable flagged maintainance order via API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are they any plans in the SAP roadmap to enhance the API to make it possible ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Gregor_Graf1_0-1758620909541.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318780iF7D6E3FD46E0BC44/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Gregor_Graf1_0-1758620909541.png" alt="Gregor_Graf1_0-1758620909541.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Gregor_Graf1_1-1758620909545.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318779i82C95FBCDA3954A8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Gregor_Graf1_1-1758620909545.png" alt="Gregor_Graf1_1-1758620909545.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Gregor_Graf1_2-1758620909548.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318781i56CF89A1CAEB1026/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Gregor_Graf1_2-1758620909548.png" alt="Gregor_Graf1_2-1758620909548.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/api-call-api-maintainanceorder-ends-with-http-rc-423-and-message-quot/qaq-p/14225480"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:01:41.401000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/manage-cancellations-app-to-cancel-quantity-confirmations/qaa-p/14225483#M84354</id>
    <title>Re: 'Manage Cancellations' app to cancel quantity confirm...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:02:33.561000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marcobarat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/129227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>i know the feelings...</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/manage-cancellations-app-to-cancel-quantity-confirmations/qaa-p/14225483#M84354"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:02:33.561000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-cloud-platform-integration-cpi-use-cases-of-node-functions-in-message/bc-p/14225485#M175605</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Cloud Platform Integration (CPI): Use cases of node functions in message mapping</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:02:43.605000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eloise27</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1475709</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Very clear and crisp&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-cloud-platform-integration-cpi-use-cases-of-node-functions-in-message/bc-p/14225485#M175605"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:02:43.605000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/manage-cancellations-app-to-cancel-quantity-confirmations/qaa-p/14225486#M84355</id>
    <title>Re: 'Manage Cancellations' app to cancel quantity confirm...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:03:00.287000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marcobarat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/129227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>i know the feelings... in the meantime you could post a suggestion in the sap influence portal (i know that this is the standard sap.me support answer lol)</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/manage-cancellations-app-to-cancel-quantity-confirmations/qaa-p/14225486#M84355"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:03:00.287000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/sap-public-cloud-quality-certificate-doesn-t-print-the-mean-value-results/qaa-p/14225488#M84356</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud: Quality Certificate doesn't print t...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:03:50.511000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AM1987</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1485573</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, Chris!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your input. I have follow your recommendations and i would like to confirm what you say about&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;summarized&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;result in inspection point:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AM1987_0-1758622180225.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318791iB6BD5A284539FEC1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AM1987_0-1758622180225.png" alt="AM1987_0-1758622180225.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;About the other conditions: MIC is &lt;STRONG&gt;summ. recording&lt;/STRONG&gt; and certificate profile is set as shown before. The quality certificate now prints a blank result:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AM1987_1-1758622639729.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318795iE996EEE1D9F62FF9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AM1987_1-1758622639729.png" alt="AM1987_1-1758622639729.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have some new tip to solve this, I will appreciate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;André&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/sap-public-cloud-quality-certificate-doesn-t-print-the-mean-value-results/qaa-p/14225488#M84356"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:03:50.511000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-s-4hana-private-cloud-deleting-an-auc-assignment-from-the-wbs-element/qaq-p/14225489</id>
    <title>SAP S/4HANA private Cloud: Deleting an AuC assignment from the WBS element</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:05:18.206000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marleenkk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140597</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we are currently facing the challenge that we created an investment project with several WBS elements, all of which were assigned an investment profile that automatically generates an AuC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now the customer has noticed that for one WBS element, the AuC already existed as an asset in the legacy system, which is why settlement should now be made to this asset.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I can assign the asset in the settlement rule, however, the system always reverts back to the AuC. We have already reversed all previous settlements so that no values should remain on the AuC. It is also deactived.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="marleenkk_2-1758618716372.png" style="width: 719px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318747i9327E7A517E3A869/image-dimensions/719x164/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="719" height="164" role="button" title="marleenkk_2-1758618716372.png" alt="marleenkk_2-1758618716372.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first line is greyed out and cannot be changed&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="marleenkk_3-1758618783012.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318748iE78095D7E592C608/image-dimensions/400x485/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="400" height="485" role="button" title="marleenkk_3-1758618783012.png" alt="marleenkk_3-1758618783012.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="marleenkk_0-1758618507948.png" style="width: 600px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318744i3A594E75D803BED7/image-dimensions/600x287/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="600" height="287" role="button" title="marleenkk_0-1758618507948.png" alt="marleenkk_0-1758618507948.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the investment profile which I want to change to an investment profile without an AuC (Z9999), but I am getting the following error &lt;SPAN&gt;KD 199 "Enter a valid value for the settlement type".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following line items exist on the WBS element (postings and reversals): &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="marleenkk_4-1758621742867.png" style="width: 588px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318785iFF00C51FC9D08817/image-dimensions/588x479/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="588" height="479" role="button" title="marleenkk_4-1758621742867.png" alt="marleenkk_4-1758621742867.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What else is missing so that I can remove the AuC from there?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Marleen&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-s-4hana-private-cloud-deleting-an-auc-assignment-from-the-wbs-element/qaq-p/14225489"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:05:18.206000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/bc-p/14225501#M184781</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP test cockpit (ATC) recommendations for governance of clean core ABAP development</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:18:32.062000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OlgaDolinskaja</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6638</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/162177"&gt;@mischarf&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;this SAP Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3593439" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3593439&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;should help to exclude the Key User objects from the ATC check&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Olga.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/bc-p/14225501#M184781"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:18:32.062000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/not-able-to-escape-the-approval/qaq-p/14225504</id>
    <title>not able to escape the approval</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:22:08.630000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jerrysam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/893077</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we have deactivated all sorts of workflow for sales from manage sales document workflow app somehow still it shows in approval status in sap public cloud .How can we find out to see in whose workflow it is and how to escape from this workflow approval thing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jerrysam_0-1758622890737.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318797i07DCC2DAF701D740/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jerrysam_0-1758622890737.png" alt="jerrysam_0-1758622890737.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/not-able-to-escape-the-approval/qaq-p/14225504"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:22:08.630000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/sap-btp-trail-sap-build/td-p/14225506</id>
    <title>SAP BTP Trail - SAP Build</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:27:05.989000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shinksy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/704577</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am working through the SAP Build demo and it states to add the resource for S4HANA_JOULE_PRODUCT. I do not see this available on my account. Is this something I can add in BTP or should it automatically be created for my trail account?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://trials.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/learning-journey/BT-Build_code/102-5_Build_Code" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://trials.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/learning-journey/BT-Build_code/102-5_Build_Code&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shinksy_0-1758623145146.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318798i980916D84D89759C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shinksy_0-1758623145146.png" alt="shinksy_0-1758623145146.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any help is much appreciated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Martin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/sap-btp-trail-sap-build/td-p/14225506"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:27:05.989000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/in-co11n-no-auto-goods-receipt-issues-for-materials-having-serial-number/qaa-p/14225507#M4227825</id>
    <title>Re: In CO11N, no auto goods receipt &amp; issues for material...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:27:58.933000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ashutosh6</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1500301</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Two different control keys&lt;/STRONG&gt; were used in the same routing (PP01 and PP03).&amp;nbsp;PP03 has &lt;STRONG&gt;Auto GR ticked&lt;/STRONG&gt; by standard, PP01 does &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Because the production order had mixed control keys&amp;nbsp;(&lt;STRONG&gt;Both with Auto GR because of manual intervention&lt;/STRONG&gt;), the system couldn’t determine consistently where/how to trigger the 101 GR. As a result, the &lt;STRONG&gt;101 goods receipt line item was missing entirely&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Root cause:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;clash of Auto GR indicators in multiple control keys within the same order&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/in-co11n-no-auto-goods-receipt-issues-for-materials-having-serial-number/qaa-p/14225507#M4227825"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:27:58.933000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/message-no-m7093/qaa-p/14225510#M4227826</id>
    <title>Re: Message No. M7093</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:30:38.428000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xujun</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>ok i'll help you</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/message-no-m7093/qaa-p/14225510#M4227826"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:30:38.428000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/message-no-m7093/qaa-p/14225512#M4227827</id>
    <title>Re: Message No. M7093</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:32:46+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xujun</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>who are u?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/message-no-m7093/qaa-p/14225512#M4227827"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:32:46+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/absence-counting-rules-2-0-in-time-management-2h-2023/bc-p/14225514#M61899</id>
    <title>Re: Absence Counting Rules 2.0 in Time Management - 2H 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:35:46.633000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aszukala</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/59473</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15303" target="_blank"&gt;@priyanka&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have requirement to count public holidays as an absence for specific time types according to work schedule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means that if employee works e.g. from Mon-Thu 8h and on Fri 4h then public holiday which is between Mon-Thu should be counted as 8h (or 1 day) while when public holiday is on Fri then 4h should be taken (or half day). Company have a lot of work schedules. What is the best approach to handle such a request?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ania&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/absence-counting-rules-2-0-in-time-management-2h-2023/bc-p/14225514#M61899"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:35:46.633000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/badi-to-validate-all-the-warehouse-tasks-in-one-go-at-the-time-of-creation/qaa-p/14225518#M207241</id>
    <title>Re: BADI to validate all the warehouse tasks in one go at the time of creation via /scwm/todlv_o</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:41:36.932000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, thank you for your question. I've forwarded it to the experts. Kind regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/badi-to-validate-all-the-warehouse-tasks-in-one-go-at-the-time-of-creation/qaa-p/14225518#M207241"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:41:36.932000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/date-of-last-sales-order/qaa-p/14225519#M4227828</id>
    <title>Re: Date of Last Sales Order</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:42:24.182000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MarisaF-UPI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/61240</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you. I will check.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/date-of-last-sales-order/qaa-p/14225519#M4227828"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:42:24.182000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/step-into-sap-digital-manufacturing-with-our-q4-onboarding-webcast/ba-p/14225520</id>
    <title>Step into SAP Digital Manufacturing with Our Q4 Onboarding Webcast</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:42:27.484000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ines_Bastos</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1660623</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Are you new to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Digital Manufacturing&lt;/STRONG&gt; and looking for clear guidance on how to start your implementation the right way?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join our &lt;STRONG&gt;Q4 Onboarding Webcast&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;on October 23rd&amp;nbsp;and gain the insights you need to kick off your project with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this live session, we’ll provide customers and partners with the &lt;STRONG&gt;essential knowledge, tools, and resources&lt;/STRONG&gt; to navigate the SAP Digital Manufacturing onboarding journey successfully.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ll learn about the four key phases of onboarding and what to expect in each step:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plan Your Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prepare to Go Live&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t miss this opportunity to set a strong foundation for your SAP Digital Manufacturing journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register in &lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center/sap-customer-onboarding-webcasts/sap-digital-manufacturing-onboarding-webcasts.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="request 2323.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318804i204AE72473A517B8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="request 2323.png" alt="request 2323.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/step-into-sap-digital-manufacturing-with-our-q4-onboarding-webcast/ba-p/14225520"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:42:27.484000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/generative-ai-use-cases-for-ecommerce-implementations/ba-p/14110806</id>
    <title>Generative AI use cases for ecommerce implementations</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:43:21.594000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>swapnachirra</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/799251</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The crucial step which converts a browse to a buy in ecommerce applications is the product search. A user browses an ecommerce site for an interested product using a keyword or a descriptive search, finds the relevant product and continues to place an order for the same. Any difficulty in finding the desired product leads to an unpleasant user experience, leading to customer support calls or leaving of the site without a purchase.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The advent of Generative AI has revolutionized the ecommerce domain like many other domains.&amp;nbsp;Generative AI is the ability of Large Language Models (LLMs / SLMs) to create contextual and personalized content.&amp;nbsp;Generative AI, powered by Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), has seen massive impact in building applications and chatbots that can utilize enterprise data to power the LLM generations.&amp;nbsp;Personalization and Hyper-personalization help building an elevated customer experience. The Gen AI Agents are driven by instruction or prompt templates that can capture the user questions and related parameters to generate a response referring to the context provided to the LLM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Main Portion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The power of Generative AI can weaponize ecommerce applications in enhancing the user purchase experience in multiple ways. There are two such use cases which are most common in global purchasing experiences.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the use cases is product search, where almost all ecommerce applications provide a search option to accept user's input and show relevant product search results for the user to choose from.&amp;nbsp;Gen AI Powered Product Search supporting natural intent based &amp;amp; personalized conversational search, providing the ability to search based on descriptive content and not only the attribute data model, short searches and abbreviations the search queries, accept typos and grammatical errors to not impact search results. The below features would be possible&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Search using natural language and free flowing text-based interaction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Independent of underlying field mappings, preset rules and domain intricacies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Personalized Search Experience along with Recommendations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Second use case is a purchase assistant chatbot. Ecommerce websites usually provide a chat support to help the users through a live customer support agent integrating with a third-party solution or an automated chatbot which can support with limited set of responses while sharing a contact number for further support. With Gen AI powered purchase assistant chatbot, the users can be given a personalized purchasing experience by recommending products based on user prompts combined with user's previous purchase history. This would help user with guidance for quickly placing the desired order. The below would be possible features&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User can ask questions from a generic context through prompts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User can make purchases based upon product facets&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User can make purchases based upon keyword driven searches&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Generative AI solutions would in summary empower an ecommerce application with&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Semantic &amp;amp; Intent based searches​ and chat interfaces&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Relevance ranking of results​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Auto spell corrections&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Personalized suggestions based on user’s past search history​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collaborative filtering to recommend items bought by similar users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recommend next best products to be ordered referring to the order history of purchases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While these solutions can be custom built as per the ecommerce applications using various available technologies like Open AI GPT models, Langchain, Vector DB etc., the ecommerce platforms are also coming up with their own GEN AI tool kits which can be integrated. An example would be SAP CX AI Tooklit by SAP Commerce Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As Generative AI opens a new era in ecommerce transforming selling, marketing and customer experiences, the existing and new ecommerce applications would have a competitive advantage by adapting the Gen AI solutions for identified relevant use cases and staying ahead in the digital ecommerce landscape.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/generative-ai-use-cases-for-ecommerce-implementations/ba-p/14110806"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:43:21.594000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/date-of-last-sales-order/qaa-p/14225521#M4227829</id>
    <title>Re: Date of Last Sales Order</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:44:12.409000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MarisaF-UPI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/61240</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you. I will check that report w/options. The other option is very easy and quick to do for one-offs, but I need a report I can run.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/date-of-last-sales-order/qaa-p/14225521#M4227829"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:44:12.409000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/abap-cloud-number-ranges-the-abap-rap-commit-work-conflict-and-the-simple/ba-p/14221714</id>
    <title>ABAP Cloud Number Ranges: The ABAP RAP COMMIT WORK Conflict and the Simple Fix</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:45:39.845000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>suzanne_alivand</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/848404</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many business applications require unique numbers, for example, to complete the keys of data records. In order to get numbers from an interval, a number range object must be defined which can contain different properties. Standard Number ranges are typically maintained via customizing in each system (Test and Production). However, the process for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;custom&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Number Range Objects in the S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition is different.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These custom objects must be created in the development environment, configured in the customizing client, and then transported through the landscape. This blog outlines that end-to-end process, including a frustrating short dump I encountered and the surprisingly simple configuration change that solved it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 1: The Developer's Task - Defining the Blueprint in ADT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unlike the on-premises world, the process for a custom number range begins in the developer's toolkit: ABAP Development Tools (ADT). Here, you create the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;definition&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;or the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;blueprint&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;of your number range object.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your ABAP package, right-click and choose&amp;nbsp;New&amp;nbsp;-&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;Other ABAP Repository Object.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Search for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Number Range Object"&lt;/STRONG&gt;, give it a name and a description.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign it to a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workbench Transport&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the object editor, the most important property is the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Number Length Domain&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It’s a best practice to create a custom domain for this to define the length and type. For my&amp;nbsp;ZPO_RUN_ID, I used a domain of type&amp;nbsp;NUMC(10).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;activate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;the object.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="suzanne_alivand_7-1758216453231.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316647iBAD6D68F8E9EC235/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="suzanne_alivand_7-1758216453231.png" alt="suzanne_alivand_7-1758216453231.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system now knows what a&amp;nbsp;ZPO_RUN_ID&amp;nbsp;is, but it has no actual number intervals defined.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 2: The Customizer's Task - Setting Intervals in Fiori&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where we move to the Fiori Launchpad, specifically in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customizing Client&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in to your Customizing client and open the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Manage Number Range Intervals"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fiori app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Search for your newly created object,&amp;nbsp;ZPO_RUN_ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to the "Number Ranges" tab and click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Create"&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Here you'll define your interval, for example,&amp;nbsp;01&amp;nbsp;with its lower and upper limits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="suzanne_alivand_8-1758216453232.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316646i0A9308E96CB6625D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="suzanne_alivand_8-1758216453232.png" alt="suzanne_alivand_8-1758216453232.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="suzanne_alivand_13-1758216499507.png" style="width: 663px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316652i70CFA2444947FDD8/image-dimensions/663x226/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="663" height="226" role="button" title="suzanne_alivand_13-1758216499507.png" alt="suzanne_alivand_13-1758216499507.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 3: The Transport &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system needs a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customizing Transport&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to record this change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In a new tab, open the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Export Customizing Transports"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fiori app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="suzanne_alivand_10-1758216453236.png" style="width: 237px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316649iD7EFC91ECED66A4B/image-dimensions/237x191/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="237" height="191" role="button" title="suzanne_alivand_10-1758216453236.png" alt="suzanne_alivand_10-1758216453236.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Customizing Request"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and give it a description. It's a good practice to set this as your "Default" request using the "Change Category" button.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="suzanne_alivand_11-1758216453238.png" style="width: 734px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316650i3B8DE8A478A85F6C/image-dimensions/734x90/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="734" height="90" role="button" title="suzanne_alivand_11-1758216453238.png" alt="suzanne_alivand_11-1758216453238.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go back to the Number Range app and save your interval again. This time, it will find your open request and save the change successfully.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="suzanne_alivand_12-1758216453239.png" style="width: 823px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316651i263BA5C692E50873/image-dimensions/823x99/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="823" height="99" role="button" title="suzanne_alivand_12-1758216453239.png" alt="suzanne_alivand_12-1758216453239.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now you have two transports: the Workbench TR from ADT with the object definition, and the Customizing TR from Fiori with the interval data. The Workbench TR should be a prerequisite for the Customizing TR when you import them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 4: The Payoff - Using the Number Range in RAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With everything configured, it was time to use it in my ABAP RAP application. The correct, released API is the class&amp;nbsp;CL_NUMBERRANGE_RUNTIME.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I had two main options for assigning an ID based on the business requirement:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;An&amp;nbsp;early numbering&amp;nbsp;determination, which runs before the save phase.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A&amp;nbsp;determination on save, which runs during the final save transaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I initially chose early numbering&amp;nbsp;determination. My&amp;nbsp;earlynumbering_create method was clean and used the correct class.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;METHOD earlynumbering_create.

    DATA: latest_num   TYPE cl_numberrange_runtime=&amp;gt;nr_number.

    DATA(All_entities) = entities.
    DELETE All_entities WHERE  RunId IS NOT INITIAL.

    TRY.
        cl_numberrange_runtime=&amp;gt;number_get(
          EXPORTING
            nr_range_nr = '01'
            object      = 'ZPO_RUN_ID'
            quantity = CONV #( lines( all_entities ) )
          IMPORTING
            number      = latest_num
            returncode = DATA(code)
            returned_quantity = DATA(return_qty) ).

      CATCH cx_nr_object_not_found INTO DATA(lx_obj_not_found).
      CATCH cx_number_ranges INTO DATA(lx_ranges_error).

        LOOP AT All_entities INTO DATA(entity_line).

          APPEND VALUE #( %cid = entity_line-%cid
                          %key  = entity_line-%key ) TO failed-run.
          APPEND VALUE #( %cid = entity_line-%cid
                          %key = entity_line-%key
                          %msg = lx_ranges_error ) TO reported-run.
        ENDLOOP.
        EXIT.
    ENDTRY.

    DATA(curr_num) = latest_num - return_qty.

    LOOP AT All_entities INTO entity_line.
      curr_num = curr_num + 1 .
      APPEND VALUE #( %cid = entity_line-%cid
      RunUuid = curr_num ) TO mapped-run.

    ENDLOOP.
  ENDMETHOD.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;I ran the app, created an entry, clicked "Save," and was met with a short dump:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP Runtime error 'BEHAVIOR_ILLEGAL_STATEMENT'&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The "Aha!" Moment: The&amp;nbsp;COMMIT WORK&amp;nbsp;Conflict and the Simple Fix&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My code was correct. The class was correct. The configuration was correct. So, what was wrong?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The problem was my number range was&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;not buffered&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After a long debugging session, I discovered that when&amp;nbsp;cl_numberrange_runtime&amp;nbsp;is called for a non-buffered number range, it&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;must&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;perform an immediate database&amp;nbsp;UPDATE&amp;nbsp;and its own&amp;nbsp;COMMIT WORK&amp;nbsp;to guarantee the number is reserved. The RAP framework, in its strictly controlled Save phase, saw this independent&amp;nbsp;COMMIT&amp;nbsp;as a violation of its own transaction and triggered the dump to prevent data inconsistency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The solution wasn't in my ABAP code at all. It was in the configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling buffering solves this transactional conflict.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Here’s why:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;With buffering, the class gets the next number from the application server's&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;memory&lt;/STRONG&gt;, not directly from the database.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Getting a number from memory requires&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;no immediate database update&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and, crucially,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;no conflicting&amp;nbsp;COMMIT WORK&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I edited the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Properties&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;of my&amp;nbsp;ZPO_RUN_ID&amp;nbsp;object and changed the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Buffering&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;type to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Main Memory Buffering"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with a size of 10.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With that one configuration change, everything worked perfectly. My&amp;nbsp;determination on save&amp;nbsp;now executes without any issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the ABAP Cloud, writing correct code is only half the battle. We also have to deeply understand and respect the strict transactional model of the RAP framework. A seemingly simple configuration choice, like buffering, can be the key to resolving what looks like a complex runtime error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you ever face an unexpected&amp;nbsp;BEHAVIOR_ILLEGAL_STATEMENT&amp;nbsp;dump, consider what your code might be doing that could be trying to interfere with the framework's unit of work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/abap-cloud-number-ranges-the-abap-rap-commit-work-conflict-and-the-simple/ba-p/14221714"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:45:39.845000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/talent-intelligence-hub-implementation-key-learnings-from-client-projects/bc-p/14225523#M7140</id>
    <title>Re: Talent Intelligence Hub Implementation: Key Learnings from Client Projects</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T12:51:36.806000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JM_1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/18159</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1666155"&gt;@NeelamPandya&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can check our SAP Learning Journey that covers Talent Intelligence Hub. There is no specific certification but this course includes all about TIH (permissions, configuration, import/export data, AI features...)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/configuring-sap-successfactors-platform-advanced-topics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/configuring-sap-successfactors-platform-advanced-topics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this will help,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Jordi&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/talent-intelligence-hub-implementation-key-learnings-from-client-projects/bc-p/14225523#M7140"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T12:51:36.806000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/i-have-a-requirement-where-2030-costs-needs-to-be-distributed-in-planning/qaa-p/14225539#M4927159</id>
    <title>Re: I have a requirement where 2030 costs needs to be dis...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:02:05.208000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MoonJun</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1480435</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2225911"&gt;@Pallavi_Dasgupta98&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to distribute the same amount across the planning periods, the following data action script can be a solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Model - Version dimension&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For each planning version, the planning period must be defined as a property.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;2025_Plan:&amp;nbsp;Plan_Start=202601,&amp;nbsp;Plan_End=202912&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;2026_Plan:&amp;nbsp;Plan_Start=202701,&amp;nbsp;Plan_End=202912&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Version_Start_End.png" style="width: 856px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318805i9B695A4A536B72D5/image-dimensions/856x148/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="856" height="148" role="button" title="Version_Start_End.png" alt="Version_Start_End.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Data Action Script (Advanced formulas)&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-c"&gt;&lt;code&gt;//Date scope is set based on the Version Property Plan_Start &amp;amp; Plan_End
MEMBERSET [d/Date] = [d/Version].[p/Plan_Start] TO [d/Version].[p/Plan_End]

//Define Integer variable @No_Of_Plan_Month.
INTEGER @No_Of_Plan_Month

//Calculate how many months the planning period spans.
@No_Of_Plan_Month = DATEDIFF([d/Version].[p/Plan_Start], [d/Version].[p/Plan_End], "MONTH") + 1

//2030.Jan costs is distributed in planning years.
DATA([d/Account] = "Cost_01") = RESULTLOOKUP([d/Account] = "Cost_01", [d/Date] = "203001") / @No_Of_Plan_Month&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Source Data &amp;amp; Calculated result&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Version: 2025_Plan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Planning Period: 202601 ~ 202912 &lt;STRONG&gt;(48 months)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Source value: &lt;STRONG&gt;4,800&lt;/STRONG&gt;(Date=203001, Account=Cost_01)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Plan_2025.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318807i3706993663D01791/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Plan_2025.png" alt="Plan_2025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Version: 2026_Plan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Planning Period: 202701 ~ 202912 &lt;STRONG&gt;(36 months)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Source value: &lt;STRONG&gt;7,200&lt;/STRONG&gt;(Date=203001, Account=Cost_01)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Plan_2026.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318808i0D7E1169CA5A2FE8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Plan_2026.png" alt="Plan_2026.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this is helpful to you, and if I have misunderstood anything, please feel free to reach out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moonjun&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/i-have-a-requirement-where-2030-costs-needs-to-be-distributed-in-planning/qaa-p/14225539#M4927159"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T13:02:05.208000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/absence-counting-rules-2-0-in-time-management-2h-2023/bc-p/14225541#M61900</id>
    <title>Re: Absence Counting Rules 2.0 in Time Management - 2H 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:02:28.579000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PriyankaAgarwal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/26791</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/59473"&gt;@aszukala&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are planning to expose the original hours from the work schedule in the absence counting rule parameters. This will hopefully help in&amp;nbsp; deciding that if a day was a working day but also a holiday, you still need to count as 1 day.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Would that help?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Priyanka&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/absence-counting-rules-2-0-in-time-management-2h-2023/bc-p/14225541#M61900"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T13:02:28.579000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/btp-abap-environment-update-where-used-list/qaq-p/14225544</id>
    <title>BTP ABAP Environment - Update Where-Used List</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:04:14.972000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Attila</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/129182</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Cloud-ers,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;do You know how-to update the where-used-list on BTP ABAP Environment for standard repository objects ?&lt;BR /&gt;I did not find any alternative to&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;saprseub report. Activation of standard objects is also not possible, which would implicitly update the where-used index.&lt;BR /&gt;So far using the ABAP Code Search plugin by DevEpos as an alternative, but I do not want to scan and wait a full scan for each time I am looking for something.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;It is a BTP ABAP Free Tier Environment.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Thank You&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Attila&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/btp-abap-environment-update-where-used-list/qaq-p/14225544"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T13:04:14.972000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/how-to-configure-email-alerts-for-cpi-failures-using-sap-btp/bc-p/14225547#M50346</id>
    <title>Re: How to Configure Email Alerts for CPI Failures Using SAP BTP</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:09:23.587000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>petergeukens</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35983</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you for this detailed blog!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was wondering why this solution would be preferred instead of using alerts &amp;amp; notifications via ALM?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/how-to-configure-email-alerts-for-cpi-failures-using-sap-btp/bc-p/14225547#M50346"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T13:09:23.587000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/message-no-m7093/qaa-p/14225548#M4227834</id>
    <title>Re: Message No. M7093</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:09:58.043000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaymondGiuseppi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/185148</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Read (if not already) KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2638505/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2638505 - Error Message M7093 - Fld selectn for type differs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Also good old one&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/9281/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;9281 - Fld select. for G/L acct/movement type do not match&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Did you run report RM07CUFA&amp;nbsp; as suggested in message long text&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/message-no-m7093/qaa-p/14225548#M4227834"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T13:09:58.043000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/user-list-who-are-not-using-afo-in-table-rsfec-we-are-getting-the-hostname/qaa-p/14225550#M4927161</id>
    <title>Re: User list who are not using AFO .In Table RSFEC , we...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:11:38.639000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>manu_allaert</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/299754</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If they are not using AfO these users will not have logged into your BW system after a certain date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use tcode SUIM and the option indicated&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="manu_allaert_0-1758625127435.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318813iECD64A529B1133DD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="manu_allaert_0-1758625127435.png" alt="manu_allaert_0-1758625127435.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And use a selection similar to the screen below&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="manu_allaert_2-1758625670959.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318819iED9708B283350B35/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="manu_allaert_2-1758625670959.png" alt="manu_allaert_2-1758625670959.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manu&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;an thi&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/user-list-who-are-not-using-afo-in-table-rsfec-we-are-getting-the-hostname/qaa-p/14225550#M4927161"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T13:11:38.639000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/custom-report-in-project-system/qaq-p/14225552</id>
    <title>Custom Report in Project System</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:13:37.651000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>akashtilokani</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1934161</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are planning costs on the WBS using unit cost method. The planned costs on a WBS is sum of planned costs for various item categories, obtained using simple multiplication of price and quantity. The costs will be planned in different versions. My client requires a report that compares the price, quantity, value of each item category in different versions for a particular WBS element or for the whole project (but WBS element wise). I am trying to prepare the functional specification of the report for ABAP development. CONSIDER A SITUATION WHERE BUDGET IS NOT PLANNED. I started by passing the project definition in PSPHI table of PRPS table and passing the WBS element in POSID field of the same table. I obtained OBJNR from this. I then passed OBJNR in RPSCO table along with the version in VERSN and obtained the details on planned costs with WRTTP for planned values. I am now unable to understand the link between RPSCO and CKHS table. If I pass OBJNR directly in CKHS, I am able to obtain KALNR. This KALNR is further passed in CKIS table to get the item category wise detail, i.e., price, quantity and value corresponding to each item category. Can you please guide me to establish a link between RPSCO and CKHS table? This link is necessary to pull the version in. If budget is planned, I can directly see BPGE table for VERSN and obtain KALNR and then pass KALNR in CKIS table to obtain the details at the level of item category. Will this still be the solution in cases of no budgets? Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/custom-report-in-project-system/qaq-p/14225552"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T13:13:37.651000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
