<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-12-03T20:29:01.563249+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/app-run-proposal-error/qaa-p/14283126#M256766</id>
    <title>Re: APP run proposal error</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:07:33.284000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MdDilshad_Khan67</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255895</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;ACTIVLY MARKING THE TICK ' START IMMEDIATELY ' BUT STILL THE ERROR IS COMMING&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/app-run-proposal-error/qaa-p/14283126#M256766"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:07:33.284000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/app-run-proposal-error/qaa-p/14283128#M256767</id>
    <title>Re: APP run proposal error</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:11:00.881000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MdDilshad_Khan67</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255895</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Divyesh, Thanks for responding&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;open item is created,&lt;BR /&gt;bank detials are correct,&lt;BR /&gt;Payment method mtd is given in vendor master,&lt;BR /&gt;while run iam activly marking tick (start immediately), and deleted current proposal and made another proposal with different identifiction number, but still same error is occuring.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;NEED SOL ON THIS : HOW TO DELETE ALL OLD PROPOSALS WHICH ARE PENDING , IN FBZP EDIT PROPOSAL LIST IS FREEZED, UNABLE TO OPEN PROPOSAL LIST.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/app-run-proposal-error/qaa-p/14283128#M256767"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:11:00.881000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fwso-error-in-ap/qaa-p/14283129#M4232598</id>
    <title>Re: FWSO Error in AP</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:11:59.893000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jithendrashiva</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/846337</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we manually update interest rate adjustment every month in TJ05 so if we miss to update we are getting error as&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Interest rate adjustment for 11/26/2025 must take place before posting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;can you please let us know how to update interest rate adjust automatically or avoid error&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interest rate adjustment for 09/26/2025 must take place before posting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please share your thoughts on this&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Jitendra Shivashankar&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fwso-error-in-ap/qaa-p/14283129#M4232598"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:11:59.893000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management-blog-posts/digital-adoption-mit-walkme-im-%C3%BCberblick-und-in-aktion-bei-stada/ba-p/14283133</id>
    <title>Digital Adoption mit WalkMe im Überblick und in Aktion bei STADA Arzneimittel AG</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:14:15.009000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ThomasJenewein</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/594</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Anbei die Zusammenfassung des Webinars mit einer allgemeiner Einführung zu WalkMe und einem Blick in die Praxis bei STADA Arzneimittel AG.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Zu Beginn erklärte &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hamidborna/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hamid Borna&lt;/A&gt; von SAP die Notwendigkeit und Strategie von Digital Adoption Plattformen:&amp;nbsp;Digital Adoption Plattformen sind längst kein Nice-to-Have mehr, sondern ein Must-Have für Unternehmen. Denn die Geschwindigkeit technologischer Entwicklungen nimmt stetig zu.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Das zentrale Problem dabei: Die Investitionen in Technologie und der nachhaltige betriebswirtschaftliche Mehrwert entwickeln sich nicht parallel. Diese Lücke wird als Digital Adoption Gap bezeichnet. Ohne gezielte Maßnahmen wird diese Kluft immer größer. Die Herausforderung ist dabei kein Technologieproblem, sondern ein Changemanagement-Problem. Mitarbeiter müssen befähigt werden, neue Technologien zu nutzen und damit ihre tägliche Arbeit effizienter zu gestalten.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766463047"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Die Herausforderung traditioneller Veränderungs-Prozesse&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditionelle Change-Prozesse folgen einer bekannten Learning-Kurve, auf die unmittelbar eine noch steilere Vergessenskurve folgt. Ein Großteil des Gelernten wird innerhalb einer Woche vergessen, wenn es nicht direkt und regelmäßig angewandt wird. In der Realität haben Unternehmen nicht nur eine Applikation, sondern multiple SAP- und Non-SAP-Systeme. Bei jeder Einführung oder Weiterentwicklung entsteht die gleiche Herausforderung: Mitarbeiter reiten buchstäblich über Change-Wellen und sind früher oder später "lost in Change".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569949542"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wie sieht eine Digital Adoption Strategie aus?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Eine erfolgreiche Digital Adoption Strategie basiert auf drei Hauptkomponenten:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transparenz und Risikominimierung&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Unternehmen müssen in der Lage sein, Probleme in Geschäftsprozessen transparent zu machen. Wo gibt es Prozessbrüche? Wo haben Anwender Schwierigkeiten? Diese Visibilität ermöglicht es, Risiken bei der Software-Einführung zu minimieren.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;People-First-Ansatz&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Die Nutzung von Software muss aus der Perspektive des Nutzers betrachtet werden. Können Mitarbeiter ihre tägliche Arbeit damit gut gestalten? Das Ziel ist nicht nur ein Aha-Effekt, sondern im Besten Fall ein Wow-Effekt, der zu höherer Produktivität führt.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Readiness für konstanten Wandel&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Größere Transformationsprojekte laufen über verschiedene Rollouts, Phasenmodelle oder regionale Einführungen. Eine Digital Adoption Strategie muss die Agilität bereitstellen, um diese kontinuierlichen Changes zu begleiten.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1373436037"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;WalkMe im SAP-Ecosystem&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;WalkMe wurde 2024 von SAP akquiriert und in kurzer Zeit in zentrale Bestandteile des SAP-Technologie-Stacks integriert. Die Plattform ist nun Teil des Business Transformation Management, neben Signavio für Prozesse und LeanIX für Infrastrukturarchitektur.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ein besonderes Highlight ist die Integration mit &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-assistant.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule, SAPs AI-Assistent&lt;/A&gt;. WalkMe setzt auf die Deep UI AI-Technologie auf, wodurch Joule applikationsübergreifend präsent ist. Diese fortschrittliche AI-Technologie merkt sich Interaktionen auf der Oberfläche. Wenn sich nach einem Release ein Button verschiebt, muss dies nicht manuell nachgepflegt werden – WalkMe AI weiß, wo das Feld war und wo es jetzt ist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176922532"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Die WalkMe-Plattform: Funktionen und Möglichkeiten&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;WalkMe läuft multimedial über Web, Desktop und mobile Geräte und besteht aus drei Hauptbestandteilen:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Daten und Visibilität&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Unternehmen können Prozesse analysieren und sehen, wie viel Zeit mit und zwischen einzelnen Prozessschritten verbraucht wird. Diese Transparenz ermöglicht gezielte Verbesserungen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aktionen und In-App-Guidance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Mitarbeiter werden durch Prozesse geführt, mit gleichzeitiger Berücksichtigung von Datenvalidität und Compliance-Richtlinien. Die Unterstützung erfolgt applikationsübergreifend – ein Procure-to-Pay-Prozess kann über mehrere SAP- und Non-SAP-Applikationen hinweg begleitet werden.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Experience und Feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Am Ende eines Prozesses oder Prozessschrittes können Umfragen eingebaut werden. Solange die Wahrnehmung noch frisch ist, können Anwender Bewertungen abgeben und Freitext-Feedback liefern. Diese Informationen sind für Process Manager und Change Manager wertvoll für Continuous Process Improvement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DigitalAdoptionStrategywithWalkMe-Webinar26112025 .jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348118iA9FFC16346E42D7F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DigitalAdoptionStrategywithWalkMe-Webinar26112025 .jpg" alt="DigitalAdoptionStrategywithWalkMe-Webinar26112025 .jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-980409027"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Künstliche Intelligenz in WalkMe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Da AI gerade ein Top Thema ist, fragen sich sicher viele, wie WalkMe KI nutzt. WalkMe bietet AI-Unterstützung über drei Kanäle:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Immer dabei innerhalb der In-App-Guidance, bietet sofort Unterstützung abhängig von den laufenden Applikationen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proactive AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Die AI-Bar erscheint auf dem Bildschirm und gibt proaktiv Empfehlungen oder zeigt, was als nächstes zu tun ist.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On-Demand AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ein WalkMe-Chat ermöglicht Freitext-Fragen. Die AI liefert Antworten mit entsprechenden Quellen und hilft, zu den richtigen Anwendungen und Hilfestellungen zu gelangen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Diese AI-Unterstützung ist kontextbasiert und berücksichtigt den Bildschirminhalt, den User und die Organisation. Sie steht applikationsübergreifend für Geschäftsprozesse zur Verfügung.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-783895522"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;WalkMe Learning Arc: Die Zukunft des Lernens im Arbeitsfluss&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;WalkMe Learning Arc ist ein neues Autoren-Tool für digitale Lerninhalte im Arbeitsfluss auf der WalkMe Plattform, das im Dezember generell verfügbar wird. &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eur-sap-walkme/de_de/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hier findet Ihr weitere Infos dazu wie Webinare, Blogs und Roundtables&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Weitere Infos zu WalkMe und Kundenbeispielen findet ihr auch unten in den weiterführenden Links.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-587382017"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;WalkMe in der Praxis bei STADA Arzneimittel AG&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/victorpostu/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Victor Postu&lt;/A&gt; von STADA Arzneimittel AG teilte seine konkreten Erfahrungen aus der Praxis. STADA hat WalkMe in 40 Ländern ausgerollt, 12.000 Mitarbeiter nutzen es, und etwa 50 Workflows wurden damit automatisiert oder erleichtert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Die Ausgangssituation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: STADA führte SAP SuccessFactors in einem straffen Zeitplan von zwei Jahren ein (Ende 2019 bis Ende 2021). Um alle Module schnell einzuführen und die Prozesse für Kollegen verständlich zu machen, wurde WalkMe parallel implementiert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Branding und Kommunikation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Bei STADA heißt SAP SuccessFactors intern "Hero" und WalkMe ist der "Hero Navigator". Diese einheitliche Kommunikation half, beide Tools als Einheit zu etablieren. Der Hero Navigator ist immer präsent und kann verschoben werden.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technische Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Früher war eine Browser-Extension notwendig, die von der IT auf alle PCs installiert wurde. Seit 2025 kann WalkMe direkt im SAP-System enabled werden, was die Nutzung deutlich vereinfacht.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Warum WalkMe statt traditioneller Trainings&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Statt PowerPoints und PDFs auf Teams-Ordnern zu speichern, wo Mitarbeiter zwei Bildschirme brauchen und ein Medienbruch besteht, bietet WalkMe Guided Training direkt im System. Dies reduzierte die Support-Tickets erheblich.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-519951231"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Konkrete Anwendungsfälle von WalkMe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Guided Workflows zeigen Schritt für Schritt, wie man ein Training sucht oder eine Adresse ändert&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Shoutouts machen auf Updates, neue Features oder Events aufmerksam – direkt dort, wo Mitarbeiter arbeiten&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Smart-Tips sind kleine Buttons, die überall im System hinzugefügt werden können&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Surveys erfassen Feedback direkt nach Prozessabschluss&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rollenbasierte Guidance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In SAP SuccessFactors kann Guidance zielgerichtet für einzelne Gruppen, Länder, Rollen oder Departments erstellt werden. Nur die relevanten Personen sehen die entsprechenden Inhalte.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics und Optimierung&lt;/STRONG&gt;: WalkMe ermöglicht die Auswertung von Prozessen – wie viele Interaktionen gab es? Wo dauerte es am längsten? Wo gab es Fehler? Diese Insights helfen bei der kontinuierlichen Prozessverbesserung.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-323437726"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Herausforderungen und Lern-Erfahrungen bei der Nutzung von WalkMe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interner Aufwand&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Es braucht definitiv jemanden, der sich mit dem WalkMe-Editor auskennt und das System gut kennt. Die größte Herausforderung ist, Content-Experten zu haben, die sowohl das Fachsystem als auch WalkMe beherrschen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Übersetzungen&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Jedes Tutorial muss in alle relevanten Sprachen übersetzt werden. AI-Übersetzungen werden voraussichtlich Ende 2025 verfügbar sein, was die Sache deutlich vereinfachen wird.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Neue Prozesse außerhalb des Browsers&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Viele Prozesse entwickeln sich außerhalb des Browsers, beispielsweise in Microsoft Teams. Die Integration von WalkMe mit solchen Szenarien ist eine aktuelle Herausforderung.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wartung nach Releases&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Nach jedem Release (bei SuccessFactors im Mai und November) muss geprüft werden, ob Walkthroughs aktualisiert werden müssen – allerdings nur, wenn sich am dahinterliegenden Prozess etwas verändert hat.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Betriebsrat und Datenschutz&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Bei STADA wurde der Betriebsrat eng eingebunden, Daten werden anonymisiert. Die Survey-Funktion von WalkMe wird in Deutschland nicht verwendet, da Qualtrics mit dem Betriebsrat abgestimmt ist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Globale Skalierung mit lokaler Expertise: &lt;/STRONG&gt;STADA etablierte ein hybrides Modell: Ein zentrales globales HR IT Team verantwortet WalkMe, während in jedem größeren Land Content-Experten mit Editor-Rechten vorhanden sind. Diese Kombination aus zentraler Steuerung und lokaler Expertise ermöglichte sowohl Konsistenz als auch Flexibilität.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Zum Schluss fasste Victor seine Erfahrungen zusammen: konsequente In-App-Guidance ermöglichten eine schnellere Adoption und höhere Produktivität, da Mitarbeiter direkt im System geführt werden statt auf externe Dokumentation angewiesen zu sein. Der strategische Erfolg basiert auf einheitlichem Branding, rollenbasierter Guidance und kontinuierlicher Optimierung.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Wir haben das Gerüst aufgebaut, jetzt schauen wir weiter" - Victor sieht WalkMe als strategische Plattform, die kontinuierlich ausgebaut wird, besonders im Kontext von AI-Integration (z.B. mit Joule oder zur Übersetzung) und applikationsübergreifenden Szenarien sowie die Erweiterung auf weitere SAP-Applikationen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--2158498"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Eindrückliche Aussagen aus dem Webinar&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Wir haben kein Technologieproblem, sondern ein Changemanagement-Problem – Mitarbeiter müssen befähigt werden, neue Technologien zu nutzen."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Ohne WalkMe hätten wir Schwierigkeiten gehabt, die Prozesse in jedem Land so einfach durchzubekommen – wir haben sehr viel weniger Tickets bekommen als erwartet."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Learning wird innerhalb der Applikation geliefert, genau dort, wo es gebraucht wird – Just-in-Time-Learning direkt am Arbeitsplatz."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"WalkMe kann über die gesamte Prozesskette hinweg In-App-Guidance liefern und führt über verschiedene Applikationen hinweg – SAP und Non-SAP."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-148582354"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fragen und Antworten zum Einsatz von WalkMe - Gruppiert nach Themen&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Es gab sehr viele Fragen im Chat und am Ende des Webinars. Anbei die Auflistung, gerne weitere in den Kommentaren hier im Blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--341334158"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Übergang von SAP Enable Now zu WalkMe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Wie sieht der Übergangspfad von SAP Enable Now zu WalkMe aus?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Learning Arc ist das Nachfolgeprodukt von SAP Enable Now. Mehr Informationen allgemein und zu Transition Szenarien gibt es im nächsten Webinar und in den Roundtables. Für Bestandskunden gibt es ein Move-Program.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ersetzt WalkMe Learning Arc den Enable Now Producer?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ja, WalkMe Learning Arc wird ein eigenes Produkt auf der WalkMe-Plattform sein und SAP Enable Now ablösen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--537847663"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technische Integration und Funktionalität&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Funktioniert WalkMe auch für SAP GUI oder nur Fiori Apps?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: WalkMe unterstützt sowohl SAP GUI als auch Fiori Apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Funktioniert WalkMe auch für Nicht-Browser-Applikationen?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Muss von Fall zu Fall individuell betrachtet werden. Es gibt eine Desktop-Variante.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Kann man AI deaktivieren bei WalkMe?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: AI ist nicht per Default dabei und kann deaktiviert werden.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--734361168"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content-Erstellung und Wartung&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Wie viel Zeit braucht man für die Erstellung eines neuen Walkthroughs?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Bei einem Prozess mit 45 Schritten ungefähr eine Stunde. Das Übersetzen dauert zusätzlich.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Gibt es Standard-Content seitens SAP oder muss man alles selbst bauen?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: WalkMe wird mit vorkonfigurierten Templates geliefert, die angepasst werden können.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Wie einfach lassen sich End-to-End User Journeys erstellen?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Man kann problemlos Guidance erstellen, die über mehrere Applikationen hinweggeht und Daten automatisch mitkopiert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Müssen Walkthroughs nach einem Release aktualisiert werden?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Nur wenn sich am dahinterliegenden Prozess etwas verändert hat. WalkMe AI kann viele Änderungen automatisch erkennen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--930874673"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Übersetzungen und Mehrsprachigkeit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Kann man AI-Übersetzungen nutzen?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Voraussichtlich ab Ende 2025 wird es getestet und vermutlich bald darauf allgemein verfügbar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1127388178"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics und Auswertung&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Wie gut lassen sich Adoption Rates evaluieren, wie ist der Unterschied zu Signavio?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: WalkMe fokussiert auf User Adoption mit vielen Reporting-Möglichkeiten auf User-Ebene (anonymisierbar), nicht auf Prozess-Ebene wie Signavio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1030498676"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration mit anderen Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Kann man auf Signavio WalkMe Guidance erstellen?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ja, man kann auf Signavio WalkMe Guidance erstellen. Signavio läuft komplett im Browser, und WalkMe funktioniert auf allen webbasierten Anwendungen. Tiefere Integrationen sind auf der Roadmap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Gibt es eine Verbindung zu Signavio für Prozessgestaltung und Review?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Guidance ist möglich, tiefere Integration auf der Roadmap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1520415188"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Organisatorische Aspekte bei STADA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Welche Ressourcen und Rollen kümmern sich um WalkMe? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Bei STADA ist es das globale HR IT Team. In größeren Ländern gibt es Content-Experten mit Editor-Rechten. Man kann es zentralisiert oder dezentral organisieren.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Wie hoch ist der interne Aufwand, um Inhalte aktuell zu halten?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Man braucht definitiv jemanden, der sich mit dem Editor auskennt und das System gut kennt. Die größte Herausforderung ist, Content-Experten zu haben.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Wie wurden Betriebsräte bezüglich KI überzeugt?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Betriebsrat wurde eng eingebunden, Daten werden anonymisiert, KI-Funktionen wurden erklärt. Vorherige Erfahrung mit eigener GPT-Umgebung half.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1716928693"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Spezifische Anwendungsfälle von WalkMe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Lässt sich WalkMe auch für Admins einsetzen?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ja, über rollenbasierte Permissions können z.B. Tutorials nur für Admins zugänglich gemacht werden.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ist WalkMe in der Learningadministration einsetzbar (im SF LMS)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ja, ist möglich, da es innerhalb von SAP SuccessFactors ist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Kann es im Onboarding eingesetzt werden?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ja, definitiv. Onboarding in jeder Applikation ist ein gängiger Use-Case. Natürlich auch in der originären Onboarding Applikation von SuccessFactors ist WalkMe nutzbar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1913442198"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;WalkMe Learning Arc&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frage&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In welcher Form gibt Learning Arc den Content aus? &lt;STRONG&gt;Antwort&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Als digitale Inhalte in der App. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1648369005"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Konkrete Tipps für die Praxis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Startet mit einem Bereich&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Viele erfolgreiche Kunden fangen in einem Bereich an (z.B. HR oder Support) und sammeln Lernerfahrungen, bevor sie WalkMe weiter ausrollen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Kombiniert WalkMe mit Kommunikation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Nutzt einheitliches Branding wie STADA mit "Hero" und "Hero Navigator".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nutzt Shoutouts für Change Communication&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Statt nur im Intranet oder Teams zu kommunizieren, nutzt Shoutouts direkt dort, wo Mitarbeiter arbeiten – besonders bei Release-Updates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plant Ressourcen für Wartung ein&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Nicht nur für das Projekt, sondern auch für die kontinuierliche Optimierung nach Go-Live.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Startet mit Templates&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Nutzt die vorkonfigurierten Templates von WalkMe und passt diese an, statt alles von Null aufzubauen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bindet Content-Experten ein&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Die größte Herausforderung ist, Personen zu haben, die sowohl das Fachsystem als auch WalkMe beherrschen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nutzt Analytics für kontinuierliche Verbesserung&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Schaut regelmäßig, wo Mitarbeiter Zeit verlieren oder Fehler machen, und optimiert dann gezielt.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bezieht den Betriebsrat früh ein&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Besonders bei AI-Funktionen und Analytics ist frühe Einbindung und Transparenz über Anonymisierung wichtig.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Testet im Testsystem&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Nutzt die Möglichkeit, im Editor zu arbeiten und Änderungen zu testen, bevor sie live gehen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Denkt applikationsübergreifend&lt;/STRONG&gt;: WalkMe kann über mehrere Systeme hinweg führen – nutzt dies für End-to-End-Prozesse.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1844882510"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resümee&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Digital Adoption Plattformen wie WalkMe sind heute essentiell, um die wachsende Kluft zwischen Technologie-Investitionen und tatsächlichem Mehrwert zu schließen. Es geht nicht um Technologieprobleme, sondern um Changemanagement und die Befähigung von Mitarbeitern.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;WalkMe bietet eine umfassende Plattform für In-App-Guidance, die applikationsübergreifend funktioniert und durch AI-Unterstützung noch leistungsfähiger wird. Die Integration mit SAP Joule und die Verfügbarkeit von WalkMe Learning Arc als Nachfolger von SAP Enable Now zeigen die strategische Bedeutung für das SAP-Ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Das Praxisbeispiel von STADA demonstriert, wie WalkMe bei einer schnellen SuccessFactors-Einführung in 40 Ländern die Adoption erleichterte und Supportaufwände reduzierte. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Für Unternehmen, die vor der Einführung stehen, gilt: Klein anfangen, Lernerfahrungen sammeln, Content-Experten aufbauen und dann skalieren. Die Investition in Digital Adoption zahlt sich durch höhere Produktivität, geringere Support-Kosten und zufriedenere Mitarbeiter aus.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Danke an Victor und Hamid für das Teilen Ihrer Erfahrungen. Weiter geht es dann im Januar mit einem Blick im&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eur-sap-walkme/de_de/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Webinar&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;auf die neue Learning Arc Komponente.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--2041396015"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Weitere Quellen und Infos&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eur-sap-walkme/de_de/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Weitere Infos zu WalkMe Learning, Webinare und Roundtables&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management/gh-p/training-change" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community – Blogs rund um Learning, Change, Adoption&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/groups/8682361/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn Gruppe – mit Up to date Infos&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.walkme.com/customer-stories/stada/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;WalkMe Website – Kundenbeispiel von STADA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management-blog-posts/digitale-adoption-mit-walkme-in-der-praxis-erfahrungen-der-deutschen/ba-p/14112479" target="_blank"&gt;Blog: Digitale Adoption mit WalkMe bei der Telekom&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/von-der-einf%C3%BChrung-zur-skalierung-nestl%C3%A9s-digital-mit-jenewein-aj7me/?trackingId=gXGt39iAQw27c8Gu7zn8AA%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Interview: Nestlé’s Digital Adoption mit WalkMe&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management-blog-posts/digital-adoption-mit-walkme-im-%C3%BCberblick-und-in-aktion-bei-stada/ba-p/14283133"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:14:15.009000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/manage-group-to-team-assignments-for-sac-within-identity-provisioning/qaa-p/14283134#M4932947</id>
    <title>Re: Manage group to team assignments for SAC within Ident...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:14:25.553000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dyaryura</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/103697</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163345"&gt;@renejurmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We're using SAML mapping for Teams and works perfectly fine. I don't see any issue with that. Currently SAC does not support OIDC, so you might have configured IAS to Entra as a proxy with OIDC, but in SAC the trust configuration to IAS can be done only using SAML. I have not seen any other option there.&lt;BR /&gt;The array is perfeclty fine, you then map each group. In our case we're using the groups from Entra. sample below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dyaryura_1-1764771196428.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348122i44238C0C6D7AEE84/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dyaryura_1-1764771196428.png" alt="dyaryura_1-1764771196428.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then the mapping in SAC, in this case we're using groups from entra (Entra as a proxy in IAS getting the Groups ID in the groups attribute using OIDC)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dyaryura_0-1764771155866.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348121iD0B5C82496CFD390/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dyaryura_0-1764771155866.png" alt="dyaryura_0-1764771155866.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/manage-group-to-team-assignments-for-sac-within-identity-provisioning/qaa-p/14283134#M4932947"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:14:25.553000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/now-available-earn-your-sap-central-business-configuration-badge/bc-p/14283136#M62675</id>
    <title>Re: Now Available: Earn Your SAP Central Business Configuration Badge!</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:15:39.706000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FabianAckermann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131646</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Abhishek Anand,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Just saw your comment, thanks for reaching out! Once you've completed the course and passed the quiz, you can should be able to access your badge under&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;My Learning &amp;gt; Activity &amp;gt; Completed&lt;/EM&gt;. If that's still not the case, please do not hesitate to create a case via the following page (see button at the end of the page):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/helpcenter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/helpcenter&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Fabian&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/now-available-earn-your-sap-central-business-configuration-badge/bc-p/14283136#M62675"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:15:39.706000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/%D0%B1%D0%B5%D0%B7%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%88%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%BD%D1%96-%D1%82%D0%B5%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%96-%D0%B2%D0%B5%D1%80%D1%81%D1%96%D1%97-sap/ba-p/14283144</id>
    <title>Безкоштовні тестові версії SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:17:52.618000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1637380360"&gt;Безкоштовні тестові версії SAP: спробуйте найновіші технології без зобов’язань&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP пропонує IT-фахівцям, аналітикам, розробникам та всім, хто цікавиться цифровими інноваціями, безкоштовно протестувати рішення компанії. На офіційних сторінках доступні пробні версії від 30 до 90 днів, які охоплюють ERP, аналітику, управління персоналом, ШІ та інші бізнес-рішення. Це можливість спробувати найновіші версії програмного забезпечення SAP для бізнесу, щоб підвищити ефективність, знизити ризики та забезпечити стабільну діяльність.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Basic Trials&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— ознайомлення з продуктами SAP з обмеженими правами адміністратора та зразками даних. За&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/try-sap.html?sort=latest_desc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;посиланням&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;ви знайдете понад 30 доступних пробних версій рішень SAP по різним напрямкам: Artificial intelligence (AI), Data and analytics, Business technology platform, Cloud ERP applications, CRM and customer experience, Financial management, Human capital management, Spend management, Supply chain management, Sustainability management, Industries (SAP Cloud for Energy, SAP&lt;BR /&gt;E-Mobility, SAP Sports One, SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, public sector).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced Trials&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— розширені пробні версії з можливістю експериментувати з власними даними. За&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/try-sap.html?sort=latest_desc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;посиланням&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;доступно більше 10 пробних версій по таким напрямкам: Business process transformation, Business technology platform, Cloud ERP applications, Supply chain management and Industries (SAP S/4HANA Utilities).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;На цих сторінках також доступні&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/try-sap.html?sort=latest_desc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;demo videos&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;та&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/try-sap.html?sort=latest_desc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;product tours&lt;/A&gt;, щоб швидко ознайомитися з функціоналом та потенціалом рішень SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Тестові версії SAP — це можливість:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;дослідити, як рішення SAP інтегруються у вашу IT-екосистему;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;перевірити сценарії оптимізації бізнес-процесів;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;протестувати ШI-моделі для аналітики, прогнозування та автоматизації.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Інтерактивні демонстрації — Value Journeys&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP також пропонує&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interactive Value Journey (IVJ)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— це безкоштовні інтерактивні демонстрації SAP, що дозволяють побачити роботу бізнес-процесів у системі в реальному режимі. Кожна подорож містить покрокову інструкцію, коментарі та готові приклади даних, щоб користувач міг швидко зрозуміти, як працює конкретний сценарій. Доступ відкритий для всіх, тому IVJ є зручним способом ознайомитися з можливостями SAP без технічної підготовки та додаткових інсталяцій.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (Build and develop)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— ця інтерактивна подорож показує як цифрове рішення допомагає компаніям підвищувати ефективність і прискорювати цифрову трансформацію. У прикладі CIO компанії S.MART використовує інструменти SAP Build для оптимізації операцій, швидкої розробки рішень і автоматизації процесів. У результаті досягнено: кращий контроль запасів і узгодження між складами та магазинами, прозорість та узгодженість даних у всій компанії, гнучкі хмарні рішення, що швидко адаптуються до змін у бізнесі, швидке виявлення та усунення процесних проблем завдяки аналітиці й AI-підказкам. Переглянути подорож можна&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ivj-vx.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/journey/0ecc97c4-0e3f-4964-9b17-e37519e6311a/intro" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"&gt;за посиланням&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;– вона стає доступною після створення безкоштовного облікового запису на сайті SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— інтерактивна подорож демонструє, як SAP Business Suite об’єднує додатки, дані та штучний інтелект у єдину платформу для управління бізнесом. У сценарії показано, як компанії можуть впроваджувати інтегровані рішення, що охоплюють всі функції: від фінансів і ланцюга постачання до HR та продажів.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Модульний підхід: вибір спеціалізованих пакетів для різних бізнес-процесів.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Єдина система даних з різних джерел, що забезпечує прозорість і узгодженість.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Вбудований ШІ: аналітика, автоматизація, агент-рішення для комплексної підтримки бізнесу.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Орієнтація на хмару та масштабованість для розвитку компанії.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Цей сценарій допомагає оцінити, як SAP Business Suite створює основу для бізнес-інновацій і цифрової трансформації. Сценарій доступний&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ivj-vx.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/journey/f61f086d-82fd-4af3-bdc5-99821901c873/intro" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"&gt;за посиланням&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;після створення облікового запису SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business AI – плейлист SAPPHIRE 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Цей плейлист присвячений можливостям штучного інтелекту в бізнесі (Business AI) від SAP, які були представлені на SAPPHIRE 2025. У добірці зібрані інтерактивні сценарії (IVJ), що показують, як ШІ допомагає компаніям оптимізувати процеси, автоматизувати рутинні операції та приймати кращі рішення на основі даних.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;До плейлиста входить:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;огляд ключових новинок Business AI від SAP;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;демонстрації реальних бізнес-сценаріїв з використанням ШІ;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;приклади інтеграції ШI у фінанси, операційні процеси, клієнтський сервіс та ланцюги постачання;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;показ того, як ШІ підсилює продуктивність команд і пришвидшує цифрову трансформацію.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ознайомтеся&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ivj-vx.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/playlist/1de2b2ef-330c-4b62-be0b-3594ce6ec949" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"&gt;за посиланням.&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Для перегляду достатньо створити безкоштовний SAP-аккаунт.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Спробуйте SAP безкоштовно — і переконайтеся, як штучний інтелект, аналітика та автоматизація допомагають компаніям працювати ефективніше вже сьогодні.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="testovi-versiyi.jpg" style="width: 509px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348120i6AA891C2DF71EF09/image-dimensions/509x286/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="509" height="286" role="button" title="testovi-versiyi.jpg" alt="testovi-versiyi.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/%D0%B1%D0%B5%D0%B7%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%88%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%BD%D1%96-%D1%82%D0%B5%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%96-%D0%B2%D0%B5%D1%80%D1%81%D1%96%D1%97-sap/ba-p/14283144"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:17:52.618000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/clarification-on-causes-for-accrual-item-obsolete-and-accrual-subobject/qaq-p/14283149</id>
    <title>Clarification on Causes for “Accrual Item Obsolete” and “Accrual Subobject Prematurely Finished” Sta</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:21:07.903000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rohini_dutta21</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265196</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are encountering two recurring statuses in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud related to Purchase Order–based accruals, and we would like to confirm our understanding as well as check whether there are any additional system-driven triggers we may be missing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1895545803"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1) &lt;EM&gt;Accrual Item is Obsolete&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our current understanding:&lt;BR /&gt;The accrual item status is automatically set to &lt;STRONG&gt;Obsolete&lt;/STRONG&gt; when the corresponding PO item is marked for deletion. Once the PO item has a deletion flag, the accrual item moves into Obsolete status and no further status changes are possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Request for clarification:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this understanding correct?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are there any other conditions (besides PO item deletion) that can cause an accrual item to become Obsolete?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rohini_dutta21_0-1764771480610.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348132i0117F2ACF087C7C4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rohini_dutta21_0-1764771480610.png" alt="rohini_dutta21_0-1764771480610.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1699032298"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2) &lt;EM&gt;Accrual Subobject Status: “Prematurely Finished”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our understanding based on SAP documentation:&lt;BR /&gt;If a user closes a PO—for example, by selecting the &lt;STRONG&gt;Final Invoice&lt;/STRONG&gt; checkbox in &lt;EM&gt;Display Purchase Order&lt;/EM&gt;—the system posts a release to clear the accrual balance and sets the subobject to &lt;STRONG&gt;Prematurely Finished&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This is considered a final status, though it can be undone via &lt;STRONG&gt;Undo Premature Termination&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rohini_dutta21_1-1764771641634.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348135iB9DFF44595CD4E53/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rohini_dutta21_1-1764771641634.png" alt="rohini_dutta21_1-1764771641634.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reason for our query:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We have observed multiple cases where the &lt;EM&gt;Prematurely Finished&lt;/EM&gt; status appears even when the Final Invoice checkbox is &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; selected or when the documents do not match the typical scenario described.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Request for clarification:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are there additional system-driven conditions that can trigger the Prematurely Finished status in Public Cloud?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could there be background logic or configuration that automatically sets this status even when the Final Invoice checkbox is not used?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;We want to ensure our understanding is complete so we can correctly explain the behavior to the business and avoid misinterpretation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any insights, detailed documentation references, or similar experience would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rohini Dutta&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/clarification-on-causes-for-accrual-item-obsolete-and-accrual-subobject/qaq-p/14283149"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:21:07.903000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/tm-transportation-cockpit-changing-field-attribute-to-editable/qaa-p/14283150#M208422</id>
    <title>Re: TM Transportation Cockpit - Changing field attribute...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:21:36.293000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>beata_d</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/331990</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello Rogerio, Thank You for checking my question. Yes, I do agree that in general the quantity fields should not be editable. In this case there is a de-central TM (without EWM). The alternative quantity (loading meter) should be editable because at the beginning of the planning proces it only serves as an estimate, later on the value will be updated with correct figure. But my question is still open: can we change the editability of the standard field via field catalogue? The note 3562800 mentions only custom fields but not the standard fields. Or how can I change the editability of a standard field with the new field catalogs (and if such manipulation is possible at all)? Thank You. Best regards, Beata</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/tm-transportation-cockpit-changing-field-attribute-to-editable/qaa-p/14283150#M208422"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:21:36.293000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/cannot-resolve-reference-to-bean-springsecurityfilterchain-while-setting/qaa-p/14283151#M458286</id>
    <title>Re: Cannot resolve reference to bean 'springSecurityFilterChain' while setting bean property</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:21:40.462000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Robertto</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1488798</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/cannot-resolve-reference-to-bean-springsecurityfilterchain-while-setting/qaa-p/14283151#M458286"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:21:40.462000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/your-path-to-sap-sales-amp-service-cloud-v2-starts-here-understanding-the/ba-p/14283154</id>
    <title>Your Path to SAP Sales &amp; Service Cloud V2 Starts Here: Understanding the DTT</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:26:45.041000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MMEHLICH</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1525102</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Your Path to SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud V2 Starts Here: Understanding the DTT&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Introduction to the Data Transfer Tool (DTT)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, I would like to introduce you to the&amp;nbsp;Data Transfer Tool (DTT)&amp;nbsp;in the&amp;nbsp;SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud.&lt;BR /&gt;Before we dive into the tool itself, let’s take a look at the steps and prerequisites required to enable and use the DTT successfully.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites &amp;amp; Activation of the Data Transfer Tool&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Create an Incident&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open an incident in&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP for Me&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;with the appropriate component “LOD-LE-MIG-CNS”.&lt;BR /&gt;Important: You need to have a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;V2 system&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that is connected to your&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud V1 system&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the transition. Both systems must be referenced in the incident.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Enable the Tool for Administrators&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the Data Transfer Tool has been approved, you need to enable it for your administrators or colleagues performing the transition.&lt;BR /&gt;Go to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administration Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in your V1 system and enable the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;“Transition” Work Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the relevant business role.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MMEHLICH_0-1764771378904.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348127i667DB15E95470E25/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MMEHLICH_0-1764771378904.png" alt="MMEHLICH_0-1764771378904.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: End User Access&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the role assignment, end users will see the Transition Work Center and gain access to the Data Transfer Tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MMEHLICH_1-1764771378904.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348128iCA4677D8CFDE5E34/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MMEHLICH_1-1764771378904.png" alt="MMEHLICH_1-1764771378904.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Start Working with the DTT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once everything is set up, you can begin preparing and executing your data migration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note #1 – Preparation Is Key&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before performing any migration, it is highly recommended to&lt;BR /&gt;review the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Help Page of each relevant data object&lt;/STRONG&gt;. These pages contain essential information on:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;✔&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Prerequisites&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example: For&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cases/Tickets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Case Types&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;must be manually created in the V2 system before migration, so they can be mapped correctly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;✔&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Restrictions&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example: For&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Registered Products&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, the migration of KUT fields is currently not supported.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;✔&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Data Sequences&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example: For&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leads&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, activities and master data (such as Business Partners) must be migrated first.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Tip:&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migration Activity Plan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to keep track&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; of dependencies, required sequences, and task responsibilities.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;User Interface Overview of the Data Transfer Tool&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The DTT interface provides several columns and sections that help you understand the migration status at a glance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MMEHLICH_2-1764771378904.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348129iF465F1AC18887E1B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MMEHLICH_2-1764771378904.png" alt="MMEHLICH_2-1764771378904.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Column overview (left to right):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Objects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– List of all data objects that can be migrated via DTT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;More Information&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Link to the object-specific Help Page&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Existing Instances&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Number of records in the V1 system&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Triggered By&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– User who initiated the migration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Triggered On&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Timestamp of execution&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sending Instances&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Number of records sent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Error Sending Instances&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Error messages for failed records&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Send Status&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Shows status (e.g.&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Finished&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;when complete)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Received Instances&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Number of records received in the V2 system&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Delta Mode&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Automatically activated after a successful initial migration (shown in green)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Target Tenant&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– URL of the V2 target system&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic Object Scoping: Extension Fields and Additional Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below the object list, additional information may appear depending on the selected object, such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MMEHLICH_3-1764771378904.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348130i6F7EE1185C23AD51/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MMEHLICH_3-1764771378904.png" alt="MMEHLICH_3-1764771378904.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extension Fields (KUT Fields)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Node Name&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Location of the field in the data model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Field Name&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– UI name&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Usage Rate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Indicates whether the field is actively used&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Owner&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– e.g. KUT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transition Ability&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Whether the field can be migrated via DTT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transfer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Selection to include or exclude the field during migration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transfer History&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Listing the last migration executions for the related Data Object&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Error Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Listing the details of migration errors&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Document Type Mapping (e.g. for Data object “Case”)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is the place were you would configure the Case type mapping bevore you are executing the migration of Tickets from SAP Sales and Service Cloud to SAP Sales and Service Cloud V2.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Actions in the Upper-Right Section of the DTT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This area contains the main execution functions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MMEHLICH_4-1764771378904.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348131iF7F524B26226A012/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MMEHLICH_4-1764771378904.png" alt="MMEHLICH_4-1764771378904.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Test Data Transfer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Transfers a single data object including its Business Configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transfer Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Transfers&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;all&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;data records of the selected object plus its Business Configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transfer BC&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Transfers only the Business Configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stop Delta&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Deactivates the delta mechanism&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start Post-Processing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Triggers object-specific follow-up processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Documentation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Access to the latest DTT documentation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Note #2 – Advantages &amp;amp; Limitations of the Data Transfer Tool&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advantages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Configuration is transferred&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unlike migration via Data Workbench, the DTT also transfers the related configuration of the data object.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Preserves Object IDs and UUIDs&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The DTT keeps the same object IDs from V1, ensuring seamless continuity for integrations and historical references.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automatic Mapping&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Relationships between master data and transactional data remain intact after migration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current Limitations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;No filtering available&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The DTT currently does not support filtering records before migration—everything is transferred.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Limited monitoring capabilities&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;There is no detailed, record-level monitoring, making it difficult to identify missing or failed data without additional effort.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/your-path-to-sap-sales-amp-service-cloud-v2-starts-here-understanding-the/ba-p/14283154"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:26:45.041000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-document-and-reporting-compliance-germany/qaq-p/14283159</id>
    <title>SAP Document and Reporting Compliance Germany</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:32:35.900000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CPzeres1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1531592</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are using SAP DRC to receive invoices from suppliers for the German mandate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are having difficulties connecting our SAP DRC to the PEPPOL network, even though we have configured it according to the SAP note. We sent a test invoice, but we did not receive anything in our SAP DRC (using the OZG_RE test portal and Billit).. Can you help us with the configuration of SAP DRC on the PEPPOL network? Why does the DRC not have any records of entry into the Peppol network. How can we make it an access point on the PEPPOL network so that invoices sent to our participant IDs are forwarded to our SAP DRC?&amp;nbsp;Has anyone else been through this?&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-document-and-reporting-compliance-germany/qaq-p/14283159"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:32:35.900000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-on-odn-for-italy/qaa-p/14283162#M4932948</id>
    <title>Re: Issue on ODN for Italy</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:35:38.713000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>david_evans_gsk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/571299</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Same issue, ODN isn't working. We've done all config. We are creating ODNs (option C that doesn't worry about dates).&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;SAP Customizing Implementation Guide -&amp;gt; Cross-Application Components -&amp;gt; General Application Functions -&amp;gt; Cross-Application Document Numbering -&amp;gt; Italy -&amp;gt; Assign Document Classes to Document Types&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-on-odn-for-italy/qaa-p/14283162#M4932948"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:35:38.713000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/record-client-open-and-close-changes/qaq-p/14283163</id>
    <title>Record Client Open and Close Changes</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:35:48.799000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VarunSinha</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1482058</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a table or report that records every time a client is opened in SAP? And if yes, does it also log what was done when the client was opened? I think T000 only records an entry when a client was opened through SCC4 and a change was made? If the client was just opened but nothing was changed for T000, it would not record the change. Objective is to know anytime a client is opened, what was changed in the system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any help with this will be appreciated!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Varun&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/record-client-open-and-close-changes/qaq-p/14283163"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:35:48.799000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-export-process-model-bpmn-from-signavio-collaboration-hub-into/qaa-p/14283164#M4932949</id>
    <title>Re: How to export Process Model ( BPMN) from Signavio Col...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:38:17.847000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Philipp_Maschke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/59738</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Leandro Ribeiro,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It sounds like you are talking about different workspaces:&lt;BR /&gt;You see the mentioned diagram in the Collaboration Hub of workspace A and want to make it available for editing in workspace B.&lt;BR /&gt;Correct?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unfortunately the BPMN export is currently only available in the Process Manager (we are planning to also bring it to the Collaboration Hub next year).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently it depends heavily on what licenses and permissions you have in workspace A - can you navigate to the Process Manager in that workspace and navigate to the folder of the process? If so, then you can export the desired diagram from there, then switch to workspace B and import it there.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alternatively you can install the corresponding Value Accelerator from the library. However that will also install all other diagrams, folders, etc into workspace B even if you dont need all of them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps,&lt;BR /&gt;Philipp&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-export-process-model-bpmn-from-signavio-collaboration-hub-into/qaa-p/14283164#M4932949"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:38:17.847000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/clarification-needed-on-revised-cost-appearing-higher-than-po-value/qaa-p/14283165#M256769</id>
    <title>Re: Clarification Needed on Revised Cost Appearing Higher...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:44:16.644000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rohini_dutta21</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265196</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you for the earlier explanation. We have a follow-up query based on our client’s requirement. We would like to understand the technical logic behind the Revise Costs (TC) percentage exceeding Total A/D Amt (TC) in the Review Purchase Order Accruals app. 1) Does the system technically allow posting more than 100%? From our testing, the system allows increasing the revised cost percentage above 100% (for example, from 100% to 130%). We also see that the system only triggers a warning message, not a hard error. Our question is: Is this standard system behavior in SAP Public Cloud? Does SAP intentionally allow posting more than 100%, or is there any other internal trigger behind this behavior? 2) Can we configure or restrict the system to prevent crossing 100%? Our client wants to know whether we can add any control so that revised costs cannot exceed 100%. We are aware the system issues a warning, but we would like to confirm: Is there any way (BAdI, extensibility, SSCUI, configuration) in SAP Public Cloud to convert this warning into a hard stop? Or is the warning the only possible system control?We want to ensure that our understanding aligns with SAP standard logic before advising the client. Any confirmation or additional insights from experts would be highly appreciated. Thank you.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/clarification-needed-on-revised-cost-appearing-higher-than-po-value/qaa-p/14283165#M256769"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:44:16.644000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/duration-based-time-profile-with-clock-time-based-work-schedule/qaq-p/14283168</id>
    <title>Duration based Time Profile with Clock Time Based Work Schedule?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:48:36.024000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>clumbert</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/23513</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;My customer currently has Time Profile and Work Schedules defined as Clock Times. They would like to change the Time Profile to duration so that the employees can just enter the number of hours for absence rather then start/end time.&amp;nbsp; When I try to assign a duration based Time Profile, I get an error because the work schedule is based on clock times.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have tried leaving the Time Recording Variant as Clock Times, but still get an error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have also done a rule trace to rule out that any custom rules are generating the error.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone confirm if this is possible? They are not using time sheet in SuccessFactors currently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cindy&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/duration-based-time-profile-with-clock-time-based-work-schedule/qaq-p/14283168"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:48:36.024000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/change-source-bin-and-source-hu-when-picking-using-rf/qaa-p/14283169#M208423</id>
    <title>Re: Change Source Bin and Source HU when picking using RF</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:51:05.762000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Good day&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1851796"&gt;@Charisma_fitra&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Yes, you can but the system only allows that under specific conditions and within allowed RF transactions. An example would be your Warehouse Process Type allowing alternative source bin or HU picking, your RF configuration screen must include input fields for Source Bin or HU (like in your screenshot), your storage type settings must allow manual bin entry, etc. Note that the public cloud’s clean-core principle limits some functionalities unlike in the On-premise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/change-source-bin-and-source-hu-when-picking-using-rf/qaa-p/14283169#M208423"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:51:05.762000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/the-g-l-accounts-are-not-displayed-in-the-manage-global-hierarchies-app/qaq-p/14283174</id>
    <title>The G/L accounts are not displayed in the Manage Global Hierarchies app.</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:57:36.505000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Expert,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When attempting to add a G/L Account to a G/L Account Hierarchy in the G/L Account Node there are no G/L Accounts displayed from the value search.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;It is not possible to add general ledger accounts to a hierarchy as they are missing in the "F4" search.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/the-g-l-accounts-are-not-displayed-in-the-manage-global-hierarchies-app/qaq-p/14283174"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:57:36.505000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/the-g-l-accounts-are-not-displayed-in-the-manage-global-hierarchies-app/qaa-p/14283175#M4232601</id>
    <title>Re: The G/L accounts are not displayed in the Manage Glob...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:57:44.318000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Please check the resolution documented in the KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003691021" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3691021&lt;/A&gt; - G/L accounts are not displayed in the Manage Global Hierarchies app&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/the-g-l-accounts-are-not-displayed-in-the-manage-global-hierarchies-app/qaa-p/14283175#M4232601"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:57:44.318000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/prepare-for-advent-of-code-2025-amp-share-your-cool-ideas-and-puzzles/m-p/14283176#M3347</id>
    <title>Re: Prepare for Advent of Code 2025 &amp; Share your cool ideas and puzzles</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T15:58:44.434000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://adventofagents.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://adventofagents.com/&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/prepare-for-advent-of-code-2025-amp-share-your-cool-ideas-and-puzzles/m-p/14283176#M3347"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T15:58:44.434000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/mdg-materials-duplicate-check/qaa-p/14283178#M4932950</id>
    <title>Re: MDG Materials Duplicate Check</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:00:35.636000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stefan_bogesch</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/387529</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253375"&gt;@MOHAMMED_BASER&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thanks for your response, that helped me to understand it better.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We use HANA search and have the thresholds set to 50 and 80.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So would it help to set them higher? Do both need to be set higher?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stefan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/mdg-materials-duplicate-check/qaa-p/14283178#M4932950"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:00:35.636000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/dynamic-value-for-title-annotation-is-it-possible/qaa-p/14283180#M4932951</id>
    <title>Re: Dynamic value for @title annotation - is it possible?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:01:49.179000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CronJorian</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1721226</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;What you should be able to do, is to pass it like so:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;'{= "{json&amp;gt;/country}"}'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not sure whether it works within an Entity Definition, however it certainly works within the `annotations.cds` for the Label property.&lt;BR /&gt;That way it is also possible to handle labels conditionally.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I did it in my case like so:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    $Type : 'UI.DataField',
    Value : myValue,
    Label : '{= %{myValue} === 1 ? "{i18n&amp;gt;label1}" : "{i18n&amp;gt;label2}"}',
},&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/dynamic-value-for-title-annotation-is-it-possible/qaa-p/14283180#M4932951"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:01:49.179000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/bridging-data-quality-gaps-in-sap-successfactors-tih-with-csvvalidationapp/ba-p/14283170</id>
    <title>Bridging Data Quality Gaps in SAP SuccessFactors TIH with CSVValidationApp and Vibe Coding</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:06:10.964000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DivyaTiwari</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17995</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1895545887"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality challenges in SAP SuccessFactors Talent Intelligence Hub (TIH) often go unnoticed until they impact user experience. When thousands of attributes are imported without proper validation, issues like HTML tags, broken formatting, and unescaped characters can disrupt Growth Portfolios and compromise analytics/employee experience. This blog introduces &lt;STRONG&gt;CSVValidationApp&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a solution designed to bridge this gap using &lt;STRONG&gt;functional expertise and modern development practices like Vibe Coding&lt;/STRONG&gt;—and opens the door for community collaboration on similar innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1699032382"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Talent Intelligence Hub is a strategic enabler for skills-based workforce planning. It helps organizations create dynamic career paths, leverage AI-driven skill recommendations, and empower employees through Growth Portfolios. These capabilities unlock smarter talent decisions and a more agile workforce.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;To fully realize these benefits, &lt;STRONG&gt;data integrity during imports is critical&lt;/STRONG&gt;. According to &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-platform/using-talent-intelligence-hub/importing-entities?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=successfactors+attribute+import+talent+intelligence&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal,&lt;/A&gt; importing entities like attributes, tags, and behaviors into TIH requires strict adherence to structure and format. Common issues include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Incorrect headers or missing mandatory fields in CSV files&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improper encoding (non-UTF-8) causing character display errors&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unescaped quotes or HTML tags in descriptions, which can truncate or break content&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Large file sizes impacting performance (recommended limit: 25,000 records per file)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Incorrect date formats for proficiencyAssignedDate when updating Growth Portfolio attributes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These challenges can lead to incomplete or inaccurate data in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Attributes Library&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Growth Portfolio&lt;/STRONG&gt;, affecting AI-driven recommendations and user experience. Adding a validation step before import ensures clean, consistent data—reducing manual troubleshooting and enabling HR teams to focus on strategic initiatives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1502518877"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Perspective and Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Having worked extensively across &lt;STRONG&gt;implementations, integrations, and functional solution design&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SuccessFactors, I’ve seen how small data issues can create big challenges downstream. This experience shaped my approach: build a tool that doesn’t just validate data but actively improves it before it enters TIH.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I chose &lt;STRONG&gt;Vibe Coding&lt;/STRONG&gt; as the development approach because it accelerates delivery through real-time collaboration, instant previews, and iterative design—all within SAP Business Application Studio. This allowed me to focus on business logic and user experience rather than boilerplate coding, ensuring the solution was delivered quickly without compromising quality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1306005372"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How CSVValidationApp Fits into the TIH Workflow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;CSVValidationApp acts as a &lt;STRONG&gt;data quality gatekeeper&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the integration process. In the following example workflow after data is exported from Integration Center, the file passes through CSVValidationApp for cleansing and validation. Once clean, the data is transformed and mapped to TIH-compatible attributes before being imported back into the system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="DivyaTiwari_0-1764771625951.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348134iF204DFBBBA9998B1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DivyaTiwari_0-1764771625951.png" alt="DivyaTiwari_0-1764771625951.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;This workflow ensures that what enters TIH is not just valid but optimized for rendering and usability. The result? A clean, enriched skills library that supports AI-driven recommendations and future enhancements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1109491867"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Makes CSVValidationApp Powerful&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;CSVValidationApp performs comprehensive checks tailored for SuccessFactors Integration Center requirements. It detects encoding issues, validates structure, identifies problematic characters, and removes HTML tags and entities. Beyond validation, it offers &lt;STRONG&gt;auto-correction&lt;/STRONG&gt;, generating clean content with proper quoting and escaping. A preview feature and detailed statistics give administrators confidence before import.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By automating these steps, CSVValidationApp transforms a tedious, error-prone process into a seamless experience—empowering HR teams to focus on strategic tasks rather than data cleanup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912978362"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Looking Ahead: Unlocking the Full Potential of TIH&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Talent Intelligence Hub is continuously evolving to help organizations stay ahead in a skills-based economy. Upcoming innovations include &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-driven skill inference&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;integration with external taxonomies&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;expanded APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;advanced analytics for workforce agility&lt;/STRONG&gt;. These capabilities will empower HR teams to make smarter decisions and deliver personalized employee experiences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Clean, validated data is the foundation for these advancements. By ensuring data integrity from the start, organizations can confidently leverage AI recommendations, predictive insights, and future integrations without disruption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CSVValidationApp supports this vision by acting as a proactive data quality gatekeeper. Future enhancements will include &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered attribute correction suggestions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;direct SAP API integration for one-click imports&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;support for additional modules like Learning and Recruiting&lt;/STRONG&gt;—making the process even more seamless and intelligent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-716464857"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Getting Started&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;CSVValidationApp is built as an SAP Fiori application using SAP Business Application Studio. To run it locally, simply clone the repository, install dependencies, and start the app:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.tools.sap/I046576/CSVValidationApp.git
cd validatecsv
npm install
npm start&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-519951352"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality is the backbone of any successful talent strategy. In SAP SuccessFactors TIH, importing thousands of attributes via CSV files is a common practice—but without validation, organizations risk introducing HTML tags, malformed characters, and inconsistent formatting that can disrupt Growth Portfolio screens and degrade user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To address this challenge, I built &lt;STRONG&gt;CSVValidationApp&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a Fiori-based application developed using &lt;STRONG&gt;Vibe Coding principles&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This tool automates cleansing and validation of CSV files before import, ensuring clean, consistent data and saving HR administrators countless hours of manual work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-323437847"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Thoughts &amp;amp; Community Ask&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data quality may seem like a technical detail, but in reality, it’s a strategic enabler. By combining functional expertise with modern development practices, CSVValidationApp delivers a solution that not only solves today’s challenges but positions organizations for tomorrow’s opportunities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’d love to hear from the SAP Community:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Have you built similar tools using &lt;STRONG&gt;Vibe Coding&lt;/STRONG&gt; or other rapid development approaches?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What other gaps do you see in &lt;STRONG&gt;data validation for SuccessFactors integrations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and how can we bridge them together?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Share your thoughts, examples, and ideas in the comments. Let’s collaborate to make data quality a strength, not a challenge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/bridging-data-quality-gaps-in-sap-successfactors-tih-with-csvvalidationapp/ba-p/14283170"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:06:10.964000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-set-environment-variables-without-overwriting-existing-values-with/qaa-p/14283184#M4932952</id>
    <title>Re: How to set environment variables without overwriting...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:09:46.220000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RonnyZ</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/846367</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;modules:
  - name:...
    parameters:
      keep-existing:
        env:true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-set-environment-variables-without-overwriting-existing-values-with/qaa-p/14283184#M4932952"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:09:46.220000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/register-now-sap-joule-agents-in-sap-signavio-beta-program-be-the-first-to/ba-p/14282447</id>
    <title>REGISTER NOW: SAP Joule Agents in SAP Signavio Beta Program – Be the First to Experience!</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:12:02.523000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Maria_Nugroho</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2260578</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;AI is transforming how businesses manage processes—and SAP Signavio is leading the change. The &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2025/11/1e1873c7-2d7f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Agents in SAP Signavio&lt;/A&gt; Beta Program offers SAP Signavio customers early access to five innovative AI agents designed to enhance efficiency, insight, and decision-making across your core business processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is your opportunity to test these agents with your own processes, data, and system landscape before the official release—and influence the next generation of process transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Join the Beta Program?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Early Access:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Be among the first to experience Joule Agents in SAP Signavio.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-World Testing:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Validate AI capabilities in your own environment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Influence Development:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Provide feedback that shapes the product roadmap.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exclusive Support:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Get dedicated resources during the beta phase.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Registration is now open and closes January 31, 2026.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet the Five Joule Agents in SAP Signavio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s what you’ll experience in the beta:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Dashboard Analyzer Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Turn complex process mining dashboards into clear, actionable insights. This agent interprets event logs and KPIs, detects inefficiencies, and recommends next-best actions—delivering natural-language summaries that explain what’s happening, why it matters, and how to improve.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Focus on decisions, not data interpretation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Spot trends and anomalies instantly&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prescriptive recommendations for continuous optimization&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Value:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;80% faster access to process mining insights&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;5% reduction in value erosion from misinterpreted data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Process Content Recommender Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Get curated content lists, including process models, KPIs, and accelerators tailored to your query—within seconds. This agent searches thousands of SAP best practices and your own models to deliver prioritized recommendations and actionable guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Eliminate manual content search&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce information overload&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accelerate process improvement with context-aware suggestions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Value:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;50% reduction in time spent searching for content&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;5% productivity boost for BPM teams&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Screen Guide Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Your context-aware assistant for SAP Signavio screens. It explains what each screen does, highlights key data, and guides users through actions—making complex dashboards and models intuitive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simplify navigation and interpretation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Highlight what matters most&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accelerate onboarding and boost productivity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Value:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;30% faster interpretation of screens&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;50% lower onboarding and training costs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Value Case Creation Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Move from process insights to financially justified business cases—fast. This agent automatically identifies inefficiencies, suggests improvement initiatives, and estimates monetary impact, creating editable value case drafts for quick validation and collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automated value case generation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clear financial impact for any user level&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prioritize high-value opportunities confidently&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Value:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;70% faster value case creation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;5% reduction in value erosion from delayed action&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Workspace Administration Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simplify user onboarding and workspace setup at scale. This agent automates license assignment, role provisioning, and bulk user enrollment—ensuring immediate access and consistent governance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Instant access for new users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced administrative workload&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scalable, compliant workspace management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Value:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;90% reduction in time to grant access rights&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Access and Activate Agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You have met the prerequisites for your product of the SAP Signavio Process Transformation Suite. For more information, select your product-specific documentation in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Product Documentation&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;section located in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/signavio-process-transformation-suite" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Signavio Process Transformation Suite&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;page.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You already have Joule activated in your workspace. For more information about activating and integrating Joule, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap-solutions-eac-9f9313e986d24fc495b820f9f725a824/integration-with-sap-signavio-process-transformation-suite" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration with SAP Signavio Process Transformation Suite&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customers who do not yet have Joule can still register but must ensure it is activated in their account by January 2026. Further details will be shared in an upcoming blog.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Although registration begins in December 2025, official enablement will start in January 2026.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Getting Access to Agents:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To access agents in&amp;nbsp;SAP Signavio, follow these steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Register yourself with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/link-disclaimer?site=https%3A%2F%2Finfluence.sap.com%2Fsap%2Fino%2F%23campaign%2F3987" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Influence Opportunity&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;page. From this page, select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assessment Form&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and enter your details, including your Customer ID, the agents you wish to enable for your organization, your email address, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Remember: &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The customers are selected for the beta program by SAP. Once you &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;register for the program, we'll review your application and reach out for next steps, &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;if you're selected.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Sign a Test and Evaluation Agreement (TEA).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Share your SAP BTP sub-account name, BTP sub-account ID and region so that we can enable the agents in your account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note: &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;All SAP products that you want to integrate with Joule have to use the same&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Cloud Identity services tenant and Global User ID. For more information, &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity/system-integration-guide/global-user-id-in-integration-scenarios?version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Global User ID in Integration Scenarios&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Your SAP Cloud Identity Services (SCI) admin needs to create groups in SCI for the agents. For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/signavio-process-transformation-suite/joule-in-sap-signavio-solutions-beta/accessing-and-activating-agents?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=SHIP#loiof514f492cea34370a07e7391826e8e81__section_e4o_dog_olv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Activating Agents for Users&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Next for Future Roadmap?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay informed on SAP Signavio future releases by accessing our &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73554900100800003811&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73554900100800003813&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73554900100800003814&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73554900100800003815&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73555000100800003392&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73555000100800003980&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73555000100800004732&amp;amp;PRODUCT=F71E8E8587BC1EEE9FB5474ED9D6152D&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;roadmap explorer&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learn more about SAP Joule Agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Visit this &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-agents.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;page&lt;/A&gt; on SAP website.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Joule Agents in SAP Signavio Beta Program presents an unparalleled opportunity for beta testers to experience the transformative power of AI-enabled process transformation. By joining the program, you gain early access to five innovative AI agents that promise to enhance efficiency, provide actionable insights, and streamline operations across your business processes. This is your chance to be at the forefront of technological innovation, influencing the development and validation of features tailored to real-world requirements. With limited seats available, don’t miss out on this exciting journey towards, more agile business operations—register now and be a part of shaping the future of process transformation.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/register-now-sap-joule-agents-in-sap-signavio-beta-program-be-the-first-to/ba-p/14282447"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:12:02.523000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14283188#M14605</id>
    <title>Re: Reimagining Certification for the Way We Work Today</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:17:34.197000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Neel_C</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2062113</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Diana,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I tried the SAP Generative AI Developer exam yesterday. I submitted the exam carefully after completing the exercise. It shows that it didnt pass with no real feedback of what went wrong. I did everything as asked in the exercise, saved with the correct names, and versions, in the right scenario. Everything textbook as asked in the exercise.&amp;nbsp; I cant remember what could go wrong. I wrote the system and role user messages in a notepad first and then copied it to the SAP AI Launchpad while creating a prompt, because the session was very unreactive, the scroll bar while typing moves too rapid, hence. Not really sure what happened with the assessment with the AI proctor.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Could it be reviewed and I could know what went wrong so that part could be improved? I wouldnt want to waste another attempt as I could be repeating a thing that the AI proctor thinks is a mistake and I shoot another arrow in the dark.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Neel.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14283188#M14605"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:17:34.197000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cds-view-for-the-pegged-requirements-list/qaq-p/14283196</id>
    <title>CDS view for the Pegged Requirements List</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:22:02.164000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rahul_Prasath</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1739203</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Greetings,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a custom requirement to build a custom application that displays pegged requirement for multiple FG material in single list view, similar to the functionalities available in MD04. In MD04 we can display one material at a time. We need a consolidated view for planning and analysis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, is there any CDS views available which I can use that to map this requirement. Please advise on this issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rahul&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cds-view-for-the-pegged-requirements-list/qaq-p/14283196"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:22:02.164000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/simplify-deployment-and-monitoring-with-the-cap-console/bc-p/14283198#M186862</id>
    <title>Re: Simplify Deployment and Monitoring with the CAP Console</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:23:31.930000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ddusart_mtl2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14853</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1584697"&gt;@Vincentius&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It seems I had to restart my computer as it doesn't seem to recognize the default browser to open the login page after first installation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's corrected now.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/simplify-deployment-and-monitoring-with-the-cap-console/bc-p/14283198#M186862"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:23:31.930000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/observability-for-third-party-components-components-using-sap-cloud-alm/bc-p/14283199#M186863</id>
    <title>Re: Observability for third party components components using SAP Cloud ALM</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:25:35.380000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>schroederman12</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/138242</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/239747"&gt;@andrea_campo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; We using the SAP landscape including SAP Commerce. The Idea is to do as described, using the java agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But where should the collector run? The BTP has no Docker Service. Is it possible to run it as java application in the BTP?&lt;BR /&gt;Is there a description for this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ingo Schröder&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/observability-for-third-party-components-components-using-sap-cloud-alm/bc-p/14283199#M186863"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:25:35.380000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/consolidation-link-group-transaction-types-transaction-type/qaa-p/14283200#M4232602</id>
    <title>Re: Consolidation: link group transaction types / transaction type</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:26:10.321000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NH_FICO</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2130208</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello! please did you find any solution for this problem?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/consolidation-link-group-transaction-types-transaction-type/qaa-p/14283200#M4232602"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:26:10.321000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/auto-instrumentation-for-java/qaq-p/14283201</id>
    <title>Auto-instrumentation for Java</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:26:30.579000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alfonsoarmenta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/624527</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've recently deployed a java application in SAP BTP. I've followed the guide here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/alm/sap-cloud-alm/operations/expert-portal/data-collection-infrastructure/autoinstrumentation-for-java.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://support.sap.com/en/alm/sap-cloud-alm/operations/expert-portal/data-collection-infrastructure/autoinstrumentation-for-java.html&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;using the&amp;nbsp;SAP Java buildpack setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Although I can see the dashboards with populated data in Cloud Logging, I am also seeing exceptions in our application logs such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;EXMLogRecordProcessorImp - tenant id not available&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;EXMLogRecordProcessorImp - saas - subscriber tenant info not available&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OkHttp https://dcr.ngdci.eu20.alm.cloud.sap/...] i.o.e.internal.http.HttpExporter : Failed to export spans. Server responded with HTTP status code 404. Error message: Unable to parse response body, HTTP status message:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;What am I missing?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I don't believe I am missing any data in the dashboards, but the errors are significant and before I simply turn off logging for the corresponding classes (and potentially miss on actual errors), can someone point me in the right direction as to why these errors are happening in the first place?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The application uses SpringBoot 3.5.8, the OTEL libraries are not included in my build, but get added by using the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;sap_java_buildpack_jakarta&lt;/FONT&gt; buildpack.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/auto-instrumentation-for-java/qaq-p/14283201"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:26:30.579000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/consolidation-link-group-transaction-types-transaction-type/qaa-p/14283203#M4232603</id>
    <title>Re: Consolidation: link group transaction types / transaction type</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:28:31.144000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NH_FICO</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2130208</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello! please did you find any solution for this problem?We are using ECC</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/consolidation-link-group-transaction-types-transaction-type/qaa-p/14283203#M4232603"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:28:31.144000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/positioning-sap-cloud-erp-and-finance-intelligence-with-sap-business-data/ba-p/14283185</id>
    <title>Positioning SAP Cloud ERP and Finance Intelligence with SAP Business Data Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:30:00.027000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoseBastidas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Positioning SAP Cloud ERP and Finance Intelligence with SAP BDC.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348147i841A85596BE88F7F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Positioning SAP Cloud ERP and Finance Intelligence with SAP BDC.png" alt="Positioning SAP Cloud ERP and Finance Intelligence with SAP BDC.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your customers are asking, “How do we get real value from our ERP and data investments, not just more dashboards?” — this webinar is for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join us for &lt;STRONG&gt;“Positioning SAP Cloud ERP and Finance Intelligence with SAP Business Data Cloud”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, designed specifically for SAP Partners across sales, presales, consulting, and architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ll demystify &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ERP Intelligence Private&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and preview what’s coming with &lt;STRONG&gt;Finance Intelligence for SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &amp;nbsp;We’ll connect:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business value to real architecture patterns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP‑managed data products to outcomes like &lt;STRONG&gt;working capital insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BW modernization and other GTM plays to concrete engagement plans&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Plus, you’ll see how to use demo environments, TDD licenses, and certifications to kick‑start confident customer conversations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt; and leave with a clear story, structure, and next steps for your customers.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/nov/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012280.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/nov/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012280.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPBTP #SAPPartner #SAPBusinessDataCloud #SAPCloudERP #FinanceIntelligence #SAPTraining&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/positioning-sap-cloud-erp-and-finance-intelligence-with-sap-business-data/ba-p/14283185"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:30:00.027000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/item-from-the-previous-manual-delta-accruals-flowing-into-the-manual-delta/qaq-p/14283205</id>
    <title>Item from the previous manual delta accruals flowing into the manual delta accruals settlement doc</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:30:50.337000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HariBoyapati2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1912127</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have created two manual delta accruals settlement documents(ZS4B and ZS4C) which are copies of 0S4B. ZS4B has "Distribution" active and for ZS4C, "Distribution" is inactive. For ZS4B, distribution type is "3 - Distribution Based on Accruals(CCM)". The problem I am facing is that after the distribution in ZS4B, a line item is generating for the item from ZS4C. Is there a way to distribute the manual delta accruals only with the materials from the Business volume.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ZS4C:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HariBoyapati2_0-1764775069233.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348151iF66F7023898FAF67/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="HariBoyapati2_0-1764775069233.png" alt="HariBoyapati2_0-1764775069233.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ZS4B - with Distribution:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The second line item in the distribution is generated for the previous manual delta accruals. This should not come in the distribution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HariBoyapati2_1-1764775307955.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348157i01D05D0F14A34B5C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="HariBoyapati2_1-1764775307955.png" alt="HariBoyapati2_1-1764775307955.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hari&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/519"&gt;@MichaelWerner&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/155910"&gt;@GauthierVictor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/item-from-the-previous-manual-delta-accruals-flowing-into-the-manual-delta/qaq-p/14283205"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:30:50.337000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/issue-with-sending-email-notifications-for-po-approval-workflow-in-sap-s/qaa-p/14283209#M4232604</id>
    <title>Re: Issue with Sending Email Notifications for PO Approva...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:35:29.095000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dawid90</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172309</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235611"&gt;@youssef_hassnien&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below checklist that usually fixes it:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Make sure outbound email is actually allowed in CBC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Define Allowed Email Receiver Domains For Email Outbound (101312)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3407435" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3407435&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Define Allowed Email Sender Domains For Email Outbound (101313)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/2660904" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/2660904&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Define Default Email Sender Address For Email Outbound (101311) Some scenarios fail or behave unexpectedly if a sender can’t be determined&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Important. These email outbound configurations are non-transportable and must be maintained in each tenant/system&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3556392" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3556392&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. DKIM is mandatory in Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create an SAP support request (component XX-S4C-OPR-SRV) to request DKIM activation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP provides DKIM details&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You update your DNS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP validates/activates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3223182" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3223182&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Publish SPF. Even if your email shows as Completed/Sent, delivery can fail because:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SPF not published, and/or&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;DKIM not set up&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3274509" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3274509&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Use Monitor Email Transmissions app to see what’s happening&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3274509" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3274509&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3265907" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3265907&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dawid&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/issue-with-sending-email-notifications-for-po-approval-workflow-in-sap-s/qaa-p/14283209#M4232604"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:35:29.095000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sfpls-41208-manage-languages-custom-translations-updated-without-changes/qaa-p/14283211#M49737</id>
    <title>Re: SFPLS-41208 | Manage Languages | custom translations...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:37:01.330000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SoumyadiptaPal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/25052</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The new Shell bar does support custom translations via Manage Languages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The problem with inconsistent display of&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;custom translations, is that addressed now?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sfpls-41208-manage-languages-custom-translations-updated-without-changes/qaa-p/14283211#M49737"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:37:01.330000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-power-of-version-management-in-sap-analytics-cloud-for/bc-p/14283214#M186865</id>
    <title>Re: Unlocking the Power of Version Management in SAP Analytics Cloud for Planning</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:42:47.988000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>IW2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1514593</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11638"&gt;@Mark_P_Burke&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;What is the future of the Rapid FP&amp;amp;A Suite with the arrival of SAP Business Data Cloud?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could we see Rapid FP&amp;amp;A appear as an Intelligent Application?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-power-of-version-management-in-sap-analytics-cloud-for/bc-p/14283214#M186865"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:42:47.988000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-knowledge-base/application-decisions-for-sales-order-management-in-cx-part-2/ta-p/14283206</id>
    <title>Application Decisions for Sales Order Management in CX - Part 2</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:42:53.134000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alvaro_guzman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/204675</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the key functions within the sales process is the creation of a Sales Order, typically followed by its replication to the back-office system (whether SAP ERP or SAP S/4HANA). This process, known as Sales Order Management, is part of the Lead-to-Cash enterprise process and is a common scenario across multiple industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This document is the second part of a two-part series: The first covers the functional and business aspects (you can access it&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-knowledge-base/application-decisions-for-sales-order-management-in-cx-part-1/ta-p/14274899" target="_self"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;), while this one focuses on the technical details. At the end of this document, you’ll find a conclusion that summarizes both parts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution Options&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the customer experience domain, two options could cover the giving capabilities (not including a back-office system):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud for Customer (C4C) - Sales Cloud: Sales Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2: Sales Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Note:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Although SAP S/4HANA Sales manages sales orders lifecycle through its Order and Contract Management functionality, this document does not aim to describe or analyze those standard features.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Criteria to determine the most suitable target solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Several factors will determine the best solution for handling Sales Orders within your architecture. Here are some of the most relevant ones, focusing on&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;technical&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;requirements:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;1. Integration with the back-office&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud for Customer - Sales Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP C4C, several integration scenarios with the back-office (SAP ERP or SAP S/4HANA) are available including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replicate Sales Orders created in C4C to the back-office&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replicate Sales Orders created in back-office to the C4C&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a Sales Order in the back-office from a Quote created in C4C&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a Sales Order in the back-office from an Opportunity created in C4C&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sales Order Simulation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Status Update Synchronization&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replicate Attachment from back-office&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;These integration scenarios for Sales Order document flows rely on middleware solutions, such as SAP Cloud Integration (recommended as part of the SAP Integration Suite) or SAP Process Integration (PI), to enable seamless data exchange between systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information about these integrations scenarios please refer to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-cloud-for-customer/solution-guide-for-sap-sales-cloud/integrate-sales-orders-with-sap-erp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integrate Sales Orders with SAP ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-cloud-for-customer/prepackaged-integration-with-sap-s-4hana/prepackaged-integration-with-sap-s-4hana" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;C4C Prepackaged Integration with SAP S/4HANA (including Cloud Integration and Process Integration)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-cloud-for-customer/prepackaged-integration-with-sap-erp-97f5b6f7272b4501b99c693e53bd8474/scope-and-methodology" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;C4C Prepackaged Integration with SAP ERP (including Cloud Integration and Process Integration)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud Integration includes prepackaged integration flows (iFlows) that support this integration. You can find more information at the following links::&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPHybrisCloudforCustomerIntegrationwithSAPS4HANACloud/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud for Customer Integration with SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPHybrisCloudforCustomerIntegrationwithSAPERP/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud for Customer Integration with SAP ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly to C4C, Sales Cloud Version 2 offers several integration scenarios with the back-office solution including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replicate Sales Orders created in Sales Cloud Version 2 to the back-office&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replicate Sales Orders created in back-office to the Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a Sales Order in the back-office from a Quote created in Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a Sales Order in the back-office from an Opportunity created in Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sales Order Simulation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="446"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Delete Sales Order Ref. from S/4HANA&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="168"&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Retrieve Document Flow&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;X&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;These integration scenarios rely on the SAP Cloud Integration packages that facilitate the data exchange.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For additional information of these scenarios please refer to the following links:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES/ea5ff8b9460a43cb8765a3c07d3421fe/ac31245a52a047aab6b8d7c1719a4fe6.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Replicate Sales Orders from External SAP Systems&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES/ea5ff8b9460a43cb8765a3c07d3421fe/d946c3a50a4a436e9ebdfb18809fc3f1.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Simulation and Transfer of Sales Orders&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES_SVC/8bd4421e7f9542208c9918dbe8046714/dafb6d6eb7e1447ab4864a26685c3a22.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sales Cloud and SAP Service Cloud Version 2 Integration with SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES_SVC/271570f5220f48ce807721f8d17a7bbb/99e790ee55bb49e7aea5487ca4b60ca4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sales Cloud and SAP Service Cloud Version 2 Integration with SAP ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud Integration includes prepackaged integration flows (iFlows) that support this integration. You can find more information at the following links::&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPSalesCloudVersion2IntegrationofSalesProcesseswithSAPS4HANAorSAPS4HANACloud/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 Integration for Sales Processes with SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPSalesCloudVersion2IntegrationforSalesProcesseswithSAPERP/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 Integration for Sales Processes with SAP ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;2. API Strategy&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud for Customer - Sales Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following continue to be supported in C4C:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SOAP (A2X) &amp;amp; REST (OData) APIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SOAP-based A2X and OData V1 services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Traditional gateway approach&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Authorization methods: Basic Authentication, Certificate-based&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customization: In-system customizations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More information at the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-cloud-for-customer/odata-services/sap-cloud-for-customer-odata-api" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud for Customer OData API&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;help page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following APIs are supported in Sales Cloud Version 2:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;API-driven microservices architecture&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Individual REST APIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cloud-native API management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Authorization methods: Basic Authentication, Certificate-based, OAuth2 token-based&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customization: Clean core + side-by-side extensibility&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More information at the Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SVC/56436b4e8fa84dc8b4408c7795a012c4/672931631b2a462ba1c8d56c7ae28152.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;API Guidelines&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud for Customer - Sales Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP C4C comes with several ways to adapt the solution in the Sales Order management area including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Custom fields at Account, Product, Sales Order header/item levels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can use KUT (Key User Tools) and PDI (Partner Development Infrastructure) which is not necessarily Clean Core compliant&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 extensions range from customizing through to the development of add-ons or composites. It comes with low-code tools that makes it easier to extend the solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You also can extend your system using SAP Build Apps by designing, developing, and embedding these extensions on your system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;4. Analytics&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud for Customer - Sales Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using the extensive and flexible business analytics features, you can easily create custom reports using the guided procedures. You can define your own Reports, Data Sources, and Views. The Analytics data in the solution is real time. More information in the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-cloud-for-customer/sap-cloud-for-customer-analytics-guide/overview-of-analytics?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Overview of Analytics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;section of the help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, you can integrate&amp;nbsp;your SAP C4C with SAP Analytics Cloud either using OData Services or using the SAP Analytics Cloud, Embedded Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system is available with a prepackaged integration with SAP Analytics Cloud, offering an embedded solution to all users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following are the SAP Analytics Cloud, Embedded Edition features available in the system:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Query Designer&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Linked Analysis&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, please visit this&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES/ea5ff8b9460a43cb8765a3c07d3421fe/f60ea8b6997a4122af138397ec1884cc.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;link&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. New releases and innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud for Customer - Sales Cloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP releases quarterly updates of C4C delivering innovations to users through a combination of new functionalities and improvements, cloud-based architecture, and integration with other SAP solutions. These new releases can’t be evaded, and the date and time are well known. Please check the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-cloud-for-customer/sap-cloud-for-customer-release-dates-and-timelines/release-schedule-and-dates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;help portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for detail information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Note&lt;/U&gt;: C4C has scheduled maintenance windows (with a downtime of max. 4 hours) weekly and major upgrade windows (with a downtime of max. 12 hours) quarterly. More information in the link above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Like C4C, SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 releases quarterly updates. Since SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 is built on a microservices-based cloud architecture, it allows for continuous updates and faster delivery of new features without disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comparison Table&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, here’s a short overview of the decision criteria we presented including both areas, functional (describe in the previous document) and technical:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP C4C Sales Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Order Types&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Internal and External&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Internal and External&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Determination&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Determination rules and code list restrictions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Party roles and the connected determination rules&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pricing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Internal and External.&lt;BR /&gt;Offline pricing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Internal and External&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Master Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Master data synchronization&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Improved data model&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Approvals&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multiple approval levels.&lt;BR /&gt;Approvals via E-Mails&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Approval workflows.&lt;BR /&gt;More flexibility to transport&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mobile App&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mobile App available including offline mode&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mobile App available but no offline support&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Machine Learning and Generative AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Gen AI: Sales Order Summary&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration with the back-office&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use of SAP Cloud Integration or&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Process Integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud Integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;API Strategy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SOAP-based A2X and OData V1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;API-driven microservices, REST APIs and Cloud-native API management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;KUT (Key User Tools) and PDI (Partner Development Infrastructure)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Low-code tools, SAP Build Apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reports&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud, Embedded Edition&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New releases and innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="286"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Quarterly&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="292"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Quarterly.&lt;BR /&gt;Based on microservices&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your organization can select a solution from the Customer Experience (CX) portfolio such as C4C or Sales Cloud Version 2 to cover your current SAP CRM Sales Order Management requirements. The key decision criteria outlined above focus on criteria commonly observed with our customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud for Customer offers a mature and flexible Sales Order Management process with strong offline capabilities, internal pricing options, and broader functional coverage. In contrast, SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 delivers a modern, streamlined, and S/4HANA-aligned approach focused on real-time pricing, cleaner integration, and a cloud-native architecture, although its offline functionality and advanced SO features are still maturing.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-knowledge-base/application-decisions-for-sales-order-management-in-cx-part-2/ta-p/14283206"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:42:53.134000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/batch-processing-automation-of-sap-notes/bc-p/14283220#M62676</id>
    <title>Re: Batch Processing: Automation of SAP Notes</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:46:15.963000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FabioPagoti</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172350</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I wonder why there are no comments here just yet.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is one of the coolest features implemented by SAP. I've just started using it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/731998"&gt;@abhyarthana&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the nice blog.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/batch-processing-automation-of-sap-notes/bc-p/14283220#M62676"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:46:15.963000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/manage-group-to-team-assignments-for-sac-within-identity-provisioning/qaa-p/14283223#M4932955</id>
    <title>Re: Manage group to team assignments for SAC within Ident...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:48:07.265000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dyaryura</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/103697</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/manage-group-to-team-assignments-for-sac-within-identity-provisioning/qaa-p/14283223#M4932955"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:48:07.265000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-secure-2-0-act-section-603/bc-p/14283224#M62677</id>
    <title>Re: U.S SECURE 2.0 Act - Section 603</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:49:38.917000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laxmi2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170427</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/155621"&gt;@Aquistapace&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Hello, i have setup the roll over Wage type correctly as per the latest documentation(by copying BC32 and updated it in my roll over field as per note. However, even though employee met age and 145k limit, still roll over is not happening into this WT. My selection of 603 option is "ROLL". Could you please help?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-secure-2-0-act-section-603/bc-p/14283224#M62677"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:49:38.917000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/hi-i-need-section-weight-available-in-the-worksheet-how-to-do-it/qaa-p/14283225#M49738</id>
    <title>Re: Hi I need Section weight available in the worksheet how to do it</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:54:05.093000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I think the second point by David is really what you should explain to your customer first: if there is potentially different section weights for different records due to different bonus plans THEN for employees with more than one assignment we cannot display two values, only an averaged one (sum of all records section weight divided by number of records) as per David's comment. I would have my customer confirm the requirement based on this limitation because they might tell you to drop it alltogether and instead prefer to go down the path of a custom statement which can show every single section weight.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/hi-i-need-section-weight-available-in-the-worksheet-how-to-do-it/qaa-p/14283225#M49738"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:54:05.093000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/hi-i-need-section-weight-available-in-the-worksheet-how-to-do-it/qaa-p/14283226#M49739</id>
    <title>Re: Hi I need Section weight available in the worksheet h...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:54:32.275000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Answered by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721"&gt;@DavidSomelofske&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;below.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/hi-i-need-section-weight-available-in-the-worksheet-how-to-do-it/qaa-p/14283226#M49739"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:54:32.275000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-discussions/do-i-need-to-have-bw-experience-to-work-with-sap-bdc/td-p/14283236</id>
    <title>Do I need to have BW experience to work with SAP BDC?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:57:09.554000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LGarcia321</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2030875</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I do not have BW&amp;nbsp;experience but I see it is mentioned a lot whenever I read about BDC. So now I am a bit concerned I have chosen to study a topic that I will struggle with.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-discussions/do-i-need-to-have-bw-experience-to-work-with-sap-bdc/td-p/14283236"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:57:09.554000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/romania-vat300/qaq-p/14283241</id>
    <title>Romania VAT300</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T16:58:50.464000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cz_irina</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/134117</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Romania VAT300 declaration for Public Cloud Edition&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dear all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Romania there was a legal change in the VAT&amp;nbsp; regulation. One of the mandatory reports is VAT300 declaration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have seen that there was a Hotfix in Oct on 31.10.2025 including also this topic:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3630491/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3630491/E&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But in the tax box structures&amp;nbsp; definition I was not able to find the following lines included in the declaration: 9.1, 24.1 and 25.1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I could not find an additional information in the OSS notes. It seems that the stucture is not the latest one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can anyone generate successfully the D300 declaration in Public Cloud for Romania, save it and validate the generated report with ANAF? If yes, I would kindly ask for your guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/romania-vat300/qaq-p/14283241"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T16:58:50.464000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-custom-basis-calculation-and-role-change-adjustment/qaa-p/14283243#M49740</id>
    <title>Re: Variable Pay-Custom Basis Calculation and Role Change...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:02:36.667000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1428485"&gt;@Olskar&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;That's what I mean by customizing... you need to also customize the calculation of earnings through calculated ALCF fields. And as a consequence in every section (busgoal, indgoal, ...) and end up with a 100% customize varpay template. At this time it is not possible to add non-numeric fields in custom basis formula but as per roadmap presented at SuccessConnect the Product team is planning on allowing if-then conditions in custom bass formula for one of the next releases -no guarantee it will be delivered however, it's still in the works.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-custom-basis-calculation-and-role-change-adjustment/qaa-p/14283243#M49740"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:02:36.667000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/successfactors-org-design-when-to-go-standard-custom-or-keep-it-simple/ba-p/14283247</id>
    <title>SuccessFactors Org Design: When to Go Standard, Custom, or Keep It Simple</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:06:54.781000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RamyaRaja</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163708</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Not every day does a SuccessFactors consultant get to play detective with organizational structures. Usually, businesses handle the heavy lifting of aligning their data to SuccessFactors (SF) org units. But recently, I got a chance to consult on this very topic—and wow, it made me think hard about one question:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;When do we create a child object in the org unit vs. a custom object vs. just a field in Job Info?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Org Structures: More Than Just Fancy Boxes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For most large organizations, the classic three-level hierarchy—&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Unit &amp;gt; Division &amp;gt; Department&lt;/STRONG&gt;—is like wearing a one-size-fits-all T-shirt. It works for some, but for global companies with multiple countries and quirky local structures, it’s a tight squeeze. Each country lead might have their own flavour of hierarchy. But we don’t want to go wild and create a spaghetti org chart with endless layers. Complexity is not our friend here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, before we start harmonizing data and designing the “to-be” org structure, we need to ask:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s the purpose of the org structure in SuccessFactors?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where do we use SF Org Structure?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Permissions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Org units act as filters. Example: Give Sales folks access to certain features while keeping HR out of the party.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reporting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It shows how your company looks on paper (or screen).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Filters help too. Example: “How many HR employees left the Organization last year?”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Legal &amp;amp; Compliance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Some countries require managers to be from the same country. Org structure helps enforce this rule with matching the position hierarchies to Org Structure and by managing matrix relationships in position hierarchy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Touchpoints&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Org units flow into S/4HANA and Employee Central Payroll (ECP) if integration is in scope.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;They can also sync with other downstream systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Harmonize the Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before we dream of a perfect org chart, we need to group data logically across countries. Can we streamline it? Once we know what we have, we can decide how many layers we need. Let’s say we need &lt;STRONG&gt;five levels&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Now comes the million-dollar question:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Do we create child divisions and departments, a custom org unit, or just store info in Job Info fields?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 1: Child Units&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pros:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Standard configuration—no extra setup.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easy to maintain and works with standard templates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cons:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visualization shows five levels, but employee assignment supports only &lt;STRONG&gt;three levels&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Child units appear twice in the org chart (yes, there’s a workaround, but it’s extra effort).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reporting still works, but permissions need creative filtering.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Case Study: Retail beverages company&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;They opted for a simple 3 level structure to manage Org hierarchy and managed to create custom fields to drive Talent Grouping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 2: Custom Org Unit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pros:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can extend the structure to &lt;STRONG&gt;four levels&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Employees can have four-level assignments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cons:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Not standard—requires configuration effort.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Does not appear as a standard permission filter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Case Study: Logistics and Supply chain company with multiple subsidiaries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;They first considered adding child departments but realized employees could only be assigned to three levels creating difficulty in identifying the multiple subsidiary units.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;They opted for a &lt;STRONG&gt;custom org unit&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling four-level assignments for better reporting.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Result:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Balanced complexity with functionality.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 3: Custom Field in Job Info&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ask yourself: Do we really need extra layers if they don’t serve multiple purposes? For example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If it’s just for payroll grouping, why not reuse &lt;STRONG&gt;PayScale Group&lt;/STRONG&gt;?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If it’s for benefits or location grouping, add a custom field like “Benefit Group” or “Location Area.”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach is simple, flexible, and avoids unnecessary complexity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Case Study: &lt;STRONG&gt;Multinational Hair care company&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A multinational hair care company had employees acquired out of M&amp;amp;A. Instead altering their Org structure, they created a custom field in Job info to flag them for time related groupings (such as different annual leave quota for them).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Result:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Simple, flexible, and avoided unnecessary hierarchy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before adding layers like an onion, ask: &lt;STRONG&gt;Does this serve a real business purpose?&lt;/STRONG&gt; If yes, go for it. If not, keep it simple. Sometimes, a custom field beats a fancy org chart.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What do you think? Have you faced similar challenges? Drop your thoughts—I would love to hear your take!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/successfactors-org-design-when-to-go-standard-custom-or-keep-it-simple/ba-p/14283247"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:06:54.781000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-of-predefined-billing-document-number-range-ir-1000000000-1999999999/qaa-p/14283257#M4232605</id>
    <title>Re: Change of Predefined Billing Document Number Range IR...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:11:26.334000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JRBG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13889</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-of-predefined-billing-document-number-range-ir-1000000000-1999999999/qaa-p/14283257#M4232605"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:11:26.334000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-of-predefined-billing-document-number-range-ir-1000000000-1999999999/qaa-p/14283260#M4232606</id>
    <title>Re: Change of Predefined Billing Document Number Range IR...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:12:24.590000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JRBG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13889</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, please the Oss note&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;3253020 - How to set up flexible billing document numbering,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3253020/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3253020/E&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-of-predefined-billing-document-number-range-ir-1000000000-1999999999/qaa-p/14283260#M4232606"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:12:24.590000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-continuous-influence-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-q4-2025/ba-p/14283227</id>
    <title>SAP Continuous Influence for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition –  Q4/2025 Review Results</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:13:30.074000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DoreenBaseler</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/92695</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Blog_Banner.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/125701i4F79391A036D988D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog_Banner.png" alt="Blog_Banner.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dear Customers and Partners,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;We’re pleased to share an update on the progress made in response to your valuable feedback submitted via the &lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Influence portal&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Your input continues to shape our public cloud product, and we remain committed to addressing qualified requests—while also considering those below the voting threshold when strategically aligned and feasible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q4/2025 Review Highlights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore the latest outcomes and improvements delivered during the recent review cycle. For detailed spotlights, check out the individual blog posts from each &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Continuous Influence session&lt;/STRONG&gt; for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your continued engagement and collaboration throughout 2025!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="640px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Session&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Review Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP Central Business Configuration for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3728" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Advanced Variant Configuration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3692/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Asset Management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1172/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, CDS View Extraction Enablement&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;See&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3024/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Data Management and Data Migration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3734" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Enterprise Portfolio and Project Management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3720" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Finance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3731" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition and Private Edition, Environment, Health and Safety&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3615" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition and Private Edition,&lt;BR /&gt;Group Reporting&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3732" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Localization&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3673/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Manufacturing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1171/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Master Data Maintenance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1713/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Product Compliance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3334/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Professional Services Automation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3722" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Sales&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3723" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Service&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3729" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Sourcing and Procurement&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3730" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Supply Chain Logistics&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2897/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, User Experience and Cross-Topics&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3727" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q4/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-continuous-influence-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-q4-2025/ba-p/14283227"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:13:30.074000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/search-and-maintain-customer-extension-fields-from-focused-build-fiori/bc-p/14283282#M186866</id>
    <title>Re: Search and Maintain Customer Extension Fields from Focused Build Fiori Application</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:20:09.383000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RiccardoEscher</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/174029</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello all!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I want to add a bit of knowledge, may be here is the right place.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to transport your work from a SolMan Development System to a Production System, strangely, you have to repeat in the Production System the customizing for the table&amp;nbsp;AXT_SYSTAB using transaction AXTSYS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Usually this transaction is needed only in the development system, because it steers the way your AET extensions are recorded in a package and subsequently into a transport; the prefix is intended to avoid possible overwrites when AET extensions&amp;nbsp;from more than one development system are transported&amp;nbsp; to the common productive system: you maintain for every development system a dedicated unique prefix and in the productive system the AET extensions will coexist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is also the reason why the maintenance of this table is local, as you can only have one prefix in one system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And everything in FB works after your transport from FB Dev to FB Prod, you can use your FB Custom Fields in the Mass Change App and you can use them in the Analytics, except in the Document Fiori App itself :-]]]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The reason is that the Gateway service /SALM/CRM_SERVICE, when it reads the Custom Fields Entity Set, for some reason behaves differently than the other apps, because it wants to use the AXT_SYSTAB to determine the namespace of the AXT extension (usually "Z"), but ignoring the prefix, when constructing dynamically the Custom Fields names, thus breaking the CRM extension architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, SAP note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3317607/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3317607/E&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;"Error when generating the Field Control properties for the Extension Fields - Focused Build" is incomplete (or a second note would be needed), because it addresses the execution of AXTSYS only in the development system, but oddly this local maintenance has to be repeated also on all subsequent SolMan systems. If you don't do this, you will see in the Fiori App the fragment titel "Custom Fields" appearing, but the fields are missing.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/search-and-maintain-customer-extension-fields-from-focused-build-fiori/bc-p/14283282#M186866"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:20:09.383000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/measure-based-on-last-variable-selected/qaa-p/14283283#M4932956</id>
    <title>Re: Measure based on last variable selected</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:23:34.410000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FrancescoPetrocelli</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1579799</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Anyone knows??? I need also a restricted measuer for the first value of the variable</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/measure-based-on-last-variable-selected/qaa-p/14283283#M4932956"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:23:34.410000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-video-series-for-sap-datasphere-data-marketplace/bc-p/14283284#M186867</id>
    <title>Re: New video series for SAP Datasphere data marketplace</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:24:01.596000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Darshan_12345</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2125804</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;HI&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5959" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;FlorianN,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To create a data provider profile, you must have the following privilege assigned to your role:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. &lt;STRONG&gt;Spaces (Update) Privilege&lt;SPAN&gt;: This privilege is essential for both creating a new data provider profile and editing an existing one.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To verify that you have this privilege, follow these steps:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;1. Navigate to the side navigation area.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Click on the Security section.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Select Roles.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;4. Choose the role you are using to create or update the data provider profile.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. Check that the Spaces (Update) privilege is enabled.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I need your help regarding an issue in SAP Datasphere. Even though I already have the DW Space Administrator, DW Administrator, and DW Modeler roles, all with the Space (Update) privilege enabled, I am still unable to create the Data Provider Profile. I am confused if any additional roles or privileges are required for this activity. Could you please check and confirm what exact roles or permissions are needed to create a Data Provider Profile and whether anything else needs to be enabled on my user? Your guidance will really help me resolve this issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Darshan_12345_2-1764778653477.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348207i06CAD7253222F4D9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Darshan_12345_2-1764778653477.png" alt="Darshan_12345_2-1764778653477.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-video-series-for-sap-datasphere-data-marketplace/bc-p/14283284#M186867"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:24:01.596000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/error-message-5xu-drc-germany/qaa-p/14283285#M256771</id>
    <title>Re: Error message 5XU DRC Germany</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:25:57.942000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Toan_Ha</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1417507</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Matze,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I think&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lakshmipathi gave a very good recommendation. You can find more details of those&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;configuration steps for Communication System/Arrangements in the below documentation. Pls validate also if other steps are completed:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-edition/sap-document-and-reporting-compliance-cloud-edition/integrating-peppol-exchange-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-edition/sap-document-and-reporting-compliance-cloud-edition/integrating-peppol-exchange-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If problem still persists, pls raise an incident to this component:&amp;nbsp;CA-GTF-CSC-EDO-PAP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Toan&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/error-message-5xu-drc-germany/qaa-p/14283285#M256771"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:25:57.942000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/consolidation-link-group-transaction-types-transaction-type/qaa-p/14283290#M4232607</id>
    <title>Re: Consolidation: link group transaction types / transaction type</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:26:29.052000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NH_FICO</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2130208</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello! please did you find any solution for this problem?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/consolidation-link-group-transaction-types-transaction-type/qaa-p/14283290#M4232607"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:26:29.052000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/intercompany-stock-transfer-net-value-1p9-mx-sap-s-4-hana-cloud-public/qaa-p/14283291#M256772</id>
    <title>Re: Intercompany Stock Transfer NET VALUE (1P9_MX) SAP S/...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:26:43.339000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Good day&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146474"&gt;@AngelT&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Have a look at the following reference.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/e6175604fc874bfe84aa14d2f9ae1fbd/83c2865585be44f49206cfac787a64b0.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Intercompany Allocation&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a376cd9ea00d476b96f18dea1247e6a5/1d71ab44f6b2435db5687d5a306d982c.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Sales Price Workflows&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Based on the details I can read on your screenshot, your condition record for P101 seems correctly maintained but the Intercompany Price condition is not being picked up in the billing document. That hints at either a missing or incorrect pricing procedure assignment in your intercompany setup.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your invoice shows 0 net value because the condition type P101 is either not included in the pricing procedure or your billing document was created before you maintained the price condition. I suggest you check your pricing procedure, ensure P101 is active and then recreate the invoice to then apply pricing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Chris1973_0-1764779177847.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348210i6DE779FDBB7C26C7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Chris1973_0-1764779177847.png" alt="Chris1973_0-1764779177847.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Chris1973_1-1764779185911.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348211i2EF3F0F7FD499454/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Chris1973_1-1764779185911.png" alt="Chris1973_1-1764779185911.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This Blog &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/new-resource-related-intercompany-billing-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public/ba-p/13573408" target="_blank"&gt;New Resource-Related Intercompany Billing in SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition&lt;/A&gt; also provides more insight.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let me know if you have further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/intercompany-stock-transfer-net-value-1p9-mx-sap-s-4-hana-cloud-public/qaa-p/14283291#M256772"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:26:43.339000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/calculate-the-critical-project-path-with-sap-project-and-resource/ba-p/14274779</id>
    <title>Calculate the Critical Project Path with SAP Project and Resource Management</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:29:21.411000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ellen_Reuther</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1661335</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Project and Resource Management (SAP PRM) enables to do bottom-up project scheduling, offering the flexibility to choose between forward and backward scheduling methods. Additionally, the tool visually highlights critical components in the Gantt Chart. This article provides insights into how the scheduling algorithm operates, the process of identifying critical elements, and the various types of scheduling conflicts that may arise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scheduling Method:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;While editing the project plan, you have the option to choose your preferred scheduling method. To do so, click the 'Settings' button located in the top right corner. Currently Bottom-Up scheduling available and you can choose between Backward or Forward Scheduling&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_0-1763733464132.png" style="width: 556px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343677i23E206084BFBA920/image-dimensions/556x257/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="556" height="257" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_0-1763733464132.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_0-1763733464132.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Forward Scheduling:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When you select ‘Forward Scheduling’ in the ‘Settings’, the system uses the project start date to align the logical first project plan element (this can be Milestones or Work Packages) that does not have child-elements. Following this, other elements are organized according to their Parent-Child Hierarchy, Finish-to-Start Relationships, or Date Constraints. &lt;/SPAN&gt;Then the dates are aggregated into a holistic project timeline. &lt;SPAN&gt;If any sequence conflicts arise, the system provides warnings for the impacted project plan elements (See the following section on ‘Conflicts’).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Backward Scheduling:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Backward scheduling similarly arranges project plan elements, but begins with the project end date, positioning the logical last element that has not child-elements underneath.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Critical Project Element Calculation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;When you click ‘Schedule’, the algorithm calculates both forward and backward scheduling, assigning &lt;EM&gt;Early Start&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;Early Finish Dates&lt;/EM&gt; for forward scheduling, and &lt;EM&gt;Late Start&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;Late Finish Dates&lt;/EM&gt; for backward scheduling. The &lt;EM&gt;Scheduled Dates&lt;/EM&gt; are then copied to &lt;EM&gt;Planned Dates&lt;/EM&gt;, which project managers can adjust as needed. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_1-1763733464139.png" style="width: 557px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343678i75A3DA752EB02756/image-dimensions/557x273/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="557" height="273" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_1-1763733464139.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_1-1763733464139.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Project plan elements are highlighted as critical—like &lt;EM&gt;Critical Milestone&lt;/EM&gt; or &lt;EM&gt;Critical Work Package&lt;/EM&gt;—and colored red if their &lt;EM&gt;Float&lt;/EM&gt; is zero. This may be due to their position on the critical path or a Must Start/Finish On constraint.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_2-1763733464142.png" style="width: 565px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343676iCA8DD734152173D0/image-dimensions/565x587/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="565" height="587" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_2-1763733464142.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_2-1763733464142.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conflicts:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As previously noted, various factors can lead to conflicts arising. For instance, two elements of a work project plan might not align correctly due to their relationship being out of sequence (refer to image 1), or child dates might not be properly aggregated (refer to image 2). The project plan elements that are impacted are highlighted, and warning messages will assist you in comprehending the conflict more thoroughly.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_3-1763733464146.png" style="width: 557px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343680iC11CF3C344B04341/image-dimensions/557x199/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="557" height="199" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_3-1763733464146.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_3-1763733464146.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Image 1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_4-1763733464151.png" style="width: 558px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343679i86C4B0632CCEA073/image-dimensions/558x207/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="558" height="207" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_4-1763733464151.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_4-1763733464151.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Image 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Milestone Calculation:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Since milestones lack a duration (they have only a Finish Date), when a Work Package consists solely of milestones as children, the duration of this Parent Work Package remains unaffected by its milestone children. However, this changes if additional work packages are defined as children. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_5-1763733464161.png" style="width: 556px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343681iF61E8C3625802335/image-dimensions/556x610/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="556" height="610" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_5-1763733464161.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_5-1763733464161.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Milestone Display:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Milestones are positioned based on their Finish Date, which is always displayed on the right end of the respective Date Bar.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ellen_Reuther_6-1763733464163.png" style="width: 555px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343682iF41A7D0A550C07AE/image-dimensions/555x102/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="555" height="102" role="button" title="Ellen_Reuther_6-1763733464163.png" alt="Ellen_Reuther_6-1763733464163.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For general insights into &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/schedule-projects-with-sap-project-and-resource-management/ba-p/14137576" target="_blank"&gt;project scheduling with SAP PRM&lt;/A&gt;, refer to this blog post or explore specific details on &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/date-constraints-in-sap-project-and-resource-management/ba-p/14213305#M61776" target="_blank"&gt;Date Constraints&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/bridging-project-planning-integrating-sap-cloud-erp-with-sap-project-and/ba-p/14265338" target="_self"&gt;Bi-Directional Integration&lt;/A&gt;. For more comprehensive product details, please visit the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/project-resource-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;product website.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/calculate-the-critical-project-path-with-sap-project-and-resource/ba-p/14274779"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:29:21.411000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-blog-posts/welcome-all-sap-community-members-start-here/bc-p/14283293#M37449</id>
    <title>Re: Welcome all SAP Community members, start here!</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:30:45.898000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>evelucas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1796876</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am Évelyn from Brazil and I am g&lt;SPAN&gt;lad to join the SAP community!!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-blog-posts/welcome-all-sap-community-members-start-here/bc-p/14283293#M37449"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:30:45.898000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ers-flag-in-po/qaq-p/14283294</id>
    <title>ERS Flag in PO</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:32:33.666000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ananthula_sumanth</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/292902</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, I am looking for some support regarding ERS flag&amp;nbsp;EKPO-XERSY how it will be determined.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vendor masters LFM1 has XERSY and XERSR and LFM2-XERSY and XERSR and EINE-XERSN.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How the values are considered for Standard PO and Return PO process.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ers-flag-in-po/qaq-p/14283294"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:32:33.666000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/where-can-i-find-the-sybase-software-developer-kit-sdk/qaa-p/14283295#M4932957</id>
    <title>Re: Where can I find the Sybase Software Developer Kit (SDK) ?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:34:36.497000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sladebe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/282098</uri>
    </author>
    <content>The developers edition product doesn't exist anymore</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/where-can-i-find-the-sybase-software-developer-kit-sdk/qaa-p/14283295#M4932957"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:34:36.497000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/1h-2025-release-km-19826-minor-visual-changes-in-1h-2025/qaa-p/14283296#M49741</id>
    <title>Re: 1H 2025 Release | KM-19826 | Minor Visual Changes in...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:40:08.747000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SoumyadiptaPal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/25052</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Custom Translations maintained by customers are not revoked/overwritten by the release, provided the underlying label key remains unchanged (which is usually the case).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/1h-2025-release-km-19826-minor-visual-changes-in-1h-2025/qaa-p/14283296#M49741"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:40:08.747000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/wrong-planning-level-assigned-in-miro/qaq-p/14283297</id>
    <title>Wrong planning level assigned in MIRO</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:40:47.937000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>khaledgnt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/880486</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP experts ,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'd like some assistance or explanation for a system behavior .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While posting an invoice through MIRO , and while using a vendor that has the planning group field filled ( LFB1-&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;FDGRV), the system takes the planning level from the reconciliation account of said vendor instead of the planning level assigned to the planning group .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;If we empty the planning level from the reconciliation account, then the system takes the correct planning level from the group.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In fb60/FB50, this behavior is not present , and the correct planning level is taken from the planning group.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This is a problem because the planning level assigned to the group can be assigned to vendor line items , but the one in reconciliation account gives us the error RQ107, because it can only be assigned to GL line items.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Am i missing something in SPRO ? or is there a note i can implement .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Thank you for your help.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/wrong-planning-level-assigned-in-miro/qaq-p/14283297"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:40:47.937000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-of-work-package-end-date-gives-error-quot-cannot-update-or-delete/qaq-p/14283299</id>
    <title>Change of Work Package End Date gives error "Cannot update or delete. Actuals have been posted."</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:44:01.289000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In Plan Customer Projects I try to change the Work Package End Date but get error message "Cannot update or delete. Actuals have been posted." even though there are no postings after the date I am entering.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-of-work-package-end-date-gives-error-quot-cannot-update-or-delete/qaq-p/14283299"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:44:01.289000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-of-work-package-end-date-gives-error-quot-cannot-update-or-delete/qaa-p/14283300#M4232610</id>
    <title>Re: Change of Work Package End Date gives error "Cannot u...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:44:08.836000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The system checks the Posting Date of actuals on the Work Package between the Start and End date. If an actual cost exists outside either the Start or End date then message "Cannot update or delete. Actuals have been posted." will be given. So, even though the user is only changing the End date, the system also checks the Start date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check in app Display Line Items in General Ledger for the range of Posting Dates for the Work Package and set your Start and End Dates accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-of-work-package-end-date-gives-error-quot-cannot-update-or-delete/qaa-p/14283300#M4232610"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:44:08.836000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/s-4hana-cloud-add-header-level-conditions-to-po/qaa-p/14283303#M4932958</id>
    <title>Re: S/4HANA Cloud - Add header level conditions to PO</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:49:32.463000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KDN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46397</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Have the same issue, off course item level cond gets apportioned at the Header Level. But there you can only choose condition defined as item condition. Adding a real header condition ( which should be distributed based on alternate Kondbasis) is not possible.is not possible with the app</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/s-4hana-cloud-add-header-level-conditions-to-po/qaa-p/14283303#M4932958"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:49:32.463000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-export-analytical-model-output-from-sap-datasphere-to-azure-data/qaq-p/14283304</id>
    <title>How to Export Analytical Model Output from SAP Datasphere to Azure Data Lake Storage?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:51:46.079000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karteeksap</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2240010</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am working on a requirement where I need to export the output of an &lt;STRONG&gt;Analytical Model&lt;/STRONG&gt; in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt; into &lt;STRONG&gt;Azure Data Lake Storage (ADLS)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Connections to both &lt;STRONG&gt;Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Azure&lt;/STRONG&gt; are already established.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Question:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Is there a way to export Analytical Model data into ADLS?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I attempted to create a &lt;STRONG&gt;Replication Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt; with Datasphere as the source. However, when selecting the source object, I only see:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Local Tables&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fact Views&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dimension Views&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Analytical Models&lt;/STRONG&gt; do not appear as selectable source objects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone implemented this scenario or knows if Analytical Models are supported in Replication Flows or if there is an alternative approach?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Datasphere/pd-p/73555000100800002141" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="16-1"&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Cloud+Integration/pd-p/67837800100800006801" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="361-1"&gt;Cloud Integration&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Cloud+Connector/pd-p/0f95abc4-29f3-477d-874c-7c758b81f779" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1193-1"&gt;Cloud Connector&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-export-analytical-model-output-from-sap-datasphere-to-azure-data/qaq-p/14283304"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:51:46.079000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/s-4hana-cloud-add-header-level-conditions-to-po/qaa-p/14283305#M4932960</id>
    <title>Re: S/4HANA Cloud - Add header level conditions to PO</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T17:52:28.768000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KDN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46397</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Have the same issue, off course item level cond gets apportioned at the Header Level. But there you can only choose condition defined as item condition. Adding a real header condition is not possible with the App - use the Web GUI transaction and everything works as expected. Other thing I have header conditions with condition base net weight - in the App cant find the weight at all, Web GUI ok.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/s-4hana-cloud-add-header-level-conditions-to-po/qaa-p/14283305#M4932960"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T17:52:28.768000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/high-volume-data-handling-in-sap-integration-suite-our-journey-to-10/bc-p/14283309#M176611</id>
    <title>Re: High-Volume Data Handling in SAP Integration Suite - Our Journey to 10 Million Records</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:06:11.562000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MateuszPiotrowski</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1161523</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Great insights!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A few questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Just curious - what kind of apps return 50k+ records in one response? Don't you hit timeout or performance issues?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You mentioned: "Even if SAP IS is configured for a custom page size (e.g., 1,000 or 10,000), the adapter always respects the server-side limit." I get that OData V4 only has server-side pagination, unlike OData V2 which has both options.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Approach 2 - are you talking about not checking "Process in Pages" (so using built-in pagination) and adding custom splitting/pagination logic in the iFlow to deliver in chunks to the target app?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Anyway - I'm seeing again that HTTP adapter can handle things where other more specialized adapters fall short (OData V4 here, OData V2 in my case for different reasons).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/high-volume-data-handling-in-sap-integration-suite-our-journey-to-10/bc-p/14283309#M176611"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:06:11.562000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-maintain-the-header-condition-discount-in-manage-purchase-order-app/qaa-p/14283311#M4232611</id>
    <title>Re: How to maintain the header condition discount in Mana...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:06:56.758000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KDN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46397</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In the app '&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage Purchase Order'&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;adding header condition is not possible, use Web GUI App change purchase order advanced and it works.&lt;BR /&gt;Got also an issue because my header condition has as basis net weight - not in the app - Qty/weight tab missing only GUI helps&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-maintain-the-header-condition-discount-in-manage-purchase-order-app/qaa-p/14283311#M4232611"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:06:56.758000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/are-these-sap-authorizations-strictly-read-only/qaq-p/14283312</id>
    <title>Are These SAP Authorizations Strictly Read-Only?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:19:48.108000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChinmayiGP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1808546</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Can someone confirm whether the following SAP authorizations are strictly &lt;STRONG&gt;read-only&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or if any of them allow update or modification operations?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Authorization Object: S_RFC

RFC_TYPE: Function Module

RFC_NAME: *

Activity: Execute

Authorization Object: /SDF/E2E

Activity: 03

Authorization Object: S_ADMI_FCD

S_ADMI_FCD: ST0R

Authorization Object: S_RZL_ADM

Activity: 03

Authorization Object: S_TABU_DIS

DICBERCLS: &amp;amp;NC&amp;amp;, EDI0, SA, SC, SS, SPWD

Activity: 03&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chinmayi G Panicker&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/are-these-sap-authorizations-strictly-read-only/qaq-p/14283312"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:19:48.108000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issues-with-learning-sap-com/qaa-p/14283316#M4932962</id>
    <title>Re: Issues with learning . sap . com</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:28:35.831000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kzagni</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1592746</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I am facing the same issue in "SAP Certified Associate - Integration Developer" certification learning journey : "Developing with SAP Integration Suite"</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issues-with-learning-sap-com/qaa-p/14283316#M4932962"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:28:35.831000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ers-flag-in-po/qaa-p/14283317#M4232612</id>
    <title>Re: ERS Flag in PO</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:29:51.148000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ankurch</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11196</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/292902"&gt;@ananthula_sumanth&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; - Its updated from supplier LFM1 - XERSY and XERSR, logic is written in subroutine -&amp;nbsp;LMEPOF7Y, you can take help from ABAP team if more input needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ankur&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ers-flag-in-po/qaa-p/14283317#M4232612"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:29:51.148000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/cluster-table-j-1bnfw-sc-clu/td-p/14283320</id>
    <title>Cluster Table J_1BNFW_SC_CLU</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:32:49.995000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ronaldo_aparecido</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/202053</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi community, does anybody know how I could view the cluster table in SAP HANA, specifically the cluster table J_1BNFW_SC_CLU? Accessing it via SE16 and SE11 is not possible, and I don’t have access to SE84. I need to know which tables constitute it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/cluster-table-j-1bnfw-sc-clu/td-p/14283320"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:32:49.995000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/common-formula-issues-in-comp-custom-fields/bc-p/14283321#M7394</id>
    <title>Re: Common Formula Issues in Comp Custom Fields</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:34:23.784000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Congrats on your first blog ! yes, breaking down formulas is the best tip here that can save hours: create one column for each condition in your formula then make sure it is working in each column. This way you will spot what is not working and then you can delete the extra columns used for troubleshooting. Also, do a search in the community because it is most likely that we've already provided replies on formula issues in many spots. &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2020/09/29/how-to-use-dates-in-formulas-in-compensation-worksheets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;This blog&lt;/A&gt; also references everything about working with date-based formulas.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/common-formula-issues-in-comp-custom-fields/bc-p/14283321#M7394"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:34:23.784000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/manage-kpis-and-report-issue-with-allow-cds-views-annotations-on-off/qaq-p/14283326</id>
    <title>Manage KPIs and Report issue with Allow CDS Views Annotations ON/OFF</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:39:00.002000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>gibram_habib</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/887140</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello experts!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am having an issue about the APP Manage KPIs and Reports:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the creation of a KPI, in the section 'Data Source Details' there is a check called 'Allow CDS Views Annotations', I set it OFF, but when I run it, in the Adapt Filters option the fields are not correct, there are appearing multiple times, here is my custom CDS, then some screenshots&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;@AbapCatalog.sqlViewName: 'ZVIEWNOTASSG'&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15206"&gt;@analytics&lt;/a&gt;.query: true&lt;BR /&gt;@ObjectModel.modelingPattern: #ANALYTICAL_QUERY&lt;BR /&gt;@ObjectModel.supportedCapabilities: [ #ANALYTICAL_QUERY ]&lt;BR /&gt;@AccessControl.authorizationCheck: #NOT_REQUIRED&lt;BR /&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Products not assigned'&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15206"&gt;@analytics&lt;/a&gt;.settings.runtimeExtensibility.allowed: true&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2001388"&gt;@vdm&lt;/a&gt;.viewType: #CONSUMPTION&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1599241"&gt;@odata&lt;/a&gt;.publish: true&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;define view ZC_ProdNotAssignAB_Query&lt;BR /&gt;with parameters&lt;BR /&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Number of Days Back'&lt;BR /&gt;@Consumption.hidden :false&lt;BR /&gt;P_NumOfDays : int4&lt;BR /&gt;as select from ZI_ProdNotAssignABCube(P_NumOfDays:$parameters.P_NumOfDays)&lt;BR /&gt;{&lt;BR /&gt;AllocatingEntity,&lt;BR /&gt;Plant,&lt;BR /&gt;product,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;$parameters.P_NumOfDays as NumberOfDaysBack,&lt;BR /&gt;@AnalyticsDetails.query.axis:#ROWS&lt;BR /&gt;@Consumption.filter :{ selectionType: #SINGLE, multipleSelections: true, mandatory: false }&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;NumberAssignmentMissing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS_FioriLaunchPath.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348220iCE335A3D8BA138E0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SS_FioriLaunchPath.png" alt="SS_FioriLaunchPath.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS_FilterFails.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348221i6AF1B232D3CFF61A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SS_FilterFails.png" alt="SS_FilterFails.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can see, when I select one Entity at the bottom does not appear the correct value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But if I delete those annotations from my view, everything works fine:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;@AbapCatalog.sqlViewName: 'ZVIEWNOTASSG'&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15206"&gt;@analytics&lt;/a&gt;.query: true&lt;BR /&gt;@ObjectModel.modelingPattern: #ANALYTICAL_QUERY&lt;BR /&gt;@ObjectModel.supportedCapabilities: [ #ANALYTICAL_QUERY ]&lt;BR /&gt;@AccessControl.authorizationCheck: #NOT_REQUIRED&lt;BR /&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Products not assigned'&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15206"&gt;@analytics&lt;/a&gt;.settings.runtimeExtensibility.allowed: true&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2001388"&gt;@vdm&lt;/a&gt;.viewType: #CONSUMPTION&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1599241"&gt;@odata&lt;/a&gt;.publish: true&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;define view ZC_ProdNotAssignAB_Query&lt;BR /&gt;with parameters&lt;BR /&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Number of Days Back'&lt;BR /&gt;@Consumption.hidden :false&lt;BR /&gt;P_NumOfDays : int4&lt;BR /&gt;as select from ZI_ProdNotAssignABCube(P_NumOfDays:$parameters.P_NumOfDays)&lt;BR /&gt;{&lt;BR /&gt;AllocatingEntity,&lt;BR /&gt;Plant,&lt;BR /&gt;product,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;$parameters.P_NumOfDays as NumberOfDaysBack,&lt;BR /&gt;@AnalyticsDetails.query.axis:#ROWS&lt;BR /&gt;@Consumption.filter :{ selectionType: #SINGLE, multipleSelections: true, mandatory: false }&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;NumberAssignmentMissing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS_FLPOK.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348223iEC17138BFA279B03/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SS_FLPOK.png" alt="SS_FLPOK.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS_FilterOK.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348225i921262B9D6CCF221/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SS_FilterOK.png" alt="SS_FilterOK.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can see in the above images, without the annotations the filters are working correct, not duplicating the values (first image) and then in the bottom of the second image is appearing the description and value&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does anyone have an idea what is happening? Maybe I am not using correctly that check 'Allow CDS Views Annotations'. Or any hint that you can share?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance for your help.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/manage-kpis-and-report-issue-with-allow-cds-views-annotations-on-off/qaq-p/14283326"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:39:00.002000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-joule-for-developers-abap-ai-capabilities-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private/bc-p/14283328#M186868</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Joule for Developers, ABAP AI capabilities for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:40:50.488000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>wagener-mark</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179540</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10947"&gt;@SebastianBaskovich&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;We are struggling with some certificate issues. Is there some more guidance on these points:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Your system needs to be configured so that it trusts server certificates according to the "required" section of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/link-disclaimer?site=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fsap-software%2Fbtp-trust-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;BTP Trust Store&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Your system needs to use a client certificate issued by a CA listed in the "required" section of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/link-disclaimer?site=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fsap-software%2Fbtp-trust-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;BTP Trust Store&lt;/A&gt;. One way to obtain a client certificate can be found on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/use-destination-certificates?version=Cloud#procedure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Destination Certificates&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(under "Generate a Certificate").&lt;/EM&gt;"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-joule-for-developers-abap-ai-capabilities-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private/bc-p/14283328#M186868"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:40:50.488000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/trm-daily-compounding-calculation-logic/qaq-p/14283331</id>
    <title>TRM- Daily Compounding calculation logic</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:47:10.596000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ktemma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1657872</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am working on an IRI with daily compound. From what I understand from the system is that when we set it as compounding interest, the system will automatically use both the SOFR + Margin rate as a single rate which will be applied to calculate the cumulative interest. However, I am trying to configure the system to where ONLY the SOFR rate is being compounded daily while the Margin rate is not. Please let me know if this possible on the system, if so, how will I configure this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ktemma_0-1764783048346.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348222iDCA544E2EDED40F0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ktemma_0-1764783048346.png" alt="ktemma_0-1764783048346.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can see the SAP use the all-in rate (SOFR+ Margin) to calculate the interest and adds it to the based amount.&amp;nbsp; We would like to see if it's possible for the system to calculate the new base amount by only adding compounded the SOFR amount and not the margin rate.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ktemma_1-1764783314617.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348226iB04A4CC44E05CD12/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ktemma_1-1764783314617.png" alt="ktemma_1-1764783314617.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/trm-daily-compounding-calculation-logic/qaq-p/14283331"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:47:10.596000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/key-user-custom-fields-adding-or-removing-business-contexts/ba-p/14283242</id>
    <title>Key User Custom Fields: Adding or Removing Business Contexts</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T18:53:15.206000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>georg_wilhelm</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/457497</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to&amp;nbsp;add&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;business context to&amp;nbsp;an&amp;nbsp;existing&amp;nbsp;custom field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From the very beginning, the&amp;nbsp;Custom&amp;nbsp;Fields&amp;nbsp;Fiori&amp;nbsp;app offers two ways to enable an existing&amp;nbsp;custom field&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;additional&amp;nbsp;business contexts:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By enabling a business scenario for a custom&amp;nbsp;field, additional&amp;nbsp;business contexts&amp;nbsp;are enabled automatically. The corresponding&amp;nbsp;data flows between these involved business contexts are activated, too.&amp;nbsp;Therefore,&amp;nbsp;custom field data is automatically transferred from one business context to the other&amp;nbsp;in copy processes of the extended applications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;By&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;enabling a standard CDS view for a given key user field that exposes data from several business contexts (this can happen in cases where the CDS view represents&amp;nbsp;a union of different business object nodes)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So far, so good. But what happens if none of the options above enable you to&amp;nbsp;propagate your existing&amp;nbsp;custom field&amp;nbsp;into&amp;nbsp;your required&amp;nbsp;business context?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this case, you can use our new feature. It allows you to propagate&amp;nbsp;an existing&amp;nbsp;custom field&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;any arbitrary business context, even if there are no corresponding business scenarios or&amp;nbsp;union&amp;nbsp;CDS views.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s have a look at how that works. We'll provide a concrete&amp;nbsp;example&amp;nbsp;for the new “Add Business Context” feature:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s assume you created a&amp;nbsp;custom field&amp;nbsp;“YY1_INVOICE_TYPE” of type code list (with a fixed set of&amp;nbsp;possible code&amp;nbsp;values&amp;nbsp;like&amp;nbsp;“Standard Invoice”,&amp;nbsp;“Partial&amp;nbsp;Invoice”, “Corrected&amp;nbsp;Invoice”,&amp;nbsp;…)&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;business context&amp;nbsp;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accounting: Journal Entry Item&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;”&amp;nbsp;(FINS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM). Afterwards&amp;nbsp;it turned out that you also needed this&amp;nbsp;field for&amp;nbsp;business&amp;nbsp;context&amp;nbsp;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Group Reporting: Journal Entry Item”&amp;nbsp;(FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As there is no business scenario&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;no union view available that would allow you to propagate the field into the “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;” business context, in the past, the only&amp;nbsp;option&amp;nbsp;would have been to&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;create another&amp;nbsp;custom field&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;business context “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;” with a similar name (you can't have the same name twice)&amp;nbsp;and&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;define (and&amp;nbsp;later on&amp;nbsp;maintain) the exact same code values&amp;nbsp;for each of the custom fields&amp;nbsp;separately&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the new “Add Business Context”&amp;nbsp;feature, this is no longer necessary. You&amp;nbsp;simply&amp;nbsp;can&amp;nbsp;add the custom field to the business context “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the screenshot below, you can see the custom field&amp;nbsp;“YY1_INVOICETYPE” that's already been created&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;the business context&amp;nbsp;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FINS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM”.&amp;nbsp;As soon as&amp;nbsp;you select this field,&amp;nbsp;the “Add Business Context” button on the&amp;nbsp;bottom right corner is clickable.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_0-1764777353762.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348169i7B7F812859FCBC4F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_0-1764777353762.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_0-1764777353762.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom Field&amp;nbsp;on&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;business&amp;nbsp;context&amp;nbsp;“FINS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As soon as you click “Add Business Context”, the&amp;nbsp;standard&amp;nbsp;business context search help popup is shown allowing you to select an&amp;nbsp;additional&amp;nbsp;business context.&amp;nbsp;Here, you can choose the business context&amp;nbsp;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_1-1764777353763.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348167iBA887C52A75A0E79/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_1-1764777353763.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_1-1764777353763.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Choosing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;business&amp;nbsp;context&amp;nbsp;FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As soon as you choose the business&amp;nbsp;context&amp;nbsp;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM”, the business context is immediately added to the custom field.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_2-1764777353764.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348168i3D5F26DE823935CF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_2-1764777353764.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_2-1764777353764.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;B&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;usiness&amp;nbsp;context&amp;nbsp;“FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM”&amp;nbsp;has been added to the custom field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That’s&amp;nbsp;it. You&amp;nbsp;can now publish the custom&amp;nbsp;field&amp;nbsp;and then you are done.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please note that&amp;nbsp;this feature is available starting from&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA&amp;nbsp;2025.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This functionality&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;also available for&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA&amp;nbsp;2023&amp;nbsp;with support package&amp;nbsp;4.&amp;nbsp;For older&amp;nbsp;support packages&amp;nbsp;it's available via&amp;nbsp;deploying SAP note&amp;nbsp;3567408&amp;nbsp;–&amp;nbsp;“Change Type of a Custom Field / Add or Remove Business Contexts to a Custom Field”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next, let's take a look at how to remove business contexts from a custom field.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to remove a business context from a&amp;nbsp;custom field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s assume that a couple of&amp;nbsp;days&amp;nbsp;after you enabled&amp;nbsp;business context “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM” for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;custom field “YY1_INVOICETYPE”, it turns out that&amp;nbsp;the situation has&amp;nbsp;changed,&amp;nbsp;and you don't need&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;business context&amp;nbsp;any longer in this custom field.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the past, there was no way to remove a&amp;nbsp;dedicated&amp;nbsp;business context from a&amp;nbsp;custom field.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the new feature, it's now possible to remove&amp;nbsp;a dedicated business context from a given&amp;nbsp;custom field. Within the&amp;nbsp;field list shown in the&amp;nbsp;Custom&amp;nbsp;Fields Fiori&amp;nbsp;app, you&amp;nbsp;mark the entry for the business context&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;you want to remove&amp;nbsp;of custom field&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“YY1_INVOICETYPE”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;As soon as you've done that, the “Delete” button on the bottom right corner of the screen is clickable.&amp;nbsp;Once&amp;nbsp;you click on the down&amp;nbsp;arrow&amp;nbsp;within the “Delete” button, the option “Remove Field from Business Context” appears (see the screenshot below).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_3-1764777353764.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348170i00ECDDF98C6BBA54/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_3-1764777353764.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_3-1764777353764.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Remove Field from Business Context” option in the&amp;nbsp;Custom&amp;nbsp;Fields app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As soon as you click on this&amp;nbsp;option, a popup is shown asking you whether you really want to&amp;nbsp;delete&amp;nbsp;the field from this business context&amp;nbsp;(&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;see the screenshot below).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_4-1764777353765.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348172iD0C11DBF24AFD3BF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_4-1764777353765.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_4-1764777353765.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Confirmation popup&amp;nbsp;“Do you want to remove selected field from&amp;nbsp;business context”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once&amp;nbsp;you click on “Delete”, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;selected business context is removed from the field and the publishing process for this change is automatically triggered.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With&amp;nbsp;this, you are done. You successfully removed the business context&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM” from custom field&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“YY1_INVOICETYPE”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_5-1764777353766.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348171i04F7ADCD796298F2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_5-1764777353766.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_5-1764777353766.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom field successfully removed from business context&amp;nbsp;“FINCS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Congratulations!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please&amp;nbsp;note that in the&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Editions, a removal&amp;nbsp;of a business context from a custom field is only possible&amp;nbsp;if&amp;nbsp;the adding of the business context to this custom field has not been&amp;nbsp;released with a software collection so far.&amp;nbsp;Afterwards, you can still delete&amp;nbsp;the entire custom&amp;nbsp;field,&amp;nbsp;but&amp;nbsp;you can no longer choose to only remove the business context you've added.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This functionality is also available for&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA&amp;nbsp;2023 with support package 4. For older support packages, it's available via deploying SAP note&amp;nbsp;3567408&amp;nbsp;–&amp;nbsp;“Change Type of a Custom Field / Add or Remove Business Contexts to a Custom Field”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please note that this blog has been elaborated by a team of experts. I want to thank Yasmina van Rooij (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1393455" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;YasminavanRooij&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;), Christian Fuhlbruegge(&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1574633" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ChristianFuhlbruegge&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;),&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;Karsten Schaser (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/164194" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Karsten_Schaser&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;)&amp;nbsp;for their extremely helpful contributions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feedback, Comments, or Questions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You’re&amp;nbsp;cordially invited to provide feedback, comments, or questions in the comments section below. Please follow our profiles to get updates when we publish more posts on these topics.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feel invited to post and answer questions here (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://answers.sap.com/tags/270c4f37-c335-46e1-bfad-a256637d5e26" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://answers.sap.com/tags/270c4f37-c335-46e1-bfad-a256637d5e26&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) and read other posts on the topic (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/tags/270c4f37-c335-46e1-bfad-a256637d5e26/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://blogs.sap.com/tags/270c4f37-c335-46e1-bfad-a256637d5e26/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Other&amp;nbsp;related&amp;nbsp;blog&amp;nbsp;posts:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/key-user-custom-fields-when-to-use-what-type-of-code-list/ba-p/13557853" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key User Custom Fields: When to use what type of code list&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-key-user-extensibility-custom-field-with-context-dependent/ba-p/13530963" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Key User Extensibility: Custom field with context-dependent value help&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-key-user-extensibility-powered-by-embedded-steampunk-custom/ba-p/13533713" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Key User Extensibility powered by Embedded Steampunk: Custom Field with ABAP implemented Value Help&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/enrich-sap-s-4hana-key-user-custom-fields-with-intent-based-navigation/ba-p/13554319" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enrich SAP S/4HANA Key User Custom fields with Intent-Based Navigation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/key-user-custom-fields-adding-or-removing-business-contexts/ba-p/14283242"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T18:53:15.206000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-delete-the-leading-zero-in-sac-dimension-from-sap-business-bydesign/qaa-p/14283335#M4932963</id>
    <title>Re: How to delete the leading zero in SAC Dimension from...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T19:03:05.129000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KalyanVerma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1605630</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If it is a string, use ToNumber(). This will remove the leading zeros.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-delete-the-leading-zero-in-sac-dimension-from-sap-business-bydesign/qaa-p/14283335#M4932963"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T19:03:05.129000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/trying-to-get-ytd-with-1-month-offset-sap-analytics-cloud/qaq-p/14283337</id>
    <title>Trying to get YTD with 1 month offset SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T19:17:01.997000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rodrigo_Passos</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2188762</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am kind of new to SAC and it's my first time posting, so if my question is kind of simple, I apologize and apreciate the help. I'm trying to get a Year to Date with a month offset look back direction of 1 month in a Restricted Account (Sorry, confusing). Right now I am offsetting by 1 month and looking back a year or almost a year. But this is not what I want or was trying to achieve.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rodrigo_Passos_0-1764776879103.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348166iB414C7D74DBD3BDB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rodrigo_Passos_0-1764776879103.png" alt="Rodrigo_Passos_0-1764776879103.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is my current Range. I don't want to get any months from the year before, just the year I'm filtered for (2025). I'm using the months in 2024 because I know they have no data, but once they do, this filter will not be what I need. But I've been trying to make it work and just can't. I need it to be just from January to the month before the filter (in this case, September, since the filter is in October). I'm trying to do a Waterfall Chart that compares the accumulated value from January to the month before the filter (So Jan-Sept) to the accumulated value from January till the month chosen in the filter (Jan-Oct).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rodrigo_Passos_1-1764777456376.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348173i7A572FA80C4D6958/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rodrigo_Passos_1-1764777456376.png" alt="Rodrigo_Passos_1-1764777456376.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I don't know if it needs to be done with a script (which I have limited knowledge of also, so if you could provide one, if it needs to be done this way, I would be very grateful), if it's a limitation from the system or just lack of knowledge on my part, but I would appreciate the help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you all!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/trying-to-get-ytd-with-1-month-offset-sap-analytics-cloud/qaq-p/14283337"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T19:17:01.997000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/configure-an-sap-cap-application-to-connect-to-an-sap-hana-cloud-database/bc-p/14283338#M176612</id>
    <title>Re: Configure an SAP CAP Application to Connect to an SAP HANA Cloud Database in Another Global Acco</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T19:24:45.206000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Uli_42</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5093</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1550940" target="_blank"&gt;@JhoelAnthonyRamosRomeroPE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;,&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I am a complete newbie just checking the scenario , how to use a HANA DB on another subaccount .&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;can you explain the sentence &amp;lt;&amp;lt;When your SAP HANA Cloud database is in another&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Global Account&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;or subaccount&lt;/U&gt;, which prevents the natural use of the HDI container for database object management&amp;gt;&amp;gt; ?&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Does it mean, i can not use HDI when the HANA DB shall be used in another subaccount even of the same global account?&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;I could not find this restriction,&amp;nbsp; or&amp;nbsp; hints, how to handle that situation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Uli&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/configure-an-sap-cap-application-to-connect-to-an-sap-hana-cloud-database/bc-p/14283338#M176612"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T19:24:45.206000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-s-4hana-group-reporting-subitem-for-fixed-assets/qaq-p/14283339</id>
    <title>SAP S/4HANA Group Reporting - Subitem for Fixed Assets</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T19:35:26.660000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sveinn</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1860726</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In S/4HANA Group Reporting (On Premise), I have a question regarding Subitem determination for Fixed Asset journal entries when releasing accounting data from ACDOCA to ACDOCU.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, a Fixed Asset posting in &lt;STRONG&gt;ACDOCA&lt;/STRONG&gt; has the following values:&lt;BR /&gt;Transaction type (RMVCT) = 120&lt;BR /&gt;Subitem (SUBIT) = 120&lt;BR /&gt;Asset Transaction type (ANBWA) = 100&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Break Down Category (BDC) of the FS item does not allow Subitem 120, only 9xx Subitems. We are using the standard FS items delivered in SAP Best Practice (1SG).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is the recommended approach to handle this scenario?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adding Transaction type 120 to the BDC or&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Us Substitution to overwrite the Subitem (change from 120 to 920)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Or is there another SAP-recommended way to handle this.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-s-4hana-group-reporting-subitem-for-fixed-assets/qaq-p/14283339"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T19:35:26.660000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/simplify-deployment-and-monitoring-with-the-cap-console/bc-p/14283341#M186869</id>
    <title>Re: Simplify Deployment and Monitoring with the CAP Console</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T19:36:45.026000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ali-kaplan15</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121201</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/41902"&gt;@BirgitS&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;great blog , thanks!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1584697"&gt;@Vincentius&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a question: since the SAP BTP trial update states that new trial accounts created after October 15 no longer receive runtime memory quota for Cloud Foundry — effectively freezing deployment for those accounts — how does that impact the deployment options described in this blog post?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/bc-p/14257250" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/bc-p/14257250&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a new btp trial and would really love to try it out, so this limitation feels a bit discouraging. Any opinion on this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/simplify-deployment-and-monitoring-with-the-cap-console/bc-p/14283341#M186869"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T19:36:45.026000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14283342#M14606</id>
    <title>Re: Reimagining Certification for the Way We Work Today</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T19:40:02.345000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>phillip_morgan2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/873684</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10529"&gt;@DianaRoesner&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I understand that not all exams have the new practical format. Is there a list somewhere (apart from the ones mentioned in your post) or does the course clearly mention if it will be old (questions) or new (practical) format?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14283342#M14606"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T19:40:02.345000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/cluster-table-j-1bnfw-sc-clu/m-p/14283346#M272</id>
    <title>Re: Cluster Table J_1BNFW_SC_CLU</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T19:48:22.210000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;J_1BNFW_SC_CLU is a View Cluster (cluster of tables/maintenance views).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;View Cluster Definition: SE54.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data display or maintenance: SM34.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/cluster-table-j-1bnfw-sc-clu/m-p/14283346#M272"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T19:48:22.210000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/msg-group-accelerates-innovation-with-sap-joule-for-developers/bc-p/14283348#M186870</id>
    <title>Re: msg group Accelerates Innovation with SAP Joule for Developers</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T19:54:53.487000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>iwona_hahn</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4326</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Find more references for SAP BTP ABAP Environment, ABAP Cloud, ABAP Test Ccokpit and SAP Joule for Developers, ABAP AI capabilities &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/abap.html#customers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/msg-group-accelerates-innovation-with-sap-joule-for-developers/bc-p/14283348#M186870"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T19:54:53.487000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-export-process-model-bpmn-from-signavio-collaboration-hub-into/qaa-p/14283349#M4932965</id>
    <title>Re: How to export Process Model ( BPMN) from Signavio Col...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T20:05:37.211000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LeandroRibeiro14</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/42834</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you for the answer Philipp. I understand that the solution will be to install the corresponding Value Accelerator from the library, even adding other diagrams, folders, etc. that will not be used. The requirement is simple: Add a standard process (best practices) to the Signavio Process Manager. I can't find it in the client's current folders (perhaps because they haven't been installed) and I'm unable to "transfer" it from the Collaboration Hub (where I can identify it) to the Process Manager.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-export-process-model-bpmn-from-signavio-collaboration-hub-into/qaa-p/14283349#M4932965"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T20:05:37.211000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ekpo-abueb-field-is-filling-automatically/qaa-p/14283350#M4232615</id>
    <title>Re: Ekpo-abueb field is filling automatically</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T20:10:09.623000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAUMYA_GUPTA86</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2268802</uri>
    </author>
    <content>This issue is only for Z* output type</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ekpo-abueb-field-is-filling-automatically/qaa-p/14283350#M4232615"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T20:10:09.623000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-sto-using-bapi/qaq-p/14283353</id>
    <title>How to Create STO Using BAPI</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T20:17:30.817000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NomanRaza</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2116598</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;i have a requirement to create STO Using bapi with Hardcoded Values&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;after i will move on real-time requirement&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;please suggest some steps or blog which will help to achieve the requirement&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;can suggest blog also i can't find good blog for it&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-sto-using-bapi/qaq-p/14283353"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T20:17:30.817000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/integration-center-a-viable-and-flexible-alternative-for-lms-connectors/bc-p/14283354#M7396</id>
    <title>Re: Integration Center - A viable and flexible alternative for LMS Connectors !</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T20:29:26.420000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EricAbrams</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/50184</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Is there a way to send a "Delta" file daily (only records that have been changed since the last time the file ran), and then send a "Full File" (all records, or all active records) once a week, to make sure everything stays in sync?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/integration-center-a-viable-and-flexible-alternative-for-lms-connectors/bc-p/14283354#M7396"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T20:29:26.420000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-return-an-order-of-type-cbfd/qaq-p/14283355</id>
    <title>How to return an order of type CBFD</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T20:38:51.619000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to create a return for a order of type CBFD, which document type should I use? I'm using the scope item Free of Charge Delivery (BDA).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-return-an-order-of-type-cbfd/qaq-p/14283355"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T20:38:51.619000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-return-an-order-of-type-cbfd/qaa-p/14283356#M4232617</id>
    <title>Re: How to return an order of type CBFD</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T20:38:59.610000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To return items of a document type CBFD, that use item category CBXN, you can use the returns order type CBAR.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further information, refer to the bellow documentation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/2508/SolP/BKP?region=DE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Customer Returns (BKP)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a376cd9ea00d476b96f18dea1247e6a5/ef17554b70b946e588cf4fb378fa4622.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Customer Returns Processing | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-return-an-order-of-type-cbfd/qaa-p/14283356#M4232617"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T20:38:59.610000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-is-sap-rpt-1-a-table-specialized-model-explained-through-the-original/bc-p/14283358#M186871</id>
    <title>Re: What Is SAP-RPT-1? A Table-Specialized Model Explained Through the original RPT Paper</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T20:42:26.291000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Pierre_Col</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/63</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great explanation, thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1390198"&gt;@Ryota_Ito&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_up:"&gt;👍🏻&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-is-sap-rpt-1-a-table-specialized-model-explained-through-the-original/bc-p/14283358#M186871"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T20:42:26.291000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/agent-mining-in-sap-signavio-understand-agent-behavior/bc-p/14283361#M186873</id>
    <title>Re: Agent Mining in SAP Signavio: Understand agent behavior</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T20:45:12.497000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Pierre_Col</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/63</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great blog post&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/315943"&gt;@hoangvu&lt;/a&gt;, thanks! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_up:"&gt;👍🏻&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/agent-mining-in-sap-signavio-understand-agent-behavior/bc-p/14283361#M186873"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T20:45:12.497000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/entry-bkpf-does-not-exist-in-tojtb/qaa-p/14283362#M4932967</id>
    <title>Re: Entry BKPF does not exist in TOJTB</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T20:46:16.389000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sudarshan_sundararajan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/887395</uri>
    </author>
    <content>What is the detailed error message on view details in the second screen?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/entry-bkpf-does-not-exist-in-tojtb/qaa-p/14283362#M4932967"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T20:46:16.389000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-sap-teched-on-tour-brought-the-best-out-of-berlin/bc-p/14283365#M993</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community Voice: SAP TechEd on Tour brought the best out of Berlin, Bengaluru, and Sydney!</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T20:56:55.657000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MarceloPinheiro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1042</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;It looks like a very busy and constructive time for everyone here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Special thanks to the ones involved in the TechEd. This is more than a technology event, it's a great time for connecting people.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-sap-teched-on-tour-brought-the-best-out-of-berlin/bc-p/14283365#M993"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T20:56:55.657000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/me2n-help/qaq-p/14283367</id>
    <title>ME2N Help</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T21:07:39.073000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bmallio</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2269028</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am using ME2N to find &lt;STRONG&gt;delivery date&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the current month. Once I run ME2N with the delivery date months and purchasing group data. I then hit &lt;STRONG&gt;Delivery Schedule&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Shift + F11).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The data that appears once in&amp;nbsp;Delivery Schedule is what I am trying to have automatically reported and emailed to me at the beginning of each month.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have tried saving &lt;STRONG&gt;Delivery Schedule&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;as a layout but as far as I know there is no way to have SM36 run a layout (let alone&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivery Schedule&lt;/STRONG&gt;) after running a variant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can anyone help me out, I am not very familiar with SAP&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/me2n-help/qaq-p/14283367"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T21:07:39.073000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/fast-track-ai-driven-insights-with-zero-copy-data-access-between-sap-bdc/ba-p/14283360</id>
    <title>Fast-track AI-driven Insights with Zero-Copy Data Access between SAP BDC and Google BigQuery</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T21:10:14.287000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sangeetha_K1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/86176</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP launched&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; SAP Datasphere &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;with&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; its &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;business data fabric architecture and open data ecosystem&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/drive-business-innovation-using-sap-and-google-cloud-data-platforms/ba-p/13573574" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in 2023&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;with Google as one of its first partners&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;Since&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;then, we’ve continued helping customers drive innovation with a data and analytics strategy that unifies SAP data and analytics with the strengths of Google Cloud’s BigQuery platform&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Building on this partnership, we recently announced &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/10/sap-google-cloud-redefine-enterprise-ai-zero-copy-data-google-bigquery/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) Connect for Google BigQuery at SAP Connect 2025&lt;/A&gt;, further strengthening our collaboration and enabling secure, zero-copy data access to curated SAP data products directly from BigQuery. SAP BDC Connect for Google BigQuery is planned to be generally available by the &lt;STRONG&gt;end of H1 2026.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;With SAP BDC Connect for BigQuery&lt;/STRONG&gt;, organizations can build a business data fabric and connect their existing Google BigQuery environments to #SAP Business Data Cloud—offering data and AI teams real-time access to semantically rich SAP data products without the duplication or operational burden of multiple ETL pipelines. SAP BDC Connect&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for BigQuery w&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ill&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;also&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; be&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; bidirectional, so organizations can &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;b&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;reak &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ilos and democratize data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; with an ecosystem of business-ready data products&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; exchanged between SAP BDC and Google Cloud Cortex Framework in BigQuery. This milestone reflects a clear architectural transformation, unlocking the potential of enterprise data for analytics and AI innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog, we take a sneak-peek into the technology behind this integration and offer prescriptive guidance with reference architectures for building seamless data integration between SAP Business Data Cloud and Google Cloud’s data and AI&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BDCGBQ_ArchCenter.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348238i8DD9F86BE5414A37/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BDCGBQ_ArchCenter.jpg" alt="BDCGBQ_ArchCenter.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Fig &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;1 :&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP BDC – GBQ Integration reference architecture.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BDC Connect for BigQuery will enable&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; seamless, secure data sharing between SAP BDC and Google BigQuery—simplifying customer landscapes and accelerating AI-driven insights and innovation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Third-party data, such as Google Cloud’s Weather, Trends, Geo, and Ads, can then be effortlessly integrated and harmonized with valuable SAP data like finance and supply chain. Leveraging open data protocols and advanced data fabric architectures, this approach will simplify data sharing and unify access to information across multiple systems in a heterogenous landscape. The result will be a centrally governed, holistic data environment that supports efficient analytics and AI/ML-driven use cases—all built on industry-standard open protocols.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Challenges addressed by SAP BDC Connect for BigQuery:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This new zero-copy integration with BigQuery aims to solve challenges caused by data &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;duplication&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;copies&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Loss of governance:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Data governance becomes a major challenge once data is replicated and siloed into multiple disparate systems.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Loss of valuable semantics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Data extracted from business applications loses its critical semantics and business context, making it incredibly difficult to rebuild accurately and leading to issues in data quality.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;High total cost of ownership&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;(&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;TCO)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Managing ETL pipelines with&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;expensive third-party tools adds operational complexity and overhead, elevating the total cost of ownership (TCO) across the data landscape.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Innovation delays:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Complex and fragile data pipelines hinder organizational agility, delays the delivery of actionable business insights, and restrict the pace of AI innovation and data-driven initiatives.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key differentiating capabilities that will be introduced by the SAP BDC Connect for BigQuery architecture include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Access to AI-ready data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Accelerate AI-driven insights by combining Google Cloud's Vertex AI capabilities and analytics tools with curated, AI-ready SAP data products securely shared and governed directly from SAP Business Data Cloud.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unified Data View:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Deliver a harmonized view by integrating SAP data and third-party data across Google BigQuery and SAP Business Data Cloud without duplication. Build a unified, semantically rich data foundation to fuel next-gen data and AI/ML workloads using SAP Joule, Google Vertex AI, and Google Cortex framework.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bi-directional data sharing:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Share data products bi&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;directionally between SAP Business Data Cloud and Google BigQuery &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;via their respective catalogs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;This enables interoperability and re&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;use of these blended data sets&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;and derived data products&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delta Shar&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; protocol&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Leverage bidirectional data integration between SAP BDC and BigQuery, powered by the combination of industry open standards such as Delta Sharing open data protocol and other open table formats. This enables real-time interoperability across different computing platforms, cloud environments, and applications without duplicating data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Opens up flexible infrastructure choices:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Leverage the highly scalable infrastructure of Google BigQuery&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;, and powerful enterprise analytics capabilities of SAP Business Data Cloud to handle large volumes of data and complex analytics workloads. Share data products from Google BigQuery back to SAP BDC for analytics and planning in SAP Analytics Cloud and AI solutions with SAP Business AI as well.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Governed and secure data exchange:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Provide a secure and governed experience with enhanced control over data shared via centralized access, managed by data stewardship roles. BDC Connect leverages security protocols such as mutual Transport Layer Security (mTLS) and OpenID Connect (OIDC) to ensure safe data exchanges&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Increased scalability and data exchange speed: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the zero-copy&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;integration,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;the bottleneck of slow data transfer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (as seen with data federation architecture) will be solved SAP BDC Connect that offers efficient data sharing at great scale than before.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The technical integration (SAP BDC Connect for Google &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BigQuery&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;) enables powerful, AI-driven use cases across these business functions, detailed in the sources as strategic focuses for the partnership&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Function&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use Cases Enabled&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="98px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain &amp;amp; Operations&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="98px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Predictive Inventory Optimization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Combining live SAP inventory data with marketing campaign data (e.g., TikTok, Meta, Google Ads) and external signals like weather data or Google Trends for demand forecasting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-Powered Logistics: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Integrating SAP order and fulfillment data with external data (like GPS/traffic) to optimize delivery routes and predict delays.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="84px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhanced Demand Forecasting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Using machine learning to analyze historical SAP sales data combined with market trends and promotions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Marketing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cross-Channel Campaign Optimization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Combining SAP customer sales history with audience data (e.g., LiveRamp) and campaign performance from Google Ads, YouTube, Meta, and TikTok to optimize spend and ROI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Personalized Marketing Campaigns&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Using enriched SAP customer and product data to create highly personalized campaigns on platforms like Google Ads and social media.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales &amp;amp; Service&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;360-Degree Customer View: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consolidating customer data from SAP (billing, service history) with sales data (Salesforce) and service interactions (ServiceNow).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manufacturing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unified IT/OT Data for AI: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ingesting granular asset-level data from the shop floor (OT data) and sensor data and combining it with enterprise (IT) data for Manufacturing to improve productivity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Production Optimization: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Gaining cross-enterprise intelligence by tracking marketing campaigns to inform product demand, production, and staffing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance &amp;amp; Analytics&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build Grounded, Trustworthy AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Ensuring that Google BigQuery AI models and agents operate on the most current and complete view of the business using real-time SAP data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sustainability&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ESG Reporting and Optimization: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrating sustainability data from SAP with other external data sources to create a unified view for comprehensive reporting and using AI to analyze energy consumption or carbon emissions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhancing and scaling use cases with SAP BDC connect for Google BigQuery&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This expanded partnership also allows us to enhance previous SAP Datasphere and BigQuery use cases. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/datasphere-fedml/tree/main/Datasphere" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;FedML&lt;/A&gt; successfully enabled machine-learning use cases on Google Cloud Platform using SAP data, further scaling was necessary to support data at larger volumes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Users could also replicate data to Google BigQuery using SAP Datasphere &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/replication-flows-sap-datasphere-and-google-big-query/ba-p/13581256" target="_self"&gt;replication flows.&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For example, analyzing historical SAP sales data alongside market trends and promotions typically required either replicating the data needed—complex, costly, and time-consuming—or using connector-based data federation, which is faster but less scalable.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now, SAP BDC Connect for Google BigQuery provides a simpler, secure, and scalable option with one-click, zero-copy data sharing via BDC catalog. This eliminates the need for data duplication , reduces data access delays usually seen with federated access, and ensures secure and governed data access (which was missing with service user-based connectors).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In summary, the zero-copy architecture enabled by BDC Connect for Google BigQuery addresses business challenges with greater speed, lower cost, improved quality, enhanced security, and unprecedented scale.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Credits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The above reference architectures are the results of teamwork and contributions from both SAP and Google. I would like to thank the following SAP team members for their contribution to this content &amp;nbsp;: Kevin Poskitt, Katryn Cheng, Mariusz Cisek, San Tran And &amp;nbsp;Sivakumar N, &amp;nbsp;Anirban Majumdar, Haridas Nair for their support and guidance. &lt;SPAN&gt;We also extend special thanks to the Google team members who helped assemble the guiding use-case list.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;If you have any questions, please leave a comment below or contact us at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="mailto:paa@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;paa@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/fast-track-ai-driven-insights-with-zero-copy-data-access-between-sap-bdc/ba-p/14283360"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T21:10:14.287000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/this-is-regarding-poland-e-invoicing-is-there-any-field-to-store-ksef-id-in/qaa-p/14283369#M4232618</id>
    <title>Re: This is regarding Poland e-invoicing, Is there any fi...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T21:10:38.243000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ldzierza</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1935</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Without DRC, you can use third-party solutions, such as XEF.tax (an SAP add-on running on ECC and S/4). Feel free to contact me.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/this-is-regarding-poland-e-invoicing-is-there-any-field-to-store-ksef-id-in/qaa-p/14283369#M4232618"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T21:10:38.243000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
