<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-09-13T13:14:01.368101+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/table-tobj-list-of-authorization-ehp8/qaq-p/14216050</id>
    <title>Table TOBJ list of authorization EHP8</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T20:26:35.954000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>manthana99c17</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/823346</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Expert,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have list authorization of table TOBJ for object class SD after upgrade to EHP8.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyway to know that this is new authorization object after upgrade to EHP8?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And do i need to assign this new authorization object to user role one by one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/table-tobj-list-of-authorization-ehp8/qaq-p/14216050"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T20:26:35.954000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/reporting-on-lms-data-in-story-reporting/qaq-p/14216056</id>
    <title>Reporting on LMS data in Story Reporting</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T20:38:29.060000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tduncan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/22681</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have a question related to Story reports.&amp;nbsp; We are having difficulty with reporting on learning data.&amp;nbsp; In our output, the data does not look correct.&amp;nbsp; For example, we are seeing the same item title for different individual items.&amp;nbsp; Also, when reporting on user completions, do we start with the user block or another, in the story report?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Is there an implementation guide or documentation on table structures to point me to which fields would be course titles? Or are you familiar with the LMS tables to point me to what below would be course titles for example?&amp;nbsp; Looking for some guidance and best practices on how to report on data using story reporting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/reporting-on-lms-data-in-story-reporting/qaq-p/14216056"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T20:38:29.060000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/abap-trial-2023-licence-issues-and-permanent-compiling-issues/td-p/14216064</id>
    <title>ABAP Trial 2023 - Licence issues and Permanent Compiling issues</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T20:45:26.070000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JSchirra</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163531</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I installed SAP ABAP Trial 2023 in the last week. In the past I had already installed 1909 or one release higher. In the past, the application started comparatively quickly. Now - on the same environment - it requires three times the time. Anybody experiencing the same behaviour with 2023 compared to the former 2 releases?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More importantly and much more annoying are the following issues:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Licence issue:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;When I had installed the trial in docker, and started the system, I wanted to login using the user developer and the initial password. This was not possible. The system message was "Logon not possible (Error in license check)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Obviously the license is already expired after the installation. No issue - in the installation description there is a good explanation how to renew the license. Having done this, it worked with the user developer. I could login. But... here is the issue:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every time after a restart of the application the same issue comes up. And after every restart of the docker, the same procedure to renew the license has to be done compeletely, because the hardware key seems to change every time. And I have now clue why. It seems to be not sufficient to store the hardware key somewhere in a document and to quickly renew the license and reinstall the license file. No, you first need to login with the user SAP*, check the hardware key, which changes every time and then to renew the license file and reinstall that. Doing this every time after a restart is so annoyoing that I have concerns whehter this system is really usable for me.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does anybody experienced the same issue? I have not experienced this behaviour using one of the former ABAP Trial releases. My first idea was: Well, I just keep the system up and running. But this also does not work either. When I don´t use the system, e.g. because I go to bed, the next day the system is not running any more. Obviously the container stops to work after some idle time. So I do need to restart the system whenever I want to use it and then the license issues comes up. Any idea how to solve this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Issue Permanent compiling starting any transaction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once I solved the license issue, I can login, but then the next issue comes up, which I also never experienced in the former releases. The system is compiling for every transaction. Every experience SAP guy will now say: Use transaction SGEN and compile one time and you have fixed it. I did so, no resolution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These 2 issues are really annoying and make it impossible for me to work with the system. Does anybody know a solution for these two really nasty issues?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks in advance for any help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joachim&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;P.S: As&amp;nbsp;@JuliePlummer mentioned or asked for in different places, I tried to add or to choose the hashtag&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;#ABAP_Trial &lt;/STRONG&gt;here in SAP Managed Tags. There was no such has tag unfortunately...&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/abap-trial-2023-licence-issues-and-permanent-compiling-issues/td-p/14216064"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T20:45:26.070000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/automatic-posting-to-account-foreign-exchange-gain-realized-during-vendor/qaq-p/14216065</id>
    <title>Automatic Posting to Account Foreign exchange gain realized during Vendor Clearing</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T20:45:36.588000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dasun_T</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1945152</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you pls explain regarding below entry( Vendor Clearing)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manual posted value is 237,094.42 ( Loss) to the account 50162020.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is an amount automatically posted to the account 50162050 - 72,952.13/= ( Income)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Need to know how this amount comes - 72,952.13/=&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dasun_T_0-1757702585979.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313675i91107A3C4B59B73A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Dasun_T_0-1757702585979.png" alt="Dasun_T_0-1757702585979.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/automatic-posting-to-account-foreign-exchange-gain-realized-during-vendor/qaq-p/14216065"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T20:45:36.588000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/manage-incoming-payment-files-will-not-import-valid-records/qaq-p/14216066</id>
    <title>Manage Incoming Payment Files will not import valid records</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T20:57:50.253000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>P_Quiroz_23</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1481431</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When importing BAI files using Manage Incoming Payment Files, sap will reject the entire file when one entry (account number) is not present in bank account management.&amp;nbsp; Why can't the system import the valid records and include the invalid records in an error log.&amp;nbsp; This all or nothing approach is not user friendly and it would take considerable effort to have our banks adjust which records they send in our consolidated BAI files.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/manage-incoming-payment-files-will-not-import-valid-records/qaq-p/14216066"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T20:57:50.253000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/not-able-to-see-functional-location-and-equipment-on-the-map-in-ssam-2410/qaa-p/14216071#M4227064</id>
    <title>Re: Not able to see Functional Location and Equipment on...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T21:15:16.362000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NavPres</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2237953</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I would like to close the thread as I have figured it out by passing the custom fields to map services.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Naveen Chawla&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/not-able-to-see-functional-location-and-equipment-on-the-map-in-ssam-2410/qaa-p/14216071#M4227064"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T21:15:16.362000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/alguien-podr%C3%ADa-explicarme-c%C3%B3mo-funciona-la-constante-pmnnt-del-m%C3%ADnimo-neto/qaq-p/14216075</id>
    <title>¿Alguien podría explicarme cómo funciona la constante PMNNT del mínimo neto a pagar en nómina?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T21:16:23.510000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mayra1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1431790</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Buen día, alguien tan amable pudiera explicarme como se calcula el porcentaje definido en la constante PMNNT de la tabla T511K?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tenemos definido "30" en esa constante, sin embargo en el recibo no logró empatar esos 30 con la cantidad que deja en neto.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ejemplo:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Percepciones brutas:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;$7,740&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Deducciones:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Descuento general - $1,200&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fondo de ahorro - $300&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pensión alimenticia - $1,548&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ISR en contra - $1,281.01&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cantidad pendiente - $15&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Aportación IMSS - $181.27&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Aportación Infonavit - $1,631.40&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Total deducciones $6,156.68&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Total neto a pagar: $1,583.32&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(aquí es donde no logró llegar al 30% que tiene estipulado, ya que en ciertas deducciones, por ejemplo INFONAVIT, me esta disminuyendo la cantidad original para poder dejar ese neto a pagar).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Gracias de antemano por su tiempo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Saludos.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/alguien-podr%C3%ADa-explicarme-c%C3%B3mo-funciona-la-constante-pmnnt-del-m%C3%ADnimo-neto/qaq-p/14216075"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T21:16:23.510000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-message-finoc165-and-finoc297-manage-cost-centers-f1443a/qaa-p/14216079#M4227066</id>
    <title>Re: Error message: FINOC165 and FINOC297 - Manage Cost Ce...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T21:30:17.949000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Please note that you cannot change the Profit Center in S/4HANA because, the profit center is part of the time‑dependent master data of a cost center. Once there are &lt;STRONG&gt;actual postings&lt;/STRONG&gt; (even if reversed), the system protects the historical link between cost center and profit center to avoid inconsistencies in reporting and reconciliation (especially in Universal Journal ACDOCA and Asset Accounting). Reversing a posting doesn’t remove the original line from the database — it just adds an offsetting entry — so the system still sees “postings exist” for that validity period.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The SAP notes what you tried 3477968, 3514994, 3567063 are part of SAP’s delivery of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Profit Center Reorganization&lt;/STRONG&gt; functionality and related message control. They introduce new message numbers (like 297, 165) that can be set to warning in OBA5 to allow changes under certain conditions. In &lt;STRONG&gt;FPS01&lt;/STRONG&gt;, those message numbers weren’t yet delivered and they appear &lt;STRONG&gt;only from FPS02&lt;/STRONG&gt; onwards, which is why you can’t find them in &lt;STRONG&gt;OBA5&lt;/STRONG&gt; in your system.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Since the message control entries aren’t in your release, you have three main paths:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Option A – Use Profit Center Reorganization&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;This is the supported way to change profit center assignments for master data with historical postings.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In On‑Premise, you can activate and run the Profit Center Reorganization process (transaction FAGL_REORG* family).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;It creates transfer postings in the Universal Journal to move balances from the old profit center to the new one as of a key date.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Option B – Create a new cost center&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If reorg is too heavy for your case, create a new cost center with the correct profit center and change assignments in dependent objects (e.g., work centers, internal orders, assets).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Close the old cost center for postings.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Option C – Upgrade to FPS02 or apply targeted SAP Notes&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;FPS02 delivers the message control for 297 and 165, allowing you to set them to warning in OBA5.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If you can’t upgrade, check with SAP Support if they can provide a down‑ported correction for FPS01 to deliver those message numbers.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-message-finoc165-and-finoc297-manage-cost-centers-f1443a/qaa-p/14216079#M4227066"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T21:30:17.949000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-hobbies-series-mind-your-step-walking-and-hiking/bc-p/14216098#M330</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community Hobbies Series: Mind Your Step (Walking and Hiking)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T21:47:35.574000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>moshenaveh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/29</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/82"&gt;@TammyPowlas&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Would love to hear more about it! I remember you shared it in the past and it was magnificent!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-hobbies-series-mind-your-step-walking-and-hiking/bc-p/14216098#M330"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T21:47:35.574000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-revolution-accelerates-the-abap-developer-who-built-enterprise-apps/ba-p/14216073</id>
    <title>ABAP AI Revolution Accelerates: The ABAP Developer Who Built Enterprise Apps in Minutes</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T21:50:13.192000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SimonaM</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9367</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The ABAP AI revolution just got a massive functionality upgrade and stays FREE OF CHARGE for another year&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remember John, our seasoned ABAP developer who discovered the power of Joule for AI-assisted coding? His journey has taken an incredible turn. What started as relief from "quick questions" and real-time assistance has evolved into something he never imagined possible – building entire applications and transforming legacy systems through conversation in minutes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;John's incredible journey is about to accelerate even further with game-changing news:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule for Developers remains FREE OF CHARGE for another year&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– the promotion has been extended with no commercial barriers, allowing every customer and partner to benefit from AI-driven development through material numbers 8019124 (customers) and 8019541 (TDD partners). This offer is now available not only for the BTP ABAP environments (Steampunk) and SAP Cloud ERP Public, but also to our SAP Cloud ERP Private customers using the latest 2025 release version. For a deep dive in more commercial details see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568" target="_blank"&gt;ABAP AI - Chapter 2&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;blog written by my colleague&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179726"&gt;@AlexanderRother&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;See John's ABAP AI complete evolution with 2505, 2508 and 2025 ABAP releases:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Game-Changer: ABAP Cloud Application Generation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intelligent Business Logic with RAP Business Logic Prediction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seamless Integration with OData Consumption&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced Extensibility with Extensibility AI Assistant&amp;nbsp;for SAP Cloud ERP Public&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Migration Revolution: Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&amp;nbsp;for SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760086936"&gt;The Game-Changer: ABAP Cloud Application Generation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;John's latest project required a library application with multiple entities. Opening his package in ADT, he right-clicks and selects "Generate ABAP Repository Objects." The new&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData UI Service from Scratch Wizard with Joule Chat&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;appears.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Create a library application with entities for branches, book stock, users and borrowing information. Generate the appropriate fields which fit the business case for the entities." John prompts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_0-1757699149723.png" style="width: 831px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313657iF75C055449D3BA74/image-dimensions/831x489/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="831" height="489" role="button" title="SimonaM_0-1757699149723.png" alt="SimonaM_0-1757699149723.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Within seconds, Joule responds with a comprehensive proposal including all entities, fields, and relationships. One click on "Accept" and the wizard auto-populates all configuration fields. Minutes later, John has a complete, runnable RAP application with data model, behavior definitions, service bindings, and OData services ready for UI consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563573431"&gt;Intelligent Business Logic with RAP Business Logic Prediction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;But the magic doesn't stop at application generation. John's application needs sophisticated business logic – validations for booking dates, automatic stock calculations, and borrowing permission determinations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigating to his behavior implementation class, John finds empty method stubs for his determinations and validations. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP Predict Business Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;capability kicks in, understanding the entity structure, field relationships, and business context to generate complete validation logic within the method implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_2-1757699553027.png" style="width: 671px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313659i2E91AAAC0E2D0475/image-dimensions/671x255/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="671" height="255" role="button" title="SimonaM_2-1757699553027.png" alt="SimonaM_2-1757699553027.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"It's not just generating code," John marvels. "It's understanding the business context and implementing proper RAP patterns automatically."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367059926"&gt;Seamless Integration with OData Consumption&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When John needs to integrate with external booking services, he opens his service consumption model and starts the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule chat&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/consume&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;slash command. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;capability generates complete, ready-to-use ABAP code for consuming OData calls via the OData Client Proxy, tailored to his specific service model.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_5-1757699897856.png" style="width: 909px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313662iC303D01AD9C0D39A/image-dimensions/909x507/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="909" height="507" role="button" title="SimonaM_5-1757699897856.png" alt="SimonaM_5-1757699897856.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What used to take hours of documentation reading now happens in seconds with Joule providing example prompts and OData request generation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170546421"&gt;Enhanced Extensibility with Extensibility AI Assistant for SAP Cloud ERP Public&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As business requirements evolve, the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;guides John through adding custom fields for regulatory compliance. It assists him in:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creating Custom Fields&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for borrowing information&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding Business Contexts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for the right extension points&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling Usages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;where custom fields can be exposed in UIs, APIs, and analytical views&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling Business Scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for data flow between business objects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding Value Help Views&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for code list-based custom fields&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding BAdIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;based on natural language input&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_6-1757700405040.png" style="width: 841px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313665i86F9A9FF94CFD78E/image-dimensions/841x547/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="841" height="547" role="button" title="SimonaM_6-1757700405040.png" alt="SimonaM_6-1757700405040.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974032916"&gt;The Migration Revolution: Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;for SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2025 release&lt;/STRONG&gt;, John faces his organization's biggest challenge: migrating 15 years of custom ECC code to SAP ERP Cloud Private 2025. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;will&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;transforms this experience (on October 2025 planned release).&amp;nbsp; These use cases are currently not available on the older releases, however the use cases delivered on 2025 versions will be soon provided also as part of the&lt;STRONG&gt; Custom Code Migration Application&lt;/STRONG&gt; which is a standalone BTP ABAP environment (Steampunk) application &lt;STRONG&gt;which can connect freely to any ERP OnPrem or Cloud system to support RISE migrations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using the Explain Capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;: "Explain this legacy report," John types, selecting a 500-line ABAP program. The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explain capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;provides detailed explanations of the ABAP program, breaking down complex concepts with support for ABAP classes, ABAP programs, and CDS artifacts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explain ATC Findings Capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: When running ATC checks with S/4HANA readiness variants, John uses the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explain ATC Findings capability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;on his S/4HANA readiness findings. This capability provides detailed explanations and step by step resolution proposal on ATC findings from check variants for SAP S/4HANA Readiness, specifically for:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;S/4HANA: Field Length Extensions,&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA: Search for Database Operations and&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA: Search for Usages and Simplified Objects. Each finding links to simplification items, which Joule explains in detail.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Documentation Migration Assistance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Using the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, John opens the Joule chat view,&amp;nbsp; type in /docs to start chatting about simplification items related to Custom Code Migration and ABAP SAP Help documentation.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To chat with the assistant about SAP S/4HANA simplification items and Custom Code Migration, just start asking topic-related questions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Code proposal for code adaptation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;coming in SAP S/4HANA 2025 FPS01, John will soon receive in addition of the step-by-step description of how to solve the ATC findings provided currently by ATC Explain functionality and a custom code adaptation automatically.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SimonaM_0-1757704750948.png" style="width: 906px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313685iB65B0C26D2DE969E/image-dimensions/906x562/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="906" height="562" role="button" title="SimonaM_0-1757704750948.png" alt="SimonaM_0-1757704750948.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777519411"&gt;The Complete ABAP Lifecycle Revolution&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;John's journey now encompasses the entire ABAP development and transformation lifecycle:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build new cloud applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData UI Service from Scratch Wizard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implement intelligent business logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP Predict Business Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrate seamlessly&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extend dynamically&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility AI Assistant in SAP Cloud ERP Public&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transform existing solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant for RISE&amp;nbsp;in SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;John tells now to everyone: "Six months ago, I was struggling with syntax," John explains to his manager. "Today, I'm generating complete applications with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData UI Service from Scratch Wizard&lt;/STRONG&gt;, implementing business logic with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RAP Predict Business Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;, consuming services with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;, extending solutions with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and leading our S/4HANA migration with the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– all through natural language conversations."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The impact is transformative:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Application Development&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Dramatically faster with&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP Cloud Application Generation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Logic Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Massive reduction in development time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migration Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;: From weeks to hours using&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Code Migration AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Significantly less code required for side-by-side extension scenarios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581005906"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The AI Revolution Accelerates – &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-chapter-2/ba-p/14210568" target="_self"&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/A&gt; Awaits!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;John's incredible transformation is just the beginning as we enter the next phase of ABAP AI evolution. Even more exciting, SAP is pioneering a revolutionary&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;side-by-side ABAP AI service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;that will bring full AI capabilities to older SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition releases, enabling immediate access to new AI innovations without waiting for upgrades or support packages across hybrid landscapes. Get ready for&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TechEd 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;where all the groundbreaking details of this hybrid AI service will be unveiled – the future of ABAP development is about to get even more transformative!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Ready to evolve your ABAP development approach? Check out the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-ai/generative-ai-in-abap-cloud/generative-ai-in-abap-cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;hands-on documentation in SAP Help&lt;/A&gt; and join the growing community redefining what's possible in enterprise development.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-ai-revolution-accelerates-the-abap-developer-who-built-enterprise-apps/ba-p/14216073"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T21:50:13.192000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-hobbies-series-mind-your-step-walking-and-hiking/bc-p/14216099#M331</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community Hobbies Series: Mind Your Step (Walking and Hiking)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T21:51:28.968000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>moshenaveh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/29</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/126934"&gt;@MichelleMachado&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Beautiful place! Have you been there? In two weeks from today I’m expected &lt;SPAN&gt;to be in my mother’s home and I’ll look for pictures from that trip. Then I only had stills camera&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":beaming_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😁&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-hobbies-series-mind-your-step-walking-and-hiking/bc-p/14216099#M331"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T21:51:28.968000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/onboarding-user-group-discussions-sunset/qaa-p/14216102#M47961</id>
    <title>Re: Onboarding User Group Discussions Sunset?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T22:05:24.667000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>paddykoltsaklis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/37649</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I have messaged the help admin and contacted our CSMs as this is a huge loss of resources for customers.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/onboarding-user-group-discussions-sunset/qaa-p/14216102#M47961"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T22:05:24.667000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/cash-flow-report-with-document-types/qaa-p/14216103#M255127</id>
    <title>Re: Cash-Flow Report with Document Types</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T22:09:27.105000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eduardo_Lombard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/134189</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Meliskulbay,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I understood that you want to use FI document type to segregate amounts between cash flow statement rows. For me, the best way to create a cash flow statement is using reporting rules and even if you add FI document type in ACDOCU you won't be able to use it in reporting rules. This is the reason that I suggested to use transaction types (subitems)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/cash-flow-report-with-document-types/qaa-p/14216103#M255127"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T22:09:27.105000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crforvs-stuck-forever-on-13-0-26-type-initializer-for-crystaldecisions/qaa-p/14216104#M4926185</id>
    <title>Re: CRforVS stuck forever on 13.0.26? (type initializer f...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T22:09:51.026000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DonWilliams</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121895</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Andre,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Good find... Beware that 4.5 framework is no longer supported, 4.7 or 4.8 only now due to Microsoft deprecating 4.5. Check the Platform's PDF for details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check your App properties and be sure you are specifying 4.7 or 4.8 framework and don't use AnyCPU, specify x64, much safer to do this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That is why the main BOE products stopped using MSIExec it install the products, Microsoft just never "cleaned" up using the uninstall function. BOE uses a MSI file per dll, sort of, the same thing Microsoft does. Years ago someone in Support created a batch file to uninstall COM dll's, before .NET. To uninstall .NET assemblies you need to use the GACUtil app and manually remove them if you really want them gone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also note that file belongs to Apache and is used for debugging .NET applications, I believe it's a requirement of Visual Studio .net Applications, but like you I'm not sure of the details as to why:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DonWilliams_0-1757707873369.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313707i5987F39B2834AA4D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DonWilliams_0-1757707873369.png" alt="DonWilliams_0-1757707873369.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I see both are x86 versions, CR may be thunking to x64 platform. I'll check with DEV if there is a 64 bit version.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SO I'm not sure why the X64 MSI package didn't install the log4net file, but like you suggested something in your project may be redirecting it to an unknown location. You can use ORCA to browse the MSI's.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I don't have a PC I can test the MSI installer on but it should be here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;C:\Program Files (x86)\SAP BusinessObjects\Crystal Reports for .NET Framework 4.0\Common\SAP BusinessObjects Enterprise XI 4.0\win64_x64\dotnet\iPoint&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To sum up:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log4net is an Apache dll for logging various parts in Visual Studio, not sure but I think it's legacy part of CR for VS or could&amp;nbsp; be a dependency in Visual Studio .NET projects... Like a lot of 3rd party dependencies SAP includes them due to version specific hooks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Set your project to 4.7 or 4.8 Framework&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check your applications Project file, it sometimes has redirects pointing to various locations and versions, I was hooked into this one time after upgrading my project after upgrading my may test app, VS didn't update the file completely. Drove me nuts why it wouldn't build or run...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I always suggest when installing CR for VS on your Development PC to always install the 32 bit, won't be a problem end of this year due to SAP no longer building x86 runtime. You will be able to set your project to x86 mode but CR will use the x64 runtime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks again and have a great day&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crforvs-stuck-forever-on-13-0-26-type-initializer-for-crystaldecisions/qaa-p/14216104#M4926185"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T22:09:51.026000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/problem-with-activation-of-business-function-bs-sets-are-not-activated/qaq-p/14216112</id>
    <title>Problem with activation of Business function (BS sets are not activated automatically)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T22:22:18.893000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Olj</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/185016</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Good day, we have new fresh system S/4HANA 2023 FPS03.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After initial configuration of system we tried to activate business function EA-HR (one of the main BF's) via standard SFW5 transaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But activation was not successful,&amp;nbsp; we got errors:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Olj_0-1757706847766.png" style="width: 431px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313704i00281A5B50633FC2/image-dimensions/431x262/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="431" height="262" role="button" title="Olj_0-1757706847766.png" alt="Olj_0-1757706847766.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;in text:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Error when comparing BC Set EA-HR-AKH with customizing tables&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Postprocessing necessary when upgrade/update completed&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Activation of BC Set EA-HR-AKH terminated&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Postprocessing necessary when upgrade/update completed&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Error when comparing BC Set EA-HR-IMG with customizing tables&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Postprocessing necessary when upgrade/update completed&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Activation of BC Set EA-HR-IMG terminated&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Postprocessing necessary when upgrade/update completed&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Error when comparing BC Set EA-HR-MENU with customizing tables&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Postprocessing necessary when upgrade/update completed&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Activation of BC Set EA-HR-MENU terminated&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Postprocessing necessary when upgrade/update completed"&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If we check problem BC set EA-HR-AKH in SCPR20 transaction, we can see no activations logs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Olj_1-1757707835523.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313706i4F7CA04AC540C6A8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Olj_1-1757707835523.png" alt="Olj_1-1757707835523.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looks like SFW5 didn't try to activate it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SFW_BROWSER shows next:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Olj_2-1757707937031.png" style="width: 583px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313709i6A297943881E6550/image-dimensions/583x201/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="583" height="201" role="button" title="Olj_2-1757707937031.png" alt="Olj_2-1757707937031.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have double checked all prerequisites:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. User has SAP_ALL auth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Client role is 'Customizing'.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. System modifiable (SE06).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also&amp;nbsp; Sapnotes&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2313533/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2313533 - SFW5: Termination of activation process&lt;/A&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0002313533" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2313533 - SFW5: Termination of activation process,&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2770392" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2770392 - SFW_BROWSER: This object is switched inconsistently&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;have been checked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you have any suggestions please help me.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;PS: Sorry for text formatting, I didn't find how to remove spaces between lines in new editor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/problem-with-activation-of-business-function-bs-sets-are-not-activated/qaq-p/14216112"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T22:22:18.893000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-checkin-url-attachment-with-api-cv-attachment-srv/qaq-p/14216113</id>
    <title>How To CheckIn URL Attachment with API_CV_ATTACHMENT_SRV CreateUrlAsAttachment</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T22:22:31.220000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>k_sood</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/630456</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this API I can successfully create URL Original in the Document Info Record, However that created URL Original is not checked In, How to do CheckIn with this API ? I dont see any parameter in this API to do CheckIn ? Is there any Other API which could do CheckIn as well ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enclosed the Successful Call with which the URL Original was created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapt0400.sbb.ch:44300/sap/opu/odata/sap/API_CV_ATTACHMENT_SRV/CreateUrlAsAttachment?BusinessObjectTypeName='DRAW'&amp;amp;LinkedSAPObjectKey='RNA000000000000005000000002701000'&amp;amp;Url='https://dmstest.sbb.ch/OTCS/llisapi.dll/open/48469056'&amp;amp;UrlDescription='LinkToRmsOriginal'&amp;amp;MIMEType='text/url" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://server:44300/sap/opu/odata/sap/API_CV_ATTACHMENT_SRV/CreateUrlAsAttachment?BusinessObjectTypeName='DRAW'&amp;amp;LinkedSAPObjectKey='ART000000000000005000000002701000'&amp;amp;Url='https://test.com'&amp;amp;UrlDescription='Link'&amp;amp;MIMEType='text/url&lt;/A&gt;'&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As it can be seen in the Screenshot below, the Original was not locked, which means it is not checked In.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any Hint, how can i achieve this Lock along with the creation of the URL attachment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-12 221631.png" style="width: 771px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313711i78206B8C0993CEBD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-12 221631.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-12 221631.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ketan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-checkin-url-attachment-with-api-cv-attachment-srv/qaq-p/14216113"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T22:22:31.220000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-discussions/ea19-document-date-check/td-p/14216128</id>
    <title>EA19 Document date check</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T22:57:37.780000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>christian_arias</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/790622</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello experts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a customer requierment for do not allow document date be greater than current date in EA19 transaction. Is there a standard way to apply this check?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_arias_0-1757710564444.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313724i00E6094995650B49/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="christian_arias_0-1757710564444.png" alt="christian_arias_0-1757710564444.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Christian.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-discussions/ea19-document-date-check/td-p/14216128"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T22:57:37.780000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-a-archive-job-in-sap-pipo-for-a-specific-interface/qaa-p/14216132#M4926187</id>
    <title>Re: How to create a archive job in SAP PIPO for a specifi...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:06:00.479000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marksmyth</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/97409</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes! Refer to&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SUPPORT_CONTENT/xi/3362976544.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;PI Troubleshooting Tips: Message persistence&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;"note: if you are configuring a custom Archive Job, it is really important that you use the Rules option to specify messages from particular interfaces to send to the Archive. If you configure a custom Archive Job with no Rules, then every version, of every message of every interface is sent to the Archive store"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also view the help pages&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_NETWEAVER_750/5cf7d2de571a45cc81f91261668b7361/b8ca9b0c2e2c46579126fcf2d913968f.html?version=7.5.16" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Background Job Types&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_NETWEAVER_750/5cf7d2de571a45cc81f91261668b7361/48b2e0006b156ff4e10000000a42189b.html?version=7.5.16" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Defining Rules&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for more details.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;BR /&gt;Mark&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-a-archive-job-in-sap-pipo-for-a-specific-interface/qaa-p/14216132#M4926187"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:06:00.479000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crystal-reports-2020-auto-resize/qaa-p/14216134#M4926188</id>
    <title>Re: Crystal reports 2020 : Auto resize ?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:09:29.829000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DonWilliams</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121895</uri>
    </author>
    <content>That would be a great enhancement request, unfortunately I no longer work for SAP, retired now, so I can't access their Enhancement Request system, requires a S-User ID to submit one. I'll pass your request onto one of the Rep's and see if he cna do it for You.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crystal-reports-2020-auto-resize/qaa-p/14216134#M4926188"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:09:29.829000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/no-aparece-el-concepto-38b-mx-cambios-deducciones-de-pr%C3%A9stamos-infonavit/qaa-p/14216138#M47962</id>
    <title>Re: No aparece el concepto /38B - [MX] Cambios: Deduccion...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:22:08.384000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Moni22</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2042706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hola Rogelio, ayer hubo una actualizacion en la nota, sobre la regla MX14&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Delete the XPDD schema and X024 rule and change the call of PRART payroll&lt;BR /&gt;function to use MX14 payroll rule instead of X014 payroll rule&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Puedes validar si eso te ayuda.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/no-aparece-el-concepto-38b-mx-cambios-deducciones-de-pr%C3%A9stamos-infonavit/qaa-p/14216138#M47962"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:22:08.384000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/easier-integration-of-sap-cis-with-bdc-sac-dsp-bdcc-with-a-new-identity/ba-p/14165026</id>
    <title>Easier Integration of SAP CIS with BDC (SAC, DSP, BDCC) with a new Identity Provider Administration</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:22:51.740000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JimmyYang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121467</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1736045447"&gt;Overview&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services (CIS) are a group of services which enable you to integrate identity and access management between systems. The goal is to provide a seamless single sign-on experience across systems while ensuring that system and data access are secure.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CIS provides several out-of-the-box features that your BDC Components and Non-BDC SAC/Datasphere do not have.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new IDP Admin tool will be turned on sometime in Q3. We will have a phased deployment strategy on different landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1539531942"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1343018437"&gt;Why should we integrate with IAS?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integration with SAP CIS will solve many of the identity challenges facing BDC and Non-BDC tenants. Over the years, we've had a number of influence requests asking for features related to identity in SAC and Datasphere. With a deeper integration with CIS, we can tackle many of those influence requests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are just some of the benefits you will receive with integration with CIS:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ability to bypass SSO&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Moves the Groups=sac requirement onto IAS, instead of your corporate IDP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports multiple corporate Identity Providers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Single IAS can be used for SuccessFactors and then BDC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improved Monitoring and Auditing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improved Security in which you can use SAML or OpenID Connect&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Future proofing as most enhancements to authentication will be made to IAS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;To make it easier to "bundle" with CIS, we have updated our Identity Provisioning Administration Tool (IDP-Admin).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;In this blog, I'll show you how to do this step by step&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1146504932"&gt;Getting Started&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Persona: Administrator - You are the System Owner of tenant (SAC, DSP or BDCC)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Terminology: When referring to BDC Components or BDC, we are referring to SAP Analytics Cloud, Datasphere and Databricks. Although our example is coming out of SAP Analytics Cloud.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The bundling tool is also available for Non-BDC SAC and Datasphere. In general, you may see this grouped in with BDC as the workflows are the same.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-949991427"&gt;How to do it?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the below example, I'll cover the most common scenario our customers are dealing with. Your SAC or Datasphere is currently configured with your Corporate IDP directly.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1011643360"&gt;CIS Integration with your Corporate Identity Provider&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;In tenants where you are already using your corporate IDP with SAC/DSP/BDCC or you intend on using your corporate IDP, follow these steps.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to System &amp;gt; Administration &amp;gt; Security and scroll down to click on Launch Identity Provider Administration Tool&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_0-1754687513826.png" style="width: 702px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/298794i12BCDEB28BAC1F3B/image-dimensions/702x634?v=v2" width="702" height="634" role="button" title="JimmyYang_0-1754687513826.png" alt="JimmyYang_0-1754687513826.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Logon to Identity Provider Administration Tool (IDP Admin) using the System Owner user. If you don't have an account, click Register to create a new account.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once logged in, you will see a tile representing the BDC Component (either SAC, DSP or BDCC).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In our example, we have an SAC system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_0-1757709917518.png" style="width: 789px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313720iF69F7369D41B26DC/image-dimensions/789x558/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="789" height="558" role="button" title="JimmyYang_0-1757709917518.png" alt="JimmyYang_0-1757709917518.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the context menu, Repair IdP will allow you to revert back to the default IDP or update the IDP metadata.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;For bundling, please select Add SAP Cloud Identity Services&lt;BR /&gt;** Note down the Tenant Type as this will be important in a few steps **&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The next screen will show you a list of all CIS tenants that you have deployed. You are entitled to Production and Test CIS tenants. If an IAS tenant is already used by another tenant like SuccessFactors or Ariba, this will appear on the list.&amp;nbsp; In addition, if you have purchased an IAS separately, it will also appear on this list.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_2-1754688240390.png" style="width: 930px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/298796i58364C49DC7F1E0D/image-dimensions/930x321?v=v2" width="930" height="321" role="button" title="JimmyYang_2-1754688240390.png" alt="JimmyYang_2-1754688240390.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As a best practice, it is recommended you select the IAS tenant that matches your tenant type from the Tile (in Step 3)&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you do not have any CIS provisioned yet, the Provision New SAP Cloud Identity Services Tenant button is enabled. This will provision a IAS which you can then bundle to.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Input the System Owner details&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_3-1754688394301.png" style="width: 892px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/298798i8D37AFA1F196B89D/image-dimensions/892x348?v=v2" width="892" height="348" role="button" title="JimmyYang_3-1754688394301.png" alt="JimmyYang_3-1754688394301.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The last step is a summary of actions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_6-1755012277781.png" style="width: 908px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299987i62014484865CC276/image-dimensions/908x295?v=v2" width="908" height="295" role="button" title="JimmyYang_6-1755012277781.png" alt="JimmyYang_6-1755012277781.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Click Finish&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CIS will be provisioned with your current tenant. This step does NOT change over the authentication source quite yet.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_2-1754690127808.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/298801i403F51C4063CAFB3/image-dimensions/800x148?v=v2" width="800" height="148" role="button" title="JimmyYang_2-1754690127808.png" alt="JimmyYang_2-1754690127808.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Success!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_0-1754944055022.png" style="width: 795px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299507iC1DF097AACF32407/image-dimensions/795x153?v=v2" width="795" height="153" role="button" title="JimmyYang_0-1754944055022.png" alt="JimmyYang_0-1754944055022.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;Clicking Continue will bring you to the final set up stage which is to validate and turn on authentication. In our case, since we are planning on integration our corporate IDP solution, we will click Close.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log into CIS and go to Applications &amp;amp; Resources &amp;gt; Applications. You will see a new entry representing the BDC tenant that was just bundled.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;** Note although the application has been created and some pre-configuration has been done, the authentication has not switched over to IAS yet. **&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_0-1754693677802.png" style="width: 887px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/298804i41A813B7459C3587/image-dimensions/887x468?v=v2" width="887" height="468" role="button" title="JimmyYang_0-1754693677802.png" alt="JimmyYang_0-1754693677802.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The next step is an important step because we are going to use the same corporate IdP as before. To do this, follow these steps here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/create-corporate-idp-in-administration-console?version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/create-corporate-idp-in-administration-console?version=Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure that the Application's default authenticating Identity Provider is set to the corporate identity provider&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_0-1755015229690.png" style="width: 863px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300017iC06471C80253E52F/image-dimensions/863x82?v=v2" width="863" height="82" role="button" title="JimmyYang_0-1755015229690.png" alt="JimmyYang_0-1755015229690.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check the Corporate Identity Providers in IAS to make sure "&lt;SPAN&gt;Use Identity Authentication user store" is enabled. This will make sure that the assertions contain the data needed by SAC/DSP/BDCC&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Now that you have configured your corporate IdP, it's time to finish the configuration and switch over the authentication.&lt;BR /&gt;Go back to IDP Admin and then go to the Tile.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You can see the tile still says it is pending. Simply click on the&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select an attribute type (default Email), provide the subject name identifier and select dynamic user creation if desired.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_0-1755011521066.png" style="width: 891px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299979iFC6E9EAD229BC035/image-dimensions/891x441?v=v2" width="891" height="441" role="button" title="JimmyYang_0-1755011521066.png" alt="JimmyYang_0-1755011521066.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;**Note: Dynamic User creation will create new users during the logon time.&lt;BR /&gt;For instance, I send a story to Sarah in SAC. Sarah has never used SAC before. She clicks on the link and she is prompted for her corporate portal login. A SAC user is created for Sarah and her user will now appear in System &amp;gt; Users. Sarah is now able to view the story.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The next step requires you open a new tab in incognito mode and use the validation URL. Make sure any existing Incognito windows signed into SAC are closed before opening the new one.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_1-1755011585094.png" style="width: 891px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299980i204B38D73383C4B5/image-dimensions/891x283?v=v2" width="891" height="283" role="button" title="JimmyYang_1-1755011585094.png" alt="JimmyYang_1-1755011585094.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Log onto the tenant and then you should see:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_2-1755011662025.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299981i841E4E2A57CB186C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="JimmyYang_2-1755011662025.png" alt="JimmyYang_2-1755011662025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;Close the tab&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go back to the previous window and select validate login:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_3-1755011714357.png" style="width: 869px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299982i8144CBB90837D113/image-dimensions/869x276?v=v2" width="869" height="276" role="button" title="JimmyYang_3-1755011714357.png" alt="JimmyYang_3-1755011714357.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review the settings and then click Finish&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_7-1755012299882.png" style="width: 868px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299988i600BE6C3406CCF03/image-dimensions/868x282?v=v2" width="868" height="282" role="button" title="JimmyYang_7-1755012299882.png" alt="JimmyYang_7-1755012299882.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The following success message should appear:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_5-1755012038530.png" style="width: 591px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299985i53C76A9937F9D5C9/image-dimensions/591x164?v=v2" width="591" height="164" role="button" title="JimmyYang_5-1755012038530.png" alt="JimmyYang_5-1755012038530.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The tile has now been updated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JimmyYang_8-1755012438529.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/299989iB5D97B56CCE32DB7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="JimmyYang_8-1755012438529.png" alt="JimmyYang_8-1755012438529.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You have now completed the bundling exercise. You can now take advantage of the amazing features that IAS brings. Find all the documentation here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-686047136"&gt;Quick Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Q: I have set up my corporate IDP, but I want to bypass SSO to log into SAC or Datasphere. How do I do that?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A: Use Conditional Authentication in IAS for the application. Create a rule specifically for a email domain or a group to use the Identity Authentication (local IAS user) instead of the corporate IDP.&amp;nbsp; More details &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/configure-conditional-authentication-for-application" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Q: How do I set up multiple Corporate IDP's?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A: Add a second IDP through IAS &amp;gt; Identity Providers &amp;gt; Corporate Identity Providers. After that, in the IAS application, add conditional authentication to support multiple IDP's based on email domain or groups.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Q: Does having multiple Corporate IDPs impact licensing for SAC?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A: No it should not impact licensing as the license thresholds are based on SAC Users that are created in the system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Q: How will a greenfield situation work where a tenant is new and has no users&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A: The steps for greenfield will nearly be the same. At a high level, you would still go to IDP Admin and trigger the bundling. After the bundling step is done, you can configure the corporate IDP or just choose to leave it IAS as the main identity provider.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/easier-integration-of-sap-cis-with-bdc-sac-dsp-bdcc-with-a-new-identity/ba-p/14165026"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:22:51.740000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-download-and-from-where-sap-bo-3-1-installers-for-server-and-client/qaa-p/14216141#M4926189</id>
    <title>Re: How to download and from where SAP BO 3.1 Installers...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:23:55.445000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eduardo_Florian</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1485330</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Joe Peters, thanks for your response .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. The only messages that I could get, appear in a csv file created bt the tool :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Column Result: "The wid report can not be created"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Column WorkAround: "Eliminate passowrd if is enabled"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Column Errortext : "The document can not be read"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Column Cause: "The BusinessObjects or Desktop Intelligence Document can not be opened"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Where can I get the ful installers for BO 3.1 SP3 or BO 4.1 ? Because in SAP support download area&amp;nbsp; I can only see the Updates or fixes , I mean there are no full installers to download. only the fixes / Updates&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-download-and-from-where-sap-bo-3-1-installers-for-server-and-client/qaa-p/14216141#M4926189"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:23:55.445000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/2025-update-alternatives-to-scope-item-2jd-fiori-analytical-apps-for/qaa-p/14216144#M4227068</id>
    <title>Re: 2025 Update: Alternatives to Scope Item 2JD (Fiori An...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:26:06.474000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello Sergio, glad to have been able to help you. Best of success in your project. Do not hesitate to reach out should you have further questions. Best regards</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/2025-update-alternatives-to-scope-item-2jd-fiori-analytical-apps-for/qaa-p/14216144#M4227068"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:26:06.474000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cji3-report-alternative-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/qaq-p/14216147</id>
    <title>CJI3 report alternative in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:32:49.540000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition we use transaction CJI3 to track our project related costs. We need a similar report or app in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cji3-report-alternative-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/qaq-p/14216147"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:32:49.540000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cji3-report-alternative-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/qaa-p/14216148#M4227070</id>
    <title>Re: CJI3 report alternative in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public E...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:32:56.821000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;App Project Cost Report (F2513) is the nearest to CJI3. Please refer to SAP Help &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/f369b2eff700401494ba6e7c9a573288/e0ef91efe26d4a27be7df2a53d8302b3.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/f369b2eff700401494ba6e7c9a573288/e0ef91efe26d4a27be7df2a53d8302b3.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use View Details to drilldown to Project Cost Report - Line Items (F2538).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cji3-report-alternative-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/qaa-p/14216148#M4227070"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:32:56.821000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/issues-updating-journal-entry/qaq-p/14216150</id>
    <title>Issues updating  journal entry</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:36:33.726000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JackN11</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253554</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Hello experts,&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;While trying to post this Journal entry, I received the following error. Can someone guide me on what to do? See screenshot below for more details. Thank you for your support.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JackN11_0-1757712803030.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313736iECC7CC7DD2E1CA2C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="JackN11_0-1757712803030.png" alt="JackN11_0-1757712803030.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Jack&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/issues-updating-journal-entry/qaq-p/14216150"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:36:33.726000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/journal-document-upload-error/qaq-p/14216153</id>
    <title>Journal Document upload Error</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:42:49.400000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JackN11</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253554</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Dear community experts&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;While trying to upload a payment document on the journal entry, the system produced an error requesting customisation. See error message below.&amp;nbsp; Please see my attached screenshot. Does anyone know how I can go&amp;nbsp;about this?&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="JackN11_0-1757713273313.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313738i52FA8D6CBF305726/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="JackN11_0-1757713273313.png" alt="JackN11_0-1757713273313.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Jack&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/journal-document-upload-error/qaq-p/14216153"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:42:49.400000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fiscal-year-is-closed-for-asset-accounting-message-number-faa-post403/qaq-p/14216154</id>
    <title>“Fiscal year is closed for asset accounting.” Message Number: FAA_POST403</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:43:35.939000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When trying to post into special period 13/2024 I am getting error: &lt;EM&gt;“Fiscal year is closed for asset accounting.” Message Number: FAA_POST403&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fiscal-year-is-closed-for-asset-accounting-message-number-faa-post403/qaq-p/14216154"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:43:35.939000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fiscal-year-is-closed-for-asset-accounting-message-number-faa-post403/qaa-p/14216155#M4227072</id>
    <title>Re: “Fiscal year is closed for asset accounting.” Message...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:43:43.239000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In order to post into special period 13/2024, normal periods 1-12 should be closed and special adjustment period 13 should be open in Manage Posting Periods app.&lt;BR /&gt;In Asset Accounting you also need 2024 open.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fiscal-year-is-closed-for-asset-accounting-message-number-faa-post403/qaa-p/14216155#M4227072"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:43:43.239000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/we20-id-is-not-given-in-agent-filed-still-getting-idoc-messages-in-inbox/m-p/14216206#M2042460</id>
    <title>Re: WE20: ID is not given in Agent filed, still getting IDOC messages in INBOX?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:47:34.280000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JayaPrakash96</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1801777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;How can we revert the OYEA settings, if not needed..?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/we20-id-is-not-given-in-agent-filed-still-getting-idoc-messages-in-inbox/m-p/14216206#M2042460"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:47:34.280000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-create-a-new-ship-to-address-and-assign-it-to-delivery-on-creation/bc-p/14216243#M175442</id>
    <title>Re: How to create a new ship-to address and assign it to delivery on creation using exit in ECC?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:49:00.638000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shiva_Ram</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171920</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you check exit&amp;nbsp;EXIT_SAPLV09A_001 (enhancement&amp;nbsp;V09A0001 ) of any help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-create-a-new-ship-to-address-and-assign-it-to-delivery-on-creation/bc-p/14216243#M175442"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:49:00.638000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-message-finoc165-and-finoc297-manage-cost-centers-f1443a/qaa-p/14216244#M4227073</id>
    <title>Re: Error message: FINOC165 and FINOC297 - Manage Cost Ce...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T23:49:58.568000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gustavo28</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1987006</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Dear Lakshmipathi, Thank you very much for your extremely detailed and clear response! I truly appreciate the time and effort dedicated to explaining why it's not possible to directly change the Profit Center in S/4HANA due to its status as time-dependent master data, and the system's need to maintain the historical link, even after reversals. This completely clarifies my doubts about the ineffectiveness of reversals in this specific case. Your elucidation regarding the SAP Notes (3477968, 3514994, 3567063) and the difference in message control availability between FPS01 and FPS02 was particularly helpful. I now perfectly understand why I couldn't find those messages in our OBA5 transaction. The three options presented are very valuable and provide a clear path forward: Option A – Profit Center Reorganization: I understand this is the recommended method, and I will investigate the FAGL_REORG* process further. I had previously tried via the app, but without success, so I will attempt it via t-code. Option B – Create a new cost center: This is an alternative that can be considered depending on the scope. I had already suggested this workaround to the client previously. Option C – Upgrade to FPS02 or specific SAP Notes: I will discuss with my team the feasibility of an upgrade or requesting a targeted correction for FPS01. I had also already created an SAP Note for this, and I will inform you as soon as I receive a response. This comprehensive guidance is exactly what I needed to move forward with the solution. Thank you again for your invaluable assistance, kindness, and expertise. Best regards, Acacio</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-message-finoc165-and-finoc297-manage-cost-centers-f1443a/qaa-p/14216244#M4227073"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T23:49:58.568000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/capacity-requirement-kpi-not-showing-in-schedule-labor-app-in-sap-dmc/qaq-p/14216298</id>
    <title>Capacity Requirement KPI Not Showing in Schedule Labor App in SAP DMC</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:09:29.967000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMEDAMINE_MOUNA30</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2183492</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1867780714" id="toc-hId-1889171644"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Digital+Manufacturing/pd-p/73555000100800001492" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="533-1"&gt;SAP Digital Manufacturing&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dear All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m currently working with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud integrated with SAP Digital Manufacturing&lt;/STRONG&gt; and faced an issue in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Schedule Labor&lt;/STRONG&gt; app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As shown in the screenshot below, the &lt;STRONG&gt;KPI&amp;nbsp;Capacity Requirement&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;stays at 0 hrs. even though:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Work center and shift are maintained.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Operators are assigned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Production orders are dispatched.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Demand (Planned) and Demand (Scheduled) values are visible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Work center allocation is also showing values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MOHAMEDAMINE_MOUNA30_0-1757714743950.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313877i134D4A5EB9A14EAC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MOHAMEDAMINE_MOUNA30_0-1757714743950.png" alt="MOHAMEDAMINE_MOUNA30_0-1757714743950.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Still, the &lt;STRONG&gt;Capacity Requirement KPI&lt;/STRONG&gt; remains 0 hrs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone faced this issue before?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What could prevent &lt;STRONG&gt;Capacity Requirement&lt;/STRONG&gt; from being calculated?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a specific setting in the work center, routing, or integration that I might be missing?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any guidance would be greatly appreciated &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":folded_hands:"&gt;🙏&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/capacity-requirement-kpi-not-showing-in-schedule-labor-app-in-sap-dmc/qaq-p/14216298"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:09:29.967000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hardware-os-from-rhel-8-1-to-rhel-8-8-in-the-cluster-environment-in-aws/ba-p/14216299</id>
    <title>SAP Hardware : OS from RHEL 8.1 to RHEL 8.8 in the cluster environment in AWS</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:17:41.816000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rammi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1619550</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The purpose of this document is to outline the steps taken to update the OS from RHEL 8.1 to RHEL 8.8 in the cluster environment in AWS&amp;nbsp; . Detailed steps include the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Take an AMI of each AWS instance being upgraded.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SPECIFIC FOR Individual system – MAKE SURE TO BACKUP THE FOLLOWING FILE – &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;/lib/ocf/resource.d/heartbeat/&amp;lt; Path for VIP&amp;gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stop PAS and AAS&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sapcontrol -nr 0 -function StopSystem&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stop the app cluster&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;pcs cluster stop --all&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stop the DB cluster&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;pcs cluster stop --all&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Initiate the OS upgrade on the app cluster – both nodes can be done at the same time.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;yum --releaserver=8.8 update&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Initiate the OS upgrade on the db cluster – both nodes can be done at the same time.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;yum --releaserver=8.8 update&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Update the /etc/yum/vars/releasever from 8.1 to 8.8 on all servers after the upgrade is completed.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;vi /etc/yum/vars/releasever&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;8.8&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;wq!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reboot the app cluster hosts ONCE upgrade is complete on &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;BOTH&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; servers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reboot the DB cluster hosts ONCE upgrade is complete on &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;BOTH&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; servers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;USE THIS STEP FOR&amp;nbsp; CLUSTER ONLY &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once both db and app servers are back online post-upgrade. Stop the cluster on both db and app. You will see the IP resource is failing to start.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; pcs cluster stop –all&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Update the contents of the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;/lib/ocf/resource.d/heartbeat/aws-vpc-move-ip&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; file taken in step 2 with what you see in the backup file you have (specifically these parameters found at the top of the file). Stage values shown below (PROD WILL BE DIFFERENT for the first parameter).&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; OCF_RESKEY_routing_table_role_default=”arn:aws:iam::885497102981:role/coreerp-tradenext-ec2-role”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; OCF_RESKEY_lookup_type_default=”NetworkInterfaceId”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After the file is updated on all nodes, start the cluster and the IP resource should assign properly to each node.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; pcs cluster start --all&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validate the DB cluster and App Cluster start in a proper state.&amp;nbsp;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;pcs status&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cluster Status BEFORE UPDATE -&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;DB&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_108-1757714627049.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313857iAE643E8743CA49D0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_108-1757714627049.png" alt="Rammi_108-1757714627049.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;App&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_109-1757714627093.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313858i7F5CE32D9A1ED982/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_109-1757714627093.png" alt="Rammi_109-1757714627093.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the AMI is good and the cluster is stopped, perform the steps below in each server.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;pcs cluster stop –all&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;yum --releasever=8.8 update&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;vi /etc/yum/vars/releasever&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;8.8&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stop App Cluster&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_110-1757714627101.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313856i9DB2BDE310307158/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_110-1757714627101.png" alt="Rammi_110-1757714627101.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Initiate OS Minor Upgrade -&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;yum --releaseserver=8.8 update&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAS 01&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_111-1757714627102.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313859iA083110689ADEDC4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_111-1757714627102.png" alt="Rammi_111-1757714627102.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_112-1757714627124.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313860iA6A09870AAB69D4A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_112-1757714627124.png" alt="Rammi_112-1757714627124.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_113-1757714627159.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313861i955564D7A76279CB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_113-1757714627159.png" alt="Rammi_113-1757714627159.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_114-1757714627183.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313863i822B21A95CD35950/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_114-1757714627183.png" alt="Rammi_114-1757714627183.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_115-1757714627213.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313864i228A34DDE776010B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_115-1757714627213.png" alt="Rammi_115-1757714627213.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Run the update on Node 2 :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_116-1757714627216.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313862i197C7A6C71E8CA63/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_116-1757714627216.png" alt="Rammi_116-1757714627216.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_117-1757714627239.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313867i18BEF6F99805D23B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_117-1757714627239.png" alt="Rammi_117-1757714627239.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_118-1757714627245.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313865iA8B333CFC7EA3F9C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_118-1757714627245.png" alt="Rammi_118-1757714627245.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reboot both servers. &amp;nbsp;Took - 5 min - App Cluster is good -&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;DB CLUSTER – Put the cluster in maintenance mode and repeat the steps as in App server .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;pcs property set maintenance-mode=true&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;After OS Update&amp;nbsp; : Take the cluster out of maintenance mode.&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;pcs property set maintenance-mode=false&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_121-1757714627281.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313870i0A24792EFAAE6FC0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_121-1757714627281.png" alt="Rammi_121-1757714627281.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Testing Cluster to make sure it works prior to OS Upgrade - Must wait for MEM to unload due to defunct WP regarding index server.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mem Unloading - Node 1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_122-1757714627295.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313871i822C04A7DB8B007A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_122-1757714627295.png" alt="Rammi_122-1757714627295.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_123-1757714627317.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313874i2B99BADD2BF28789/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_123-1757714627317.png" alt="Rammi_123-1757714627317.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_124-1757714627323.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313872i70EFC1C444D58419/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_124-1757714627323.png" alt="Rammi_124-1757714627323.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cluster is communicating -&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_125-1757714627343.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313873i7A7B82DB8D0A5E50/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_125-1757714627343.png" alt="Rammi_125-1757714627343.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stop DB and Reboot OS&amp;nbsp; respective Hyperscale Console&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_126-1757714627363.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313876i2148485602060787/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_126-1757714627363.png" alt="Rammi_126-1757714627363.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Both Nodes are available after the reboot from AWS console&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rammi_127-1757714627375.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313875i66A876F4077D9B79/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rammi_127-1757714627375.png" alt="Rammi_127-1757714627375.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hardware-os-from-rhel-8-1-to-rhel-8-8-in-the-cluster-environment-in-aws/ba-p/14216299"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:17:41.816000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/journal-document-upload-error/qaa-p/14216302#M255130</id>
    <title>Re: Journal Document upload Error</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T01:27:00.561000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253554"&gt;@JackN11&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your message to the community. Let me walk you through it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The error you experience while maintaining storage category appears because the system cannot find a valid storage category configuration for attachments in your tenant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can resolve this by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to your Manage Solution, open the SSCUI for Define Document Types and Storage Categories. Here you must ensure a valid storage category is assigned for the type of attachment you are trying to upload. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/f369b2eff700401494ba6e7c9a573288/70414d95dcfe4f588032ddca36f5d7ec.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Documents&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Verify your content repository through SAP Document Managment Service. If none is assigned, then that is the cause of the error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For Journal entry attachments, SAP delivers default storage category. So, check if this is missing in your tenant. If it is, maintain it under the SSCUI mentioned earlier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note, in some tenants, this &lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/2717751" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;customizing&lt;/A&gt; is restricted. In that case, you must raise an SAP incident under the component XX-S4C-OPR-SRV and request SAP to activate or assign the missing storage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following links will provide more details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/f369b2eff700401494ba6e7c9a573288/70414d95dcfe4f588032ddca36f5d7ec.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Documents&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/2588128" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP KBA 2588128&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3404516" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP KBA 3404516&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. Happy to answer any further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/journal-document-upload-error/qaa-p/14216302#M255130"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T01:27:00.561000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/an-introduction-to-note-analyzer-tool/bc-p/14216303#M61808</id>
    <title>Re: An Introduction to Note Analyzer tool</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T01:31:27.429000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FrancN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3388</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello - where can I download the&amp;nbsp;note Analyzer NA_demo.xml? It's not attached to Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;3200109 - SNOTE : Note Analyzer.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Franc Nguyen&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/an-introduction-to-note-analyzer-tool/bc-p/14216303#M61808"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T01:31:27.429000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/issues-updating-journal-entry/qaa-p/14216304#M255131</id>
    <title>Re: Issues updating journal entry</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T01:39:30.058000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253554"&gt;@JackN11&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The G/L account 10053 is not defined in company code 0D00 means that the account you entered does not exist or is not assigned in the chart of account for the company code you are trying to use.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To resolve that issue, check the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;G/L Account must exist. To confirm, open the Manage G/L Account Master Data app, search for account 100053, if it does not exist then you must create it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the account exists in the chart of accounts but not for company code 0D00, you must extend it to that company code. Considering you are on the public cloud, you can do this in the manage G/L account master data app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Then make sure the account type and field status are valid for manual postings. If it is a reconciliation account for example for your customers or vendors, you cannot post it directly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consult &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0fa84c9d9c634132b7c4abb9ffdd8f06/34428754dccbe85ee10000000a44176d.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage G/L Account Master Data&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;amp; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0fa84c9d9c634132b7c4abb9ffdd8f06/f99d42d9afe140e1846c5f09d5923e2e.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Operating G/L Accounts&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. Happy to answer any further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/issues-updating-journal-entry/qaa-p/14216304#M255131"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T01:39:30.058000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/manage-incoming-payment-files-will-not-import-valid-records/qaa-p/14216305#M4227074</id>
    <title>Re: Manage Incoming Payment Files will not import valid r...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T01:53:18.589000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1481431"&gt;@P_Quiroz_23&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note, when you import BAI files, the system follows a restricted approach because it requires data integrity and consistency for your bank account management reconciliation. If your entry has no present account number in the bank account management, the file you try to upload will be rejected. This is to prevent incorrect processing that could lead to some financial discrepancies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently, SAP does not provide an option for you to import only the valid records and log invalid ones separately in this app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, you can consider the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Request your bank to adjust the BAI file records to only include known account numbers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alternatively, you can process the BAI files before importing them into SAP. Make sure you separate valid and invalid entries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Make sure you review the error logs that are generated during import to identify and correct wrong entries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the manual correction features provided by SAP to handle exception after you have attempted the import.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consult &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0c676015e0414931bdc9ebacd6eb2dff/9039b5f00eea4d588745ae986b85612c.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Payment Rejections&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/cdccca8e03d74101a0135863bc522b49/a427d8941fd2413bb80deb34c8fae5e3.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Importing Files Containing Notifications of Rejected Direct Debit Instructions&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. Happy to answer any further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/manage-incoming-payment-files-will-not-import-valid-records/qaa-p/14216305#M4227074"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T01:53:18.589000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/change-language-sap-s-4-hana-cloud-public/qaa-p/14216306#M62098</id>
    <title>Re: Change Language - SAP S/4 HANA Cloud Public</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T02:12:02.109000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1396921"&gt;@Joselubc&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is important to note that in public cloud modifying or adding national language follows a structured localization approach. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;There are currently 34 languages out-of-the-box delivered for around 60 countries by sap. That means for any additional or regional language like the one you seek; you cannot simply change or add it directly as you could in R/3 or on-premise systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Instead, SAP offers Localization as Self-Service capability. This includes a tool (CLT) which enables you to create or extend local versions to suit your business requirements. Therefore, allowing you to extend existing country localisations or create new local versions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Note that changes must be done in the scope configuration before you can activate it. Direct additional languages outside the one provided by SAP is limited to ensure you maintain consistency, comply with legal requirements and ensures upgradability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consult &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/language-import-in-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/13541149" target="_blank"&gt;Language Import in SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_Cloud_for_Customer_Payments/ff6a9746002a4910824cdf64621d718b/34c6f87aea774bae81227974ed0d1d07.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Determining Display Language&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-portal-service/sap-cloud-portal-service-on-cloud-foundry/supported-languages?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supported Languages&lt;/A&gt; for more details&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. Happy to answer any further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/change-language-sap-s-4-hana-cloud-public/qaa-p/14216306#M62098"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T02:12:02.109000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-public-cloud-professional-service-project-amount-total-update/qaa-p/14216307#M4227075</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud: Professional Service Project Amount...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T02:35:58.763000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2157420"&gt;@BryAguado&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The behaviour you mentioned is correct in S/4HANA Cloud. Please note that credit memos created even with reference to existing posted invoices may not update the project amount if the WBS element linked to the credit memo is included in the work package of your customer project. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The revenue substitution you are seeing is likely due to how your system determines the leading WBS element for revenue posting. In your case, the WBS element to which the credit memo posts are not directly tied to a work package. The mapping and structure of your project might provide answer to the issue. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Make sure the WBS elements you reference on the credit memo is part of the work package.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Then review your work package definition and make sure it includes all relevant WBS elements for revenue adjustment.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regarding the message in the billing log, it indicated that the system is deriving the revenue posting WBS from a substitution rule or standard logic. Check your project configuration, substitution rules or enhancement logic in the professional services are.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can display, edit and change credit memo requests in the Fiori or manage credit memo request app. This also includes the option to review item references and WBS assignments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If required, consider creating manual credit memo requests and reference the correct WBS package or reassigning WBS elements within your project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consult &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/5d19f357eb96be12e10000000a4450e5.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Customer and Internal Project Management&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/describing-the-receivables-management-process-in-sap-s-4hana/entering-customer-invoices-and-credit-memos_bab8086c-6165-4de6-92a3-4ae5e6b8ab2c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Entering Customer Invoices and Credit Memos&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. Happy to answer any further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-public-cloud-professional-service-project-amount-total-update/qaa-p/14216307#M4227075"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T02:35:58.763000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-estimate-the-capacity-unit-with-commerce-cloud-capacity-unit/bc-p/14216309#M14662</id>
    <title>Re: How to estimate the capacity unit with Commerce Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T02:42:27.944000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Taka_Kitazume47</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/468609</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/621729"&gt;@saket_chiluveru&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hibernation saves CU consumption. You can use an estimator and change a status of an environment as &lt;STRONG&gt;Hibernated&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to see estimation during hibernation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Taka_Kitazume47_0-1757724039695.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313880i9DAA666417377894/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Taka_Kitazume47_0-1757724039695.png" alt="Taka_Kitazume47_0-1757724039695.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-estimate-the-capacity-unit-with-commerce-cloud-capacity-unit/bc-p/14216309#M14662"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T02:42:27.944000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/delivery-date-field-update-after-po-confirmation-posted/qaa-p/14216310#M4227076</id>
    <title>Re: Delivery date field update after PO confirmation posted</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T02:51:24.948000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yas6</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1959661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Define Screen Layout at Document Level, you can make certain fields display‑only after PO confirmation, so they can’t be changed without cancelling the confirmation. Can you please explain how we can do this ?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/delivery-date-field-update-after-po-confirmation-posted/qaa-p/14216310#M4227076"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T02:51:24.948000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E4%BA%A4%E8%B4%A7%E5%8D%95-amp-%E5%8F%91%E7%A5%A8%E6%89%93%E5%8D%B0-%E8%87%AA%E5%AE%9A%E4%B9%89%E5%90%88%E4%BD%9C%E4%BC%99%E4%BC%B4%E5%9C%B0%E5%9D%80/qaa-p/14216311#M4227077</id>
    <title>Re: 交货单&amp;发票打印-自定义合作伙伴地址</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T03:02:49.396000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1474902"&gt;@Joey3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;您遇到的问题是：打印送货单或发票时，数据源不会自动包含您定义的自定义交易伙伴功能。&lt;BR /&gt;根据SAP说明：&lt;BR /&gt;• 输出表单仅获取标准交易伙伴功能。但您可扩展表单数据源以添加交易伙伴功能，此操作将使打印程序能够检索并向表单传递供应商地址。&lt;BR /&gt;• 请检查公共云中是否为交货或计费对象提供了用于输出参数确定的BAdI&lt;BR /&gt;• 或可通过交易伙伴确定功能将供应商设为供应商交易伙伴功能，使其出现在标准交易伙伴表中&lt;BR /&gt;• 获取交易伙伴数据后，调整Adobe表单或Smartform以选择ZS交易伙伴，并在所需区域打印供应商地址&lt;BR /&gt;更多信息请参阅《打印交货单与供应商发票指南》。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/9832125c23154a179bfa1784cdc9577a/fbcccb53ad377114e10000000a174cb4.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Printing Delivery Notes&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/6583f0d4d799462f929b5ba0832211c7.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Print Supplier Invoices&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;希望以上说明能满足您的需求。如有其他疑问，欢迎随时垂询。&lt;BR /&gt;此致&lt;BR /&gt;敬礼&lt;BR /&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E4%BA%A4%E8%B4%A7%E5%8D%95-amp-%E5%8F%91%E7%A5%A8%E6%89%93%E5%8D%B0-%E8%87%AA%E5%AE%9A%E4%B9%89%E5%90%88%E4%BD%9C%E4%BC%99%E4%BC%B4%E5%9C%B0%E5%9D%80/qaa-p/14216311#M4227077"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T03:02:49.396000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/regarding-tab-control-in-mir4-s4-hana-sorry-the-miro-description-has-been/qaa-p/14216312#M207043</id>
    <title>Re: Regarding tab control in MIR4 (S4 HANA) *Sorry, The M...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T03:21:11.682000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CharlesFeng</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/180193</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1390154"&gt;@Hoppy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It appears that you have already resolved the issue.&lt;BR /&gt;If possible, could you please share the detailed solutions here?&lt;BR /&gt;This information could be highly beneficial to other SAP users who might have similar requests or requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Charles&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/regarding-tab-control-in-mir4-s4-hana-sorry-the-miro-description-has-been/qaa-p/14216312#M207043"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T03:21:11.682000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s4-public-cloud-0l-vs-4g-configuration/qaa-p/14216313#M4227078</id>
    <title>Re: S4 Public Cloud 0L vs 4G configuration</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T03:25:15.129000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131826"&gt;@JuliaLu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consider the following links for that scenario&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/cdccca8e03d74101a0135863bc522b49/aee9c5536a51204be10000000a174cb4.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Foreign Currency Valuation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0fa84c9d9c634132b7c4abb9ffdd8f06/c0a967eee7d843f8aceb44219b6f40b3.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Advanced Valuation in Financial Accounting&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are some additions to the customers request/question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OL is the leading ledger in S/4HANA Cloud. That means all valuations, postings and reporting rely on it. Only on leading ledger is allowed in Public Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ledger 4G is the opposite to OL. This means, it is sometimes activated by implementation partners for parallel accounting. This could be for IFRS vs. Local GAAP but is typically used for universal parallel accounting scenarios.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While classic foreign currency valuation is available in some legacy scenarios, for public clouds SAP recommends and delivers the Advanced Foreign Currency Valuation. Once this is activated in a tenant, configurations and posting will be harmonised across ledgers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, no you cannot use OL for classic FX and 4G Advanced FX valuation. Considering Foreign currency valuation is a global process, SAP does not allow you split the ledgers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the partner has activated 4G then the Advanced FX Valuation is the standard approach to be applied. One consistent FX valuation across all ledgers is the only supported configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s4-public-cloud-0l-vs-4g-configuration/qaa-p/14216313#M4227078"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T03:25:15.129000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/automating-sap-hana-system-startup-in-a-distributed-hana-environment-on-gcp/qaa-p/14216314#M4926190</id>
    <title>Re: Automating SAP HANA System Startup in a Distributed H...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T03:32:52.238000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CharlesFeng</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/180193</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1564702"&gt;@NitinKhose&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for sharing this well-structured and helpful information, particularly for providing your created shell scripts/commands.&lt;BR /&gt;I believe this will greatly benefit many other SAP users in automating their SAP system start. Your contribution is very much appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Charles&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/automating-sap-hana-system-startup-in-a-distributed-hana-environment-on-gcp/qaa-p/14216314#M4926190"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T03:32:52.238000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/lms-organization-connector-file-all-levels/qaa-p/14216315#M47963</id>
    <title>Re: LMS Organization Connector File - All Levels</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T03:36:03.627000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nathanharding</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/37447</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I highly recommend that you look up the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/sap-successfactors-learning-get-your-implementation-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Learning – Get Your Implementation Right&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;course as week 3 steps you through creating all the LMS Connectors (with videos).&amp;nbsp; It is an amazing resource that even for the most experience consultants will provide some absolute gems of SAP Best Practices!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Course.png" style="width: 646px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313881iD0FA1C3622F716BC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Course.png" alt="SAP Course.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any specific queries then please feel free to reach out to me on the below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nathan Harding&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;E: nathan.harding@epiuse.com.au&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;as week 4 steps you through Connectors (with videos). Regards, Nathan Harding E: nathan.harding@epiuse.com.au&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/lms-organization-connector-file-all-levels/qaa-p/14216315#M47963"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T03:36:03.627000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/st-a-pi-01w-731-component-is-not-installed/qaa-p/14216317#M4926191</id>
    <title>Re: ST-A/PI 01W_731 component is not installed</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T03:46:46.803000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CharlesFeng</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/180193</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109029"&gt;@josephloyaga&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have you resolved the issue?&lt;BR /&gt;If so, could you please share the root cause and solution here? This information could be helpful for other SAP users who may encounter a similar issue in the future.&lt;BR /&gt;If the issue is not yet resolved, you may create a case (component: SV-SMG-MON*) with SAP support for further analysis, as I was unable to find any useful clues to this issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Charles&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/st-a-pi-01w-731-component-is-not-installed/qaa-p/14216317#M4926191"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T03:46:46.803000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/business-partner-replication-from-s-4hana-public-cloud-to-ewm-fails-due-to/qaa-p/14216318#M207044</id>
    <title>Re: Business Partner Replication from S/4HANA Public Clou...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T03:56:37.043000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1911475"&gt;@FlorisBoon&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding your questions, here are a few facts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;There is no official SAP Note or standard fix that automatically includes the General BP role in DRF payload from S/4HANA Public Cloud. Considering it is a technical role in the backend, it is not released in any API config.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;As a workaround on the EWM side, it is possible to implement a BAdI (such as /SCWM/EX_BUPA_INBOUND). This should add the General Role to all incoming Business Partners. This also enriches the payload after receipt and thereby allowing EWM to process the BP correctly even if the General role is missing in the message from S/4&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you prefer a custom solution to enhance on the cloud side, note that extension option is limited due to SaaS restrictions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The scenario you mentioned is not fully covered out-of-the-box for public cloud to decentralized EWM. Custom logic is needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I recommend keeping the S/4HANA best practice. You can manage your requirement in EWM.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. Happy to answer any further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/business-partner-replication-from-s-4hana-public-cloud-to-ewm-fails-due-to/qaa-p/14216318#M207044"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T03:56:37.043000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-change-mass-objects-table-by-mass-t-code/qaa-p/14216319#M4926192</id>
    <title>Re: HOW TO CHANGE MASS OBJECTS/TABLE BY MASS T-CODE?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T05:02:28.891000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CharlesFeng</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/180193</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2213211"&gt;@DAVE_VUONG&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you for sharing this well-structured and helpful information, particularly for providing the step-by-step screenshots.&lt;BR /&gt;I believe this will greatly benefit many other SAP users who have similar requirement. Your contribution is very much appreciated.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Charles&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-change-mass-objects-table-by-mass-t-code/qaa-p/14216319#M4926192"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T05:02:28.891000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/in-the-sap-public-cloud-mto-make-to-order-process-the-billing-document-type/qaq-p/14216320</id>
    <title>In the SAP Public Cloud MTO (Make-to-Order) process, the billing document type F2 is not being creat</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T05:18:32.331000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Amit66</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1789325</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Expert,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the SAP Public Cloud MTO (Make-to-Order) process, the billing document type F2 is not being created. I have selected the item category group CB04 (Make-to-Order) in the material master, which results in item category CBTA being assigned in the sales order and also in the outbound delivery.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have checked the copying control, but there is no entry for item category CBTA from delivery type LF to billing type F2. Could you please suggest a solution for this?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/in-the-sap-public-cloud-mto-make-to-order-process-the-billing-document-type/qaq-p/14216320"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T05:18:32.331000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s4-public-cloud-0l-vs-4g-configuration/qaa-p/14216321#M4227080</id>
    <title>Re: S4 Public Cloud 0L vs 4G configuration</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T05:31:33.110000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JuliaLu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131826</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks Chris. If the customer needs universal parallel accounting, then the implementation partner will explain to the customer to propose to use 4G instead of 0L, or if there's no such as an usage scenario, and as the customer suggests to use 0L, the implementation partner needs to de-active 4G and then activate 0L, right??</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s4-public-cloud-0l-vs-4g-configuration/qaa-p/14216321#M4227080"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T05:31:33.110000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/invalid-function-import-parameter-linkedsapobjectkey/qaq-p/14216323</id>
    <title>Invalid Function Import Parameter 'LinkedSAPObjectKey'</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T05:49:05.505000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rawel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2116850</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Sap&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Good day&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I've been encountering this problem&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I am attaching Attachment to an Created PO&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Rawel_0-1757735225779.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313882i60C70178FC3D6F6E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Rawel_0-1757735225779.png" alt="Rawel_0-1757735225779.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This is the error i am getting&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;{&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "error": {&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "code": "00505692409C1ED98BC56577A40755A7",&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "message": {&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "lang": "en",&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "value": "Invalid Function Import Parameter 'LinkedSAPObjectKey'"&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; },&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "innererror": {&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "transactionid": "E89D9EBA99D50200E0068C3DA27EE0A1",&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "timestamp": "20250913033902.6891390",&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "Error_Resolution": {&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "SAP_Transaction": "For backend administrators: use ADT feed reader \"SAP Gateway Error Log\" or run transaction /IWFND/ERROR_LOG on SAP Gateway hub system and search for entries with the timestamp above for more details",&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "SAP_Note": "See SAP Note 1797736 for error analysis (&lt;A href="https://service.sap.com/sap/support/notes/1797736" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://service.sap.com/sap/support/notes/1797736&lt;/A&gt;)"&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; }&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; }&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; }&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;}&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/invalid-function-import-parameter-linkedsapobjectkey/qaq-p/14216323"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T05:49:05.505000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-fico-tickets-related-to-accounts-payable-accounts-recivable-gl/qaa-p/14216324#M255132</id>
    <title>Re: sap fico tickets related to accounts payable,accounts recivable,gl configuration.</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T05:57:26.738000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Deepika_16</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1876049</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Account payble</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-fico-tickets-related-to-accounts-payable-accounts-recivable-gl/qaa-p/14216324#M255132"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T05:57:26.738000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s4-public-cloud-0l-vs-4g-configuration/qaa-p/14216325#M4227081</id>
    <title>Re: S4 Public Cloud 0L vs 4G configuration</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T06:01:59.738000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mpavan_kumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131826"&gt;@JuliaLu&lt;/a&gt; The partner should deactivate 4G if parallel accounting is not needed. · However, they cannot "activate 0L" because it is always active and cannot be deactivated. It is the permanent leading ledger.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s4-public-cloud-0l-vs-4g-configuration/qaa-p/14216325#M4227081"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T06:01:59.738000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/call-sap-btp-integration-suite-api-from-postman-failing/qaa-p/14216326#M4926194</id>
    <title>Re: Call SAP BTP integration suite api from postman failing</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T06:22:46.361000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OlgenH</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/159416</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/214031"&gt;@deepak_h3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;the API URL doesn't seem correct - you're probably using the design time host of Cloud Integration. The APIs run under the runtime host which can be identified by -rt in the name, e.g.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://xxx.it-cpi002-rt.cfapps.ap10.hana.ondemand.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://xxx.it-cpi002-rt.cfapps.ap10.hana.ondemand.com&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your service key is setup correctly in BTP the above should work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/call-sap-btp-integration-suite-api-from-postman-failing/qaa-p/14216326#M4926194"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T06:22:46.361000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-enable-sap-vim-smart-coding/ba-p/14216335</id>
    <title>How to Enable SAP VIM Smart Coding?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T06:52:45.494000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arghadipkar3013</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/686417</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;How to Enable Smart Coding in SAP VIM ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to Transaction Code SE38--&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;/OTX/PS302_TRAIN_COD&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1.png" style="width: 663px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313886i887A292897785586/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1.png" alt="1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Execute and choose below option&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2.png" style="width: 915px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313887i4EA26D1D67ABE16A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.png" alt="2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below out put has been generated&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="3.png" style="width: 753px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313885i242CD791ECA3C23F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.png" alt="3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now lets go to VIM Workplace(Tcode -&amp;gt; /n/opt/vim_wp)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4.png" style="width: 583px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313884i7095FB7EFBFC1D8A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4.png" alt="4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now pick a NON-PO DP Document&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="5.png" style="width: 928px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313888i2022C114C47FFAE3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.png" alt="5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now go to Line Items and select the below option&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="6.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313889i91B66C2DC8986645/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6.png" alt="6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Magic done. The Smart Coding now proposes previous G/L Cost Center&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="7.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313890i116AB762442E1AC6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="7.png" alt="7.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conclusion&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For video version&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://youtu.be/2EwSVmgSvkY?si=X2mAQ91vqL0qSV_4" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://youtu.be/2EwSVmgSvkY?si=X2mAQ91vqL0qSV_4&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-enable-sap-vim-smart-coding/ba-p/14216335"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T06:52:45.494000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E4%BA%A4%E8%B4%A7%E5%8D%95-amp-%E5%8F%91%E7%A5%A8%E6%89%93%E5%8D%B0-%E8%87%AA%E5%AE%9A%E4%B9%89%E5%90%88%E4%BD%9C%E4%BC%99%E4%BC%B4%E5%9C%B0%E5%9D%80/qaa-p/14216336#M4227082</id>
    <title>Re: 交货单&amp;发票打印-自定义合作伙伴地址</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T07:15:53.682000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mpavan_kumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1474902"&gt;@Joey3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;您无需依赖输出确定或复杂的 BAdI，而是可以直接修改 Adob​​e 表单来读取文档的合作伙伴表 (VBPA) 并查找 ZS 合作伙伴的地址。&lt;BR /&gt;数据流非常清晰：表单 -&amp;gt; RFC 调用 -&amp;gt; VBPA 表 -&amp;gt; 地址 -&amp;gt; 表单布局。&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E4%BA%A4%E8%B4%A7%E5%8D%95-amp-%E5%8F%91%E7%A5%A8%E6%89%93%E5%8D%B0-%E8%87%AA%E5%AE%9A%E4%B9%89%E5%90%88%E4%BD%9C%E4%BC%99%E4%BC%B4%E5%9C%B0%E5%9D%80/qaa-p/14216336#M4227082"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T07:15:53.682000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerating-gxp-compliance-for-sap-digital-manufacuring-in-the-public/ba-p/14216338</id>
    <title>Accelerating GxP Compliance for SAP Digital Manufacuring in the Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T07:38:04.550000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sidharth_shah</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1762915</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The life sciences industry is rapidly adopting SAP’s public cloud offerings. According to &lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/life-sciences/our-insights/the-case-for-cloud-in-life-sciences" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;McKinsey&lt;/A&gt;, over 80% of the top 30 global pharmaceutical and MedTech companies have adopted cloud solutions across various parts of their operations. Key drivers include lower cost of ownership, scalability, and rapid innovation. Another major influence is the advent of AI and Gen-AI, which &lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/life-sciences/our-insights/generative-ai-in-the-pharmaceutical-industry-moving-from-hype-to-reality" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;McKinsey estimates&lt;/A&gt; could unlock $60b - $110b a year in economic value for the industry. However, organizations can only leverage Gen-AI at scale if they operate in the cloud. This adoption also come with a key challenge: How can organizations demonstrate GxP compliance in public clouds, when many controls are managed by SAP?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article explores the adoption journey for public cloud products, using SAP Digital Manufacturing as an example.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sidharth_shah_0-1757741476407.png" style="width: 677px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313891iFFE5EFD8306B6652/image-dimensions/677x149/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="677" height="149" role="button" title="sidharth_shah_0-1757741476407.png" alt="sidharth_shah_0-1757741476407.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discover and Prepare&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product assessment for Cloud controls&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditional on-premises compliance strategies were built around physical infrastructures and static environments. In a modern automated public cloud environment, compliance requirements need adaptation. For example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Backup and Recovery – Life sciences organizations must meet regulatory requirements for backup, including regular snapshots and defined retention schedules. Traditionally, this meant storing daily, weekly, and monthly backups for extended periods. With microservice based environments, older backups lose relevance with every update, limiting restoration usefulness. Organizations should rather adopt a risk-based approach—aligning backup requirements with &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IT_disaster_recovery" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Recovery Point Objective (RPO) and Recovery Time Objective (RTO)&lt;/A&gt; strategies—to ensure regulatory adherence and true system recoverability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Network delivery control: Network and perimeter controls should account for business continuity requirements and the latency challenges in distributed cloud environments. Different components of an application may run across geographically distant regions, impacting performance. When evaluating these factors, SAP published &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center/agreements.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;service-level agreements&lt;/A&gt; (SLAs) should be considered to get guidance on expected network performance and availability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data Residency and Sovereignty: Organizations must ensure not only that their data is hosted in compliant regions, but also that backups and replicated environments adhere to the same regulatory and regional requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supplier Assessment &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Life sciences organizations operating under GxP regulations must ensure &lt;STRONG&gt;quality, compliance, and control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;,&lt;/STRONG&gt; even when using public cloud solutions. Under the shared responsibility model, certain application responsibilities are managed by SAP, while others remain with the life sciences organizations. However, the organizations themselves remain fully accountable to regulatory bodies for demonstrating compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Due to the shared or deleted controls, organizations must qualify SAP as a supplier of GxP-relevant IT solutions. Customers may leverage the available information, questionnaires and 3rd party audit reports such as ISO 9001/27001 and SOC2. Additionally, customers may perform an on-site audit to help bridge gaps in understanding of SAP’s Quality Management System and other processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To facilitate on-site audits—such as with SAP Digital Manufacturing—customers can leverage the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/cd35a8e6ec7b491c88c4a08d9201c71f/Latest/en-US/SAP-Quality-Requirement-Schedule-For-SAP-Digital-Manufacturing%20(1).pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Quality Requirement Schedule&lt;/A&gt;, which grants limited rights to perform an on-site audit and ensures support when life sciences organizations face regulatory audits.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore and Realize&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GxP Strategy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following product and supplier assessment, GxP strategy should be defined to ensure long term viability. Key elements of this strategy can include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Application Architecture: Evaluate which processes remain on-premises and which move to the cloud. Distributed manufacturing workflows spanning ERP (SAP S/4HANA and SAP S/4HANA Cloud) and MES (SAP Digital Manufacturing) require balancing data duplication, separation of responsibilities, ease of use, performance, and validation requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extension: Extensions if required must undergo their own GxP evaluation and IQ/OQ/PQ. Consider the various API’s and dependencies utilized by the extensions and to adhere to &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/resources/what-is-a-clean-core" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;clean core principals&lt;/A&gt; to ensure minimal PQ efforts over the extension lifecycle.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner selection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many SAP customers leverage partners to accelerate adoption. Partners solutions are available through various marketplaces such as &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/store.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Store&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/partners/find/qualified-packaged-solutions/finder.html?sort=title_asc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Qualified Partner Packages&lt;/A&gt;. For software partners, a supplier assessment is recommended to verify their Quality Management processes and that any integrated solution complies with GxP requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Life sciences organizations also rely on implementation partners for consulting, deployment, and ongoing support activities. These partners should be evaluated on their ability to deliver in a GxP-regulated environment. &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/digital-manufacturing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Partner Blogs&lt;/A&gt; highlight nice capabilities, providing insight into compliant implementations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deploy and Run&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validation Strategy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Validation requirements for a public cloud are similar to on-premises, however these must be adapted to accommodate the fixed release schedule. Key practices that can assist :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Risk Based on Scope and Usage: Leverage SAP’s existing documentation, such as &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DIGITAL_MANUFACTURING/3dc010a4880d4c8691bae0ba30f2b57b?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=latest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Service Catalog&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, to define the validation scope based on business criticality and GxP impact. Organizations can exclude non-GxP functions to narrow down the scope of validation testing. Validation efforts should prioritize highly critical functionality, while lower critical functions may be tested through smoke test etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For regular release cycles the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/983fc3e099074d1ea3ea6db6caf41678?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=latest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt; can be used to identify changes in functionality that require assessment on validation requirements. Not all new functionalities must be validated – with validation only necessary before the actual usage/adoption of the functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automation: Automating Computer System Validation (CSV) reduces effort and helps ensure validation is completed on time. SAP Digital Manufacturing provides automation test modules compatible with Tricentis Test Automation (included in Enterprise Support). These automated tests can be leveraged for continuous testing and validation as part of a regression suite.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leveraging controls from SAP: GAMP5 recommends leveraging supplier testing (post supplier assessment) into verification. Organizations can inherit SAP’s controls based on the shared responsibility model around topics such as infrastructure, platform, security, data integrity etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gen-AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Generative AI can further reduce the compliance burden. By combining SAP’s structured documentation with a customer’s own documentation, it can generate automated, digitized risk assessments, documentation, and tests—significantly improving both the quality and speed of validation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maximizing SAP’s public cloud potential requires rethinking compliance controls. By adopting a risk-based approach and leveraging various tools provided by SAP, life sciences organizations can meet regulatory requirements while accelerating cloud adoption. This approach ensures compliance, fosters innovation, and builds trust in cloud-based operations.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerating-gxp-compliance-for-sap-digital-manufacuring-in-the-public/ba-p/14216338"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T07:38:04.550000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-driven-joule-enabled-warehouse-resource-amp-operations-management-for/bc-p/14216339#M7694</id>
    <title>Re: AI-driven, Joule-enabled Warehouse Resource &amp; Operations Management for SAP EWM on S/4 HANA</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T07:43:36.570000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mpavan_kumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1777459"&gt;@Tim_Dalm&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Joule and embedded AI transform SAP EWM from a reactive system into a proactive operations hub that predicts delays and automatically optimizes resources to meet shipping goals.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-driven-joule-enabled-warehouse-resource-amp-operations-management-for/bc-p/14216339#M7694"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T07:43:36.570000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/in-the-sap-public-cloud-mto-make-to-order-process-the-billing-document-type/qaa-p/14216340#M4227083</id>
    <title>Re: In the SAP Public Cloud MTO (Make-to-Order) process,...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T07:50:03.430000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1789325"&gt;@Amit66&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you check this KBA?&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3269803" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3269803&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/in-the-sap-public-cloud-mto-make-to-order-process-the-billing-document-type/qaa-p/14216340#M4227083"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T07:50:03.430000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/food-for-thought-what-s-your-favorite-holiday-celebration-dish/m-p/14216341#M3287</id>
    <title>Re: Food for thought: What’s your favorite holiday/celebration dish?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T07:53:40.492000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rowan33423</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253934</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Reading your story really made me smile because I can completely relate to how food connects us to people and memories. For me, cooking started out of curiosity too, I used to watch my grandmother make simple dishes, and I was always fascinated by how a few ingredients could bring everyone to the table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During the pandemic, I also found myself spending more time in the kitchen. What surprised me most was how much joy it brought to share those dishes with family. I remember one weekend when I invited my cousins over, and instead of ordering in, we cooked together. Everyone got involved—one was chopping vegetables, another was mixing sauces, and the kids were shaping patties. It wasn’t perfect, but it was fun, and by the end we felt closer than ever.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That day also reminded me how much comfort food can bring, whether it’s a home-cooked meal or even something from outside that becomes part of your story. For example, I still remember the first time I tried&lt;A href="https://shakeshackusa.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Shake Shack&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; with my friends after a long week—it wasn’t just about the burgers, but about the laughter, the conversations, and the shared moment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Food really does have that magic: it nourishes the body, but it also feeds the heart. Thanks for inspiring me to think back on these moments. I’d love to keep seeing more of your dishes and stories, and maybe I’ll share some of my own experiments here too.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/food-for-thought-what-s-your-favorite-holiday-celebration-dish/m-p/14216341#M3287"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T07:53:40.492000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/auto-delegation-on-the-leave-request-time-off-screen/bc-p/14216342#M7114</id>
    <title>Re: Auto Delegation on the Leave Request (Time Off) Screen</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T07:55:58.646000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hrrvic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/76798</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Parthiban,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Very nice reference article, however, upon following the same we are unable to get the auto delegation workflow to the delegatee.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you let us know any other rule/configurations to be made in addition to what is mentioned in this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sridevi&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/auto-delegation-on-the-leave-request-time-off-screen/bc-p/14216342#M7114"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T07:55:58.646000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/invalid-function-import-parameter-linkedsapobjectkey/qaa-p/14216343#M4926195</id>
    <title>Re: Invalid Function Import Parameter 'LinkedSAPObjectKey'</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T07:59:11.266000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mpavan_kumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2116850"&gt;@Rawel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Change LinkedSAPObjectkey to LinkedSAPObjectKey in your request body. This should resolve the error&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Notice the lowercase 'k' in ...Objectkey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP service expects the key to be named with an uppercase 'K'&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/invalid-function-import-parameter-linkedsapobjectkey/qaa-p/14216343#M4926195"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T07:59:11.266000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/give-a-kudo-get-a-badge/bc-p/14216344#M852</id>
    <title>Re: Give a Kudo, Get a Badge</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T08:05:15.325000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>_MansurHerfy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2024465</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This is such a fantastic initiative! The new kudos badge progression set not only rewards generosity but also reinforces the spirit of appreciation that makes SAP Community thrive. I love how the rollout is retroactive—it’s a great way to recognize long-time contributors who’ve been quietly supporting others all along.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is a digital résumé of your community impact.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/give-a-kudo-get-a-badge/bc-p/14216344#M852"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T08:05:15.325000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/talent-intelligence-hub-2024-updates-and-behind-the-scenes/bc-p/14216353#M9185</id>
    <title>Re: Talent intelligence hub - 2024 updates and behind the scenes!</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T08:30:52.972000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>visu2015</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124625</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/19490"&gt;@RinkyKarthik&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/19490"&gt;@RinkyKarthik&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Got few questions for a fresh / new Success factors Implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) Is JPB enablement required to implement TIH? &lt;STRONG&gt;Yes or NO&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If yes what features of JPB to be Configured before TIH to be implemented?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) If Client doesn't want to Enable JPB, can TIH be implemented? &lt;STRONG&gt;Yes or NO&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If Yes what features of TIH will be available to configure?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank You&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vish&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/talent-intelligence-hub-2024-updates-and-behind-the-scenes/bc-p/14216353#M9185"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T08:30:52.972000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/everything-you-need-to-know-about-sap-successfactors-talent-intelligence/bc-p/14216354#M9186</id>
    <title>Re: Everything    you need to know about: SAP SuccessFactors Talent Intelligence Hub</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T08:30:55.309000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>visu2015</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124625</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/19490"&gt;@RinkyKarthik&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Got few questions for a fresh / new Success factors Implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) Is JPB enablement required to implement TIH? &lt;STRONG&gt;Yes or NO&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If yes what features of JPB to be Configured before TIH to be implemented?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) If Client doesn't want to Enable JPB, can TIH be implemented? &lt;STRONG&gt;Yes or NO&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If Yes what features of TIH will be available to configure?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank You&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vish&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/everything-you-need-to-know-about-sap-successfactors-talent-intelligence/bc-p/14216354#M9186"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T08:30:55.309000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/in-the-sap-public-cloud-mto-make-to-order-process-the-billing-document-type/qaa-p/14216355#M4227084</id>
    <title>Re: In the SAP Public Cloud MTO (Make-to-Order) process,...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T08:32:04.668000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mpavan_kumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1789325"&gt;@Amit66&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;The solution is to add the missing entry in the Delivery-to-Billing copying control (VTFA) to map source item category CBTA (from delivery type LF) to target billing item category F2 (for billing type F2)&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/in-the-sap-public-cloud-mto-make-to-order-process-the-billing-document-type/qaa-p/14216355#M4227084"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T08:32:04.668000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-customer-checkout-manager-loyalty-records/qaq-p/14216356</id>
    <title>SAP Customer Checkout Manager Loyalty Records</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T08:37:03.711000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>raveedriaz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/700763</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear All,&lt;BR /&gt;I am facing issue when creating the a loyalty record for a receipt.&lt;BR /&gt;Previously it was working fine but suddenly it stopped working and it is giving me the error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="raveedriaz_0-1757275042269.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310627iD743EB44B0200ADD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="raveedriaz_0-1757275042269.png" alt="raveedriaz_0-1757275042269.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am also attaching the Log file of CCO Manager as well.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;CCO Manager Version :&amp;nbsp;2.0 FP20 PL03&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-customer-checkout-manager-loyalty-records/qaq-p/14216356"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T08:37:03.711000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/capacity-requirement-kpi-not-showing-in-schedule-labor-app-in-sap-dmc/qaa-p/14216359#M207045</id>
    <title>Re: Capacity Requirement KPI Not Showing in Schedule Labo...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T08:48:32.639000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mpavan_kumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2183492"&gt;@MOHAMEDAMINE_MOUNA30&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; "In Scheduling and capacity requirements settings in SPRO select capacity requirement and check it," is a crucial step in diagnosing the "Capacity Requirement = 0" issue. This points directly to the configuration of the Control Key&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/capacity-requirement-kpi-not-showing-in-schedule-labor-app-in-sap-dmc/qaa-p/14216359#M207045"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T08:48:32.639000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-control-pgi-process-between-sales-and-supply-chain-in-sap-s-4hana/qaa-p/14216360#M4227085</id>
    <title>Re: How to control PGI process between Sales and Supply C...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T08:50:23.809000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>_MansurHerfy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2024465</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The ability to perform &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PGI (Post Goods Issue)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in SAP Fiori hinges entirely on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;authorization profile&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, specifically the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Role&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Catalog&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; assignments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So yes, if &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales users&lt;/STRONG&gt; lack the catalog that includes the PGI functionality, they won’t be able to execute PGI—even if they can create deliveries. That’s by design: SAP’s role-based access ensures users only perform actions aligned with their responsibilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Who &lt;EM&gt;should&lt;/EM&gt; have access to PGI?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Typically, PGI is granted to roles such as:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Warehouse Clerks&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;Shipping Specialists&lt;/STRONG&gt; – who physically handle goods and confirm dispatch.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Logistics Execution Users&lt;/STRONG&gt; – responsible for outbound processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delivery Processing Roles&lt;/STRONG&gt; – if PGI is part of their workflow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These users would be assigned a &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Role&lt;/STRONG&gt; that includes the &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Catalog&lt;/STRONG&gt; containing the PGI app (e.g., &lt;EM&gt;"Outbound Delivery Processing"&lt;/EM&gt; catalog). You can fine-tune access further using &lt;STRONG&gt;restriction values&lt;/STRONG&gt; like shipping point, plant, or delivery type to ensure users only act on relevant data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you’re setting this up, make sure:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The correct &lt;STRONG&gt;Fiori app&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., &lt;EM&gt;Post Goods Issue for Outbound Delivery&lt;/EM&gt;) is included in the catalog.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The catalog is assigned to the right &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Role&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The role is assigned to the appropriate &lt;STRONG&gt;Business User&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-control-pgi-process-between-sales-and-supply-chain-in-sap-s-4hana/qaa-p/14216360#M4227085"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T08:50:23.809000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-control-pgi-process-between-sales-and-supply-chain-in-sap-s-4hana/qaa-p/14216361#M4227086</id>
    <title>Re: How to control PGI process between Sales and Supply C...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T08:51:11.464000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>_MansurHerfy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2024465</uri>
    </author>
    <content>To enable Post Goods Issue (PGI) functionality in SAP Fiori, you'll need to assign the correct Fiori app and Business Catalog to the relevant Business Role. Here's the precise info you need: &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":package:"&gt;📦&lt;/span&gt; SAP Fiori App for PGI App Name: Post Goods Issue for Outbound Delivery App ID: F1595 Semantic Object: OutboundDelivery Action: PostGoodsIssue This app allows users to post goods issue for outbound deliveries directly from the Fiori Launchpad. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt; Business Catalog To enable this app, assign the following catalog: Catalog ID: SAP_SD_BC_OUTBOUND_DEL_PROC_MC Catalog Name: Outbound Delivery Processing This catalog includes the PGI app along with other outbound delivery-related apps like Change Outbound Delivery, Display Outbound Delivery, and Create Outbound Delivery. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bust_in_silhouette:"&gt;👤&lt;/span&gt; Who Should Get It? Assign this catalog to roles such as: Shipping Clerk Warehouse Operator Logistics Execution Specialist Sales users typically should not have this catalog unless they are directly involved in logistics execution. This ensures proper segregation of duties and avoids unauthorized PGI actions.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-control-pgi-process-between-sales-and-supply-chain-in-sap-s-4hana/qaa-p/14216361#M4227086"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T08:51:11.464000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-customer-checkout-manager-loyalty-records/qaa-p/14216362#M457809</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Customer Checkout Manager Loyalty Records</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T09:25:15.852000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mpavan_kumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/700763"&gt;@raveedriaz&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Try creating a loyalty record for a different, simpler receipt. Does the error occur for every receipt or just a specific one? If it's just one, the problem is with that receipt's data&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-customer-checkout-manager-loyalty-records/qaa-p/14216362#M457809"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T09:25:15.852000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/invalid-function-import-parameter-linkedsapobjectkey/qaa-p/14216364#M4926196</id>
    <title>Re: Invalid Function Import Parameter 'LinkedSAPObjectKey'</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T09:27:10.719000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2116850"&gt;@Rawel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The error might be due to an invalid/ wrongly formatted 'LinkedSAPObjectKey' parameters when you are uploading the Attachment.&amp;nbsp; Check this documentation&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3544239" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3544239&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/invalid-function-import-parameter-linkedsapobjectkey/qaa-p/14216364#M4926196"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T09:27:10.719000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/top-25-sap-s-4hana-amp-abap-interview-questions-and-answers-2025/qaq-p/14216365</id>
    <title>Top 25 SAP S/4HANA &amp; ABAP Interview Questions and Answers (2025)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T09:29:44.973000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>king04aman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1445789</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Preparing for a &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ABAP or S/4HANA interview&lt;/STRONG&gt; can feel overwhelming. You spend hours revising concepts, yet when the interview starts, the real challenge is remembering &lt;STRONG&gt;which questions are most commonly asked&lt;/STRONG&gt; and how to answer them with clarity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To help you overcome this, I’ve compiled the &lt;STRONG&gt;Top 25 SAP ABAP and S/4HANA Interview Questions for 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;—based on real-world interview experiences and what hiring managers actually look for.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This post curates the &lt;STRONG&gt;most common SAP ABAP &amp;amp; S/4HANA interview questions for 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;—spanning &lt;STRONG&gt;DDIC, ALV, BDC, CDS, AMDP, Open vs Native SQL, ABAP on HANA, Web Dynpro&lt;/STRONG&gt; and more. For &lt;STRONG&gt;clear, step-by-step answers&lt;/STRONG&gt;, watch the full breakdown here:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Video:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://youtu.be/EK7dXNAY4I4" target="_new" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Top 25 SAP S/4HANA &amp;amp; ABAP Interview Questions and Answers (2025)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt; Top 25 SAP ABAP &amp;amp; S/4HANA Interview Questions (2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What is SAP ABAP?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What is the ABAP Data Dictionary (DDIC)?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Difference between transparent tables and pooled/cluster tables&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What are SmartForms and their benefits over SAP Scripts?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Difference between function modules and BAPIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What is BDC (Batch Data Communication)? Methods: recording, session, call transaction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What are modularization techniques in ABAP?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Difference between Classical Reports, Interactive Reports, and ALV Reports&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What are field symbols and how are they used?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How do you define and use internal tables?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What are the basic data types in ABAP?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What is ABAP Objects (OOP in ABAP)?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explain inheritance and polymorphism in ABAP Objects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What is a Lock Object? How is locking handled in ABAP?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open SQL vs Native SQL – differences and use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What are RICEFW objects in SAP projects?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explain CALL TRANSACTION and its use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What are CDS Views and their significance in S/4HANA?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What is AMDP (ABAP Managed Database Procedure) and why is it used?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Debugging in ABAP – breakpoints, watchpoints, ST22 dumps&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What is Web Dynpro for ABAP?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CDS vs AMDP vs Traditional Reports – when to use which?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What are the key features of ABAP on HANA?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What tools and T-codes are essential for ABAP development?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What are type groups and their purpose in ABAP?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889172509"&gt;Why this matters in 2025 (How to Crack SAP ABAP Interview)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP technology continues to evolve, especially with &lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP on HANA and S/4HANA migrations&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Interviewers are no longer just testing textbook knowledge—they want to see if you can &lt;STRONG&gt;connect concepts to real project scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;. These 25 questions cover exactly that mix of &lt;STRONG&gt;fundamentals + modern ABAP practices&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;️ For in-depth answers, examples, and explanations, check out the full video:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://youtu.be/EK7dXNAY4I4" target="_new" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Top 25 SAP ABAP &amp;amp; S/4HANA Interview Questions and Answers (2025)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Tip:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Don’t just memorize these questions—try to explain them in your own words, link them to project experience, and always be ready with a short example. That’s what makes you stand out in interviews.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/top-25-sap-s-4hana-amp-abap-interview-questions-and-answers-2025/qaq-p/14216365"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T09:29:44.973000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-find-ai-core-service-in-btp-trail-account/qaa-p/14216367#M4926198</id>
    <title>Re: cannot find AI Core service in BTP trail account</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T09:35:34.045000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>king04aman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1445789</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; In short, Trial = no AI Core. Free Tier / PAYG = AI Core.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You won’t find &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Core&lt;/STRONG&gt; in a BTP &lt;STRONG&gt;trial account&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as it isn’t part of the trial entitlements. To use it, you’ll need to switch to a &lt;STRONG&gt;Free Tier (Pay-As-You-Go or Enterprise) account&lt;/STRONG&gt; and then add the entitlement in your global account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you just want to learn, I recommend checking out the official &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-ai-core/sap-ai-core-service-guide/sap-ai-core-starter-tutorials?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI Core Starter Tutorials&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-find-ai-core-service-in-btp-trail-account/qaa-p/14216367#M4926198"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T09:35:34.045000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/in-my-btp-account-want-to-create-free-trail-account-in-order-to-get-sap-ai/qaa-p/14216368#M4926199</id>
    <title>Re: in my BTP account want to create Free Trail account i...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T09:39:29.028000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>king04aman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1445789</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; In short, Trial = no AI Core. Free Tier / PAYG = AI Core&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You won’t find &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Core&lt;/STRONG&gt; in a BTP &lt;STRONG&gt;trial account&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as it isn’t part of the trial entitlements. To use it, you’ll need to switch to a &lt;STRONG&gt;Free Tier (Pay-As-You-Go or Enterprise) account&lt;/STRONG&gt; and then add the entitlement in your global account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you just want to learn, I recommend checking out the official &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-ai-core/sap-ai-core-service-guide/sap-ai-core-starter-tutorials?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI Core Starter Tutorials&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/in-my-btp-account-want-to-create-free-trail-account-in-order-to-get-sap-ai/qaa-p/14216368#M4926199"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T09:39:29.028000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/working-with-rap-bo-events-end-to-end-event-driven-architecture-event/bc-p/14216369#M184516</id>
    <title>Re: Working with RAP BO Events end-to-end - Event-driven-architecture - Event framework</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T09:40:19.050000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbeer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122438</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157846"&gt;@mlauber&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;great blog post, thank you for that.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are currently trying to replace an old non clean exit with local RAP BO Consumption S/4 2023 FPS 2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are using the business event &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/event/OP_SUPPLIERINVOICEEVENTS/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/event/OP_SUPPLIERINVOICEEVENTS/overview&lt;/A&gt; for this.&lt;BR /&gt;This uses the RAP BO R_SUPPLIERINVOICETP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now we are observing the following behavior, which we cannot explain:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If we post the logistics incoming invoice using transaction MIRO, the event and our implementation are triggered.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;However, if the logistics incoming invoice is posted using an INVOIC IDoc, the event is not triggered.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_multiplication_x:"&gt;✖️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is the reason why document posting via IDoc does not trigger this event?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR, Alex&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/working-with-rap-bo-events-end-to-end-event-driven-architecture-event/bc-p/14216369#M184516"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T09:40:19.050000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-customer-checkout-manager-loyalty-records/qaa-p/14216370#M457810</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Customer Checkout Manager Loyalty Records</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T09:40:24.264000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>raveedriaz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/700763</uri>
    </author>
    <content>It creates successfully for a few cases, but for most of them it fails.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-customer-checkout-manager-loyalty-records/qaa-p/14216370#M457810"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T09:40:24.264000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-i-send-a-request-to-the-spa-workflow-from-custom-fiori-app/qaq-p/14216373</id>
    <title>how do I send a request to the   SPA workflow from Custom fiori app?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T09:58:22.979000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hbeyazal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1429795</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;I'm having an issue with the SAP build process automation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;I created a simple workflow structure and deployed.&amp;nbsp;After, I tested whether&amp;nbsp; the workflow service on the api.sap site and Postman.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;The workflow is working and successfully ı see task in myinbox.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;But when ı try to request from my&amp;nbsp; custom fiori it gives error.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;When I adapt the request in the post, I get a cors error.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;So&amp;nbsp; I thought I definitely needed to send a request through the destination, so I created a destination from the service instance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;my destination :&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hbeyazal_0-1757749893920.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313903i660EFF3E12A4C4A7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hbeyazal_0-1757749893920.png" alt="hbeyazal_0-1757749893920.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hbeyazal_1-1757749910786.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313904i8E73A3C4AE8C6273/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hbeyazal_1-1757749910786.png" alt="hbeyazal_1-1757749910786.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;After&amp;nbsp; I described this destinationin xs.app.json file like that&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"source"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"^/spalast/(.*)$"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"target"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"/public/workflow/rest/v1/$1"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"destination"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"spa"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"authenticationType"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"none"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"csrfProtection"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;false&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; },&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and lastly my test requests:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;fetch&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"/spalast/workflow-instances"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;method&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;"POST"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;headers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; { &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Content-Type"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;"application/json"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; },&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;body&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;JSON&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;stringify&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;({&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;definitionId&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;"eu10.integration-suite-dev-25mloa6z.employeeapitriggerprocess.employeeProcess"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;context&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; { &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;employee&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; { &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/* ... */&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; } }&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; })&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; });&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;fetch&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"/spalast/workflow-instances"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, {&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;method&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;"GET"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;headers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; { &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Content-Type"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;"application/json"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; }&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; });&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;ıt&amp;nbsp; gives 403&amp;nbsp;error&amp;nbsp; from the POST request and 404 error from the GET request.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What could be the reason for this?&amp;nbsp; Most of the blogs I read also redirect in this way.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-i-send-a-request-to-the-spa-workflow-from-custom-fiori-app/qaq-p/14216373"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T09:58:22.979000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-customer-checkout-manager-loyalty-records/qaa-p/14216374#M457811</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Customer Checkout Manager Loyalty Records</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T10:06:39.004000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mpavan_kumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/700763"&gt;@raveedriaz&lt;/a&gt; Find 2-3 failing receipts and 1-2 working ones. Write down their numbers, customer IDs, and the main items sold. Compare the Customer Master Data for a working customer and a failing customer. Look for any differences, especially in dates and loyalty-related fields.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-customer-checkout-manager-loyalty-records/qaa-p/14216374#M457811"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T10:06:39.004000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-i-send-a-request-to-the-spa-workflow-from-custom-fiori-app/qaa-p/14216388#M4926201</id>
    <title>Re: how do I send a request to the SPA workflow from Cust...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T10:31:22.188000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mpavan_kumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1429795"&gt;@hbeyazal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; check the application logs in the BTP cockpit for more detailed error messages.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-i-send-a-request-to-the-spa-workflow-from-custom-fiori-app/qaa-p/14216388#M4926201"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T10:31:22.188000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/full-stack-abap-application-in-build/qaa-p/14216398#M4926202</id>
    <title>Re: Full Stack ABAP Application In Build</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T10:47:28.082000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abinaya05</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1949642</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Even I am facing the same issue.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/full-stack-abap-application-in-build/qaa-p/14216398#M4926202"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T10:47:28.082000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/full-stack-abap-application-in-build/qaa-p/14216399#M4926203</id>
    <title>Re: Full Stack ABAP Application In Build</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T10:48:43.623000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abinaya05</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1949642</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Even I am facing the same issue.But &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3487"&gt;@sandeep&lt;/a&gt; how are you saying that the roles are assigned and connection is successful. We will not be able to access BTP with the credentials given for SAP Build right.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/full-stack-abap-application-in-build/qaa-p/14216399#M4926203"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T10:48:43.623000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/full-stack-abap-application-in-build/qaa-p/14216400#M4926204</id>
    <title>Re: Full Stack ABAP Application In Build</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T10:50:35.492000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abinaya05</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1949642</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Also it is saying to check the Prerequisites but we can't access the BTP directly with the credentials we have to check all configurations</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/full-stack-abap-application-in-build/qaa-p/14216400#M4926204"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T10:50:35.492000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-i-send-a-request-to-the-spa-workflow-from-custom-fiori-app/qaa-p/14216401#M4926205</id>
    <title>Re: how do I send a request to the SPA workflow from Cust...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T10:51:39.516000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hbeyazal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1429795</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I only see deployment logs. I couldn't find another detailed log.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-i-send-a-request-to-the-spa-workflow-from-custom-fiori-app/qaa-p/14216401#M4926205"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T10:51:39.516000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/improving-website-performance-with-sap-integration-insights/qaq-p/14216402</id>
    <title>Improving Website Performance with SAP Integration Insights</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T11:04:51.439000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jessy79</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253454</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I’ve been exploring how SAP solutions can support better &lt;STRONG&gt;site performance and user experience (&lt;A href="https://fashionismic.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Fashionismic.com&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;when businesses integrate their applications with SAP BTP. In particular, caching strategies, streamlined API calls, and optimized data models seem to play a big role.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From a UX perspective, performance directly influences how users engage with content-heavy sites, whether they’re running e-commerce stores, corporate portals, or creative platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’d love to hear from the community:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Which &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP tools or services&lt;/STRONG&gt; have you used to improve front-end performance?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any best practices for connecting SAP with modern CMS frameworks (like headless setups)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;How do you balance performance with personalization when pulling real-time data?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to your insights!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/improving-website-performance-with-sap-integration-insights/qaq-p/14216402"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T11:04:51.439000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/capacity-requirement-kpi-not-showing-in-schedule-labor-app-in-sap-dmc/qaa-p/14216406#M207046</id>
    <title>Re: Capacity Requirement KPI Not Showing in Schedule Labo...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T11:17:08.260000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMEDAMINE_MOUNA30</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2183492</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146"&gt;@mpavan_kumar&lt;/a&gt;Thank you for your response &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":folded_hands:"&gt;🙏&lt;/span&gt;. I already checked the Scheduling and Capacity Requirements settings in SPRO, and the option for Capacity Requirement is maintained correctly. But still, the Capacity Requirement in the Schedule Labor app is showing 0 hrs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MOHAMEDAMINE_MOUNA30_0-1757755044392.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313926i5CB43918EE35398C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MOHAMEDAMINE_MOUNA30_0-1757755044392.png" alt="MOHAMEDAMINE_MOUNA30_0-1757755044392.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/capacity-requirement-kpi-not-showing-in-schedule-labor-app-in-sap-dmc/qaa-p/14216406#M207046"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T11:17:08.260000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-i-send-a-request-to-the-spa-workflow-from-custom-fiori-app/qaa-p/14216410#M4926207</id>
    <title>Re: how do I send a request to the SPA workflow from Cust...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T12:13:06.371000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mpavan_kumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2248146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>in the BTP cockpit, go to Logs &amp;gt; Log Streams to view real-time logs for your application. Look for errors related to destination calls or authentication failures</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-i-send-a-request-to-the-spa-workflow-from-custom-fiori-app/qaa-p/14216410#M4926207"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T12:13:06.371000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/in-the-sap-public-cloud-mto-make-to-order-process-the-billing-document-type/qaa-p/14216411#M4227087</id>
    <title>Re: In the SAP Public Cloud MTO (Make-to-Order) process,...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T12:27:55.389000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;For information, in Public Cloud, CBTA is the standard item category for MTO (Make‑to‑Order) with item category group CB04. CBTA in the delivered scope items is usually set up for order‑related billing (billing relevance “I” – billing plan) rather than delivery‑related billing. Because of that, there is &lt;STRONG&gt;no&lt;/STRONG&gt; standard copying control entry from delivery type LF / item category CBTA to billing type F2; the system doesn’t expect you to bill from the delivery for this process. Hence, F2 is not being created in your case.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;SAP Note &lt;STRONG&gt;3269803&lt;/STRONG&gt; referred here, is a configuration content note that delivers missing copying control entries for certain item categories in S/4HANA Cloud. If your tenant is missing the LF → F2 copying control for CBTA and you want to enable delivery‑related billing for it, this note is relevant, but, in Public Cloud, you &lt;STRONG&gt;cannot&lt;/STRONG&gt; directly maintain VTFL/VTFA; you need to use the corresponding SSCUI or request SAP to adjust via Expert Configuration. The note itself won’t “switch” CBTA from order‑related to delivery‑related billing, but you’d also need to adjust the billing relevance in the item category and align the schedule line category.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If you want delivery‑related billing for MTO, CBTA’s billing relevance &lt;STRONG&gt;must be changed from “I” to “B”&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This is a scope/process change and hence, check if it aligns with your business requirement.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/in-the-sap-public-cloud-mto-make-to-order-process-the-billing-document-type/qaa-p/14216411#M4227087"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T12:27:55.389000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s4-public-cloud-0l-vs-4g-configuration/qaa-p/14216419#M4227088</id>
    <title>Re: S4 Public Cloud 0L vs 4G configuration</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T12:58:22.330000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131826"&gt;@JuliaLu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Yes, that is correct. If the customer requires Universal Parallel Accounting, then the Ledger 4G must be used. The partner should explain to the customer why 4G is required and that all process will follow the advance valuation framework.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If there is no requirement for Universal Parallel Accounting, then 4G should not be activated. Which means that in that case OL remains the leading ledger and all valuation will run against it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s4-public-cloud-0l-vs-4g-configuration/qaa-p/14216419#M4227088"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T12:58:22.330000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/why-is-my-content-marked-as-spam/bc-p/14216421#M853</id>
    <title>Re: Why Is My Content Marked as Spam?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T13:10:30.744000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sandeepmkh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/363791</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/23"&gt;@jerryjanda&lt;/a&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36" target="_blank"&gt;@AnnePetteroe&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;, could you&amp;nbsp; please release my blog , currently blocked due to spam!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;A class="" title="Https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/implementing-sap-emarsys-loyalty-management-part-1/ba-p/14216345" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/implementing-sap-emarsys-loyalty-management-part-1/ba-p/14216345" target="_blank"&gt;Https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/implementing-sap-emarsys-loyalty-management-part-1/ba-p/14216345&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Regards,&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Sandeep Kulkarni&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/why-is-my-content-marked-as-spam/bc-p/14216421#M853"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T13:10:30.744000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/manage-business-partner-edit-relationship-but-not-general-data/qaq-p/14216424</id>
    <title>Manage Business Partner-Edit Relationship but not General Data</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T13:21:12.171000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sunny_24</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/877764</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;I have a scenario (in SAP GTS e4H) where the business should be allowed to edit 'Relationships' of a Business Partner but not to change the 'General Data', as the&amp;nbsp; Business partners are coming from MDG (SAP System) and the persons are created locally in GTS.&lt;BR /&gt;Following is needed:&lt;BR /&gt;Create and edit person (Role BUP001) -&amp;gt; allowed&lt;BR /&gt;Assign contact person to a business partner (Organization)-&amp;gt; 'Relationships -&amp;gt; allowed&lt;BR /&gt;Change Business Partners (Organization) -&amp;gt; 'General Data' -&amp;gt; Not allowed&lt;BR /&gt;Would it help to restrict Change authorization to role 'BUP001' -&amp;gt; Authorization Object 'B_BUPA_RLT' -&amp;gt; ACTVT Change and RLTYP = 'BUP0001'&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/manage-business-partner-edit-relationship-but-not-general-data/qaq-p/14216424"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T13:21:12.171000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/manual-cheque-number-assignment-for-outgoing-payments/qaq-p/14216428</id>
    <title>Manual Cheque Number Assignment for Outgoing Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T13:34:42.176000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>silambarasan_RS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/184599</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are working on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Private Cloud 2023.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;is there any option for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;manual cheque number assignment&lt;/STRONG&gt; for outgoing payments / cheque payment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our requirement:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We want to record the outgoing payment / supplier payment using the&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;manual cheque number&lt;/STRONG&gt; (instead of system-generated sequence).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have already defined cheque lots in &lt;STRONG&gt;FCHI&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but the system is still proposing cheque numbers automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;How can we configure cheque lots so that the system allows us to &lt;STRONG&gt;enter the cheque number manually&lt;/STRONG&gt; while posting outgoing payments (F-58 or F110)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;is there a way to override the system-generated cheque number with a manual one?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any guidance, best practices, or SAP notes would be highly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thanks &amp;amp; Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;silambarasan R&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/manual-cheque-number-assignment-for-outgoing-payments/qaq-p/14216428"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T13:34:42.176000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/material-xxxx-does-not-exist-in-storage-location-usna-s001/qaa-p/14216433#M4227090</id>
    <title>Re: Material XXXX does not exist in storage location USNA...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T13:52:14.347000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Myselfsantanu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1903428</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;if all necessary assignments are ok, Please check the Plant code mentioned in the CMIR. Erase the Plant record and save it. I hope the issue in PGI will be resolved.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/material-xxxx-does-not-exist-in-storage-location-usna-s001/qaa-p/14216433#M4227090"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T13:52:14.347000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/hello/qaq-p/14216434</id>
    <title>Hello</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T13:53:49.598000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mg01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/126201</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am Mallika.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/hello/qaq-p/14216434"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T13:53:49.598000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/restricting-user-level-read-and-delete-access-datasphere/qaa-p/14216440#M4926210</id>
    <title>Re: Restricting User-Level Read and Delete Access - Datas...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T14:18:16.258000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Martin_Kuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/275733</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, I think that the question is more business user oriented. Not developer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In DSP the DACs control data, but not objects.&amp;nbsp;Only views support DACs anyway, so you cannot add DACs to a table at all. You also cannot allow/disallow access to specific objects to specific users. This is done space-wide.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If uploading data into DSP via CSV, you assume a developer is uploading, not a business user. So a developer has full access to the table.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Separated space for each Conso Unit would be the best approach. Another way would be to create a separate Space for CSVs, then for each Conso Unit one table, however this will not restrict the users to see 'other' tables if the want.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maybe the best way is to pre-stage the upload into SharePoint. Create an SFTP Connection from DSP to FTP server and upload the files automatically every night via task chain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Martin&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/restricting-user-level-read-and-delete-access-datasphere/qaa-p/14216440#M4926210"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T14:18:16.258000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/katowice-discussions/kilka-s%C5%82%C3%B3w-o-devtoberfest-2025/td-p/14216441</id>
    <title>Kilka słów o Devtoberfest 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T14:35:30.854000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ewelina</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-2147338842"&gt;W oczekiwaniu na największe święto w świecie SAP, czyli SAP TechEd 2025, SAP zapewnia nam 4 tygodnie dobrej zabawy podczas Devtoberfest 2025.&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Już 29 września zaczyna się festiwal dla developerów, pełen wyzwań programistycznych z dawką świetnej zabawy. Wspominałam o tym w poście na &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/katowice-discussions/nadchodz%C4%85ce-wydarzenia-sap-community-lato-jesie%C5%84-2025/td-p/14203484" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community Katowice&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Teraz tylko krótko opiszę o co chodzi i o co toczy się gra&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Najprościej mówiąc, celem gry jest osiągnięcie Nerdvana. Wśród tych "nerdów", którzy ten cel osiągną, rozlosowanych będzie 10 zwycięzców, którym zasponsorowany będzie wyjazd wraz z wejściówką na przyszłoroczny SAP TechEd 2026 wraz z dniem spędzonym razem z zespołem developer advocates! Każda aktywność podczas Devtoberfest jest punktowana, a najwięcej punktów możesz zdobyć w tzw. "scavenger hunt of 20 tutorials".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Jeżeli nie chcesz, to nie musisz brać udziału w grze, by móc uczestniczyć w aktywnościach Devtoberfest! To, co może część z nas zainteresować, to np. część edukacyjna Devtoberfest. Będzie to 7 bloków tematycznych w 5 dniach tygodnia, które będą nam towarzyszyć przez 4 tygodnie:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Poniedziałek – ABAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wtorek – Tooling &amp;amp; Frontend&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Środa – Integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Czwartek – Data &amp;amp; AI&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Piątek – CAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Udanego Devtoberfest 2025!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Jeszcze więcej informacji znajdziesz &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/gh-p/Devtoberfest" target="_blank"&gt;pod linkiem&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/katowice-discussions/kilka-s%C5%82%C3%B3w-o-devtoberfest-2025/td-p/14216441"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T14:35:30.854000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-to-send-a-message-through-sap-event-mesh-using-abap-code/qaq-p/14216442</id>
    <title>How to send a message through SAP Event Mesh using Abap code?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T14:56:05.991000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mustafacengizde62</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/623514</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;BR /&gt;Below code is trying to send a message through Event Mesh based on the status change of a&amp;nbsp; Freight Order in SAP TM. I always get HTTP 404 at the end. Can anyone tell me which part of this code is wrong? I need help especially with the URI part.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;REPORT zdemo_event_mesh_4.

DATA: lo_oa2c_client TYPE REF TO if_oauth2_client.
DATA(lv_dest_name)    = 'sample_dest_name'.
DATA(lv_auth_profile) = '/IWXBE/MGW_MQTT'.

cl_http_client=&amp;gt;create_by_destination(
  EXPORTING
    destination                = lv_dest_name
  IMPORTING
    client                     = DATA(lo_http_client)
  EXCEPTIONS
    argument_not_found         = 1
    destination_not_found      = 2
    destination_no_authority   = 3
    plugin_not_active          = 4
    internal_error             = 5
    oa2c_set_token_error       = 6
    oa2c_missing_authorization = 7
    oa2c_invalid_config        = 8
    oa2c_invalid_parameters    = 9
    oa2c_invalid_scope         = 10
    oa2c_invalid_grant         = 11
    oa2c_secstore_adm          = 12
    OTHERS                     = 13 ).

IF sy-subrc IS NOT INITIAL.
  BREAK-POINT.
ENDIF.

lo_http_client-&amp;gt;propertytype_logon_popup = if_http_client=&amp;gt;co_disabled.

TRY.
    cl_oauth2_client=&amp;gt;create( EXPORTING i_profile      = CONV #( lv_auth_profile ) i_configuration = 'sample_conf_id'
                              RECEIVING ro_oauth2_client = lo_oa2c_client ).
  CATCH cx_oa2c.
    BREAK-POINT.
ENDTRY.

TRY.
    lo_oa2c_client-&amp;gt;set_token( EXPORTING io_http_client = lo_http_client ).
  CATCH cx_oa2c.
    TRY.
        CALL METHOD lo_oa2c_client-&amp;gt;execute_cc_flow.
      CATCH cx_oa2c.
        BREAK-POINT.
    ENDTRY.

    TRY.
        lo_oa2c_client-&amp;gt;set_token( EXPORTING io_http_client = lo_http_client ).
      CATCH cx_oa2c.
        BREAK-POINT.
    ENDTRY.
ENDTRY.

DATA(ls_payload) = VALUE zmc_s_demo( carrier = 'Demo Carrier'
                                     transportation_mode = '0001'
                                     transportation_order = 'Demo Order'
                                     transportation_order_exec_sts = '07'
                                     transportation_order_type = 'Outbound'
                                     transportation_order_uuid = 'cd88888c-292b-44a8-bb9a-888888888814'
                                     transportation_shipping_type = 'Demo Type'
                                     __before-transportation_order_exec_sts = '04' ).

DATA(lv_payload) = /ui2/cl_json=&amp;gt;serialize( data        = ls_payload
                                            pretty_name = /ui2/cl_json=&amp;gt;pretty_mode-camel_case ).

DATA lv_payload_x TYPE xstring.

CALL FUNCTION 'SCMS_STRING_TO_XSTRING'
  EXPORTING
    text   = lv_payload
  IMPORTING
    buffer = lv_payload_x.

cl_http_utility=&amp;gt;set_request_uri( EXPORTING  request = lo_http_client-&amp;gt;request
*                                  uri     = '/messagingrest/v1/queues/Default/D40100EMMulSft/1/Default/D40100EMMulSft/1/FreightOrder/messages/consumption' ).
*                                  uri     = '/messagingrest/v1/queues/sap/s4/beh/FreightOrder/ExecStatusChanged/v1/messages' ).
                                  uri     = '/messagingrest/v1/topics/sap/s4/beh/FreightOrder/ExecStatusChanged/v1/messages' ).
*                                  uri     = 'sap/s4/beh/FreightOrder/ExecStatusChanged/v1' ).
*                                  uri     = 'Default/D40100EMMulSft/1/Default/D40100EMMulSft/1/FreightOrder' ).

lo_http_client-&amp;gt;request-&amp;gt;set_method( 'POST' ).
lo_http_client-&amp;gt;request-&amp;gt;set_content_type( 'application/json' ).
lo_http_client-&amp;gt;request-&amp;gt;set_data( lv_payload_x ).

lo_http_client-&amp;gt;send(
    EXCEPTIONS
      http_communication_failure = 1
      http_invalid_state         = 2 ).

lo_http_client-&amp;gt;receive(
  EXCEPTIONS
    http_communication_failure = 1
    http_invalid_state         = 2
    http_processing_failed     = 3 ).

DATA lv_response TYPE string.
lv_response = lo_http_client-&amp;gt;response-&amp;gt;get_cdata( ).

IF lv_response IS NOT INITIAL.
  BREAK-POINT.
ENDIF.

lo_http_client-&amp;gt;response-&amp;gt;get_status( IMPORTING code = DATA(lv_code) ).

WRITE: lv_code.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-to-send-a-message-through-sap-event-mesh-using-abap-code/qaq-p/14216442"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T14:56:05.991000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-community-2024-qa-formatting-quot-increase-indent-quot-doesn-t-work/qaa-p/14216445#M62099</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community 2024 QA formatting "Increase Indent" do...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T15:08:52.789000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnePetteroe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194"&gt;@Sandra_Rossi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- short answer here is that this is not a bug, but rather the editor working as intended with the current supported tags that we shared in Marian's thread. We are working on enabling additional tags, that should support your use case here.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-community-2024-qa-formatting-quot-increase-indent-quot-doesn-t-work/qaa-p/14216445#M62099"/>
    <published>2025-09-13T15:08:52.789000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
