<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-09-02T22:59:01.563402+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/handling-unit-in-shpcon-idoc-ends-up-in-error-vla311/qaq-p/14204886</id>
    <title>Handling unit in SHPCON  IDoc ends up in error  VLA311</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:02:30.863000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HariTummala</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1586264</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Scenario : Intercompany STo where Sending Plant is EWM managed and Receiving site is IM level plant representing 3PL.&lt;BR /&gt;STO - OBD - pick pack and PGI in EWM posted, updates in ERP side as well.&lt;BR /&gt;Automatic Inbound delivery gets created with Handling units copied on it.&lt;BR /&gt;Initially the status of the HU's will be PSTD after PGi of OBD posting a 68C movement.&lt;BR /&gt;When i am trying to post the GR (109) of the Inbound delivery via SHPCON IDOC adding E!EDL37 HU segment system ends up in error VLA311. How to reolve this? Further i wanted to also check if the same handling units can be returned to Sending site in OBD which will create another IBD getting the HU's copied so that the receipt part would be simple&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If anyone has the same scenario pls help to guide how this should be handled?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/handling-unit-in-shpcon-idoc-ends-up-in-error-vla311/qaq-p/14204886"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:02:30.863000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/fin-de-vida-de-onboarding-1-0-en-sap-successfactors/bc-p/14204890#M7087</id>
    <title>Re: Fin de vida de Onboarding 1.0 en SAP SuccessFactors</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:04:59.954000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lukemarson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/123003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The Silicon Partners (TSP) has developed an RPA-based solution that automates much of the transformation from Onboarding 1.0 to the new Onboarding, while allowing for process transformations, at a much lower price than a full re-implementation. I recommend customers who are looking to move to check this out:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://thesiliconpartners.com/successfactors-onboarding-migration-solution/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://thesiliconpartners.com/successfactors-onboarding-migration-solution/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/fin-de-vida-de-onboarding-1-0-en-sap-successfactors/bc-p/14204890#M7087"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:04:59.954000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-shipment-visibility-with-shippeo-and-sap-business-network-global/ba-p/14186181</id>
    <title>Unlocking Shipment Visibility with Shippeo and SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:05:10.641000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CorinnaKramer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148625</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The new &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Endorsed App data-as-a-service offering from Shippeo&lt;/STRONG&gt; marks a significant advancement for customers of &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Network+Global+Track+and+Trace/pd-p/73555000100800000602" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="635-1"&gt;SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, providing an easy and straightforward way to acquire shipment tracking data. This partnership provides a streamlined data-as-a-service solution, bringing real-time transportation visibility directly into SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace, enabling you to embed business-critical logistics insights within your SAP landscape&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this article, we will explore how this partnership works, focusing on the roles of each key player involved and the specifics around each mode of transport.&lt;BR /&gt;________________________________________&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Each Player’s Role in the Ecosystem&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace serves as a collaborative B2B platform that connects shippers and carriers, enabling efficient transportation management. It integrates seamlessly with SAP S/4HANA Transportation Management and LE-TRA, supporting the complete shipment execution process. Carriers can onboard directly into SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace or work through a visibility provider such as Shippeo.&amp;nbsp; See &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/shippeo-real-time-visibility-for-sap-business-network-global-track-and/ba-p/14204664" target="_blank"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt; for more about the value to your business.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using Shippeo as a visibility provider simplifies onboarding and easily scales by replacing complex peer-to-peer connections with a scalable, one-to-many network. Shippers gain instant access to multiple carriers through a single platform, while carriers only need one integration with Shippeo to collaborate across many shipments and customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s examine the roles of each participant in this ecosystem:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CorinnaKramer_0-1755775181239.png" style="width: 849px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303510iAE277E402ACA1E85/image-dimensions/849x174/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="849" height="174" role="button" title="CorinnaKramer_0-1755775181239.png" alt="CorinnaKramer_0-1755775181239.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA Transportation Management and LE-TRA act as the backend systems responsible for processing sales or purchase orders related to shipments. These systems are responsible for shipment planning, execution, and data management, providing the foundational information needed for transportation activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace handles the tracking of planned versus actual freight order execution. It provides status reporting as well as impact analysis by correlating individual shipment events to specific deliveries or orders. On top of that the platform incorporates embedded logic for event-driven notifications, for example to inform stakeholders about delays.&lt;BR /&gt;Shippeo initializes tracking with carriers, processes milestones and exceptions, and calculates both ETAs and ETDs using predictive analytics. It can also provide data on carbon emissions enriching the shipment data with business-relevant insights.&lt;BR /&gt;Carriers supply real-time location data through GPS devices installed on vehicles, vessels, or containers or share milestone updates.&lt;BR /&gt;________________________________________&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Multimodal transport scenarios are supported, accommodating different modes of transportation with mode-specific tracking approaches. Here, we focus on how Shippeo interacts with carriers after a tracking request is initiated from SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace for various transport modes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Road Transportation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Support for road transport includes Full Truck Loads (FTL) and Less-than-Truck Loads (LTL) carried out across the globe. Shippeo employs a hierarchical approach to initialize tracking based on available identifiers. This includes integration with carrier systems or with delegated fleet, direct ELD telematics or manual tracking input via mobile app or the Shippeo Web portal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CorinnaKramer_1-1755775255689.png" style="width: 863px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303511iA3FAD88B953C12BC/image-dimensions/863x259/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="863" height="259" role="button" title="CorinnaKramer_1-1755775255689.png" alt="CorinnaKramer_1-1755775255689.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For FTL shipments, real-time location updates are received from carriers through GPS, telematics, or smartphone applications. The system enriches these updates with geo-fencing and localized traffic or weather data, allowing dynamic, predictive ETAs that respond to real-time road conditions and driver hours of service regulations. Additionally, carbon emissions are measured in accordance with the GLEC (Global Logistics Emissions Council) protocol, providing sustainability insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;LTL shipments benefit from milestone updates and associated emissions data, enabling shippers to track progress at key points and evaluate environmental impact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ocean Freight&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Ocean shipments—whether port-to-port or inland—are supported through a combination of web scraping and direct carrier integrations. These tracking methods utilize container identifiers such as the Container ID, SCAC (Standard Carrier Alpha Code), and booking references like the Master Bill of Lading (MBL) or EDI messages such as LOA (Letter of Authorization, EDI 315).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CorinnaKramer_2-1755775310087.png" style="width: 870px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303512i02C269D9638D3ADF/image-dimensions/870x420/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="870" height="420" role="button" title="CorinnaKramer_2-1755775310087.png" alt="CorinnaKramer_2-1755775310087.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The integration hierarchy starts with Shippeo extracting status information via web scraping and progresses to direct container and vessel tracking using the carrier’s connected systems. Container GPS updates are generated approximately every six hours, providing timely position information, while vessel locations and ETAs are updated with similar frequency. Shippeo also delivers container milestone updates shortly after they occur, alongside carbon emissions data at shipment closure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;________________________________________&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The partnership between SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace and Shippeo simplifies carrier onboarding and provides enriched, real-time tracking data within the SAP ecosystem. The new Shippeo Endorsed App data-as-a-service empowers businesses to make smarter, timelier logistics decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more, visit the Shippeo press release (&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.shippeo.com/press-releases/real-time-transportation-visibility-data-as-a-service-from-shippeo---now-available-as-sap-endorsed-app-on-sap-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;English&lt;/A&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.shippeo.com/press-releases/les-donnees-de-visibilite-de-transport-de-shippeo-comme-data-as-a-service-desormais-disponibles-en-tant-que-sap-endorsed-app-dans-le-sap-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Français&lt;/A&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.shippeo.com/press-releases/shippeo-bringt-data-as-a-service-fur-echtzeit-transparenz-im-transportwesen-als-sap-endorsed-app-in-den-sap-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Deutsch&lt;/A&gt;)&amp;nbsp;and explore the SAP Business Network Global Track and Trace product page. This collaboration exemplifies SAP's commitment to delivering smarter, more transparent supply chains—enabling your organization to stay ahead in today’s complex logistics environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;________________________________________&lt;BR /&gt;For questions or further discussions, feel free to leave a comment below!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-shipment-visibility-with-shippeo-and-sap-business-network-global/ba-p/14186181"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:05:10.641000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/e-error-converting-to-time-stamp-in-n-scwm-rfui/qaa-p/14204891#M4226108</id>
    <title>Re: E: Error converting to time stamp (In /N/SCWM/RFUI)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:07:43.810000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Some of the root causes could be&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;even if the format is mm/dd/yyyy, hidden characters can cause parsing failures. Your user profile settings may show the correct format, but, if the system time zone is different, then, you will have this issue.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Coming to RFUI transactions, it rely on precise time stamp. If your inbound delivery has a date &amp;amp; time that is not converted properly, then, you will have this issue.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Finally and most importantly, if one of the HU has incorrect date/time format, it will affect the entire delivery.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Also, see whether you need to carry out code corrections as recommended in SAP note&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2090154&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/e-error-converting-to-time-stamp-in-n-scwm-rfui/qaa-p/14204891#M4226108"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:07:43.810000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/it-is-not-possible-to-verify-credit-in-bp-of-different-segments/qaq-p/14204892</id>
    <title>It is not possible to verify credit in BP of different Segments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:11:13.596000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GustavoStevens2024</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1789508</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When verifying credit in a BP with different segments, the BP"s original segment is not considered. A message is displayed indicating that the BP has no data in the segment. The relationship between the BPs is FUKM001.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/it-is-not-possible-to-verify-credit-in-bp-of-different-segments/qaq-p/14204892"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:11:13.596000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/handling-unit-in-shpcon-idoc-ends-up-in-error-vla311/qaa-p/14204894#M206771</id>
    <title>Re: Handling unit in SHPCON IDoc ends up in error VLA311</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:12:18.201000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Check SAP notes 2754417 &amp;amp; 1050944&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/handling-unit-in-shpcon-idoc-ends-up-in-error-vla311/qaa-p/14204894#M206771"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:12:18.201000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/which-gid-for-sapsys-i-should-enter-if-central-instance-on-windows/qaa-p/14204895#M4924904</id>
    <title>Re: Which GID for sapsys I should enter if central instan...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:15:34+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mamartins</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45950</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you want to install another Application Server (also known as a Additional Application Server - &lt;STRONG&gt;AAS&lt;/STRONG&gt;), you should use the same SID as the ASCS/PAS.&amp;nbsp; The instance number could be anyone because it's a new server, but the recommendation is to use a different one from the already used ones.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This document is valid for S/4HANA, but doesn't differ much from a traditional ERP:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/technical-implementation-and-operation-ii-of-sap-s-4hana-and-sap-business-suite/installing-an-aas" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/courses/technical-implementation-and-operation-ii-of-sap-s-4hana-and-sap-business-suite/installing-an-aas&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/which-gid-for-sapsys-i-should-enter-if-central-instance-on-windows/qaa-p/14204895#M4924904"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:15:34+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-odata-connector-for-powerbi/bc-p/14204896#M184214</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Datasphere: OData Connector for PowerBi</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:15:43.087000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>albertosimeoni</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/829608</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we tested this and the problem is that the token expires and it needs a manual authentication through browser.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;in july 2025 SAP release a new Oauth 2.0 client purpose called "Tecnical User".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;this technical user have an expire time window up to 20 years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Basically the authentication is with Client ID, client secret and user name (not password).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The problem is that even if authenticated it can not read Odata from views and analytic models, but this is only a soft limit set up by SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I open an improvement request to unlock this functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;please feel free to upvote.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/355555" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/355555&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-odata-connector-for-powerbi/bc-p/14204896#M184214"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:15:43.087000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/leveraging-sap-reference-architecture-for-event-driven-application-in/ba-p/14204897</id>
    <title>Leveraging SAP Reference Architecture for Event-Driven Application in Missing Part Fulfilment Busine</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:15:58.170000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Cocquerel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/754</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the era of Industry 4.0, the ability to respond to real-time events in industrial production is crucial for operational efficiency. This blog outlines a proof of concept (PoC) that demonstrates how Airbus leveraged SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), SAP Build Process Automation (BPA), and Events-to-Business Actions Framework to automate and orchestrate the missing part fulfillment process within production operations. The solution leverages an event-driven architecture to automate business processes based on missing part fulfillment in real-time.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This architecture is highly repeatable and can be applied to a wide range of SAP scenarios such as plant maintenance, purchase requisitions, inventory updates, and more, making it a valuable reference for enterprises looking to scale event-driven integrations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Engagement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Cocquerel_0-1756829031891.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308081i7565797D7242D648/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Cocquerel_0-1756829031891.png" alt="Cocquerel_0-1756829031891.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The outcome described in this article was facilitated by custom adaptation of the Events-to-Business-Actions Framework by Airbus and was supported by SAP OCTO Team under &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/pavankumarpvn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;PVN Pavankumar&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario : Missing Part Fulfilment in Production&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The use case centres on streamlining the missing part fulfilment process within Airbus production operations. It begins when a missing part is detected for a work order reservation in the SAP ECC backend, which supports day-to-day production activities. From that initial identification, the process continues all the way through to the confirmation of the work order operation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Throughout this journey, the workflow leverages an event-driven architecture (EDA) to track progress in real time, integrating seamlessly with backend systems. SAP Build Process Automation (BPA) orchestrates collaboration between all involved actors by sending out forms and notifications, gathering approvals, and automating decisions based on predefined business rules. Additionally, the PoC highlights the real-time monitoring and dashboarding features of SAP Build Process Automation, ensuring end-to-end visibility across the process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This PoC showcases how we made that happen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Below is the architecture diagram representing the technical landscape for the missing part fulfilment process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Cocquerel_1-1756829031891.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308082i8B4EA8BC88B1E716/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Cocquerel_1-1756829031891.png" alt="Cocquerel_1-1756829031891.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Figure 1: End-to-end architecture of the Airbus missing part fulfillment solution using SAP BTP, Advanced Event Mesh, E2B Framework, and custom Node.js applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Implementation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This architecture leverages key components across SAP BTP, Advanced Event Mesh, and custom applications to create a robust event-to-action pipeline: The Solution Architecture is illustrated in Figure 1, and the important components along with their connectivity are explained below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business events are triggered:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Different actors interact with the SAP backend (supporting production operations). Transactions such as work order reservations, purchase orders, or outbound deliveries generate relevant business events.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Events are routed to SAP Integration Suite, Advanced Event Mesh (AEM):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These events are sent to SAP Integration Suite, Advanced Event Mesh—either directly or via Solace event brokers in Airbus Private Cloud, especially if events need to be shared with other platforms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Event-specific queues manage the flow:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Within SAP Integration Suite, Advanced Event Mesh, specific queues collect events related to predefined topics, pushing them into the Events to Business Actions (E2B) framework.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business logic and workflows are triggered:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;E2B calls SAP Build Process Automation (BPA) APIs to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Apply decision rules and determine what business action should occur based on the event payload,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Launch new workflow instances,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Update waiting tasks on running workflows,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Push events to visibility scenarios for process monitoring.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Backend queries for richer context:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;E2B also calls backend APIs to fetch more information related to business objects—such as:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Details of a reservation linked to a purchase order,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The specific station tied to a work order reservation,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The list of actors involved, leveraging Responsibility Management in SAP S/4HANA based on attributes like station.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Traceability with PartsNow:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;PartsNow, is a custom SAP Cloud Application Programming (CAP,Node.js) application, used to persist the relationship between workflow instance IDs and related work order reservation IDs. E2B registers new workflow instances and can retrieve instance details as needed via PartsNow APIs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified user experience in SAP Build Workzone:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Workzone serves as the entry point for business actors, providing:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My Inbox&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; For completing tasks such as form fills or approvals,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My Processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; For real-time workflow monitoring,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Process Visibility Dashboard&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; To track KPIs and process efficiency,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Studio Home&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Where process specialists can manage BPA decision rules.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated notifications and integration points:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finally, SAP BPA calls remote APIs to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Inform the PartsNow app about workflow instance completion,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Send email notifications to relevant actors via an SMTP server.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Developer Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a developer building this PoC, a few key learnings stand out:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Loose coupling using SAP Integration Suite, Advanced Event Mesh and queues ensures resiliency and scalability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Decision capability in SAP Build Process Automation allowed us to externalize complex logic from the app code, making it easier to maintain and extend.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using SAP BTP Destinations and Service Bindings helped standardize secure backend access across environments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deployment Steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Follow this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-events-to-business-actions-framework/tree/main/scenarios/Integration-with-AWS/IoTSiteWise" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GitHub documentation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;for detailed steps for configuration and deployment.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Closing Remarks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We hope this blog has inspired new ideas for applying event-driven automation to your own business processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Refer to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/docs/ref-arch/fbdc46aaae" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Architecture Centre&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-events-to-business-actions-framework/tree/main" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Events-to-Business-Actions Framework Repository&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for implementation details.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks to colleagues from SAP OCTO Team &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/praveenkumarpadegal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Praveen Kumar Padegal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/swati-maste/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Swati Maste&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for their support.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/leveraging-sap-reference-architecture-for-event-driven-application-in/ba-p/14204897"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:15:58.170000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/validation-required-for-the-migo-screen/m-p/14204899#M2042411</id>
    <title>Re: Validation required for the MIGO screen</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:17:22.769000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jady</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1737480</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When entering the order, can the movement type be updated automatically?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Jady_0-1756829889053.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308085i69CA3E451B710F13/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Jady_0-1756829889053.png" alt="Jady_0-1756829889053.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/validation-required-for-the-migo-screen/m-p/14204899#M2042411"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:17:22.769000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/it-is-not-possible-to-verify-credit-in-bp-of-different-segments/qaa-p/14204906#M4226110</id>
    <title>Re: It is not possible to verify credit in BP of differen...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:23:05.133000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Check the following: -&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;whether you have full authorization which can be done via &lt;STRONG&gt;su53&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;whether parent BP has credit data maintained for the relevant segment in &lt;STRONG&gt;UKM_BP&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Verify the relationship for &lt;STRONG&gt;FUKM001&lt;/STRONG&gt; which should be from parent to child; and similarly, for &lt;STRONG&gt;TUKM001&lt;/STRONG&gt; from child to parent&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/it-is-not-possible-to-verify-credit-in-bp-of-different-segments/qaa-p/14204906#M4226110"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:23:05.133000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/full-payment-submission-amendment-reversal/qaa-p/14204907#M4226111</id>
    <title>Re: Full Payment Submission Amendment reversal</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:23:36.231000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/159972"&gt;@Plamo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To correct an FPSA (Full Payment Submission Adjustment) sent with the wrong payroll period, especially when it concerns a Class 1A termination payment, the recommended approach for UK HMRC RTI reporting using SAP or similar payroll systems is as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reverse the Incorrect FPSA by submitting a new FPSA for the same payroll period as the incorrect submission but enter the Class 1A value as a negative amount to reverse the original entry. This will offset the previously submitted amount and signal to HMRC that you are amending the record for that period.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Then, submit the FPSA with the correct payroll period and the correct positive Class 1A value for the termination payment. Ensure that all other details on the resubmitted FPSA match the intended correct values.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the correction involves a previous payroll period or a late submission, select H correction to earlier submission as the reason for late reporting in your FPS submission. This is usually a drop-down or a field in the SAP upload template. You do not need to use an X in the template for reversal. Current RTI does not support that EYU marker. Corrections are handled via the negative value in the FPS and late reason.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HMRC systems use year-to-date figures as authoritative, so your amended FPSA should correctly reflect cumulative totals after the reversal and correction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ERP_HCM_SPV/2faabee7f54e4bb6be6b4260c58dfec0/94fddd5321e8424de10000000a174cb4.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=EHP5_HRSP_J4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Payroll Processing with the Payroll for the United Kingdom Solution&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the neccessary insights. Happy to answer any further question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/full-payment-submission-amendment-reversal/qaa-p/14204907#M4226111"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:23:36.231000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/content-repository-migration-in-mind/bc-p/14204908#M61695</id>
    <title>Re: Content Repository Migration in mind ?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:25:07.654000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sigurdur</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179748</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I needed to use report ZMIGRATE_ARCHIVELINK_FILES_ENH of&amp;nbsp;oss note 1043676 - Migration of ArchiveLink Documents&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To move contents from our old content server over to a new one&amp;nbsp; somewhere around 820.000 documents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The report did the work correctly, but there is a problem with temp files the report puts in directory DIR_GLOBAL&lt;BR /&gt;i.e. on my system /usr/sap/IPP/SYS/global/&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Those files are NOT deleted after use an pile up on the app server until the disk space is filled up.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To get around this I had to modify the code from&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/1043676" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/1043676&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"modified main form
form main.
* get docids to be processed
  perform get_docids using old_arc changing docs.
  perform get_pl_docids using old_arc changing docs.

* remove duplicates to process each document only once
  sort docs by doc_id doc_type.
  delete adjacent duplicates from docs.
  write: / 'FOUND ', lines( docs ), 'ITEMS'.
  if max_coun gt 0.
    write : ' LIMITED TO ', max_coun.
  endif.
  uline.

  data(lv_counter) = 0.
  loop at docs into doc.
    add 1 to lv_counter.
    clear new_doc_id.
* get current document status
    perform check_status using old_arc doc-doc_id changing status doc_type.
    if test_run ne 'X'.
* Check the status of the document and start the copying process
      if status = 'ONLINE'.
        perform copy_doc
          using old_arc doc-doc_id doc-doc_type test_run
          changing new_arc new_doc_id.
        if not new_doc_id is initial.
*     update all effected connections
          perform update_connections using old_arc doc-doc_id new_arc
          new_doc_id.

          perform update_pl_connections using old_arc doc-doc_id new_arc
          new_doc_id.
        endif.
        commit work.
      endif.
    endif.
    if lv_counter gt 499 and lv_counter mod 500 eq 0.
      perform clean_temp_files using abap_false.
    endif.
    if max_coun gt 0 and lv_counter ge max_coun.
      exit.
    endif.
  endloop.

  if test_run ne 'X'.
    perform clean_temp_files using abap_true.
  endif.
endform.

"New function
form clean_temp_files using uv_clean_all.
  data:
    lv_pvalue    type tpfyvalue-value,
    lv_dir_name  type eps2filnam,
    lv_file_mask type epsf-epsfilnam,
    lv_fdate     type datum,
    lv_ftime     type uzeit,
    lv_cut_time  type uzeit,
    lt_dir_list  type standard table of eps2fili.

  call function 'SXPG_PROFILE_PARAMETER_GET'
    exporting
      parameter_name  = 'DIR_GLOBAL'
    importing
      parameter_value = lv_pvalue.

  lv_dir_name = |{ lv_pvalue }/|.
  lv_file_mask = |{ sy-sysid case = lower }{ sy-mandt }*|.
  call function 'EPS2_GET_DIRECTORY_LISTING'
    exporting
      iv_dir_name            = lv_dir_name
      file_mask              = lv_file_mask
    tables
      dir_list               = lt_dir_list
    exceptions
      invalid_eps_subdir     = 1
      sapgparam_failed       = 2
      build_directory_failed = 3
      no_authorization       = 4
      read_directory_failed  = 5
      too_many_read_errors   = 6
      empty_directory_list   = 7
      others                 = 8.
  if sy-subrc eq 0.
    " 26.05.2025 14:03:03
    if uv_clean_all is not initial.
      lv_cut_time = sy-uzeit.
    else.
      lv_cut_time = sy-uzeit - 1800.
    endif.
    write : / |Delete from: { lv_dir_name } Older than: { sy-datum } { lv_cut_time }|.
    loop at lt_dir_list into data(ls_file).
      concatenate ls_file-mtim+6(4) ls_file-mtim+3(2) ls_file-mtim(2) into lv_fdate.
      concatenate ls_file-mtim+11(2) ls_file-mtim+14(2) ls_file-mtim+17(2) into lv_ftime.

      if ( lv_fdate lt sy-datum ) or ( lv_fdate eq sy-datum and lv_ftime lt lv_cut_time ).
        call function 'EPS_DELETE_FILE'
          exporting
            iv_long_file_name      = conv eps2filnam( ls_file-name )
            dir_name               = conv epsf-epsdirnam( lv_dir_name )
          exceptions
            invalid_eps_subdir     = 1
            sapgparam_failed       = 2
            build_directory_failed = 3
            no_authorization       = 4
            build_path_failed      = 5
            delete_failed          = 6
            others                 = 7.
        if sy-subrc eq 0.
          write : / |Delete temp file: { ls_file-name } { ls_file-mtim }|.
        else.
          write : / |Failed to delete file: { ls_file-name } { ls_file-mtim }|.
        endif.

      endif.

    endloop.
  endif.

endform.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/content-repository-migration-in-mind/bc-p/14204908#M61695"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:25:07.654000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/feed-sap-help-ui5-apis-amp-sap-community-content-into-your-ai-with-this/bc-p/14204910#M175251</id>
    <title>Re: Feed SAP Help, UI5 APIs &amp; SAP Community Content into your AI with this Open Source MCP Serve</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:26:16.899000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DiegoValdivia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143362</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/61"&gt;@Marian_Zeis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This solution is fantastic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Until now, whenever I needed "help" on some new topic, I downloaded full sections from sap help, uploaded them to Claude and started making questions. I'll try your solution ASAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By any chance you have Tutorial, video or post providing a brief overview about how to create the MCP Server and most of all, how to feed it with specific documentation? Nothing fancy, just a brief guidance would be enough.&amp;nbsp; I've been working in SAP during the last 19 years (ABAP, Workflow, Fiori and RAP). I always document all the things I learn, but after all these time, it's became a bit difficult to remember where I put certain files I created many years ago. I've been searching for some AI solutions but&amp;nbsp; haven't found anything useful yet (though I started this research a couple of days ago).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I did some tests with Claude Connectors, but somehow it's now able to find my files in Google Drive. I was planning to try ChatGPT and see if I have better luck.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm taking a Data Science Bootcamp, as of now, I'm good at Python and I'm about to complete the Machine Learning Units, though there's still some months pending before I reach the AI, Agents and MCP stuff.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/feed-sap-help-ui5-apis-amp-sap-community-content-into-your-ai-with-this/bc-p/14204910#M175251"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:26:16.899000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/migo-add-default-value-using-badi-user-exit/m-p/14204916#M2042412</id>
    <title>Re: MIGO add default value using BADI/User-Exit</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:27:30.947000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jady</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1737480</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When entering the order, can the movement type be updated automatically?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Jady_1-1756830515035.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308094iA11E7A4FE1719C0A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Jady_1-1756830515035.png" alt="Jady_1-1756830515035.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/migo-add-default-value-using-badi-user-exit/m-p/14204916#M2042412"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:27:30.947000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/no-service-found-for-namespace/qaq-p/14204919</id>
    <title>No service found for namespace ''</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:28:37.765000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GuilhermeBaptista</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2003924</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I'm trying to run some transactional features in JOULE, but I'm encountering the error "No service found for namespace" in IWFND/ERROR_LOG. I've encountered the same error more than once. I've looked for the service in IWFND/MAINT_SERVICE and also the node in SICF, but it doesn't seem to exist in my backend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could someone help me with guidance on what to do in this case, and how to obtain these services?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BASIS, SAP BW, SAP_GWFND&lt;BR /&gt;REALESE: 758&lt;BR /&gt;SP: 0001&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;S4 CORE&lt;BR /&gt;REALESE: 108&lt;BR /&gt;SP: 0001&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Below is an example of when I try to create a sales document with a reference.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GuilhermeBaptista_0-1756830396964.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308092i517F022E5E901740/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="GuilhermeBaptista_0-1756830396964.png" alt="GuilhermeBaptista_0-1756830396964.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/no-service-found-for-namespace/qaq-p/14204919"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:28:37.765000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/setting-up-cloud-tms-for-various-sap-saas-solutions/bc-p/14204927#M175252</id>
    <title>Re: Setting Up Cloud TMS for Various SAP SaaS Solutions</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:32:01.688000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Padmanabula</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171881</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1412812"&gt;@ramkrishna24&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;I updated the article with new links. Please check and let me know, if you are specifically looking for BWZ, here you go&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/ctms-setup-for-sap-build-work-zone/ba-p/14136121" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/ctms-setup-for-sap-build-work-zone/ba-p/14136121&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/setting-up-cloud-tms-for-various-sap-saas-solutions/bc-p/14204927#M175252"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:32:01.688000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/debugging-in-abap-development-tool-part-1/bc-p/14204936#M50275</id>
    <title>Re: Debugging in ABAP Development Tool (Part 1)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:37:49.352000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DiegoValdivia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143362</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Such a great post &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1431539"&gt;@M_Sumaiya_Khatoon&lt;/a&gt; thanks for sharing your tips.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would just add an extra suggestion: add SY-SUBRC as favorite so it always show its contents. For all of us who worked on SE38 it's the first thing we miss in Eclipse.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/debugging-in-abap-development-tool-part-1/bc-p/14204936#M50275"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:37:49.352000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-maintain-a-constant-bar-color-per-measure-when-measures-are-selected/qaa-p/14204939#M4924906</id>
    <title>Re: How to maintain a constant bar color per measure, whe...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:38:27.384000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SREEDHARA_SATRASALA</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1979091</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Nikhil, Its not working, Do you any Idea on the css class thats gonna change the bar color</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-maintain-a-constant-bar-color-per-measure-when-measures-are-selected/qaa-p/14204939#M4924906"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:38:27.384000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-output-title-in-sales-order-output-in-s4hc/qaa-p/14204941#M4226112</id>
    <title>Re: Change Output Title In Sales Order Output in S4HC</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:38:43.978000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1715117"&gt;@kutaysarigul&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following up on your question, below you will find detailed explanation and the steps you can take to resolve the issue you reported.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is why the Issue you reported occur&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The text “Changed Order” comes from the standard data binding in the delivered form template. Unless that binding is modified, the form will continue to render this text.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adding a new custom field in the form layout does not automatically display in the output unless it is properly bound to the sales order ID in the form context. If left unbound, it remains invisible during runtime.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is a recommendation on how you can fix the issue&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Form Template and access the Maintain Form Templates app and download the custom template. Then Open it in Adobe LiveCycle Designer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Locate the Bound Field in the Hierarchy tab, find the field currently showing “Changed Order”. Check its binding in the Data View, it is likely connected to a field such as ChangedOrderID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Update the Binding and Label by rebind the field to the correct element, e.g., SalesOrderID or the field representing the original sales order number. Change the caption text from “Changed Order” to “Order”. This ensures the label shows as required while the correct order number is displayed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save and upload the modified template and upload it back into the Maintain Form Templates App. Then test the output by triggering a sales document again.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To summarise, by rebinding the field from ChangedOrderID to the correct order number field and updating the label text to “Order”, you will be able to ensure the output form shows the correct title and number.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired result. Happy to answer any further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-output-title-in-sales-order-output-in-s4hc/qaa-p/14204941#M4226112"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:38:43.978000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-cpi-embedded-image-in-mail-body/bc-p/14204943#M175253</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CPI embedded Image in mail body</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:39:11.668000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VK_Vignesh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1772713</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;How will be storing the image in the datastore if we cannot store it as a base 64 version? what is the alternate solution if the image is not coming from any source instead it have to stored in a datastore or default paramater?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-cpi-embedded-image-in-mail-body/bc-p/14204943#M175253"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:39:11.668000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-news-for-sap-btp-abap-environment-2508/bc-p/14204944#M184215</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP News for SAP BTP ABAP Environment 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:39:59.342000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DiegoValdivia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143362</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for you help on this,&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6859"&gt;@lenapadeken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-news-for-sap-btp-abap-environment-2508/bc-p/14204944#M184215"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:39:59.342000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-prog-to-create-2-sheets-tabs-in-one-ms-excel-workbook-amp-email/qaa-p/14204946#M4924907</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP Prog to create 2 sheets/tabs in ONE MS excel wor...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:45:28.842000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>XCO is absent from ABAP 7.40. Using abap2xlsx would be the cheapest solution but if your client has money to investigate other solutions, you can try a solution like running OLE to create a new sheet via Excel running on the user's laptop. It can't work if you run the program in background. If your client agrees to these limitations, use Excel macro recorder to get the methods and properties to invoke via ABAP OLE statements. Otherwise, you may decode the XLSX or XML format of a two-sheets workbook and see how you can generate this format by program (it's what abap2xlsx does). The last solution is to pay API to generate Excel file (search the Web for software). Maybe your client prefers paying a support over using free software.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-prog-to-create-2-sheets-tabs-in-one-ms-excel-workbook-amp-email/qaa-p/14204946#M4924907"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:45:28.842000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-odata-connector-for-powerbi/bc-p/14204947#M184216</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Datasphere: OData Connector for PowerBi</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:46:16.410000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>gustavokath</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/513684</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/829608"&gt;@albertosimeoni&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you so much for the raised request and investigation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The support for Technical User in the Consumption APIs along side with an update for it on the Custom PowerBI connector will be released later this year in Q3.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you&lt;BR /&gt;Best Regards&lt;BR /&gt;Gustavo Kath - SAP Datasphere&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-odata-connector-for-powerbi/bc-p/14204947#M184216"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:46:16.410000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/brf-output-determination-for-purchase-order-po/ba-p/14204950</id>
    <title>BRF+ Output Determination for Purchase Order (PO)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:51:20.840000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Leelamohan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1512023</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;BRF+&amp;nbsp;(Business Rule Framework Plus) is SAP's modern rules engine that allows flexible, business-driven decision-making without requiring deep technical configuration changes. In the context of Output Management for Purchase Orders, BRF+ helps in determining:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which output type (Email, PDF, Print, EDI, XML) to trigger.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The format and template (Adobe Forms/ Smartforms).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Receiver details (Vendor, Internal Department, multi-party).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Conditions for Output (based on Company code, purchasing organisation, vendor, document type, etc.).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This enables procurement teams to control rules dynamically without waiting for technical transports.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt; Why BRF+ is Needed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Flexibility &amp;amp; Agility: Business teams can update rules directly (via decision tables) without developer dependency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Future-Oriented: NACE and classical message determination are considered legacy; SAP S/4 HANA encourages BRF+ adoption for output management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Centralized Control: All output determination rules across purchasing documents can be managed in one place.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration Ready: BRF+ integrates seamlessly with SAP Fiori apps and newer communication channels (EMail, EDI, XML).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why BRF+ is Better than Classical Output Determination (NACE)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aspect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;NACE/Classical Output&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BRF+ Output Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Flexibility&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Limited to condition technique, complex for multiple condition.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Very flexible, supports nested rules, decision tables, and expression.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Maintenance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Requires transport requests, ABAP knowledge, and condition tables&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Business-driven, editable via decision tables without transports&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;UI&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;SAP GUI-based, less intuitive&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Fiori-enables, user-friendly&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Scalability&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Difficult to extend for new output channels&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Easily supports new formats (XML, Email, PDFs)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sample Business Scenario:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A company wants to send Purchase Order Outputs in different ways based on vendor and region:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Domestic Vendors (India):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Output should be sent as a PDF printout and simultaneously via Email.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overseas Vendors (EU, US):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Output should be sent in XML format for EDI integration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Critical Suppliers (Strategic Vendors):&lt;/STRONG&gt; A copy should be sent to internal management team via Email for visibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; With NACE, this setup would require multiple condition records, access sequences, and technical adjustments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;With BRF+, business users can simply maintain a decision table with rules like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vendor Region&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PO Vale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vendor Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Output Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Receiver&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;India&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;Any&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;Normal&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;PDF + Email&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;Vendor + Management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;EU&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;Any&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;Normal&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;XML (EDI)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="20%" height="30px"&gt;Vendor&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_0-1756829898454.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308086i40EAF06A58C6025F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_0-1756829898454.png" alt="Leelamohan_0-1756829898454.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Manage Activation of Application Object Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Path: SPRO &amp;gt; IMG &amp;gt; Cross-Application Components &amp;gt; Output Control &amp;gt; Manage Application Object Type Activation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_1-1756830045817.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308087i56BEF07E080D6595/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_1-1756830045817.png" alt="Leelamohan_1-1756830045817.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Define Output Types&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Path: SPRO &amp;gt; IMG &amp;gt; Cross-Application Components &amp;gt; Output Control &amp;gt; Define Output Types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_2-1756830102067.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308088i5311FE6B339A0871/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_2-1756830102067.png" alt="Leelamohan_2-1756830102067.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the line item and navigate to Details&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_3-1756830134347.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308089iDDE1C792FD693D04/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_3-1756830134347.png" alt="Leelamohan_3-1756830134347.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt; Once these settings are activated, print preview option will be disabled in the Purchase Order Screen.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Define Business Rules for Output Parameter Determination&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note: &lt;/STRONG&gt;To display the rules in Fiori screen we need to upload standard XML Forms in SAP system, these forms will be imported using BRF+ Transaction code.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If the forms's aren't uploaded, we won't be able to see the output type in the Output Parameter Determination transaction. We can get the details of Form from SAP Note: 2248229.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_4-1756830371176.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308090i5024D167C84D2D63/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_4-1756830371176.png" alt="Leelamohan_4-1756830371176.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on table Settings&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_5-1756830390189.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308091iB1106468D9EB42FE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_5-1756830390189.png" alt="Leelamohan_5-1756830390189.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on Insert column &amp;gt; From Context Data Objects&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_6-1756830443766.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308095i0CF26F76E6E5031B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_6-1756830443766.png" alt="Leelamohan_6-1756830443766.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chose the Condition Parameter and click OK&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_7-1756830499609.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308096i2E339619FE525D8F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_7-1756830499609.png" alt="Leelamohan_7-1756830499609.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fill the values for the selected condition parameter&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_8-1756830526060.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308097iB12EF88E6A9C416B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_8-1756830526060.png" alt="Leelamohan_8-1756830526060.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_9-1756830533902.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308098i12688638B21A71A5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_9-1756830533902.png" alt="Leelamohan_9-1756830533902.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_10-1756830544151.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308099iC4109141B3A0F230/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_10-1756830544151.png" alt="Leelamohan_10-1756830544151.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly check for other Determination Steps (Click Activate once after maintaining relevant data in each determination rule)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Receiver&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_11-1756830594375.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308100i3EE55385C9D00A5C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_11-1756830594375.png" alt="Leelamohan_11-1756830594375.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_12-1756830611173.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308101iCB13DEEB46DD77AA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_12-1756830611173.png" alt="Leelamohan_12-1756830611173.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Channel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maintain two line items one for Email and other is for Print&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_13-1756830657554.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308102i5BE889A64BCC0FD8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_13-1756830657554.png" alt="Leelamohan_13-1756830657554.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Print Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_14-1756830676142.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308103i31C1926472221C6B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_14-1756830676142.png" alt="Leelamohan_14-1756830676142.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Email Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_15-1756830739908.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308104i7E3A607C7AC7F720/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_15-1756830739908.png" alt="Leelamohan_15-1756830739908.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/U&gt;If Email template are not available, assign the template by following below steps&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; Cross-Components Application &amp;gt; Output Control &amp;gt; Assign Form Templates&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_16-1756830783212.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308105i356AE0377BE49961/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_16-1756830783212.png" alt="Leelamohan_16-1756830783212.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Email Recipient&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If no recipient maintained, system will consider the email address from the supplier master data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_17-1756830807130.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308106i233A0D6802D018A3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_17-1756830807130.png" alt="Leelamohan_17-1756830807130.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If requirement is sending CC or BCC emails, you can change in Email type code as below&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_18-1756830873706.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308107i9FAD88033E6C9ECE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_18-1756830873706.png" alt="Leelamohan_18-1756830873706.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on Activate and then on Start Simulation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_19-1756830991101.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308108iCE332137E8389B3D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_19-1756830991101.png" alt="Leelamohan_19-1756830991101.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_20-1756831002937.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308109iDBE92CA1CAFB12E5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_20-1756831002937.png" alt="Leelamohan_20-1756831002937.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mention document type value and execute&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_21-1756831028126.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308110iD95408D12B0F3D24/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_21-1756831028126.png" alt="Leelamohan_21-1756831028126.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_22-1756831042463.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308111iDD68A0C38CA0CA07/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_22-1756831042463.png" alt="Leelamohan_22-1756831042463.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create a Purchase Order for Test case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_23-1756831073262.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308112i71CD0E5B26AC3A58/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_23-1756831073262.png" alt="Leelamohan_23-1756831073262.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to messages&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_26-1756831137817.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308115i40B7ADD7728C61BA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_26-1756831137817.png" alt="Leelamohan_26-1756831137817.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the print line item and click on display document&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_25-1756831117459.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308114iEE54AA2AF1ACC08C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_25-1756831117459.png" alt="Leelamohan_25-1756831117459.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the line item and click on Send Output, status changed to &lt;STRONG&gt;To be Output&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Leelamohan_27-1756831321311.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308116iBC2EC07013D96D9D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Leelamohan_27-1756831321311.png" alt="Leelamohan_27-1756831321311.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go back and save the PO, status will change to &lt;STRONG&gt;Completed.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;If you found this guide helpful, don’t miss my other SAP MM WM blogs covering real-world automation, configuration tips, and best practices for procurement, inventory management, and warehouse management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://linktr.ee/mleelamohan" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click to view other SAP MM Blogs - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks &amp;amp; Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mannem Leelamohan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/brf-output-determination-for-purchase-order-po/ba-p/14204950"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:51:20.840000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cpi-removecontext-deletes-a-context-value/qaq-p/14204951</id>
    <title>CPI RemoveContext deletes a context value</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T18:51:26.840000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PeterJonker</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/177509</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am facing a strange situation. I am using RemoveContext and the result is 4 context values (removeContext out). However only 3 xml tags are created and the queue of the xml tag shows only 3 context values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Am I missing something here ? Any idea how this can happen ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PeterJonker_0-1756831786064.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308117i669F615A7CD8E7F3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="PeterJonker_0-1756831786064.png" alt="PeterJonker_0-1756831786064.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cpi-removecontext-deletes-a-context-value/qaq-p/14204951"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T18:51:26.840000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/launching-our-new-feedback-feature-on-the-sap-help-portal/bc-p/14204956#M184218</id>
    <title>Re: Launching Our New Feedback Feature on the SAP Help Portal</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:04:37.642000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abbas_Ahmad</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1714339</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;HI&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/launching-our-new-feedback-feature-on-the-sap-help-portal/bc-p/14204956#M184218"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:04:37.642000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-gui-version-800-compatibility-with-windows-11/qaq-p/14204957</id>
    <title>SAP GUI version  800 compatibility with Windows 11</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:07:42.128000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Is SAP GUI 800 compatible with Windows 11?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-gui-version-800-compatibility-with-windows-11/qaq-p/14204957"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:07:42.128000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-gui-version-800-compatibility-with-windows-11/qaa-p/14204958#M4924910</id>
    <title>Re: SAP GUI version 800 compatibility with Windows 11</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:07:48.979000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please refer to &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/66971/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/66971/E&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supported platforms for SAP GUI for Windows&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP GUI for Windows 8.00:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Windows 10 32-bit (only Education, Pro, and Enterprise editions)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Windows 10 64-bit on x64 (AMD) and Intel EM64T (only Education, Pro, and Enterprise editions)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Windows Server 2016 64-bit on x64 (AMD) and Intel EM64T&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Windows Server 2019 64-bit on x64 (AMD) and Intel EM64T&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Windows 11 on x64 (AMD) and Intel EM64T (only Education, Pro, and Enterprise editions)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Windows Server 2022 on x64 (AMD) and Intel EM64T:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Windows Server 2025 on x64 (AMD) and Intel EM64T - as of patch level 11&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-gui-version-800-compatibility-with-windows-11/qaa-p/14204958#M4924910"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:07:48.979000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/service-consumption-model-2-for-odata-client-proxy/bc-p/14204960#M184219</id>
    <title>Re: Service Consumption Model 2 for OData Client Proxy</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:13:21.595000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>wagener-mark</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179540</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/257088"&gt;@bernhard_grusie&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;will this be available in S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2025 release coming in October?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/service-consumption-model-2-for-odata-client-proxy/bc-p/14204960#M184219"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:13:21.595000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-architecture-and-lessons-learned/bc-p/14204967#M175254</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Datasphere - Architecture and Lessons-Learned</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:14:40.375000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Terry_KPMG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/155608</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for sharing Hau - well researched.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;I really appreciate these kind of "lessons learned" articles.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-architecture-and-lessons-learned/bc-p/14204967#M175254"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:14:40.375000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/cds-how-to-define-hierarchy-view/bc-p/14204969#M184220</id>
    <title>Re: CDS : How to define Hierarchy View</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:15:29.726000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RONALD_FERNANDES</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2226584</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks a lot Lina, it's a very nice content.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/cds-how-to-define-hierarchy-view/bc-p/14204969#M184220"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:15:29.726000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/lac-spain-and-portugal-blog-posts/new-quick-start-guides-and-resources-for-our-academic-community/ba-p/14204980</id>
    <title>New Quick Start Guides and Resources for Our Academic Community</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:25:41.057000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AriadneRodrigues</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2046676</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are excited to share important updates that will help you and your students get the most out of &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;University Alliances teaching&lt;SPAN&gt; resources!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’ve just released &lt;STRONG&gt;two new Quick Start Guides designed to help you get started right away:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud – &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;a complete Software-as-a-Service solution for data and analytics, deeply integrated across SAP applications, and delivers intelligent applications and curated data products across all lines of business.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AriadneRodrigues_0-1756833241891.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308126i08A675E0A4903D95/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AriadneRodrigues_0-1756833241891.jpeg" alt="AriadneRodrigues_0-1756833241891.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Suite – &lt;/STRONG&gt;a cloud-native, set of integrated solutions, combining ERP and Line-of Business (LoB) applications that unites data and AI to streamline and optimize companies' enterprise management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AriadneRodrigues_1-1756833241892.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308124i53D0211FEDBD27A2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AriadneRodrigues_1-1756833241892.jpeg" alt="AriadneRodrigues_1-1756833241892.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As Quick Start Guides, they are &lt;STRONG&gt;short, beginner-friendly slide decks designed for faculty and students. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Each guide provides a fast track to understanding, testing, and teaching an SAP solution—without requiring hours of preparation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can access the new guides here:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/assets/saplearning/bzl6yuh?rc=10" href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/assets/saplearning/bZL6yuh?rc=10" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Quick Start Guide: SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/assets/saplearning/aaj1uab?rc=10" href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/assets/saplearning/aAj1UAB?rc=10" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Quick Start Guide: SAP Business Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Remember:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Quick Start Guides are meant to get you started fast. To build on that foundation, we also provide &lt;SPAN&gt;other&lt;SPAN&gt; resources that dive deeper into teaching and learning with SAP.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AriadneRodrigues_2-1756833241892.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308125i709C434D7425A0DC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AriadneRodrigues_2-1756833241892.jpeg" alt="AriadneRodrigues_2-1756833241892.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Want to check other SAP University Alliances available resources? Check out our blogpost &lt;A class="" title="https://community.sap.com/t5/lac-spain-and-portugal-discussions/sap-materials-for-classroom/td-p/13706882" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/lac-spain-and-portugal-discussions/sap-materials-for-classroom/td-p/13706882" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/lac-spain-and-portugal-blog-posts/new-quick-start-guides-and-resources-for-our-academic-community/ba-p/14204980"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:25:41.057000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/the-regular-wagetype-is-getting-processed-in-off-cycle-payroll/qaa-p/14204984#M4226113</id>
    <title>Re: The regular wagetype is getting processed in off-cycl...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:30:26.353000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>corriveau_remi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/641577</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If I remember correctly, there is a Processing Class in Table view V_512W_D that relates to Off-Cycle processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Che&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ck your Wage Type's values, and compare them to a similar WT that is processed correctly (table view C_512W_O is useful for comparisons).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/the-regular-wagetype-is-getting-processed-in-off-cycle-payroll/qaa-p/14204984#M4226113"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:30:26.353000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-output-title-in-sales-order-output-in-s4hc/qaa-p/14204987#M4226114</id>
    <title>Re: Change Output Title In Sales Order Output in S4HC</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:33:15.090000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kutaysarigul</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1715117</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121"&gt;@Chris1973&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you for answer and help us in this situation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the next user who may encounter this issue&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For sales quotation output we solved our problem with delete binding of txtChangedDocument under the frmHiddenGlobalFields.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="kutaysarigul_5-1756834362439.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308138iFCEFF0C8FE5F3F67/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="kutaysarigul_5-1756834362439.png" alt="kutaysarigul_5-1756834362439.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="kutaysarigul_6-1756834365672.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308139i3157B8CC6E2BC1E1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="kutaysarigul_6-1756834365672.png" alt="kutaysarigul_6-1756834365672.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-output-title-in-sales-order-output-in-s4hc/qaa-p/14204987#M4226114"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:33:15.090000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-goalresult-visibility/qaq-p/14204990</id>
    <title>Variable Pay goalResult visibility</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:40:26.973000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karolina_lotocka</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2182754</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Community,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was wondering if any of you are showing achievement (goalResult) and its Payout % and Payout amount in the statements. I am trying to achieve that but in the entry level I am not sure if there is a standard way of using it, or shall it be part of some more complex formula.&amp;nbsp; For more context I am using only business goals :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="karolina_lotocka_0-1756829524043.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308084i37D17F493A868C7E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="karolina_lotocka_0-1756829524043.png" alt="karolina_lotocka_0-1756829524043.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="karolina_lotocka_1-1756834700166.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308140iCF68CD5A80549554/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="karolina_lotocka_1-1756834700166.png" alt="karolina_lotocka_1-1756834700166.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your help!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Karolina&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-goalresult-visibility/qaq-p/14204990"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:40:26.973000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/credit-stamp-loan-app-review-91-9241266719-852-1705-703-call-now/qaq-p/14204992</id>
    <title>Credit Stamp Loan. App. review +91) 9241266719 -//- 852-1705-703 Call Now</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:47:03.151000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ankhan118881</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2247736</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Credit Stamp Loan. App. review +91) 9241266719 -//- 852-1705-703 Call Now&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/credit-stamp-loan-app-review-91-9241266719-852-1705-703-call-now/qaq-p/14204992"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:47:03.151000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/bop-is-not-working-for-mto-scenerio/qaa-p/14204993#M206772</id>
    <title>Re: BOP is not working for MTO scenerio</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:47:29.329000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S0024831430</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Hi Laxmi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Thanks for the input. When we executed the BOP after the planned order is firmed, system is picking the sales order. But it is not confirming.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;When i changed the Strategy "Win", It ended up with error Stating Processing Status as "Alert - Win or Gain Strategy" and Confirmation Status as "Partially Confirmed or Unconfirmed".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="S0024831430_1-1756835866792.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308142i479B9FAA5486C29F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="S0024831430_1-1756835866792.png" alt="S0024831430_1-1756835866792.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;When i used the Strategy "Improve",&amp;nbsp; It ended up with error&amp;nbsp; Confirmation Status as ""Partially Confirmed or Unconfirmed"".&amp;nbsp;But the Processing Status looks fine.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="S0024831430_0-1756835803586.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308141i2846D0CD5B6B7D74/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="S0024831430_0-1756835803586.png" alt="S0024831430_0-1756835803586.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any insights on the error?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vinu Nanjan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/bop-is-not-working-for-mto-scenerio/qaa-p/14204993#M206772"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:47:29.329000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/credit-stamp-loan-app-review-91-9241266719-852-1705-703-call-now/qaa-p/14204994#M4226116</id>
    <title>Re: Credit Stamp Loan. App. review +91) 9241266719 -//- 8...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:49:06.868000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ankhan118881</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2247736</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Credit Stamp Loan. App. review +91) 9241266719 -//- 852-1705-703 Call Now&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/credit-stamp-loan-app-review-91-9241266719-852-1705-703-call-now/qaa-p/14204994#M4226116"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:49:06.868000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/it-is-not-possible-to-verify-credit-in-bp-of-different-segments/qaa-p/14204997#M4226119</id>
    <title>Re: It is not possible to verify credit in BP of differen...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:51:04.434000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GustavoStevens2024</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1789508</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you for your reply.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/it-is-not-possible-to-verify-credit-in-bp-of-different-segments/qaa-p/14204997#M4226119"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:51:04.434000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/credit-stamp-loan-app-91-9241266719-852-1705-703-call-now/qaq-p/14204998</id>
    <title>Credit Stamp Loan. App.  +91) 9241266719 -//- 852-1705-703 Call Now</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:52:25.575000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ankhan118881</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2247736</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Credit Stamp Loan. App.&amp;nbsp; +91) 9241266719 -//- 852-1705-703 Call Now&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/credit-stamp-loan-app-91-9241266719-852-1705-703-call-now/qaq-p/14204998"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:52:25.575000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-cloud-alm-interface-documentation-next-level/bc-p/14205005#M175255</id>
    <title>Re: 🚀 SAP Cloud ALM: Interface Documentation Next Level! 🔍💡</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:56:45.800000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Michael_Walker</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1458073</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This looks a lot like the interface documentation used in LeanIX. Is there a plan to integrate these and have one system of record?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-cloud-alm-interface-documentation-next-level/bc-p/14205005#M175255"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:56:45.800000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/measurement-document-list-display/qaq-p/14205011</id>
    <title>Measurement document list display</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T19:58:27.029000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jaya0511</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/812530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Only 50 measurement documents are displayed from equipment IE02/IE03. Is this standard? Is there a way to remove the restriction from 50 via IE02/IE03. We have removed the restriction in IK17/Ik18.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Jaya&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/measurement-document-list-display/qaq-p/14205011"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T19:58:27.029000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/errors-during-act-trans-in-ecc-ehp8-up-to-date-installation/qaa-p/14205023#M4226133</id>
    <title>Re: Errors during ACT_TRANS in ECC EHP8 up-to-date installation</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:03:58.860000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StefanFerreira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2129824</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Could this be a SQL compatibility issue? I'm using SQL Server 2014 as that is the highest version supported by the initial release of ECC 6.0 EHP8, but maybe the newer SPS levels no longer support SQL 2014?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/errors-during-act-trans-in-ecc-ehp8-up-to-date-installation/qaa-p/14205023#M4226133"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:03:58.860000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/it-is-not-possible-to-verify-credit-in-bp-of-different-segments/qaa-p/14205028#M4226136</id>
    <title>Re: It is not possible to verify credit in BP of differen...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:05:11.488000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GustavoStevens2024</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1789508</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you for your reply. Ihave checked each of the points, but the problem persists. It seems to only check when both BP codes belong to the same segment.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/it-is-not-possible-to-verify-credit-in-bp-of-different-segments/qaa-p/14205028#M4226136"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:05:11.488000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/credit-stamp-loan-app-91-9679867061-96-79-61-8-8-0call-now/qaq-p/14205029</id>
    <title>Credit Stamp Loan. App.  +91) 9679867061= -//- 96✓=79-61*8-8-0Call Now</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:06:44.499000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ankhan118881</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2247736</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Credit Stamp Loan. App. review +91) 9679867061= -//- 96✓=79-61*8-8-0Call Nowff&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/credit-stamp-loan-app-91-9679867061-96-79-61-8-8-0call-now/qaq-p/14205029"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:06:44.499000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/credit-stamp-loan-app-91-9679867061-96-79-61-8-8-0call-now/qaa-p/14205031#M254935</id>
    <title>Re: Credit Stamp Loan. App. +91) 9679867061= -//- 96✓=79-...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:07:04.185000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ankhan118881</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2247736</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Credit Stamp Loan. App. review +91) 9679867061= -//- 96✓=79-61*8-8-0Call Nowhhh&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/credit-stamp-loan-app-91-9679867061-96-79-61-8-8-0call-now/qaa-p/14205031#M254935"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:07:04.185000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-creating-transport-request-erp-public-cloud/qaq-p/14205062</id>
    <title>Error creating transport request ERP public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:19:04.881000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>diana_gonzalezcr60</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/805383</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I attempted to create a new, transportable package outside of the ZLOCAL component. However, the system still produces an error when I try to create the transportation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I suspect the root cause may not be just the package type, but the extension methodology itself. My understanding is that for S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, classic extensions (like creating an ENHO object from Eclipse) are not permitted in order to maintain a "Clean Core." Instead, the recommended approach is to use the "Custom Logic" Fiori app to implement BAdIs that SAP has explicitly released for the cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My specific question is: Is the BADI_WHT BAdI enabled for extension via Eclipse ADT in our public cloud environment, or is it mandatory that we find an alternative, released BAdI within the "Custom Logic" app?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am attaching screenshots of the new error I receive when using the transportable package.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I appreciate your guidance in ensuring we are using the correct extensibility method for our platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Diana&lt;BR /&gt;I only have ZLOCAL and Z001 for superpackage&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;more information (my question):&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-creating-badi-enhancement-implementation-quot-sap-object-enhs-cannot/qaq-p/14195538" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-creating-badi-enhancement-implementation-quot-sap-object-enhs-cannot/qaq-p/14195538&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;BaDI:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/badi/BADI_FIBRREI_WHT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/badi/BADI_FIBRREI_WHT&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="new external package.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308150i12C202D6A85288B6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="new external package.png" alt="new external package.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="layer.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308151i6E09FD0A8B15331D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="layer.png" alt="layer.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="transport error.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308152iB83DCE45E0774EA5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="transport error.png" alt="transport error.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="object.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308153iAAB3B896B3B2E25E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="object.png" alt="object.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-creating-transport-request-erp-public-cloud/qaq-p/14205062"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:19:04.881000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-reuse-a-component-from-another-application-in-webide/qaq-p/14205069</id>
    <title>How to reuse a component from another application in webide?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:28:58.917000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>r199703212</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/865006</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Expert,&lt;BR /&gt;I have two application parent and child. I have build child application which I want to reuse in multiple parent application in WEBIDE .&lt;BR /&gt;I followed below approach-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In child application-&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="r199703212_2-1756836599325.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308148iAE63C9125C68C03B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="r199703212_2-1756836599325.png" alt="r199703212_2-1756836599325.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;neo-app.json&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;{&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"path": "/zpsbudget_component",&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"target": {&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"type": "application",&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"name": "zpsbudget_component"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;},&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"description": " Reuse Component"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;}&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Then deployed the child application.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In Parent Application&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="r199703212_7-1756837554899.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308157i2762993539449A20/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="r199703212_7-1756837554899.png" alt="r199703212_7-1756837554899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Allocation.Fragment.XML&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="r199703212_3-1756836965472.png" style="width: 683px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308149i1B13384D56E1CFE9/image-dimensions/683x190/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="683" height="190" role="button" title="r199703212_3-1756836965472.png" alt="r199703212_3-1756836965472.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Menifest.json&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="r199703212_4-1756837068001.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308154i161FCF49FA0ED58F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="r199703212_4-1756837068001.png" alt="r199703212_4-1756837068001.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Component.js&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="r199703212_0-1756838025620.png" style="width: 595px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308158i58A6953F5BC10D50/image-dimensions/595x458/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="595" height="458" role="button" title="r199703212_0-1756838025620.png" alt="r199703212_0-1756838025620.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;After following above steps.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;I am not getting resource option in webide.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="r199703212_6-1756837272062.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308156i648E04159B26BACE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="r199703212_6-1756837272062.png" alt="r199703212_6-1756837272062.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly assist me to get resource in parent application.&lt;BR /&gt;Thankyou&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-reuse-a-component-from-another-application-in-webide/qaq-p/14205069"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:28:58.917000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/3-must-know-configuration-setups-in-variable-pay/bc-p/14205068#M9133</id>
    <title>Re: 3 Must-Know configuration setups in Variable Pay</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:29:04.184000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46749"&gt;@Ritanshi9&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Did anything change as well on the Bonus Eligibile Earnings ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the answer to the above question is "no nothing changed" then try adding merge="false" (like you did for PayGrade) on the Basis field in your varpayemphistdata background then reimport and test.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the answer to the above question "yes" then there is nothing you can do to pull only the latest paygrade. In that case you would need to do a custom config where you pull the paygrade at entry level (hence as of EC effective date of the varpay template) then send it down to an ALCF field.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the best,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Xavier&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/3-must-know-configuration-setups-in-variable-pay/bc-p/14205068#M9133"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:29:04.184000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/howto-in-sap-dm-a-step-by-step-guide-to-using-list-type-parameters-in-data/ba-p/14195275</id>
    <title>HowTo in SAP DM:  A Step-by-Step Guide to 'Using List Type parameters in Data Collection'</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:36:15.498000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnilTota</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1581054</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1867900805"&gt;Introduction:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;You want to use the "&lt;STRONG&gt;List&lt;/STRONG&gt;" type parameter in Data Collection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1671387300"&gt;Steps to follow:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step1&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Create a new "&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Field&lt;/STRONG&gt;" of type "List" from "Manage Data Fields" application.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can mark one of the Option as "&lt;STRONG&gt;Default&lt;/STRONG&gt;".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-27 at 7.59.00 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305591iAC7F806916BB1FE7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-27 at 7.59.00 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-27 at 7.59.00 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step2&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Goto "Manage Data Collection" App and create a new Parameter in an existing or a new "Data Collection Group"&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The parameter should be of type "&lt;STRONG&gt;List&lt;/STRONG&gt;"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Additionally, provide the previously created data field eg. "&lt;STRONG&gt;COLOR&lt;/STRONG&gt;", in the field "&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Field List&lt;/STRONG&gt;"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assign&lt;/STRONG&gt; the DC group to the right object.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-27 at 8.09.52 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305599i466CE4307E9BB731/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-27 at 8.09.52 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-27 at 8.09.52 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step3&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Launch the POD to perform data collection for list type parameter&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The parameter is defaulted to the maintained default value in "&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Field&lt;/STRONG&gt;" definition&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can choose to change the parameter value from the value list&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-27 at 8.19.01 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305605iF99CD0383A1666C0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-27 at 8.19.01 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-27 at 8.19.01 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1474873795"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1278360290"&gt;Pro Tips:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;list&lt;/STRONG&gt; type parameter when you have handful of options to be used as a list. Example Colors, Models. If you have hundreds and thousands of options, go for &lt;STRONG&gt;text&lt;/STRONG&gt; type if possible.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The "Log DC" public api also now supports list type parameters. But point to note here is, the value passed for the parameter during log dc is not validated by the system, this could be due to keep the performance of the api intact. Always pass the right value during log as mostly the api would be used in Automation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope you like the blog, do provide your feedback in the comments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anil.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/howto-in-sap-dm-a-step-by-step-guide-to-using-list-type-parameters-in-data/ba-p/14195275"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:36:15.498000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extracting-sap-s-4hana-data-tables-amp-cds-views-to-external-storages/qaq-p/14205080</id>
    <title>Extracting SAP S/4HANA Data (Tables &amp; CDS Views) to External Storages</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:36:39.984000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndriusK</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/136822</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hey&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m looking into options for extracting data from SAP S/4HANA (tables and CDS views) into external, non-SAP storages such as AWS S3 / Redshift or Oracle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So far, I see a few directions, but I couldn’t find a clear statement on SAP’s official strategy for:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP-native options&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Third-party tools (how does SAP position ETL tools such as Informatica or Theobald? Are those SAP-certified?)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP’s current position on BDC? Specifically Datasphere, which could also be used for data replication to an external target database?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any references (SAP Notes, blogs, architecture guides, or project experience) would be very helpful.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extracting-sap-s-4hana-data-tables-amp-cds-views-to-external-storages/qaq-p/14205080"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:36:39.984000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/fixtures-fittings-for-land/qaa-p/14205081#M254944</id>
    <title>Re: Fixtures &amp; Fittings for Land</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:37:36.443000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kun1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1540370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>How do you assign fixtures and fittings in Property/Land Master record?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/fixtures-fittings-for-land/qaa-p/14205081#M254944"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:37:36.443000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-reuse-a-component-from-another-application-in-webide/qaa-p/14205090#M4924914</id>
    <title>Re: How to reuse a component from another application in webide?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:44:36.947000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marian_Zeis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/61</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Last time I used webide was 2019, are you not able to use BAS or VS Code?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-reuse-a-component-from-another-application-in-webide/qaa-p/14205090#M4924914"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:44:36.947000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/bop-is-not-working-for-mto-scenerio/qaa-p/14205095#M206774</id>
    <title>Re: BOP is not working for MTO scenerio</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:45:17.012000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Andreas_Krause1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131598</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;let me share an example where a material with strategy group B6 is selected and confirmed using Backorder Processing. Indeed, the requirement as well as the supply is in special stock 'E'. But BOP can handle this by using supply/demand elements from that very special stock segment to calculate availability and - in case possible - confirm.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See also short demo video:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_nejewsyc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://video.sap.com/media/t/1_nejewsyc&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You may want to check the Display Product Availability to see the supply element for your specific sales order:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DisplayProdAvaily_FG228_B6.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308160i89ED7681BA7584D9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DisplayProdAvaily_FG228_B6.png" alt="DisplayProdAvaily_FG228_B6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Andreas&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/bop-is-not-working-for-mto-scenerio/qaa-p/14205095#M206774"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:45:17.012000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/sap-community-meetup-lisbon/ev-p/14205097</id>
    <title>SAP Community Meetup Lisbon</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:47:36.924000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lauraschmitz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/31</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Join us for an inspiring evening with the SAP community in Lisbon!&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Connect with peers, exchange ideas, and update your SAP knowledge.&amp;nbsp;Discover the latest trends and insights. Don’t miss this chance to learn, grow, and network—save the date!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Junte-se a nós para uma noite inspiradora com a comunidade SAP em Lisboa!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Conecte-se com colegas, troque ideias e atualize os seus conhecimentos em SAP.&amp;nbsp;Descubra as últimas tendências e insights.&amp;nbsp;Não perca esta oportunidade de aprender, crescer e criar networking — marque já na agenda!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Venue:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Luz by Chakall,&lt;BR /&gt;Estádio Sport Lisboa e Benfica,&amp;nbsp; – Porta 10 –&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Av. Eusébio da Silva Ferreira&lt;BR /&gt;1500-313 Lisboa&lt;BR /&gt;Portugal&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/sap-community-meetup-lisbon/ev-p/14205097"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:47:36.924000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/update-the-certificate-type-in-purchase-order/qaa-p/14205100#M4226148</id>
    <title>Re: Update the certificate type in purchase order</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:48:46.407000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>boniek1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/800073</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;You can delete the item and create another one, now the QM data will be copied successfully&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/update-the-certificate-type-in-purchase-order/qaa-p/14205100#M4226148"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:48:46.407000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/n%C3%B3mina-para-asimilados-a-salarios-en-m%C3%A9xico/qaa-p/14205102#M47647</id>
    <title>Re: Nómina para asimilados a salarios en México</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:49:37.644000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HugoRodriguez</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53000</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hola Oscar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Si van a procesar la nómina en SAP para este tipo de personal, entonces si lo tienen que registrar en datos maestros (como contratas a culquier empleado asalariado).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Al tratarse de alguien externo, entonces deberán registrar el IT0369 sin relación con el IMSS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Por tratarse de asimilados, tendrán que utilizar un concepto de pago diferente al resto del personal en el IT0008. Ese mismo concepto lo deberán configurar en la tabla V_T77PAYMX_CFDIC para que sea tratado correctamente para el CFDi.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;En cuanto al subsidio al empleo, si no lo van a aplicar a este tipo de trabajadores, entonces deberán programar el user-exit 003 de ISR para ello.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Espero esto te sea de utilidad.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/n%C3%B3mina-para-asimilados-a-salarios-en-m%C3%A9xico/qaa-p/14205102#M47647"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:49:37.644000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/process-overview-of-client-refresh-using-epi-use-method/bc-p/14205104#M71961</id>
    <title>Re: Process Overview of Client Refresh using EPI-USE method</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:51:05.467000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>biswanath8675</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/816979</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Can the USER master export-import be ignored, does EPI-USE has this option, so that the need of SAP* can be eradicated, asking as its almost not possible to get SAP* in private cloud scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/process-overview-of-client-refresh-using-epi-use-method/bc-p/14205104#M71961"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:51:05.467000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-party-determination-of-sales-data-in-sales-cloud-v2/ba-p/14205109</id>
    <title>Understanding Party Determination of Sales Data in Sales Cloud V2</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:53:26.805000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogesh__Vijay</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/227756</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When it comes to managing sales in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud V2&lt;/STRONG&gt;, one of the crucial processes is determining the right &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Data&lt;/STRONG&gt; whenever a sales transaction or lead is being created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Data&lt;/STRONG&gt; typically includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales Organization&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Distribution Channel&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Division&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales Office&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales Group&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales Unit&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Getting these right ensures smooth order processing, pricing, reporting, and alignment of responsibility between sales reps and accounts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s break this down with a practical example.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario: XYZ Industries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;XYZ Industries is a global manufacturer of industrial equipment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;They sell directly to customers in some markets (&lt;STRONG&gt;B2B Distribution Channel&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;They sell via distributors in others&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Employees (sales reps) are often aligned with specific &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Organizations&lt;/STRONG&gt; (like “North America” or “Europe”), and sometimes with &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Offices&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Groups&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., “West Coast Office” or “Distributor Management Team”).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;When a sales rep creates a new lead or opportunity in the system, the platform must automatically pick the right &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Let’s see how the system does this in steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Data Determination&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Usually Sales Data determination starts with determining the correct Sales Organization and there are determination steps available in Party Schema of Lead or Opportunities. Determination happens either from Employee Data, Organization assigned to Employee, Account Sales Data or combinations of either of them.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Employee’s Sales Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The system first looks at the &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Data maintained for the Employee.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the employee has one flagged as &lt;STRONG&gt;Main&lt;/STRONG&gt;, that combination of Sales Org, Distribution Channel, and Division will be selected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If no main is set, the system picks any valid entry from the employee’s list of Sales Data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;John, a sales rep at XYZ Industries, has two sales data assignments:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;North America / Direct / Equipment (marked as Main)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Europe / Distributor / Equipment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since “North America / Direct / Equipment” is marked as Main, that gets picked automatically when John creates a new lead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intersection of Employee &amp;amp; Account Sales Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If a step requires validating both employee and account (customer) sales data, the system finds the &lt;STRONG&gt;intersection&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If an intersection exists, that combination is selected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If no overlap, the system skips to the next active determination step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;John is assigned to &lt;STRONG&gt;North America / Direct / Equipment&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;The customer account "ABC Distributors" is maintained with &lt;STRONG&gt;North America / Direct / Equipment&lt;/STRONG&gt; as valid Sales Data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intersection matches → system picks this Sales Data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the customer only had &lt;STRONG&gt;Europe / Distributor / Equipment&lt;/STRONG&gt;, there would be no intersection, so the system moves to the next step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Office &amp;amp; Sales Group&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the intersected Sales Data in the Account has &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Office or Sales Group maintained&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the system uses this detail.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If "ABC Distributors" has been linked specifically to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Los Angeles Sales Office&lt;/STRONG&gt;, then when John creates a lead for them, the system will default this into the record automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Organizational Assignment (Primary Employee Check)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the determination step uses the &lt;STRONG&gt;Organizational Structure&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the system checks where the employee is assigned as &lt;STRONG&gt;Primary&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the employee is primary for a Sales Office, the system identifies which Sales Organization is tied to that office.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If additional restrictions (like Distribution Channel or Division) are maintained in the Sales Organization, they are also defaulted.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;John is assigned as &lt;STRONG&gt;Primary Sales Rep&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the &lt;STRONG&gt;Chicago Sales Office&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;The Chicago Office belongs to the &lt;STRONG&gt;North America Sales Org&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with restriction &lt;STRONG&gt;Direct / Equipment&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;System will pick:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales Org: North America&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Distribution Channel: Direct&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Division: Equipment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales Office: Chicago&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters for Your Business&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This determination process makes sure that:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales reps don’t waste time figuring out which sales data to use&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leads and opportunities always flow into the &lt;STRONG&gt;correct reporting structures&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customers are automatically mapped to the right &lt;STRONG&gt;sales offices and groups&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring accountability and accurate pipeline visibility&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For large organizations like XYZ Industries, where one customer might be handled by multiple sales representatives and across different sales regions, this automation reduces &lt;STRONG&gt;errors, duplication, and admin work&lt;/STRONG&gt; while improving the &lt;STRONG&gt;customer experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-party-determination-of-sales-data-in-sales-cloud-v2/ba-p/14205109"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:53:26.805000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/scripting-engine-running-reports-simultaneously/qaa-p/14205115#M4924915</id>
    <title>Re: Scripting Engine - Running reports simultaneously</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T20:58:23.817000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jude_bradley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/199928</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP GUI is not the option you want to use when considering batch or simultaneous programs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The limitations are described here:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="311440 - Batch input and controls" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/311440/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;311440 - Batch input and controls&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="Symptom" id="toc-hId-1888217120"&gt;Symptom&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Errors occur when you process or record batch input sessions if the application uses frontend controls such as the ALV grid or tree. Typical cases:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(1)The batch input recorder does not record any actions or frontend control data.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(2) When you process batch input sessions in the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;background&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a termination or an ABAP short dump with the exception condition CNTL_ERROR occurs. The exception condition is caused in the control framework (program SAPLOLEA or also CL_GUI_*).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(3) When you process batch input sessions in the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;background&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a termination occurs with the message&lt;BR /&gt;'Editor could not be initialised' in the batch input log.&lt;BR /&gt;Processing a Call Transaction ... Using (processing mode N) in the background, a termination occurs with the message:&lt;BR /&gt;'Exception condition ERROR_DP initialized'&lt;BR /&gt;Since controls are only used more frequently as of Release 4.6A, these problems generally do not occur in Releases &amp;lt; 4.6.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="Reason and Prerequisites" id="toc-hId-1691703615"&gt;Reason and Prerequisites&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Frontend controls are generally&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;capable of batch input. Therefore the batch input recorder does not record any data for them and they cannot be supplied with data or actions during a BI session run.&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;2. Frontend controls cannot be accessed from a background process because it does not have an active SAPGUI connection. If such a communication is attempted by the application nevertheless, an exception condition is triggered by the control framework which causes a termination if it is not caught by the application.&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This also applies to the background batch input (mode E) or a Call Transaction ... Using (mode E or N or P, respectively) in dialog processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;3. The application uses a frontend textedit control. As with all other frontend controls, it cannot be accessed in batch input. If you try to run an application which uses this control in batch input, the system will terminate with the message BMEN 802, as for point (2). This occurs with the PFCG Transaction, for example.&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="Solution" id="toc-hId-1495190110"&gt;Solution&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;1.&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If an application is to be capable of batch input, you must make sure that the desired functions can also be executed without participation of the existing frontend controls.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If this is not possible or cannot be achieved without investing considerable time and effort, you must use alternative methods for the data transfer (direct input, BAPIs).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;2.&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If an application is running in the background or is processed in the background in dialog operation, no frontend controls may be generated and called (query on sy-batch and sy-binpt!).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The application developer should check whether the action that caused the termination was designed to be capable of batch input. If it was not, the batch input session must be changed accordingly. If it was, the application must make sure that no communication with frontend controls is attempted in the background or during batch input. This can be achieved with a consistent query.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;3. As for problem (1), the user needs to check whether another editor can be used in the application instead of the edit control. For example, the editor must be based on a step loop or table view control, so that it can also be accessed in batch input. This question will be answered by the relevant development department.&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Additional information on problems (1) and (2)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The question that is usually asked in practice is "Can I operate a transaction in batch input if it uses frontend controls?"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Although the batch input cannot run actions on controls, this does not necessarily mean that you can no longer run a transaction via batch input. This would only be the case if the controls were absolutely necessary for navigating in the transaction. A particular transaction can include several simultaneous actions that can be executed via batch input and some that cannot be executed this way at all.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;One particular problem associated with this is that batch input can allow a transaction to run in the background. In this case, the application must ensure that no controls are created and used, in order to enable batch input.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(All statements in this note also apply to applications that use fast input or CALL TRANSACTION USING.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/scripting-engine-running-reports-simultaneously/qaa-p/14205115#M4924915"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T20:58:23.817000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-crystal-report-runtime-error-when-published-in-docker/qaa-p/14205118#M4924916</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Crystal Report runtime error when published in Do...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:01:33.359000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>WagnerFVernier</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1625969</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you Don!&amp;nbsp; It worked for us;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-crystal-report-runtime-error-when-published-in-docker/qaa-p/14205118#M4924916"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:01:33.359000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-prog-to-create-2-sheets-tabs-in-one-ms-excel-workbook-amp-email/qaa-p/14205119#M4924917</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP Prog to create 2 sheets/tabs in ONE MS excel wor...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:01:33.970000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ricky_shaw</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/202195</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Ah! why all this fuss. It's a big rich client ..i can't give suggestions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Already we have a Z*prog to create an excel &amp;amp; mail it in the background (like&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;BCS_EXAMPLE_7&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt; based prog). Only thing is i need to add a logic to attach one more sheet.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-prog-to-create-2-sheets-tabs-in-one-ms-excel-workbook-amp-email/qaa-p/14205119#M4924917"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:01:33.970000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/cds-view-hierarchy-node-sign-reversal/bc-p/14205121#M184221</id>
    <title>Re: CDS View: Hierarchy node sign reversal</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:02:22.340000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RONALD_FERNANDES</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2226584</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you Lina, valuable content.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/cds-view-hierarchy-node-sign-reversal/bc-p/14205121#M184221"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:02:22.340000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/integration-of-work-instructions-from-s4-public-to-sap-dm/qaa-p/14205126#M4226149</id>
    <title>Re: Integration of Work instructions from S4-Public to SA...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:04:51.092000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RodoFK</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1757339</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/integration-of-work-instructions-from-s4-public-to-sap-dm/qaa-p/14205126#M4226149"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:04:51.092000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/user-id-for-concurrent-employment/qaa-p/14205127#M47648</id>
    <title>Re: User-id for Concurrent employment</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:06:14.499000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bamyser</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17880</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/117402"&gt;@masashiyamagi74&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope you are keeping well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User ID Auto-Population During Employment Details Import&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently, it is not possible to auto-populate or overwrite user-id with a user-id generated by Business Rule when importing Employment Details via Import Employee Data, this is confirmed in the following articles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2787336" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2787336 - Is it Possible to Generate User ID via Business Rule for Global assignment or Concurrent employments or Contingent Workers? - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2678155" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2678155 - Rule-based Generation of UserID/Username for Hires &amp;amp; Rehires with New Employment - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Limitations&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Rule Scope Restriction&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; The rule-based generation of UserID/Username through Business Rules is specifically designed for &lt;STRONG&gt;Hire and Rehire processes only&lt;/STRONG&gt;, not for general data imports. The business rules are consumed directly by the Hire/Rehire Configuration object rather than standard import processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Import Process Behavior&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; During Employment Details imports:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you manually provide an Assignment ID in the import file, that value takes precedence&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If no Assignment ID is provided, the system automatically assigns a value from the corresponding users_sys_id field.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The User ID generation rules configured in Hire/Rehire Configuration do not trigger during import processes&amp;nbsp;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Managing Mass Changes in Employee Central - Assignment ID Definition with Data Imports at: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/managing-mass-changes-in-employee-central/assignment-id-definition-with-data-imports?amp%3Bstate=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;%3Bversion=2505&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/managing-mass-changes-in-employee-central/assignment-id-definition-with-data-imports?amp%3Bstate=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;%3Bversion=2505&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Available Alternatives&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assignment ID External&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;From release 1908, SAP introduced assignment-id-external which provides more flexibility.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Can be auto-generated during import processes through Employment Settings Configuration&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Has one-to-one mapping with userid but can be changed when required&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Requires creating an employee settings configuration with a business rule for the "Generate Assignment ID External" scenario.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/mapping-employee-id-for-employee-master-replication-from-sap-successfactors/ba-p/13454046/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/mapping-employee-id-for-employee-master-replication-from-sap-successfactors/ba-p/13454046" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/mapping-employee-id-for-employee-master-replication-from-sap-successfactors/ba-p/13454046/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/mapping-employee-id-for-employee-master-replication-from-sap-successfactors/ba-p/13454046&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manual Definition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; You can manually define assignment IDs in your import file templates for:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;New employees using Basic Import template&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Concurrent Employment using Employment Details template&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Global Assignment using Global Assignment template&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;The User ID generation via Business Rules remains limited to the hiring workflow and cannot be leveraged during standard Employment Details import processes.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Auto-Generating Assignment ID External During Import&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;To auto-generate assignment-id-external during import in SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central, you need to create an Employment Settings Configuration with a business rule attached.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration Steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;U&gt;1. Create Employment Settings Configuration&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Navigate to Admin Center → Manage Data&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Select Employment Settings Configuration from the Create New dropdown&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Specify a code for the configuration&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Set the Status as Active&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Select Yes from the "Activate 'Generate Assignment ID External' by Using a Business Rule" dropdown&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;U&gt;2. Create Business Rule&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Select the Add Rule option to create a business rule&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Ensure you create a business rule belonging to the Generate Assignment ID External scenario in the Employee Central Core rule scenario category&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;The business rule is executed during the data import process&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;U&gt;3. Configure Rule Selection&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;After creating the business rule, select it from the "Rule to generate Assignment ID External" dropdown&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Save the changes.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HRIS Elements Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The required HRIS elements must be configured to add the `` field. Check the existing configuration at:&amp;nbsp; Admin Center → Manage Business Configuration → Employee Central → HRIS Elements&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Import Behavior&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Automatic Generation Process&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;The system generates assignment IDs while importing Employment Details or Global Assignment information&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;The assignment ID generated by the system can be different from the user ID of employees&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Assignment ID from the import file takes precedence over the assignment ID generated by the system.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Default Behavior Without Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;If you don't enter an Assignment ID in the import file and no business rule is configured, the system automatically assigns a value from the corresponding ' ' field&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supported Import Templates&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;This auto-generation works with:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Basic Import template (for new employees)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Employment Details template (for Concurrent Employment)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Global Assignment template (for Global Assignments)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;The business rule execution ensures consistent assignment ID generation across all import processes while maintaining flexibility for manual overrides when needed.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Managing Mass Changes in Employee Central - Setting Up a Process for Auto-Generating Assignment ID at: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/managing-mass-changes-in-employee-central/setting-up-process-for-auto-generating-assignment-id?amp%3Bstate=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;%3Bversion=2505&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/managing-mass-changes-in-employee-central/setting-up-process-for-auto-generating-assignment-id?amp%3Bstate=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;%3Bversion=2505&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Managing Mass Changes in Employee Central - Assignment ID Definition with Data Imports at: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/managing-mass-changes-in-employee-central/assignment-id-definition-with-data-imports?amp%3Bstate=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;%3Bversion=2505&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/managing-mass-changes-in-employee-central/assignment-id-definition-with-data-imports?amp%3Bstate=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;%3Bversion=2505&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Bamyser_2-1756839889085.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308166iF6B7C84EFB82BFAF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Bamyser_2-1756839889085.png" alt="Bamyser_2-1756839889085.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Hope this helps&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;All the best&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/user-id-for-concurrent-employment/qaa-p/14205127#M47648"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:06:14.499000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sftp-conection/qaq-p/14205131</id>
    <title>SFTP Conection</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:11:21.187000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aaron101</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2049085</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I want to connect an SFTP with the Change Audit Reports tool, but when validating the connection I get an error, I already entered the SFTP from the browser but it does not allow me&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sftp-conection/qaq-p/14205131"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:11:21.187000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/inventory-count-posting-only-possible-in-periods-2025-09-and-2025-08-in/qaa-p/14205134#M4226150</id>
    <title>Re: Inventory Count - Posting only possible in periods 20...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:16:57.308000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/137056"&gt;@Phil_P&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You are correct; after closing the Materials Management (MM) period, posting backdated inventory differences into that month is no longer allowed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding your question about the next time:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the MM period is still open, you can post inventory counts with a posting date in the previous month, for example, 28.08. The system will accept it because the August period remains open.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once the period is closed, postings can only be made within the currently open period, for example, September. In such cases, the posting date must be adjusted to fall within the open period.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, the timing of the period close is crucial: backdating is only effective while that MM period remains open.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With regards&lt;BR /&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/inventory-count-posting-only-possible-in-periods-2025-09-and-2025-08-in/qaa-p/14205134#M4226150"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:16:57.308000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/http-content-server-all-communication-via-sap-server/qaa-p/14205146#M4226151</id>
    <title>Re: HTTP Content Server all communication via SAP server?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:24:25.234000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnieTran</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1456423</uri>
    </author>
    <content>HI M. Palmer, I checked OAC0 in my system and impossible to find the parameters you referred to : Access via frontend or backend: set to 'Backend' (value = '2') Important: This is the key setting. By default, it might be set to "Frontend" (value = '1'), which causes the SAP GUI (user PC) to access the HTTP content server directly</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/http-content-server-all-communication-via-sap-server/qaa-p/14205146#M4226151"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:24:25.234000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unable-to-completely-terminate-a-trm-transaction/qaa-p/14205149#M4226152</id>
    <title>Re: Unable to completely terminate a TRM Transaction</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:32:06.687000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ReenaConsultant</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2159573</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348" target="_blank"&gt;@Lakshmipathi&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Are you able to tell me more about system Status BBGT? I noticed that this status is active when we settle in ftr_edit. The only time is not active is the activity is 1 Contract, 3 Give Notice.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I've been looking into TRM in SAP Help,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/e5ec5859d8e54df98492d80564a734c0/2407da531198434de10000000a174cb4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Processing Interest Rate Instruments | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;, but it doesn't seem that the system statuses are discussed.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unable-to-completely-terminate-a-trm-transaction/qaa-p/14205149#M4226152"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:32:06.687000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/rerapp-save-variant-issue/qaq-p/14205153</id>
    <title>RERAPP Save Variant issue</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:38:22.223000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Arjun13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1687396</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;BR /&gt;We had some issues with RERAPP today where a saved variant was pulling different information in on one person"s computer which was different from the details which were saved on the other users computer. Specifically, a random contract number previously entered in contract field of RERAPP was being pulled into the variant when it was ran by the 2nd employee.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We don"t understand why RERAPP pulling previously run contract information as default when we try to execute it with variant. Please advise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Jayant Patel&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/rerapp-save-variant-issue/qaq-p/14205153"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:38:22.223000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/authorization-profiles/td-p/14205156</id>
    <title>Authorization Profiles</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:41:58.439000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dan_spitzig</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/210701</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi ABAP experts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am creating an ABAP program to do a mass update of roles, rather than manually doing it with transaction PFCG.&amp;nbsp; I am removing manually-added T-Codes, then adding them to the Role Menu as Authorization Default using method CL_PFCG_MENU_MODIFY-&amp;gt;MENU_ADD_SERVICE.&amp;nbsp; This works well, changing the AGR_1251-MODIFIED field from 'U' to 'S',&amp;nbsp; However, when the Authorization Profile is generated using&lt;!-- StartFragment  --&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;PRGN_AUTO_GENERATE_PROFILE_NEW&lt;/SPAN&gt;, it also brings in a lot of unwanted authorizations, such as SE16 bringing in S_TABU_DIS and S_TABU_NAM.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The method&amp;nbsp;CL_PFCG_MENU_MODIFY-&amp;gt;MENU_DELETE_NODE will remove them, but they will come back whenever the profile is regenerated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The solution is to set the Authorization as 'Inactive', but I cannot find a Method or Function Module that will do this.&amp;nbsp; I tried doing a direct table update (which is not recommended) to AGR_1251, setting the DELETED field to 'X'.&amp;nbsp; When I do this and look at the role in PFCG and in table AGR_1251, it appears to have worked.&amp;nbsp; When someone logs into the system with that role, executes SE16, they should not be able to select any table to display.&amp;nbsp; However, even though the Authorizations are Inactive, they can still display table contents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone please help me out with how to achieve my goal?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/authorization-profiles/td-p/14205156"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:41:58.439000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/custom-email-templates-using-successfactors-document-generation/bc-p/14205157#M7088</id>
    <title>Re: Custom email templates using SuccessFactors Document Generation</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:44:20.303000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MiraAtef</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1600530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I tried the previous&amp;nbsp; steps&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But there was already a business rules is at save rules&amp;nbsp; and system reject to add another one&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So is there any another solution&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/custom-email-templates-using-successfactors-document-generation/bc-p/14205157#M7088"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:44:20.303000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/bringing-clarity-to-360-degree-feedback-process-with-sap-successfactors-ai/ba-p/14205151</id>
    <title>Bringing Clarity to 360-Degree Feedback process with SAP SuccessFactors’ AI-Driven Innovations</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:47:27.633000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PTogapur</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17620</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_0-1756844914176.png" style="width: 734px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308187i8BB1457FB5975E12/image-dimensions/734x412/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="734" height="412" role="button" title="PKT_0-1756844914176.png" alt="PKT_0-1756844914176.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Implementing a 360-degree feedback program is a smart move for many companies looking to help their employees grow and become better leaders. Getting feedback from different people is definitely valuable—but turning that feedback into something more clear, helpful and easy to understand can still be a challenge. In recent conversations with customer and partners, who are exploring or implementing SAP SuccessFactors 360 Degree Multi-Rater Reviews as part of their talent strategy, several key insights have emerged. These takeaways may be valuable for organizations moving from a third-party feedback tool or looking to enhance the impact of their existing programs. Since many of these questions come up often in discussions, I’ve put this blog together to share what we’re hearing and learning.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Here are the questions I’ve recently been reviewing - Can the system generate comprehensive and user-friendly reports? Will it support tailored feedback across different leadership levels? And how can it leverage emerging technologies like AI to make feedback easier to interpret and act upon? This blog explores these questions, highlighting common expectations around 360-degree feedback reporting, the capabilities within SAP SuccessFactors, and how Artificial Intelligence (AI) is shaping the future of multi-rater feedback.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Understanding the Need for Tailored 360-degree Feedback Reports&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;One of the key parts of a successful 360-degree feedback process is to be able to adjust reports for different roles and levels of the person getting the feedback. Many organizations group their audiences by variables like, seniority and job responsibilities—often creating different reports for senior leaders, people managers, and team members.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;This kind of role-based setup helps make sure the feedback is meaningful and supports their specific growth goals. Each group needs a different feedback experience that reflects their unique responsibilities and development needs. This separation ensures the feedback is relevant and that reports are intuitive for the respective audience. Each audience expects that the feedback is presented in a way that is both insightful and accessible, with reports designed to include clear summaries, actionable visuals, and minimal interpretation needed from HR or managers.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;One common design goal is to make the report self-explanatory, so the recipient can read and understand it directly—without needing someone else to interpret the results. This is especially important in organizations aiming to scale their 360 program or support distributed teams.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Core Reporting Expectations for 360 Reviews&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Organizations often look for the following features in their 360 feedback reports:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Participation Tracking and Management&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The system should provide a clear summary of who has completed their assessments and allow administrators to send reminders when needed.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Competency Ratings and Gap Analysis&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Reports should show average ratings for competencies or behaviors, segmented by rater category (e.g., peers, managers, direct reports). They should also allow comparisons between self-ratings and those from others to highlight gaps, helping identify potential blind spots or over-/under-estimations.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strengths and Development Areas&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Reports should highlight top and low-rated competencies or behaviors to help recipients quickly see their strengths and areas for improvement, supporting more focused development planning.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comments and Qualitative Feedback&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Including open-ended comments from raters add depth to the numerical ratings and provides actionable insights.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration with Development Planning&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Feedback should seamlessly connect with individual development goals, supporting ongoing growth beyond the review cycle.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexibility and Customization&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The reporting tool should allow organizations to choose which raters to compare and how data is presented, tailoring the experience to specific business needs.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;How SAP SuccessFactors Meets and Exceeds These Expectations&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;The Detailed 360 Reports available within SAP SuccessFactors are designed to meet these core requirements with a high degree of flexibility. It lets you combine self-feedback with anonymous input from colleagues and external sources, giving you a complete and well-rounded view of employee performance across your organization.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/STRONG&gt;: All images used in the following sections are for representational purpose only.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;The &lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Participation Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; mirrors common evaluation summaries by tracking response completion and enabling action such as reminders and recall.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_0-1756840811351.png" style="width: 521px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308170i4DA61F88CBB5E385/image-dimensions/521x232/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="521" height="232" role="button" title="PKT_0-1756840811351.png" alt="PKT_0-1756840811351.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Competency ratings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; are shown not just as overall averages but broken down by rater groups, giving a clearer picture of different perspectives.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_1-1756840811358.png" style="width: 532px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308171iBFAE8DE1F69F839F/image-dimensions/532x218/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="532" height="218" role="button" title="PKT_1-1756840811358.png" alt="PKT_1-1756840811358.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;The &lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gap Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; or comparison views allow users to select which rater categories to compare, offering more customizations.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_2-1756840811360.png" style="width: 522px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308172i6DFCCBE3FE536914/image-dimensions/522x356/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="522" height="356" role="button" title="PKT_2-1756840811360.png" alt="PKT_2-1756840811360.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rank views&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; highlight highest and lowest-rated competencies, helping recipients focus attention effectively.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_3-1756840811362.png" style="width: 526px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308173i81C4C67B1D3953B2/image-dimensions/526x226/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="526" height="226" role="button" title="PKT_3-1756840811362.png" alt="PKT_3-1756840811362.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;The &lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hidden Strengths and Blind Spots&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; view pinpoints significant differences between self and other ratings, revealing perception gaps.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_4-1756840811364.png" style="width: 528px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308175i3E6367B958477AC8/image-dimensions/528x281/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="528" height="281" role="button" title="PKT_4-1756840811364.png" alt="PKT_4-1756840811364.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comments &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;are organized by competency and rater group, making it easier to review qualitative insights.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_5-1756840811370.png" style="width: 347px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308174i9DDACBA5543ECBB1/image-dimensions/347x310/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="347" height="310" role="button" title="PKT_5-1756840811370.png" alt="PKT_5-1756840811370.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;The &lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Development Goal&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;is fully integrated, enabling users to create and monitor goals directly linked to feedback results.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_6-1756840811374.png" style="width: 483px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308176i7CD6E009499EEEDC/image-dimensions/483x220/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="483" height="220" role="button" title="PKT_6-1756840811374.png" alt="PKT_6-1756840811374.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;These capabilities give organizations the tools to create customized, detailed reports that meet their specific feedback and development needs.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The Role of AI in Enhancing SAP SuccessFactors 360-Degree Feedback&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Looking beyond current features, SAP SuccessFactors 360 Degree Multi-Rater Reviews is leveraging Generative AI (GenAI) to transform how organizations collect, interpret, and act on 360 feedback, such as:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;AI-Generated Summaries:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Instead of manually reading through numerous comments, AI can summarize key themes and insights to generate the summary of detailed 360 Report, including feedback on specific attributes such as skills or competencies, reducing the time needed to interpret feedback.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_7-1756840811381.png" style="width: 524px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308177i3D6A109F589CDEBE/image-dimensions/524x300/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="524" height="300" role="button" title="PKT_7-1756840811381.png" alt="PKT_7-1756840811381.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_8-1756840811390.png" style="width: 526px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308178i2BBE71B075DE4692/image-dimensions/526x277/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="526" height="277" role="button" title="PKT_8-1756840811390.png" alt="PKT_8-1756840811390.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;Sentiment and Tone Analysis:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP’s 360 Reviews includes AI tools that can detect the emotional tone of feedback, helping identify feelings like praise or frustration that may not be clear from ratings alone. You can run sentiment analysis on comments for specific skills or competencies to understand how raters feel about an employee’s performance. The tool reviews the comment, skill name, and other details to tag the feedback as positive, negative, mixed, or unknown.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PKT_9-1756840811398.png" style="width: 527px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308179i2EA9B74A5F9AEACD/image-dimensions/527x272/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="527" height="272" role="button" title="PKT_9-1756840811398.png" alt="PKT_9-1756840811398.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;Bias Detection:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The AI-assisted writing tool in SAP SuccessFactors’ 360 Degree feedback helps employees improve their writing when giving feedback. AI can also help make feedback fairer by flagging biased or unclear language and encouraging reviewers to write clearer, more constructive comments. This tool suggests better grammar, spelling, and word choices, while ensuring the tone fits the audience—whether professional or friendly. It can help users write more clearly and briefly, change paragraphs into bullet points, and offer helpful tips based on the task they’re doing in the system.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;Actionable Insights:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Assisted 360 Review feature provides suggestions for improvement by identifying areas where employees can grow and offering actionable recommendations. These insights help guide upskilling, career development, and personalized next steps based on the feedback received. There are more features that are being discussed, for example, to be able to include direct link to create a development goal from the insights.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;These advancements aim not to replace human judgment but to support managers and employees in making sense of complex feedback data and turning it into meaningful growth opportunities.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core requirements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;to enable and use AI features in 360-degree reviews are:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;The fundamental license required for 360-degree feature is for the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Performance and Goals&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;module.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-generated insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;on 360 reports are considered a premium and require a separate license for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Units&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Administrators to have the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administrator&lt;/STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manage AI Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Services Administration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;permission in Role based permission configurations.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Users have the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Permissions&lt;/STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Access&lt;/STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assisted Writing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;permission to use AI Assisted Writing feature. &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;For additional details, please follow implementation guide -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-performance-and-goals/implementing-and-managing-360-reviews/overview-of-sap-successfactors-360-reviews" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help – SuccessFactors 360 Reviews&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial black,avant garde"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Final Thoughts: Collaboration and Clarity Are Key&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Implementing 360-degree feedback successfully requires clear alignment between HR teams, technology partners, and stakeholders. It is essential to:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Define the key audiences and tailor the feedback experience accordingly&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Set expectations around report design, usability, and actionability&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Leverage expert guidance to ensure the technology meets organizational needs&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Explore AI-driven features thoughtfully to amplify the value of feedback&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors offers a robust 360 Review solution that can accommodate diverse use cases, provide flexible and intuitive reporting, and increasingly incorporate AI to enhance insights.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;For organizations planning or refining their 360 feedback programs, a deep understanding of these capabilities and careful planning can make all the difference between collecting feedback and creating a true culture of continuous development.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-performance-and-goals/implementing-and-managing-360-reviews/overview-of-sap-successfactors-360-reviews" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help – SuccessFactors 360 Reviews&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-platform/using-admin-center/premium-ai-features-in-sap-successfactors" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help – Premium AI Features in SAP SuccessFactors &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/configure-sap-successfactors-performance-and-goals/introducing-360-reviews_fa1aba51-d9c2-469c-bf8f-5fc1012ed7a7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learning Journey – 360 Reviews&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;I’d love to hear your thoughts—feel free to share your comments, insights, or experiences.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/bringing-clarity-to-360-degree-feedback-process-with-sap-successfactors-ai/ba-p/14205151"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:47:27.633000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/comprehensive-overview-rise-with-sap-methodology-dashboard-quot-within-sap/bc-p/14205158#M184223</id>
    <title>Re: Comprehensive Overview “RISE With SAP Methodology Dashboard" within SAP Cloud ALM</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:49:40.041000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rony_Abraham_Muthiraparampil</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1866663</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;You can only view the number of unused objects from these dashboards...and there is no drill down capability from dashboard. The RISE with SAP Dashboard provides an understanding how far the connected systems are cloud complaint and clean core&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For deeper understanding of&amp;nbsp; unused data etc the below blog will give more insights&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/abap-call-monitor-scmon-analyze-usage-of-your-code/ba-p/13313572" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/abap-call-monitor-scmon-analyze-usage-of-your-code/ba-p/13313572&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/comprehensive-overview-rise-with-sap-methodology-dashboard-quot-within-sap/bc-p/14205158#M184223"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:49:40.041000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/restrict-access-of-oauth2-0-clients-with-the-technical-user-purpose/bc-p/14205159#M175256</id>
    <title>Re: Restrict Access of OAuth2.0 Clients with the Technical User purpose</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:50:57.707000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Thibault_dockx</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1410380</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1411114"&gt;@swatisonawane&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I can't confirm this, but I assume that the User ID functions similarly to that of an actual user and therefore must be unique. This would allow the roles to be assigned in the same way as they would for a real user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Still looking for a case where I could put the restrictions to use, as they would seem most handy during consumption via OData.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/restrict-access-of-oauth2-0-clients-with-the-technical-user-purpose/bc-p/14205159#M175256"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:50:57.707000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-discussions/bring-your-own-identity-sap-s-strategic-transformation-of-identity-and/m-p/14205160#M558</id>
    <title>Re: Bring Your Own Identity: SAP's Strategic Transformation of Identity and Authentication Managemen</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:52:01.680000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichaelBuonoGKN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/67302</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I found "Identity Renovation" in the video title, as well as mentioned at 0:25, 3:00, and 6:23 -- for me, this is sufficient.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-discussions/bring-your-own-identity-sap-s-strategic-transformation-of-identity-and/m-p/14205160#M558"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:52:01.680000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/new-or-not-to-the-sap-community-share-your-story/m-p/14205162#M10331</id>
    <title>Re: New or not to the SAP Community, share your story!</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T21:52:43.986000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MadhanPallamal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1447829</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I’m from India and currently work at &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP America, Newtown Square&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Process Senior Consultant&lt;/STRONG&gt;. My SAP journey began over &lt;STRONG&gt;12 years ago&lt;/STRONG&gt; at &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Labs India&lt;/STRONG&gt;, first as a contractor and then as a &lt;STRONG&gt;full-time developer&lt;/STRONG&gt;. I later moved up to &lt;STRONG&gt;Senior Developer&lt;/STRONG&gt; before transitioning to SAP America.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Community has been a big part of my learning and growth over the years, and I’m excited to share my experiences here while continuing to learn from all of you!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- Madhan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/new-or-not-to-the-sap-community-share-your-story/m-p/14205162#M10331"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T21:52:43.986000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-remove-fields-in-smart-table-from-personalization-sap-ui5/qaa-p/14205165#M4924918</id>
    <title>回复： How to remove fields in smart table from personalizat...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T22:02:29.877000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManikS2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1511231</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/775172"&gt;@Senqi_Hu&lt;/a&gt;, any idea why this method is written in the onBeforeRebindTable and not in the other methods like init of view</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-remove-fields-in-smart-table-from-personalization-sap-ui5/qaa-p/14205165#M4924918"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T22:02:29.877000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extracting-sap-s-4hana-data-tables-amp-cds-views-to-external-storages/qaa-p/14205171#M4924919</id>
    <title>Re: Extracting SAP S/4HANA Data (Tables &amp; CDS Views) to E...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T22:24:00.386000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PrabhithPrabhakaran</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/12003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/136822"&gt;@AndriusK&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is a common and engaging discussion topic in many customer environments today. I typically reference the note below—particularly the Solution section—to guide and support my conversations on this subject.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3255746" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3255746 - Unpermitted usage of ODP Data Replication APIs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The&amp;nbsp;OData API option that exists comes with lot of limitations..&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In Summary : The preferred way forward is Datasphere (DSP). Since DSP could potentially be included as part of the BDC formation, that will undoubtedly spark another interesting discussion.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR, Prabhith&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extracting-sap-s-4hana-data-tables-amp-cds-views-to-external-storages/qaa-p/14205171#M4924919"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T22:24:00.386000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/pm-fleet-objects-equipment-additional-fields-for-vehicle-object-types/qaq-p/14205174</id>
    <title>PM Fleet objects - Equipment additional fields for vehicle object types</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T22:31:30.949000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S0027154449</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2208418</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello all... I´m wondering if in SAP S/4Hana Cloud Public Edition 2508 we can manage the fleet objects, meaning the vehicle equipment with additional standard fields related to these object types. I cannot see any information about it in the product help. I connot find an object in Migration Cockpit with those fields related to equipment. Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/pm-fleet-objects-equipment-additional-fields-for-vehicle-object-types/qaq-p/14205174"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T22:31:30.949000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-access-script-variable-in-calculation-editor-for-a-sac-story/qaq-p/14205231</id>
    <title>Cannot access script variable in calculation editor for a sac story</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T22:43:00.133000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NC8</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1761477</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cannot access the script variable&amp;nbsp;varLastDayofMonthEndDateInput&amp;nbsp; using&amp;nbsp;@varLastDayofMonthEndDateInput in calculation editor. As specified in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/18850a0e13944f53aa8a8b7c094ea29e/82bbae6b7005482c87bfd59a91735b45.html?version=2025.17" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/18850a0e13944f53aa8a8b7c094ea29e/82bbae6b7005482c87bfd59a91735b45.html?version=2025.17&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Suggest if I have to make any changes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pict090225_1.png" style="width: 865px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308205iC7B671CCDF380BAF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pict090225_1.png" alt="pict090225_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pict090225_2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308191i332DE6FA83864F07/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="pict090225_2.png" alt="pict090225_2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-access-script-variable-in-calculation-editor-for-a-sac-story/qaq-p/14205231"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T22:43:00.133000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-lifecycle-management/webinar-sap-cloud-alm-change-and-deployment-management-portugu%C3%AAs/ev-p/14205233</id>
    <title>[Webinar] SAP Cloud ALM Change and Deployment Management - Português</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T22:51:39.866000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>laura_leote</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1404711</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Junte-se a nós para uma sessão interativa em que exploraremos como o &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM Change and Deployment Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; pode apoiar sua jornada de transformação, garantindo governança, rastreabilidade e automação no ciclo de vida de mudanças. Você verá como gerenciar requisições de mudança, controlar implantações e aumentar a eficiência com processos padronizados — tudo em um ambiente de nuvem seguro e integrado.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tópicos principais:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Visão geral do Change and Deployment Management no SAP Cloud ALM&lt;BR /&gt;• Como planejar, aprovar e rastrear mudanças em toda a paisagem de sistemas&lt;BR /&gt;• Automação de implantações e integração com pipelines de CI/CD&lt;BR /&gt;• Melhores práticas para reduzir riscos e aumentar a transparência das mudanças&lt;BR /&gt;• Demonstração ao vivo de cenários de gestão de mudanças&lt;BR /&gt;• Sessão de perguntas e respostas com especialistas da SAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Público-alvo:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Gestores de TI, equipes de projetos SAP, administradores de sistemas, profissionais de DevOps e todos os clientes e parceiros interessados em melhorar o controle e a qualidade das mudanças em ambientes SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pré-requisitos&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solicitamos que você complete as seguintes etapas antes de participar do evento:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Realize o processo de ativação do seu tenant. Acesse o link para ativar seu SAP Cloud ALM (caso ainda não tenha sido provisionado):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/systemsprovisioning/provisioning" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://me.sap.com/systemsprovisioning/provisioning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Como Solicitar SAP Cloud ALM no SAP for Me -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=axFjM01ZnU0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=axFjM01ZnU0&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lembre-se do ID de usuário e da senha que foram usados para reivindicar o tenant do SAP Cloud ALM e também para o cockpit do BTP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Link para acessar o cockpit do BTP -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://account.hana.ondemand.com/#/home/welcome" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://account.hana.ondemand.com/#/home/welcome&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Verifique o e-mail de notification@sap.com para o link de acesso ao seu SAP Cloud ALM e os próximos passos.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Link para acessar Configuração e Administração para SAP Cloud ALM - Configuração da Fundação &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-alm/setup-administration/enabling-api" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-alm/setup-administration/enabling-api&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-lifecycle-management/webinar-sap-cloud-alm-change-and-deployment-management-portugu%C3%AAs/ev-p/14205233"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T22:51:39.866000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-lifecycle-management/webinar-sap-cloud-alm-change-and-deployment-management-espa%C3%B1ol/ev-p/14205235</id>
    <title>[Webinar] SAP Cloud ALM Change and Deployment Management - Español</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T22:53:05.591000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>laura_leote</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1404711</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Únase a nosotros en una sesión interactiva donde exploraremos cómo &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM Change and Deployment Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; puede apoyar su viaje de transformación, garantizando gobernanza, trazabilidad y automatización en el ciclo de vida de los cambios. Verá cómo gestionar solicitudes de cambio, controlar despliegues y aumentar la eficiencia con procesos estandarizados, todo en un entorno de nube seguro e integrado.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Temas principales:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Visión general de Change and Deployment Management en SAP Cloud ALM&lt;BR /&gt;• Cómo planificar, aprobar y rastrear cambios en todo el paisaje de sistemas&lt;BR /&gt;• Automatización de despliegues e integración con pipelines de CI/CD&lt;BR /&gt;• Mejores prácticas para reducir riesgos y aumentar la transparencia de los cambios&lt;BR /&gt;• Demostración en vivo de escenarios de gestión de cambios&lt;BR /&gt;• Sesión de preguntas y respuestas con expertos de SAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Público objetivo:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Gerentes de TI, equipos de proyectos SAP, administradores de sistemas, profesionales de DevOps y todos los clientes y socios interesados en mejorar el control y la calidad de los cambios en entornos SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Requisitos previos&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Le solicitamos que complete los siguientes pasos antes de asistir al evento:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Realice el proceso de activación de su tenant. Acceda al enlace para activar su SAP Cloud ALM (en caso de que aún no haya sido provisionado):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/systemsprovisioning/provisioning" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://me.sap.com/systemsprovisioning/provisioning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cómo Solicitar SAP Cloud ALM en SAP for Me -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=axFjM01ZnU0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=axFjM01ZnU0&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recuerde el ID de usuario y la contraseña que se usaron para activar el inquilino de SAP Cloud ALM y también para el cockpit de BTP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enlace para acceder al cockpit de BTP -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://account.hana.ondemand.com/#/home/welcome" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://account.hana.ondemand.com/#/home/welcome&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Verifique el correo electrónico de&amp;nbsp;notification@sap.com para el enlace de acceso a su SAP Cloud ALM y los próximos pasos.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enlace para acceder a la Configuración y Administración de SAP Cloud ALM - Configuración de la Fundación&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-alm/setup-administration/enabling-api" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-alm/setup-administration/enabling-api&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-lifecycle-management/webinar-sap-cloud-alm-change-and-deployment-management-espa%C3%B1ol/ev-p/14205235"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T22:53:05.591000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-lifecycle-management/webinar-por-que-o-monitoramento-continua-sendo-essencial-para-clientes-rise/ev-p/14205237</id>
    <title>[Webinar] Por que o monitoramento continua sendo essencial para clientes RISE with SAP - Português</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T22:54:42.234000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>laura_leote</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1404711</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Participe desta sessão interativa em que discutiremos &lt;STRONG&gt;por que o monitoramento continua sendo essencial para clientes RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Com o &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM Operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, você garante visibilidade, estabilidade e tratamento proativo de incidentes em toda a sua paisagem de sistemas na nuvem. Aprenda a detectar anomalias, configurar alertas e manter suas operações funcionando sem interrupções em um ambiente híbrido e desafiador.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tópicos principais:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• Por que o monitoramento ainda é crítico na era da nuvem&lt;BR /&gt;• Como o SAP Cloud ALM Operations apoia clientes RISE&lt;BR /&gt;• Integração de monitoramento em sistemas híbridos e em nuvem&lt;BR /&gt;• Alertas proativos e resolução de incidentes&lt;BR /&gt;• Casos de uso reais e demonstração ao vivo&lt;BR /&gt;• Sessão de perguntas e respostas com especialistas da SAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Público-alvo:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Clientes RISE with SAP, equipes de operações de TI, especialistas em SAP Basis, administradores de sistemas e parceiros interessados em garantir operações confiáveis em ambientes SAP na nuvem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pré-requisitos&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solicitamos que você complete as seguintes etapas antes de participar do evento:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Realize o processo de ativação do seu tenant. Acesse o link para ativar seu SAP Cloud ALM (caso ainda não tenha sido provisionado):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/systemsprovisioning/provisioning" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://me.sap.com/systemsprovisioning/provisioning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Como Solicitar SAP Cloud ALM no SAP for Me -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=axFjM01ZnU0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=axFjM01ZnU0&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lembre-se do ID de usuário e da senha que foram usados para reivindicar o tenant do SAP Cloud ALM e também para o cockpit do BTP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Link para acessar o cockpit do BTP -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://account.hana.ondemand.com/#/home/welcome" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://account.hana.ondemand.com/#/home/welcome&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Verifique o e-mail de notification@sap.com para o link de acesso ao seu SAP Cloud ALM e os próximos passos.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Link para acessar Configuração e Administração para SAP Cloud ALM - Configuração da Fundação &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-alm/setup-administration/enabling-api" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-alm/setup-administration/enabling-api&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-lifecycle-management/webinar-por-que-o-monitoramento-continua-sendo-essencial-para-clientes-rise/ev-p/14205237"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T22:54:42.234000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-lifecycle-management/webinar-por-qu%C3%A9-el-monitoreo-sigue-siendo-un-factor-clave-de-%C3%A9xito-para-los/ev-p/14205239</id>
    <title>[Webinar] Por qué el monitoreo sigue siendo un factor clave de éxito para los clientes de RISE with</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T22:56:09.892000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>laura_leote</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1404711</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Únase a nosotros en una sesión interactiva donde exploraremos &lt;STRONG&gt;por qué el monitoreo sigue siendo un factor clave de éxito para los clientes de RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Con &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM Operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, puede garantizar visibilidad, estabilidad y manejo proactivo de incidentes en toda su arquitectura de nube. Aprenderá cómo detectar anomalías, configurar alertas y mantener sus operaciones funcionando sin interrupciones en un entorno híbrido y complejo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Temas principales:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• Por qué el monitoreo sigue siendo crítico en la era de la nube&lt;BR /&gt;• Cómo SAP Cloud ALM Operations apoya a los clientes de RISE&lt;BR /&gt;• Integración del monitoreo en sistemas híbridos y en la nube&lt;BR /&gt;• Alertas proactivas y resolución de incidentes&lt;BR /&gt;• Casos de uso reales y demostración en vivo&lt;BR /&gt;• Sesión de preguntas y respuestas con expertos de SAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Público objetivo:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Clientes de RISE with SAP, equipos de operaciones de TI, expertos en SAP Basis, administradores de sistemas y socios interesados en garantizar operaciones confiables en entornos SAP en la nube.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Requisitos previos&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Le solicitamos que complete los siguientes pasos antes de asistir al evento:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Realice el proceso de activación de su tenant. Acceda al enlace para activar su SAP Cloud ALM (en caso de que aún no haya sido provisionado):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/systemsprovisioning/provisioning" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://me.sap.com/systemsprovisioning/provisioning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cómo Solicitar SAP Cloud ALM en SAP for Me -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=axFjM01ZnU0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=axFjM01ZnU0&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recuerde el ID de usuario y la contraseña que se usaron para activar el inquilino de SAP Cloud ALM y también para el cockpit de BTP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enlace para acceder al cockpit de BTP -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://account.hana.ondemand.com/#/home/welcome" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://account.hana.ondemand.com/#/home/welcome&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Verifique el correo electrónico de&amp;nbsp;notification@sap.com para el enlace de acceso a su SAP Cloud ALM y los próximos pasos.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enlace para acceder a la Configuración y Administración de SAP Cloud ALM - Configuración de la Fundación&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-alm/setup-administration/enabling-api" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-alm/setup-administration/enabling-api&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-lifecycle-management/webinar-por-qu%C3%A9-el-monitoreo-sigue-siendo-un-factor-clave-de-%C3%A9xito-para-los/ev-p/14205239"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T22:56:09.892000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/ip-details-request/qaq-p/14205243</id>
    <title>IP Details Request</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T23:01:18.917000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We need to whitelist the SAP Commerce Cloud endpoints; please advise how to access this information in the Cloud Portal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/ip-details-request/qaq-p/14205243"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T23:01:18.917000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/ip-details-request/qaa-p/14205244#M457727</id>
    <title>Re: IP Details Request</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T23:01:26.503000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To retrieve this information from Cloud Portal one should follow the steps below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open Cloud Portal home page&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to environment details page of the Commerce Cloud environment, for which public IP address must be obtained&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on any endpoint's name, what will open&amp;nbsp;"&lt;STRONG&gt;Edit Endpoint&lt;/STRONG&gt;" page (also known as&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;endpoint details page&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The public IP address will displayed in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;web proxy&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;field located in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;General Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;section.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;NOTE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Please be aware that public IP address of a SAP Commerce Cloud is the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;same for all public endpoints within one particular environment.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details are present in KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3302662" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3302662&lt;/A&gt; - How to Check SAP Commerce Cloud's IPs and IP Range.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Please let me know in case you need further assistance on the topic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Stephane&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Support&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/ip-details-request/qaa-p/14205244#M457727"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T23:01:26.503000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/creating-your-first-iflow-in-cloud-integration-for-an-ibp-s-4hana-on-prem/ba-p/14205240</id>
    <title>Creating your first IFlow in Cloud Integration for an IBP - S/4HANA (on prem/private) integration</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T23:03:31.723000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofianePebre</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476236</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Continuing this blog series on working with &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Cloud+Integration/pd-p/67837800100800006801" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="361-1"&gt;Cloud Integration&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;from&amp;nbsp; SAP BTP's &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integration+Suite/pd-p/73554900100800003241" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="23-1"&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;service.&lt;BR /&gt;We will cover in this article how to create and deploy your first customer integration flow between &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Integrated+Business+Planning/pd-p/67838200100800006742" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="664-1"&gt;SAP Integrated Business Planning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/73554900100800000266" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="799-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(on premise / private cloud).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All steps from my previous two blog entries &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-ibp-new-integration-option-introducing-sap-cloud-integration-from-btp-s/ba-p/14169516" target="_blank"&gt;BTP/IBP Technical setup&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/configuring-sap-cloud-integration-for-an-ibp-to-s-4hana-on-prem-private/ba-p/14194922" target="_blank"&gt;Integration Suite Initial Configuration&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users have been created via the BTP cockpit with the relevant roles depending on what tasks they need to perform. The three typical roles for CI are the following: &lt;EM&gt;PI_Administrator, PI_Integration_Developer and PI_Business_Expert&lt;/EM&gt;. Check the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/persona-2937e5ca6ef448cfb21451a2461cc2a6#loio2937e5ca6ef448cfb21451a2461cc2a6__business" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Personas for CI information&lt;/A&gt; to understand what each covers in order to assign the most relevant ones.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To support actions from this blog entry you need the PI_Integration_Developer role.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/ibp_s4hana_addon" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA, Supply Chain Integration Add-On for SAP Integrated Business Planning&lt;/A&gt; is configured in S/4HANA for integration purposes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creating your customer iflow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that we have done the technical setup and configured Integration Suite to define source/target systems (called destinations) and loaded the reusable iflows we can start building our own project integrations: customer iflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To begin, we can start creating a simple business iflow that calls upon a reusable iflow delivered with the August 2025 release called Generic Data Transfer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The latter is a full-fledged iflow that is built on the basis on a series of individual reusable iflows (that cannot be executed as standalone). It can be leveraged to : read the S/4HANA integration addon extractors, transform &amp;amp; map data to corresponding IBP target and load it there (triggering the IBP post processing batch).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_0-1756845520341.png" style="width: 951px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308193i9CF382BF4CADB627/image-dimensions/951x215/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="951" height="215" role="button" title="SofianePebre_0-1756845520341.png" alt="SofianePebre_0-1756845520341.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But if you want to call upon it with two different sets of parameters, i.e. calling two different extractors with corresponding filters to send POs AND PlannedOrders to IBP, then you have to have two customer iflows. It is the same in CI-DS : for two key figure objects you need two dataflows or even two tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So we can create a first customer iflow that simply calls our Generic Data Transfer iflow as a model that we’ll later copy as many times as needed to cover each object we need to send to IBP. We call this model a &lt;STRONG&gt;wrapper&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Access your Integration Suite tenant and the Design &amp;gt; Integrations and APIs section from your left side panel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on Create and fill out the needed information to set your own package.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_1-1756845520345.png" style="width: 713px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308195iE8BB5E2FCAB37B50/image-dimensions/713x381/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="713" height="381" role="button" title="SofianePebre_1-1756845520345.png" alt="SofianePebre_1-1756845520345.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think of your package as a project in CIDS, a grouping of iflows that you could attach significance to (e.g. a package per source system or type of data integrated or target planning area, etc.). You can also store documents (e.g. specifications, guides, etc.) in your package to support integration activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on Add &amp;gt; Integration Flow&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_2-1756845520349.png" style="width: 679px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308194i8095910C0BDC2448/image-dimensions/679x356/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="679" height="356" role="button" title="SofianePebre_2-1756845520349.png" alt="SofianePebre_2-1756845520349.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A blank canvas appears with the premises of your flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the top, you have various features allowing you to build your flow. Our intend here is to have one prior step, before adding a call to our main reusable iflow, called a content modifier. This object will allow us to define and pass along global parameter values to the generic reusable iflow in order to send specific data to IBP, e.g. purchase orders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the menu, select Transformation &amp;gt; Content Modifier&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_3-1756845520352.png" style="width: 736px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308196iF920B70F895E06B9/image-dimensions/736x311/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="736" height="311" role="button" title="SofianePebre_3-1756845520352.png" alt="SofianePebre_3-1756845520352.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click in the middle of the process structure to add it between the start and end events. Bring up the details section of the Content Modifier from the bottom of the screen and define a name for this step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_4-1756845520354.png" style="width: 745px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308198iE2E0860639B0D942/image-dimensions/745x465/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="745" height="465" role="button" title="SofianePebre_4-1756845520354.png" alt="SofianePebre_4-1756845520354.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A process must begin and end with events. For our purpose, let’s use a timer as a start event. Select from the upper functions Event &amp;gt; Timer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_5-1756845520357.png" style="width: 877px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308197i7239E55BD730D3DD/image-dimensions/877x277/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="877" height="277" role="button" title="SofianePebre_5-1756845520357.png" alt="SofianePebre_5-1756845520357.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Place it before our previous Content Modifier and delete the preexisting Start event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_6-1756845520358.png" style="width: 511px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308199i3AA09E091942B3AC/image-dimensions/511x205/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="511" height="205" role="button" title="SofianePebre_6-1756845520358.png" alt="SofianePebre_6-1756845520358.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can choose how the timer start works by clicking on it and updating its properties from the bottom of the screen. Go to tab Scheduler and select Basic with the below selections so that the execution of ths iflow only starts when you manually trigger its deployment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_7-1756845520361.png" style="width: 367px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308201iECE57135BCC7F84B/image-dimensions/367x687/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="367" height="687" role="button" title="SofianePebre_7-1756845520361.png" alt="SofianePebre_7-1756845520361.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is how you can also schedule your iflow to run with more frequency, for example every day/week, etc (see the Repeat criteria above) or with more complex modes (see the Advanced tab). Once you have set this, you need to save your iflow:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_8-1756845520362.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308200iA3AAFAB1FFB86D0C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SofianePebre_8-1756845520362.png" alt="SofianePebre_8-1756845520362.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To remove the preexisting Start event, click on it and then on the bin icon that appears to its right&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_9-1756845520363.png" style="width: 227px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308202i828DFAC717539F37/image-dimensions/227x253/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="227" height="253" role="button" title="SofianePebre_9-1756845520363.png" alt="SofianePebre_9-1756845520363.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can proceed the same way with the Sender /Receiver objects to the left and right of the flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, we need to add our generic reusable iflow that encodes calls to both S/4HANA and IBP. For this, you can again look for the upper function Call &amp;gt; External Call &amp;gt; Request Reply or click on the previous process step, the Content Modifier, and select the “add flow step” &amp;nbsp;option via the “+” icon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_10-1756845520364.png" style="width: 427px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308204iA6DF8CB9690FACF4/image-dimensions/427x195/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="427" height="195" role="button" title="SofianePebre_10-1756845520364.png" alt="SofianePebre_10-1756845520364.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select request reply&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_11-1756845520365.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308203iFFD0F7981D8A46E0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SofianePebre_11-1756845520365.png" alt="SofianePebre_11-1756845520365.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add it to the right of the Content Modifier, before the end event and give it a name.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_12-1756845520366.png" style="width: 506px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308206i887EB461D030ABEA/image-dimensions/506x206/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="506" height="206" role="button" title="SofianePebre_12-1756845520366.png" alt="SofianePebre_12-1756845520366.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_13-1756845520367.png" style="width: 359px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308207iACE970CF37DE623A/image-dimensions/359x136/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="359" height="136" role="button" title="SofianePebre_13-1756845520367.png" alt="SofianePebre_13-1756845520367.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This step will technically call the generic reusable iflow. To do this we will add a Receiver in the iflow definition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_14-1756845520368.png" style="width: 473px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308208i93D38BA8D283A15C/image-dimensions/473x201/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="473" height="201" role="button" title="SofianePebre_14-1756845520368.png" alt="SofianePebre_14-1756845520368.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;search for Receiver and add it to the flow.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_15-1756845520369.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308209i6695BE1092C6AFC9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SofianePebre_15-1756845520369.png" alt="SofianePebre_15-1756845520369.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note you can also add it from the upper function Participant &amp;gt; Receiver.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system now asks how you want to link the Request Reply to the Receiver by choosing from a list of adapter types. Select Process Direct to specify you need to call another process (the generic reusable iflow).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_16-1756845520370.png" style="width: 315px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308210i1B2608DC8B3129E1/image-dimensions/315x418/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="315" height="418" role="button" title="SofianePebre_16-1756845520370.png" alt="SofianePebre_16-1756845520370.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Receiver is placed outside of the integration process box, you can also rename it to better understand its use by simply clicking on the box and changing its properties.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now to link this external call to the generic reusable iflow, you need to click on the Process Direct arrow linking the two objects and look to the “Connection” tab of its properties, set the full technical ID of the reusable iflow in the Address field:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP_IBP_Add-on_Read_-_Generic_Process&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_17-1756845520372.png" style="width: 741px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308211i5E4965CEA7A3418F/image-dimensions/741x643/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="741" height="643" role="button" title="SofianePebre_17-1756845520372.png" alt="SofianePebre_17-1756845520372.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: you can find this ID by navigating to the reusable iflow itself : Design section from the left side panel, select the “SAP IBP Add-On - Reusable Integration Flows” package, open the iflow “SAP IBP Add-On Read - Generic Data Transfer”. Bring up the flow properties from the bottom of the screen and find its ID.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_18-1756845520380.png" style="width: 716px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308213iC173CC8C069807AA/image-dimensions/716x509/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="716" height="509" role="button" title="SofianePebre_18-1756845520380.png" alt="SofianePebre_18-1756845520380.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our customer iflow now has all necessary objects to run (the wrapper being a quick set up), we just need to define the global parameters for the Content Modifier we created as a first step in order to have the possibility during execution of the flow to specify what extractor should be read, what mapping should be applied, what filters should be used, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These parameters are already part of the reusable iflow so once we call them in the first step and fill them, they will be automatically read and applied.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To be able to set your own values when executing (deploying) the iflow, you need to externalize them via the Content Modifier step this way:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on your Content Modifier step, previously named Set Extraction Filters and click on Externalize from its properties section.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_19-1756845520383.png" style="width: 785px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308212iD71433B7A2021258/image-dimensions/785x204/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="785" height="204" role="button" title="SofianePebre_19-1756845520383.png" alt="SofianePebre_19-1756845520383.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create your parameters one by one (use the Add button to allow entering more parameters).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Type the parameter name in the Name column from the below table:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Non exhaustive list of available global parameters&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="1000"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parameter Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;FileName&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Name of the generated file passed to IBP that you can download from the Data Integration Jobs app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;TypeOfData&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The type of data to load, KeyFigures or MasterData (respect this way of writing).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;TimeDisaggregationLevel&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use time level values that are defined in the time profile of the planning area in IBP using the &lt;EM&gt;Planning Areas – Model Configuration &lt;/EM&gt;app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can only specify a TimeDisaggregationLevel value that is the same or higher than the base time profile level of the planning level you’re uploading data to. If TimeDisaggregationLevel is left empty, it defaults to the base time profile level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;MasterDataType&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The target Master Data type you want to load in IBP without the prefix that is usually used to distinguish master data types for different planning areas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example: your master data type is ABCPRODUCT, type in PRODUCT here. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;MasterDataPrefix&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here you can set the prefix only.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example: your master data type is ABCPRODUCT, type in ABC here.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;BatchName&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The name that appears as batch in the Data Integration Jobs app in IBP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;PostFetchFilterExtensionID&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are using an extension for defining filters, this is where you’d set its ID. Will be covered in a future blog entry.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ERPMaxPackageSize&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maximum package size coming from the S/4HANA integration addon for IBP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;MappingExtensionID&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are using an extension for mapping, this is where you’d set its ID. Will be covered in a future blog entry.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Extractor&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The S/4HANA extractor ID to use as data source.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ERPRequestedFields&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Source fields to map from S/4HANA side. Add them in any order, separated by commas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example : PRDID,LOCID,KEYFIGUREDATE,PLANNINGRELEVQTY&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;IBPFieldList&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Target fields to map to IBP. Add them in any order, separated by commas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example : PRDID,LOCID,KEYFIGUREDATE,MINRECEIPT&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;FieldMap&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mapping between above S/4HANA and IBP fields.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Separate mapping groups by commas and separate source from target with colons.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example : PRDID: PRDID,LOCID: LOCID, KEYFIGUREDATE: KEYFIGUREDATE,PLANNINGRELEVQTY:MINRECEIPT&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note: when both source and target have the same ID, you do not need to add them here, so the simplified version of the mapping in the above case that would also work is :&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;PLANNINGRELEVQTY:MINRECEIPT&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;DestinationforSAPIBP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Destination configured in BTP cockpit to represent the IBP tenant you want to use as target for the flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;PlanningArea&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The IBP planning area as target for the flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;PlanningAreaVersion&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The IBP planning area version as target for the flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Filters&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Defines the filter criteria in restricted OData format:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Relational operators&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These operators are EQ, NE, LT, LE, GT, GE, and LIKE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Logical operators&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These operators are AND, NOT, OR, (, and ).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Functions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These functions are STARTSWITH, ENDSWITH, and SUBSTRINGOF.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Separate the conditions by a comma. The objects you filter on are fields from the S/4HANA extractor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example: TIMEPROFILEID EQ '2504',TIMEPROFILELEVEL EQ '2',MRPELEMENTTYPE EQ 'BE'&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ERPDestination&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Destination configured in BTP cockpit to represent the S/4HANA tenant you want to use as source for the flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;ProcessUnchangedData&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to skip unchanged data, regardless of SAP IBP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;global parameter setting for this behavior, set this parameter to &lt;STRONG&gt;false&lt;/STRONG&gt;. If you want to process unchanged data, regardless of the SAP IBP global parameter setting, set this parameter to &lt;STRONG&gt;true&lt;/STRONG&gt;. If you leave this parameter field empty, the SAP IBP global parameter determines the behavior.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216.628px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;BatchCommand&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="405.534px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Defines the operation type. Accepted parameters are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;INSERT_UPDATE, REPLACE, DELETE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leave the Source type as Constant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Source Value allows you to either&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;give a default value that will not be modifiable when deploying the iflow,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;give a default value that the user can update upon deployment,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;set no value and let the user define it during deployment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_20-1756845520386.png" style="width: 901px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308214i268BB28F8F20068F/image-dimensions/901x237/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="901" height="237" role="button" title="SofianePebre_20-1756845520386.png" alt="SofianePebre_20-1756845520386.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To set a &lt;STRONG&gt;default value that will not be editable&lt;/STRONG&gt; by the user when deploying the iflow, simply fill in the Source Value field with your value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example: you want this iflow to always be executed in Insert/update load mode in IBP.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_21-1756845520388.png" style="width: 838px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308215iD8413BE6400FC689/image-dimensions/838x222/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="838" height="222" role="button" title="SofianePebre_21-1756845520388.png" alt="SofianePebre_21-1756845520388.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To let the user &lt;STRONG&gt;define the value only upon deploying the iflow&lt;/STRONG&gt;, fill in the Source Value field with the name of the parameter surrounded by double brackets on each side (format {{FileName}}). Once you validate, this will appear as &lt;EM&gt;&amp;lt; Define Value &amp;gt;&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_22-1756845520389.png" style="width: 825px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308216i073D9724D2AF06AB/image-dimensions/825x198/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="825" height="198" role="button" title="SofianePebre_22-1756845520389.png" alt="SofianePebre_22-1756845520389.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you validate:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_23-1756845520390.png" style="width: 842px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308217i42CCCDF4D92E05AF/image-dimensions/842x40/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="842" height="40" role="button" title="SofianePebre_23-1756845520390.png" alt="SofianePebre_23-1756845520390.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;And finally, to set a &lt;STRONG&gt;default value that can be editable when deploying the iflow&lt;/STRONG&gt;, proceed as above with the double brackets strategy and then click on the &lt;EM&gt;&amp;lt; Define Value&amp;gt;&lt;/EM&gt; value. This opens a new window where you can set your default value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example: you want your iflow to be used for loading Key Figures by default but if a user needs to change this to send Master Data, they can make that change during deployment.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_24-1756845520394.png" style="width: 726px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308218i17F8A3B10E787544/image-dimensions/726x334/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="726" height="334" role="button" title="SofianePebre_24-1756845520394.png" alt="SofianePebre_24-1756845520394.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the end, you have set all global parameters that impacts the way the integration is executed, click on OK.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_25-1756845520406.png" style="width: 748px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308219i4E573DD17D7E8A3A/image-dimensions/748x411/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="748" height="411" role="button" title="SofianePebre_25-1756845520406.png" alt="SofianePebre_25-1756845520406.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then Save.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_26-1756845520414.png" style="width: 574px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308220i14ED335F2D276762/image-dimensions/574x397/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="574" height="397" role="button" title="SofianePebre_26-1756845520414.png" alt="SofianePebre_26-1756845520414.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The configuration of your customer iflow as a wrapper of an end to end reusable iflow is finished, we can now deploy it!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deploying your customer iflow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So now we have a customer iflow that :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Starts when deployed (manually / via schedule)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Expects input global parameters to identify systems, extractor name, filters to apply, mapping, etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uses a pre configured reusable iflow that opens connections to source and target systems, reads S/4HANA data, loads data in IBP and triggers post processing there.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To deploy your customer iflow, access it from your package, click on the menu and select Configure to set your final parameters and deploy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_27-1756845520419.png" style="width: 752px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308221iC1583CC4D18C7C21/image-dimensions/752x243/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="752" height="243" role="button" title="SofianePebre_27-1756845520419.png" alt="SofianePebre_27-1756845520419.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you Deploy without the configuration, the iflow will use all your defaulted global parameter values directly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can here adapt your global parameters if needed, then click on Deploy&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_28-1756845520427.png" style="width: 722px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308222iB1559A055DD0087B/image-dimensions/722x372/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="722" height="372" role="button" title="SofianePebre_28-1756845520427.png" alt="SofianePebre_28-1756845520427.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Validate the runtime profile as CI by clicking on Yes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_29-1756845520430.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308223i8701C39217172013/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SofianePebre_29-1756845520430.png" alt="SofianePebre_29-1756845520430.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the log in the Monitor section of the left side panel. Go to Monitor Message Processing app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_30-1756845520432.png" style="width: 321px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308224iE0C568AA27802A01/image-dimensions/321x336/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="321" height="336" role="button" title="SofianePebre_30-1756845520432.png" alt="SofianePebre_30-1756845520432.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find your iflow name and select the associated entry&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_31-1756845520440.png" style="width: 803px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308225iAC22438B5FC2A10B/image-dimensions/803x322/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="803" height="322" role="button" title="SofianePebre_31-1756845520440.png" alt="SofianePebre_31-1756845520440.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that in CI you will get individual log entries for each iflow and embedded iflow. This means since we are using a wrapper iflow that calls upon a reusable iflow, itself calling upon individual reusable iflows, you will get multiple entries for your single deployment action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To identify all logs related to your deployment, you can use the Correlation ID associated to the initial entry associated to your customer iflow entry. Click on the hyperlink, this will copy this value to the header filter and only show you log entries related to your deployment action. You can appreciate all steps executed during this deployment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note : when analyzing log issues (will be handled via an example in another blog entry), always start from the last log entry and make your way upwards one by one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_32-1756845520450.png" style="width: 873px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308226iFF2CBF8CB2E02DFF/image-dimensions/873x476/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="873" height="476" role="button" title="SofianePebre_32-1756845520450.png" alt="SofianePebre_32-1756845520450.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, once you’ve checked your flow was successful, you can proceed to the target system, IBP, to confirm post processing. Access the Data Integration Jobs app from your IBP tenant and check logs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_33-1756845520457.png" style="width: 828px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308229i77946FF1B9042086/image-dimensions/828x327/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="828" height="327" role="button" title="SofianePebre_33-1756845520457.png" alt="SofianePebre_33-1756845520457.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;That’s it ! you’ve created and executed your first customer iflow in CI from S/4HANA to IBP !&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creating customer iflows per IBP object&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that you’ve successfully created a reference iflow, you can duplicate it as many times as needed and only make changes to the global parameters in order to create integration for all the necessary IBP objects for both key figures (purchase orders, production orders, sales orders &amp;amp; deliveries, actuals, stock,…) and master data (products, locations, PDS, etc.) that are supported by the S/4HANA integration addon for IBP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can select your primary customer iflow from the Design section and from its menu, select Copy&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_34-1756845520460.png" style="width: 790px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308227iE0685BE6EABA5F1F/image-dimensions/790x231/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="790" height="231" role="button" title="SofianePebre_34-1756845520460.png" alt="SofianePebre_34-1756845520460.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Give a name to your new iflows identifying what data they are integrating.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_35-1756845520462.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308228i3A3CC303ECD23A1F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SofianePebre_35-1756845520462.png" alt="SofianePebre_35-1756845520462.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For each, access the menu and select Configure. Replace mappings, filters, extractor names, etc. to adjust to the data needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example for the Production Orders iflow:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SofianePebre_36-1756845520467.png" style="width: 775px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308230i2C9240B303F9548E/image-dimensions/775x558/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="775" height="558" role="button" title="SofianePebre_36-1756845520467.png" alt="SofianePebre_36-1756845520467.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on Save. Do this for each iflow to set up your whole interfaces from S/4HANA to IBP and schedule them accordingly at a later stage as shown previously.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also copy this iflow to use for master data transfer. Make sure in that case that aside from updating the extractor name, mappings, filters, you also set the TypeOfData parameter to ‘MasterData’ and that you properly fill out the MasterDataType and MasterDataPrefix parameters.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next blog entries&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;will deal with:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tips and tricks on working the Monitor section&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Special case handling in Mapping (including mapping extensions)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Special case handling in Filtering (including filter extensions)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sources&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP IBP Help on &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_INTEGRATED_BUSINESS_PLANNING/da797ae2bf6246d58abd417f24915d55/1eee047de9db490cab837ab90cd22285.html?version=2508" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;S/4HANA integration to IBP via CI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/d9ca0a5b35214b2a9470b8e6c748c7b3/2402/en-US/b6fe07784e154bb7aa76ac71997dbce2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IBP Reusable integration flows - list and details&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/creating-your-first-iflow-in-cloud-integration-for-an-ibp-s-4hana-on-prem/ba-p/14205240"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T23:03:31.723000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sap-enable-now-java-script-error-when-generating-a-document/qaa-p/14205246#M47651</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Enable Now - JAVA script Error when generating a...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T23:18:25.743000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ShaneLipke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/398177</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It could also be an issue with one of the Resources on the one PC or the specific Simulation that documentation is being generated for. Try:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1.&amp;nbsp; A different Simulation to see if it is the Simulation causing the issue&lt;BR /&gt;2. Right click the &lt;STRONG&gt;Resources&lt;/STRONG&gt; object in Producer and select &lt;STRONG&gt;Server Bulk Action &amp;gt; Update All Objects from Server&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You could also open the Javascript Console (&lt;STRONG&gt;View &amp;gt; Javascript Console&lt;/STRONG&gt;) before generating documentation to see if the error is identified in Console.&amp;nbsp; This might help you to understand what is wrong.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If none of these things fixes the issue, please raise a support ticket using Component ID &lt;STRONG&gt;KM-SEN-PRO&lt;/STRONG&gt; and get support involved in detailed investigation of the issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;BR /&gt;Shane&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sap-enable-now-java-script-error-when-generating-a-document/qaa-p/14205246#M47651"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T23:18:25.743000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/fagl-fc-val-sp24/qaq-p/14205247</id>
    <title>FAGL_FC_VAL   -  SP24</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T23:30:07.733000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexandre_siqueira2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/310980</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;After the implementation of SP24 in the ECC, errors are occurring in the foreign currency valuation process in the FAGL_FC_VAL transaction. You are not allowing launches from balance adjustment accounts. Error message occurs due to managed account in Open Matches. Someone has worked with SP24 and had this problem ?? We have already analyzed several SAP notes. The client has only one Main Ledger and has more than 800 accounts of adjustments managed in PA. Thank you for any clarification or help to solve.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/fagl-fc-val-sp24/qaq-p/14205247"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T23:30:07.733000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/guidance-on-assignment-profile-updates-for-revised-item/qaq-p/14205248</id>
    <title>Guidance on Assignment Profile Updates for Revised Item</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T23:43:44.086000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>smulligan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/70013</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’ve revised a free-floating item that is assigned via an assignment profile. During the revision process, I opted to update all learning plans impacted by the change, and the new version has successfully replaced the old one in existing plans.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To ensure future assignments use the latest version without triggering notifications, should I update the assignment profile to include the new item revision, or can I retain the old version on the assignment profile and set the new version as a substitute to the old version?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My goal is for both current and future assignments to reflect the updated course version, while avoiding user notifications. The system is configured to notify users only of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;new&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;learning assignments. However, replacing the old item with the new one in the assignment profile appears to trigger such notifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Previously, I disabled the learning plan notification job before making changes, then re-enabled it afterward, but notifications were still sent. Is there a recommended approach to prevent this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please vote for the ability to disable the learning plan notification as part of the revision process as well as having an option in the assignment profile to disable the learning plan notification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/288756/?section=sectionDetails" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Improvement Request Details - Customer Influence&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you,&lt;BR /&gt;Susan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/guidance-on-assignment-profile-updates-for-revised-item/qaq-p/14205248"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T23:43:44.086000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/country-dimension-for-expense-reporting-not-working-for-subledger-and/qaa-p/14205249#M254948</id>
    <title>Re: Country dimension for Expense Reporting not working f...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:04:14.957000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1702523"&gt;@VirendraSharmaFICO&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What you’re observing is expected in S/4HANA Public Cloud Edition today&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The insurance details, such as Customer Country/Region, are supplied for analytical purposes. They are integrated into reports via data source extensions but are not accessible as input or target fields in Create Supplier Invoice, Manage Concur Substitution Rules, or Asset Posting substitutions. Therefore, they cannot be populated during AP entry, import into Concur, or depreciation processes run. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/6979f136cfdc43598247b086991fc443/4fbf534857cd4f17af5ae7d2e3692757.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Add Dimensions to the Analytical Apps Using Data Source Extensions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Practical options supporthe ted by cloud&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Put a country value on the FI document (ACDOCA):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a custom field for the Journal Entry, Item in Custom Fields and Logic. Be sure to enable it for Create Supplier Invoice, Advanced, and other relevant options to ensure everything works smoothly reporting. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/07e9387e827e49648201ab1003033a81.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-App Extensibility: Create Supplier Invoice - Advanced&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Map Concur’s country into the custom field, following the SAP’s Concur→S/4 journal extension pattern. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extending-journal-content-and-structure-with-sap-concur-expense-data/ba-p/13978742" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community-Extending Journal Content and Structure with SAP Concur Expense Data&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If you only need analytics:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keep the country in concur and include it in analytics (SAC/embedded) with the journal lines, or display the insurance dimensions in GL reports via data source extensions. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/6979f136cfdc43598247b086991fc443/4fbf534857cd4f17af5ae7d2e3692757.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Add Dimensions to the Analytical Apps Using Data Source Extensions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For Fixed Assets/depreciation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You cannot replace a standard “country” target in this context today. If you require expenses broken down by country, use Universal Allocation (in the Margin Analysis or Manage Allocations section) to allocate or split costs by country at the end of the period into dedicated accounts or characteristics. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/f0d042517a434458b171ff5867b18445/9ec635ecc22a4559b1070b2dd2c879e4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Universal Allocation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product gap:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you require the standard Country/Region dimension to be writeable in AP/Concur/FA flows, submit a request via SAP Continuous Influence. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/finance-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2402/ba-p/13590761" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community-Finance in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2402&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The standard insurance dimensions are mainly for reporting. To track expenses by country in FI now, you can use a custom JE item field combined with Concur mapping, or you can calculate it at the end of the period using Universal Allocation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/country-dimension-for-expense-reporting-not-working-for-subledger-and/qaa-p/14205249#M254948"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:04:14.957000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/bop-is-not-working-for-mto-scenerio/qaa-p/14205250#M206784</id>
    <title>Re: BOP is not working for MTO scenerio</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:04:26.610000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S0024831430</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Andreas,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the input. I am unable to access the short demo video. Let me know how to access it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vinu Nanjan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/bop-is-not-working-for-mto-scenerio/qaa-p/14205250#M206784"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:04:26.610000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/exploring-the-path-to-sap-certification/ec-p/14205251#M1065</id>
    <title>Re: 🟢 Exploring the Path to SAP Certification</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:08:11.404000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>agil</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1548195</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Ufff&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17466"&gt;@Sandra_Solis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;mass fiinooo. Buenas vibras &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/exploring-the-path-to-sap-certification/ec-p/14205251#M1065"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:08:11.404000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/abap-cloud-application-jobs-overcoming-key-challenges/bc-p/14205252#M50276</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP Cloud Application Jobs: Overcoming Key Challenges</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:26:24.794000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>natanael1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1557162</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Super nice article&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/404361"&gt;@octavian_savu&lt;/a&gt;, I think that good documentation, and best practices on ABAP Cloud is vastly missing&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/abap-cloud-application-jobs-overcoming-key-challenges/bc-p/14205252#M50276"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:26:24.794000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-goalresult-visibility/qaa-p/14205253#M47653</id>
    <title>Re: Variable Pay goalResult visibility</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:36:18.515000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2182754"&gt;@karolina_lotocka&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you only have only one business goal in each of your business goal sections then yes you should be able to pull it up on the entry level using standard field. by bringing out the section target and the section payout fields then dividing the two of them in a third field (there might be a standard field for it, actually).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes I've seen customers show this on statements before but most customers show the final payout only and point to the individual view of varpay if employees want to see the breakdown.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the best,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Xavier&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-goalresult-visibility/qaa-p/14205253#M47653"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:36:18.515000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/ai-launchpad-generic-secret-creation-error-creation-of-data-repository-for/qaa-p/14205254#M4924921</id>
    <title>Re: AI Launchpad, Generic Secret Creation Error, Creation...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:42:14.586000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PolinaKuznetcova</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2133620</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Getting same error as Balachandar; please ping me if you find where the error lies</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/ai-launchpad-generic-secret-creation-error-creation-of-data-repository-for/qaa-p/14205254#M4924921"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:42:14.586000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/community-feedback-list-disable-features-for-new-users/m-p/14205255#M3274</id>
    <title>Re: Community Feedback List - Disable features for new users</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:53:54.624000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FabioPagoti</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172350</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Unfortunately many people working with SAP do not own an S-user. I bet more than 80%. I got my first S-user more than 10 years after starting my SAP career.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/community-feedback-list-disable-features-for-new-users/m-p/14205255#M3274"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:53:54.624000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-cloud-application-studio-2508-installation/qaa-p/14205256#M4226155</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Cloud Application Studio 2508 installation</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:54:40.814000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TiRezzoagli</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1407076</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Charles,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has deprecated the Pilot installer and aligned the SDK with Visual Studio 2022 (Professional or Enterprise editions).&lt;BR /&gt;This ensures a modern, supported development environment and better integration with current .NET frameworks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to Resolve the Issue&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow these steps to move from the Pilot version to the supported setup:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Install Visual Studio 2022&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get a licensed copy of Visual Studio 2022 Professional or Enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Either edition will work — Community edition is not supported.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Download the SAP Extension (VSIX)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the SAP Software Download Center.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Download the latest VSIX extension matching your SDK release (e.g., 2508).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Close all open Visual Studio instances.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Double-click the .vsix file to install.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Connect to Your Tenant&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open Visual Studio 2022.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On the start page, select “Continue without code.”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to View → My Solutions / Implementation Manager.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click Log On and enter your ByDesign system URL, User ID, and Password.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Fix Common Errors&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you see a .NET Framework error, install .NET Framework 4.8 and restart Visual Studio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that the layout is slightly different from Visual Studio 2015, but the core functions (like creating patches) are still there.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5. Continue Development&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Load your solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the Implementation Manager, choose Create Patch or perform any other development activity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’re now ready to continue working in the new environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Pilot SDK is no longer supported after release 2508.&lt;BR /&gt;You must use Visual Studio 2022 (Professional or Enterprise) + the latest SAP VSIX extension.&lt;BR /&gt;.NET Framework 4.8 may be required for compatibility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once set up, you can log in, connect to your repository, and continue development as usual.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Tiago&lt;BR /&gt;SAP ByD Technical Support&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-cloud-application-studio-2508-installation/qaa-p/14205256#M4226155"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:54:40.814000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
