<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-11-17T09:14:01.674368+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/assign-activity-into-bom-component-ca02/qaq-p/14270625</id>
    <title>Assign activity into BOM component ( CA02 )</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:16:10.362000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mahadev_2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1719705</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi exparts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I tried to assign the activity to BOM components.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Mahadev_2_0-1763033464135.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340033iE434056CA5C13E65/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Mahadev_2_0-1763033464135.png" alt="Mahadev_2_0-1763033464135.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Mahadev_2_2-1763033829703.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340037i2C3421474D60283B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Mahadev_2_2-1763033829703.png" alt="Mahadev_2_2-1763033829703.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;tried using&amp;nbsp;structure 'CPS_TASK_LIST_MAINT_PRT' and&amp;nbsp; 'CPS_TASK_LIST_MAINT_PRT_X'&amp;nbsp; of FM 'ROUTING_MAINTAIN' and 'BAPI_ES_ROUTING_CHANGE'&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;but not woking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If anyone has already done this, please help.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/assign-activity-into-bom-component-ca02/qaq-p/14270625"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T05:16:10.362000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/feasibility-check-on-data-migration-approach-from-pega-cloud-to-sap-btp/qaq-p/14270626</id>
    <title>Feasibility check on data migration approach from Pega Cloud to SAP BTP</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:21:55.899000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Som_SAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/168743</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are currently defining the data layer modernization strategy for a client planning to rebuild their existing Pega-based case management and workflow solution on&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The main ask from Client is if SAP BTP offers the same or better functionality to rebuild the CPPO Application with all the specification and implementation the client currently has available for the CPPO on ASPIRE Version.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since the underlying PostgreSQL database in Pega is tightly coupled with the Pega application and not directly accessible externally, we are proposing a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;staged extraction and migration approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;using the Pega BIX tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is the detailed end-to-end data flow and migration approach we would like SAP to validate for compliance and supportability within the BTP ecosystem:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proposed Data Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Source System (Pega Application):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data to be extracted using&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pega BIX tool&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;in&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Database Schema output format&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Extracted data stored in&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pega Cloud File Storage&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as per standard Pega BIX process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Staging Database Setup:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Files from Pega Cloud File Storage transferred securely (via SFTP or equivalent) to a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Staging PostgreSQL Database&lt;/STRONG&gt;, deployed within the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;same hyperscaler region&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;where SAP BTP is hosted (e.g., AWS, Azure, or GCP).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;This staging environment will be used for initial validation, transformation, and reconciliation of extracted data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Migration to SAP BTP Data Layer:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data from the Staging PostgreSQL DB will be migrated to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Hyperscaler Managed PostgreSQL service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;using&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;native PostgreSQL utilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;such as&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;pg_dump&lt;/CODE&gt;,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;pg_restore&lt;/CODE&gt;, or&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;pg_basebackup alongside psql (for data validation)&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Target PostgreSQL DB in SAP BTP will act as the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;primary persistence layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for new SAP Build Process Automation (BPA) and SAP Build Apps-based workflow applications with CAP service as API interfaces to that persistency layer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clarification Needed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can anyone please validate on the following points:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether this&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;external data ingestion and migration pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(Pega underlying PostgreSQL DB → Pega BIX tool → Staging PostgreSQL DB → Hyperscaler PostgreSQL in SAP BTP) is&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;technically compliant and supported&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;within SAP BTP guidelines.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether &lt;STRONG&gt;any additional services&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;such as&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Data Intelligence, SAP Integration Suite, or SAP Data Provisioning Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for better orchestration or governance in this migration pattern is required or only using PostgreSQL native utilities like pg_dump/pg_restore/psql is enough.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Som&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#Pega #SAPBTP #MigrateFromPegaToSAPBTP #HyperscalerPostgreSQLOption&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/feasibility-check-on-data-migration-approach-from-pega-cloud-to-sap-btp/qaq-p/14270626"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T05:21:55.899000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyone-are-talking-about-mcp-what-is-mcp-and-how-will-it-help-for-your/bc-p/14270627#M186388</id>
    <title>Re: Everyone are talking about MCP... What is MCP and how will it help for your process</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:31:18.701000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;All SAP's listed here as contributors for MCPs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://dxt.so/mcp-server?query=sap" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://dxt.so/mcp-server?query=sap&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyone-are-talking-about-mcp-what-is-mcp-and-how-will-it-help-for-your/bc-p/14270627#M186388"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T05:31:18.701000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-art-and-science-of-sapui5-in-sap-build-insights-from-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14269053</id>
    <title>The Art and Science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build: Insights from SAP TechEd 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:35:29.369000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OliverGraeff</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4124</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At SAP TechEd Berlin 2025, we had the opportunity to present “The Art and Science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build.” The deep dive session explores how SAPUI5, SAP’s strategic UI framework, is transforming user experiences and developer efficiency across SAP. This blog post shares key takeaways from the session and questions from the audience.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If you’ve missed it, watch the session recording in &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752166265407001r3vW" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AD106v | The art and science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Berlin.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340648iB3B47006232C8262/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Berlin.png" alt="Berlin.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635711133"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Art of SAPUI5 in SAP Fiori User Experience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP’s approach to user experience (UX) centers on making applications easier and more enjoyable to use, helping users accomplish their tasks with greater efficiency and satisfaction. The framework enables the SAP Fiori design system to evolve seamlessly across SAP solutions, providing flexible tools for developers to efficiently build apps using SAP Build Code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697363066"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Web Components: Bridging Frameworks and Enhancing Extensibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Web Components extend the capabilities of SAPUI5, to other programming model, such as Angular, React, or Vue. This interoperability supports a consistent and streamlined UX throughout the SAP portfolio. SAP Web Components can now also be easily consumed in SAPUI5 apps just like regular controls. Going forward, SAP plans to provide new UI elements as SAP Web Components, minimizing the effort required for adopting new standards and ensuring compliance with SAP guidelines and modern Web standards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1500849561"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 is leading is the Way in Accessibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 is at the forefront of accessibility, with recent implementations (SAPUI5 1.136 and UI5 Web Components 2.9.0) aligned to the latest Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2. This commitment ensures that applications built with SAPUI5 are inclusive and accessible to users worldwide, meeting diverse needs and regulatory requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046170618"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Science of SAPUI5 in SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build is SAP’s unified solution to build apps and extensions, automations, agents and digital workspaces. SAP Build helps to increase developer productivity and to future-proof IT investments by leveraging proven technologies like SAPUI5, SAP Fiori elements, CAP and ABAP Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107822551"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extending SAP standard apps with SAPUI5 flexibility and Clean Core&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 flexibility enables upgrade-safe, clean core extensions with intuitive low-code/no-code tools for different personas: end users, key users, and developers. New capabilities include consistent text changes for field labels and a “What's New” / “UI Adaptation Tour” for key users. Developers creating adaptation projects benefit from a "Replace original tile option and coding efficiency with TypeScript and Joule.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The new SAPUI5 runtime repository accelerates patch updates, improves startup performance, and supports zero-downtime deployments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911309046"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Future-Proofing apps with UI5 best practices and UI5 linter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Technical debt and legacy code can slow down innovation within SAP Fiori projects. Here the UI5 linter helps finding and fixing the usage of deprecated APIs and making your code is ready for upcoming SAPUI5 versions. &lt;/SPAN&gt;The new SAPUI5 / OpenUI5 legacy-free version helps validating how compliant your code is to UI5 best practices, i.e. ensuring your code is state of the art and future-proof.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714795541"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-Powered Development: Joule Copilot and MCP server &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is revolutionizing SAPUI5 development. The Joule copilot accelerates app creation, view and control addition, code formatting, migration to TypeScript and much more. The UI5 MCP server enables agentic AI app development in SAP Build, combining generative AI with algorithmic logic if the UI5 linter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-260116598"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 delivers a streamlined, consistent UX across SAP Business Suite, driving both user satisfaction and business outcomes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build and SAPUI5 flexibility empower organizations to extend SAP standard apps efficiently, future-proofing their investments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-powered tools accelerate development and let you future-proof your apps with UI5 best practices.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-11-14 at 13.00.20.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340650iC451FC9D8A460C8C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-11-14 at 13.00.20.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-11-14 at 13.00.20.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-63603093"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Selected questions from the audience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Is Using VS code still recommended or the SAP Build for development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; In addition to the turnkey solution of SAP Build running on SAP BTP, &lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP plans to focus on releasing development tools on the VS Code marketplace. VS Code is the number-one IDE worldwide, especially among web, cloud, and full-stack developers. Investing more in VS Code helps SAP meet developers where they are, making it easier for new developers to adopt SAP technologies (such as CAP, SAP BTP, SAPUI5, ABAP Cloud).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; New controls will be components from now on?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Exactly, SAP plans to deliver most new UI components as Web Components, which can be use across any Web framework, including SAPUI5.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; How AI compatibilities work in more complex application&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Beyond Generative AI capabilities, agentic development tool (e.g. with the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_blank"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt;) offer impressive results for developing complex (fullstack) apps, from design up to deployment. You might want to check out &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_blank"&gt;Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build&lt;/A&gt; for an inside view.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What is the benefit of using the Web Components from the example compared to sap.m.Input?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Please continue using SAPUI5 controls if they fulfil your needs. There is no change to that. Most upcoming, new UI elements will be provided as Web Component, serving *all* technology stacks, including SAPUI5.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What are Components bringing when compared to Classic controls if we are using UI5 only approach&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; see above&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; how will be the future scope of Fiori elements applications over ui5, do both will have same scope&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Fiori elements is an option to develop SAPUI5 app more efficiently. SAP recommends using as much SAP Fiori elements as possible and as much freestyle SAPUI5 as needed. This is what we do in SAP as well. Check out the &lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/1.141.0/test-resources/sap/fe/core/fpmExplorer/index.html#/overview/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori Development Portal&lt;/A&gt; on more details.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What would be best approach to extend freestyle standard Fiori apps? Also, will adaptation projects have more extension powers?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/UI5_Flex" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAPUI5 flexibility&lt;/A&gt; to the strategic way to extend/adapt SAPUI5 apps. The UI5 team continues to invest a lot in this area, as it is top priority for many partners/customers. SAPUI5 flexibility covers freestyle SAPUI5 as well as apps built with SAP Fiori elements. Adaptation projects offer best capabilities to create future-proof app extensions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Will the Build Code Joule CoPilot also support the Vibe Coding with MCP in the future?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Yes, SAP plans for vibe coding tools (incl. MCP servers) in SAP Build to empower business users to create application prototypes and start new SAP solutions without heavy coding knowledge.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP develops SAPUI5 while promoting low-code tools like RAP, CAP, and key user adaptations. Isn’t it inconsistent to advance the core framework while encouraging less direct UI5 development?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Key user adaptation as well as metadata- / annotation-driven apps on RAP/CAP (using SAP Fiori elements) all use SAPUI5 as their UI technology. Innovations ‘in the UI’ are built in SAPUI5, benefitting all these models. Also, there remains a strong use case for a freestyle SAPUI5 implementation approach for apps which cannot follow the patterns of SAP Fiori elements.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a partner, if we build an SAPUI5 application and deploy it to customer systems, can SAPUI5 flexibility be used to create customer specific adaption projects for it?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is planned for Q4/2025: &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73554900100800001361&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q4%202025;INNO=000D3AAC9DD21FD0A6A548C104441945" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Developer adaptation: enabling customer and partner applications for adaptation projects&lt;/A&gt; (As always with forward-looking statements, this is subject to change.)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The build errors just prove you are really building live and not faking it. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Right. Not sure though whether Tommy enjoyed the moment &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Now that CDS support UI annotations will UI5 become obsolete?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Definitely not. SAPUI5 remains SAP’s strategic UI framework. SAP Fiori elements with its annotations is built on SAPUI5. The annotations control what SAPUI5 is showing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-art-and-science-of-sapui5-in-sap-build-insights-from-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14269053"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T05:35:29.369000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-in-creating-invoice-based-on-po-smbew-key-error-msg-no-m8782/qaq-p/14270629</id>
    <title>Error in creating invoice based on PO (SMBEW Key Error, Msg No: M8782)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:52:44.069000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yunki_lee</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2228700</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the as-is system, invoices were being created with the 'Valuation Type' field in the Purchase Order empty.&lt;BR /&gt;As a result, there are some PO items that were converted during the S/4HANA transition which also have an empty 'Valuation Type'.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While this issue can be resolved for PO items without history by manually entering the 'Valuation Type' in the PO,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;we are unable to edit the 'Valuation Type' for converted POs that already have a transactional history.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We would like to inquire about solution to process these converted POs that have a history but are missing the 'Valuation Type'.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-in-creating-invoice-based-on-po-smbew-key-error-msg-no-m8782/qaq-p/14270629"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T05:52:44.069000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/create-2-goal-sections-on-pm-form-from-samegoal-plan-but-another-goal/qaa-p/14270630#M49373</id>
    <title>Re: Create 2 goal sections on PM Form from samegoal plan,...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:54:33+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mashhood-Imran</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1908808</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks, but i want to do a bit of correction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The article suggests to use the category name, for me category ID worked. if you face any trouble using the Name like me, try using category ID.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mashhood Imran&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/create-2-goal-sections-on-pm-form-from-samegoal-plan-but-another-goal/qaa-p/14270630#M49373"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T05:54:33+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-publication-on-dwc/qaa-p/14270631#M4931759</id>
    <title>Re: SAC publication on DWC</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:56:52.120000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MandarDamle</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1785701</uri>
    </author>
    <content>This functionality is still not available as of November 2025</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-publication-on-dwc/qaa-p/14270631#M4931759"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T05:56:52.120000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/check-table-169p-entry-9849-does-not-exist/qaa-p/14270635#M4231558</id>
    <title>Re: Check table 169P: entry 9849   does not exist</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T06:01:00.937000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>asis_mallik</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265957</uri>
    </author>
    <content>It Worked for me. Thanks for the information.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/check-table-169p-entry-9849-does-not-exist/qaa-p/14270635#M4231558"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T06:01:00.937000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14270639#M14522</id>
    <title>Re: Reimagining Certification for the Way We Work Today</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T06:21:15.236000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SRudra</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6934</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Not sure if the learning content for GenAI would also get updated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14270639#M14522"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T06:21:15.236000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/quot-configure-quot-menu-not-visible-in-integration-suite-when-using-trial/qaa-p/14270640#M4931761</id>
    <title>Re: "Configure" menu not visible in Integration Suite whe...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T06:23:30.544000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chahat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1574359</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks, this worked.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/quot-configure-quot-menu-not-visible-in-integration-suite-when-using-trial/qaa-p/14270640#M4931761"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T06:23:30.544000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-record-count-mismatches-after-hana-tenant-copy-during-s-4hana-on/ba-p/14270636</id>
    <title>Handling Record Count Mismatches After HANA Tenant Copy During S/4HANA On-Premise to RISE Migration</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T06:25:35.927000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ShubhamMishra11</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1837795</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As part of a system move, We performed a HANA tenant copy from our on-premise S/4HANA system to the RISE environment. After completing the tenant copy, we compared the total record count of the SAPABAP1 schema using:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SELECT SUM(RECORD_COUNT) FROM M_TABLES WHERE SCHEMA_NAME = 'SAPABAP1'; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Source Record count:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ShubhamMishra11_0-1763355556211.png" style="width: 439px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341748iFAB3A21013B3860E/image-dimensions/439x224/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="439" height="224" role="button" title="ShubhamMishra11_0-1763355556211.png" alt="ShubhamMishra11_0-1763355556211.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Target Record count:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ShubhamMishra11_1-1763355556215.png" style="width: 445px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341749iD0FB1FE95E5A3CC6/image-dimensions/445x232/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="445" height="232" role="button" title="ShubhamMishra11_1-1763355556215.png" alt="ShubhamMishra11_1-1763355556215.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A small difference appeared between the source and the target system.&lt;BR /&gt;To validate the result, We first checked whether any column-store tables were unloaded using:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SELECT SCHEMA_NAME, TABLE_NAME FROM M_CS_TABLES WHERE LOADED = 'NO'; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No unloaded tables were found, so the values from M_TABLES were correct for comparison.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To investigate the difference, I exported and compared the table-level record counts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The mismatch came from the following tables:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Table Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Source&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;/BI0/0K00193590&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;0&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;/BI0/0K00193626&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;0&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;/BI0/0K00193632&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;0&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;/BI0/0K00193575&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;0&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;All of these objects belong to the &lt;STRONG&gt;/BI0/&lt;/STRONG&gt; namespace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Information provided by SAP clarifies that these objects are &lt;STRONG&gt;temporary BW tables&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as described in SAP Note &lt;STRONG&gt;2800007&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;They are created during BW processing and are not persistent.&lt;BR /&gt;Additional related details include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hash / union temporary tables (40-character names)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;These store intermediate results for hierarchy queries. They are copies of &lt;STRONG&gt;0BW:BIA:BI0&lt;/STRONG&gt;* objects with a retention time. Unneeded tables are removed using BW cleanup tools such as:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Report &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_DROP_TMPTABLES&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Function module &lt;STRONG&gt;TREX_DBS_DROP_BW_UNION_TABLES&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Notes &lt;STRONG&gt;2838176&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;2852066&lt;/STRONG&gt; describe adjustments and cleanup behaviour.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Temporary tables in the pattern 0BW:BIA:BI0*&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;These hold temporary hierarchy or F4 help data. They are cleaned automatically or through report &lt;STRONG&gt;RSDDTMPTAB_DELETE&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Note &lt;STRONG&gt;3316894&lt;/STRONG&gt; describes a case where automatic cleanup may not run as expected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to this information, differences in these temporary table counts between systems are normal and depend on BW usage and cleanup cycles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The record count mismatch observed after the HANA tenant copy was limited to BW temporary tables described in SAP Note 2800007. These tables are not persistent and may exist or be cleaned up at different times in different systems. Because of this, small differences in their record counts are expected and do not indicate any issue with the tenant copy. The overall tenant copy can be considered consistent and successfully completed.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-record-count-mismatches-after-hana-tenant-copy-during-s-4hana-on/ba-p/14270636"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T06:25:35.927000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-count-the-number-of-repeated-rows-in-story-table/qaa-p/14270642#M256433</id>
    <title>Re: How to count the number of repeated rows in story table</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T06:26:40.830000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tara_shi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2264248</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks, I tried this, I think the caculation itself has no issue, the issue was found by our IT guy in model.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-count-the-number-of-repeated-rows-in-story-table/qaa-p/14270642#M256433"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T06:26:40.830000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/cloud-first-ai-powered-test-automation-in-sap-cloud-alm/ba-p/14269145</id>
    <title>Cloud-first, AI-Powered test automation in SAP Cloud ALM</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T06:31:23.608000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>prashantmohan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2254181</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SmartBear participated in and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/almathon-2025-five-years-of-innovation/ba-p/14248667" target="_blank"&gt;won first prize at the ALMathon&lt;/A&gt;, the annual hackathon for SAP Partners. The challenge: Create innovative use cases to extend&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Cloud+ALM/pd-p/73554900100800002513" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. So, we integrated&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reflect&lt;/SPAN&gt;, our AI-powered test automation product, into SAP Cloud ALM to enable users to automate their manual testing process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Check out&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://youtu.be/FTimI4cGUfc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;this demo&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to see it in action!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1893795914" id="toc-hId-1893877503"&gt;The urgent need for test automation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;As organizations accelerate cloud adoption using RISE with SAP and as they keep up with frequent S/4HANA Cloud updates, testing early and often becomes essential. SAP’s&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud/continuous-delivery" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;own guidance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;highlights continuous delivery with frequent updates, which raises the bar on repeatable, reliable testing at scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manual testing can be time-consuming, error-prone, and costly. It often becomes a bottleneck that delays releases and increases business risk.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2022/01/automated-application-testing-value/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Studies&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;have shown that embracing test automation can&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;accelerate application delivery by up to 4× while reducing errors and risk.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Teams moving from mostly manual testing to more automated approaches often save thousands of person-hours and cut testing costs by 25% or more. These benefits translate into faster, more confident deployments and fewer firefights in production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697282409" id="toc-hId-1697363998"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1500768904" id="toc-hId-1500850493"&gt;A new approach to solving this problem&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reflect brings a cloud-first, AI-native experience directly into&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for test creation, execution, and results, while aligning with existing workflows that business stakeholders, IT leaders and software teams already use. Test creation, execution, and result reporting all happen within the familiar SAP Cloud ALM interface, so there’s no context-switching to external tools. Automated test results flow back into SAP Cloud ALM’s Test Management, so stakeholders can see pass/fail status and reports alongside processes, requirements, and manual tests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304255399" id="toc-hId-1304336988"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107741894" id="toc-hId-1107823483"&gt;Why is Reflect different from existing solutions?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;First of all, there’s zero configuration, Reflect truly is cloud-first.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;No installations or browser extensions are required to start automating. There is no need to download any .exe files or Chrome extensions; you simply open SAP Cloud ALM and start creating tests. The solution runs entirely on a cloud platform, and all the heavy lifting (test execution engines, browsers, etc.) is handled in the cloud. There’s no need to set up local machines or maintain VMs for test runs because the infrastructure scales for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reflect has no-code automation with AI-powered test creation, and&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;there are two intuitive ways to create tests without writing a single script.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Record&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and play&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This approach allows users to simply hit “Record” and then interact with the SAP application (or any web/mobile app) just as an end-user would. The tool captures each action and creates an automated test without the need for any manual scanning of objects to create models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-powered: This approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;enables users to automatically&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;generate automated tests from existing manual test cases documented in SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;with a click of a button. This capability shortens the path to automating existing tests and makes it easy to build new ones from scratch.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lastly, Reflect’s application coverage is broad.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Reflect supports&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;test automation for all SAP cloud applications out of the box&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Whether you’re testing&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Fiori apps, S/4HANA transactions, SuccessFactors, Ariba, Concur, or any SAP application built with SAPUI5&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Reflect can handle it. Reflect also supports non-SAP web applications and even mobile apps, enabling true end-to-end testing across hybrid workflows. In one platform, you get&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UI testing, API testing, and visual testing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;capabilities for web and mobile.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911228389" id="toc-hId-911309978"&gt;Reflects’s critical capabilities&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;To further streamline test automation, Reflect provides several advanced capabilities that are worth highlighting. These include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reusable segments:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Capture repeatable flows as reusable building blocks to speed up authoring and keep tests consistent&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI assisted self-healing:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;When the application UI updates or the underlying technology changes, tests continue to run, reducing maintenance effort over time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simple and easy debugging:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Users can troubleshoot their tests directly within the recording experience in case of errors vs going back and forth between the test modules and test execution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Execution suites&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Users can create a playlist of tests using an easy-to-use flowchart, schedule them directly from the automation interface, and run as many tests as needed in parallel&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Email and Slack notifications:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;When tests are complete, results are updated in SAP Cloud ALM, and users can configure them to be sent to their email, Slack, or MS Teams&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714714884" id="toc-hId-714796473"&gt;Accelerate your SAP testing with Reflect&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;As SAP continues to accelerate its update cycle, organizations that can adapt quickly will be best positioned to succeed. By integrating Reflect's cloud-first, AI-powered test automation directly into SAP Cloud ALM, businesses can significantly reduce the friction associated with frequent updates. This integration enables teams to test earlier and more frequently, ensuring that their SAP environments remain stable and performant. With Reflect, organizations can achieve faster time-to-market, improved quality, and reduced testing costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find us on the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/alm/partners/extensions.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud ALM Partners – Extensions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;page to learn more.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/cloud-first-ai-powered-test-automation-in-sap-cloud-alm/ba-p/14269145"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T06:31:23.608000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-do-background-scheduling-with-clean-core-including-fiori-apps/bc-p/14270644#M186390</id>
    <title>Re: How to do background scheduling with clean core, including Fiori apps, replacing se38 reports</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T06:34:19.943000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joery</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46923</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great, can't wait to start with this.&lt;BR /&gt;For now on Cloud ERP Private 2023 It will still be the classic approach then.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks for the nice step-by-step&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-do-background-scheduling-with-clean-core-including-fiori-apps/bc-p/14270644#M186390"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T06:34:19.943000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/error-select-a-key-from-the-allowed-namespace-message-no-5v019/qaa-p/14270645#M458189</id>
    <title>Re: Error: Select a key from the allowed namespace. Messa...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T06:34:35.152000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tina85jones</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265633</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This error, "Entry with key outside of the namespace you manage," typically occurs in SAP when you are attempting to create a new entry (like a Partner Function or Partner Determination Procedure) using a key (ID) that falls within the SAP standard namespace (keys starting with numbers, or letters A-X), even if you are trying to assign it to a Z or Y (customer-specific) object. The solution is to ensure both the Partner Determination Procedure ID (if you're creating a new one) and the Partner Function ID you are adding to the procedure must start with 'Z' or 'Y'. If the Partner Function itself (e.g., ZP) is already defined in the customer namespace but you are trying to insert it into a standard Partner Determination Procedure (e.g., SM0001), you should check if the error is due to the key of the determination procedure itself. If you've ensured both keys are Z/Y and the error persists, it may be a configuration issue specific to your system's upgrade protection or a custom object in a non-standard namespace that you are referencing, and you should check the object keys and number ranges in the underlying customization tables (like V_TPAR for Partner Functions or the relevant view for the Partner Determination Procedure).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/error-select-a-key-from-the-allowed-namespace-message-no-5v019/qaa-p/14270645#M458189"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T06:34:35.152000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-export-overload-data-in-fbl3h/qaa-p/14270646#M256434</id>
    <title>Re: How to export overload data in FBL3H</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T06:42:25.744000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>leah_huang71</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265614</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks for your information, but all columns displayed are required by audit, so there is no option. Regarding the way to export it in background, I think the background button exist in selection screen only? But I need to goto report output screen and select layoput first so that can't export it in background</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-export-overload-data-in-fbl3h/qaa-p/14270646#M256434"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T06:42:25.744000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/intercompany-stock-transfer-1p9-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/bc-p/14270652#M62464</id>
    <title>Re: Intercompany Stock Transfer (1P9) in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:00:11.738000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Qi_Liu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131880</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/835354"&gt;@Wei_Wum8&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;my outbound delivery dont have pricing info either. no matter it is 1P9 or 5HP. You can go ahead to proceed with supplier invoice where you will find the pricing info.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_0-1763359029668.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341753iF779C4E15438D01A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_0-1763359029668.png" alt="Qi_Liu_0-1763359029668.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/intercompany-stock-transfer-1p9-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/bc-p/14270652#M62464"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:00:11.738000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/po-receiver-rest-adapter-http-400/qaa-p/14270654#M4931762</id>
    <title>Re: PO Receiver REST Adapter HTTP 400</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:01:29.798000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ZHANGKAILU</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1582593</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, Gitanjali Yerawar, through this method, I can receive HTTP status and message, but I cannot receive response message.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ZHANGKAILU_0-1763363525893.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341779iED24BE3FA0171F6F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ZHANGKAILU_0-1763363525893.png" alt="ZHANGKAILU_0-1763363525893.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ZHANGKAILU_1-1763363540781.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341780i3B451103E2EB7E67/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ZHANGKAILU_1-1763363540781.png" alt="ZHANGKAILU_1-1763363540781.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ZHANGKAILU_2-1763363554886.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341781iD88D28899BE40958/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ZHANGKAILU_2-1763363554886.png" alt="ZHANGKAILU_2-1763363554886.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/po-receiver-rest-adapter-http-400/qaa-p/14270654#M4931762"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:01:29.798000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/in-a-world-of-uncertainty-how-does-sap-help-leaders-stay-ahead/qaq-p/14270657</id>
    <title>In a World of Uncertainty, How Does SAP Help Leaders Stay Ahead?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:02:47.327000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>neel247</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2256886</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765455024"&gt;In a World of Uncertainty, How Does SAP Help Leaders Stay Ahead?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698024238"&gt;Crisis Becomes the New Normal&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Global supply chains wobble. Regulation and compliance demands increase. Markets change overnight. For CEOs, CTOs and CHROs, this shift demands fast action, not slow response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501510733"&gt;SAP Tools Designed for Change&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP helps leaders stay ready through:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integrated data and systems:&lt;/STRONG&gt; With SAP, different systems—finance, supply chain, HR—link up so decision-makers see the full picture.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-time insight:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Data flows into dashboards fast, so leaders don’t wait for end-of-month reports.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded intelligence and automation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; AI and smart tools inside SAP solutions help reduce manual work and highlight key trends.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304997228"&gt;Why This Matters to the C-Suite&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Speed, clarity and resilience matter. With reliable data, leaders make faster, more confident decisions. Connected systems and smart tools help organizations bounce back from disruption. :contentReference[oaicite:0]{index=0}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108483723"&gt;Practical Leadership Scenarios&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A CFO sees live cash-flow changes during a supply-shock and adjusts strategy next day.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A COO uses SAP tools to switch suppliers automatically when risk levels spike.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A CHRO identifies staffing gaps across regions via unified HR and operations data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911970218"&gt;Key Actions for Leaders&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To thrive in uncertainty:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Focus on &lt;STRONG&gt;data alignment&lt;/STRONG&gt; — ensure every function shares the same definitions and metrics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Build &lt;STRONG&gt;governance&lt;/STRONG&gt; — with uncertainty comes risk, so traceability and control matter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Promote a &lt;STRONG&gt;culture of agility&lt;/STRONG&gt; — teams must adapt quickly, empowered by insights not held back by tools.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715456713"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Change isn’t slowing down; it’s speeding up. For leaders to succeed, the right systems matter as much as the right mindset. SAP provides the backbone. But it’s leadership that turns insight into impact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Soft CTA:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If you’re exploring how your organization can build resilience with SAP solutions, join peer discussions in the SAP Community or connect with experts who are navigating change every day.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/in-a-world-of-uncertainty-how-does-sap-help-leaders-stay-ahead/qaq-p/14270657"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:02:47.327000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-mdg-upgrade-after-upgrade-standard-uibb-erp-vendor-not-visible/qaq-p/14270660</id>
    <title>SAP MDG Upgrade: After upgrade standard UIBB ERP vendor not visible</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:06:04.135000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PairalaSrikanth</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1824900</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have upgraded our mdg system fps 1909 to 2023. after upgrade the standard UIBBs like ERP vendor and ERP customer are not visible while maintaining the data using CR in fiori. we did not enhance these UIBBs with any custom fields. We have two custom handler classes but they are related to different UIBBs not related to ERP vendor or customer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;please let me know the root cause of this problem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks, Srikanth&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-mdg-upgrade-after-upgrade-standard-uibb-erp-vendor-not-visible/qaq-p/14270660"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:06:04.135000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaq-p/14270661</id>
    <title>What does "Price Category HF" mean?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:07:29.524000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nagao_masahiro_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/133996</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to know the meaning of the item "Price Category HF" in the "BCPricingChanges" sheet in the file "Delta_S4CE_2502_2408_final_SAPNote.xlsx" attached to SAP note 3533745 (&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3533745" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3533745&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;BR /&gt;What does this item "Price Category HF" mean?&lt;BR /&gt;Is it a notice of future price category changes?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nagao_masahiro__0-1763359283101.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341754i439D09379EF12549/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nagao_masahiro__0-1763359283101.png" alt="nagao_masahiro__0-1763359283101.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks and Regards&lt;BR /&gt;--&lt;BR /&gt;Masahiro Nagao&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaq-p/14270661"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:07:29.524000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaq-p/14270663</id>
    <title>What does "Price Category HF" mean?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:09:43.291000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nagao_masahiro_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/133996</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to know the meaning of the item "Price Category HF" in the "BCPricingChanges" sheet in the file "Delta_S4CE_2502_2408_final_SAPNote.xlsx" attached to SAP note 3533745 (&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3533745" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3533745&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;BR /&gt;What does this item "Price Category HF" mean?&lt;BR /&gt;Is it a notice of future price category changes?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nagao_masahiro__0-1763359283101.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341754i439D09379EF12549/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nagao_masahiro__0-1763359283101.png" alt="nagao_masahiro__0-1763359283101.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks and Regards&lt;BR /&gt;--&lt;BR /&gt;Masahiro Nagao&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaq-p/14270663"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:09:43.291000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/new-mrp-controller-values-invisible-on-planned-orders-apps/qaa-p/14270665#M4231564</id>
    <title>回复： New MRP Controller values invisible on Planned Orders...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:12:22.816000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Matt_Sui</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135460</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Adrien,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have you checked whether the correct Area of Responsibility has been maintained?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Support&lt;BR /&gt;Matt&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/new-mrp-controller-values-invisible-on-planned-orders-apps/qaa-p/14270665#M4231564"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:12:22.816000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-members/configuration-settings-for-automatic-ps-project-creation-from-ppm-item/bc-p/14270666#M1700</id>
    <title>Re: Configuration settings for automatic PS Project creation from PPM Item</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:13:12.946000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KrishnaPSingh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2252860</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/459497"&gt;@bapats123&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;:&amp;nbsp; Thank you for your insightful question. Here’s my response:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For smaller organizations where a single team is responsible for creating PPM Items and PS Projects, it may be beneficial to select the Edit checkbox. However, in larger organizations with multiple departments involved in creating PPM Items, adhering to the PS Coding Mask for PPM Item IDs can be challenging. If the PPM ID does not align with the next available PS Project Code, the PS Project will not be created, and the system may not generate any error messages. This can lead to confusion for consultants who may struggle to identify the underlying issue. I recommend testing this in your test system to gain a clearer understanding of my suggestion.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-members/configuration-settings-for-automatic-ps-project-creation-from-ppm-item/bc-p/14270666#M1700"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:13:12.946000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/intercompany-stock-transfer-1p9-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/bc-p/14270673#M62465</id>
    <title>Re: Intercompany Stock Transfer (1P9) in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:23:39.845000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Qi_Liu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131880</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1486100"&gt;@yKim&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;please check the following configuration. remove the check.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SSCUI 103426 Assign Document Type, One-Step Procedure, Underdelivery Tolerance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Qi_Liu_0-1763360613268.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341761i09320F5DF107CB70/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Qi_Liu_0-1763360613268.png" alt="Qi_Liu_0-1763360613268.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/intercompany-stock-transfer-1p9-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/bc-p/14270673#M62465"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:23:39.845000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/marketplace-app-deployment-amp-lifecycle-management-using-sap-devops-tools/qaq-p/14270675</id>
    <title>Marketplace App Deployment &amp; Lifecycle Management Using SAP DevOps Tools</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:29:21.964000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tarunnagar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2259450</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This thread is dedicated to exploring how teams can efficiently deploy, manage, and optimize marketplace applications using the SAP DevOps ecosystem. Whether you're working with SAP Commerce Cloud, SAP BTP, or integrating custom marketplace features into an enterprise environment, DevOps plays a crucial role in ensuring smooth delivery and continuous improvement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this discussion, I’m inviting the community to share insights, experiences, and best practices related to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automating marketplace app deployments using SAP DevOps pipelines&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;End-to-end lifecycle management, from development to testing, rollout, monitoring, and iterative updates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Using SAP CI/CD services for stable and compliant releases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Versioning strategies, rollback plans, and handling multi-environment deployments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrating third-party tools (GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Azure DevOps, etc.) with SAP landscapes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitoring &amp;amp; observability using SAP tools or external solutions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Managing extensions, microservices, and custom modules within marketplace ecosystems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Security, governance, and compliance across the deployment lifecycle&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Common challenges teams face and how you’ve solved them&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’ve built or maintained a marketplace app within the SAP ecosystem—or if you're working on improving your DevOps workflow—your insights can help others in the community. Share your methods, lessons learned, tool recommendations, or even questions you're stuck on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/marketplace-app-deployment-amp-lifecycle-management-using-sap-devops-tools/qaq-p/14270675"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:29:21.964000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/user-exit-for-fb02/qaa-p/14270677#M4231565</id>
    <title>Re: user Exit for FB02</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:32:08.488000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sijin_Chandran</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/809</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Without much Information how can someone help you on this? Please put up the details what you did and what error you are getting.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/user-exit-for-fb02/qaa-p/14270677#M4231565"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:32:08.488000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-in-edoc-cockpit-when-creating-e-document-for-france/qaa-p/14270678#M4931765</id>
    <title>Re: Error In EDOC_Cockpit when creating E document for France</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:34:12.161000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tarique</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1716962</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Any one can please help</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-in-edoc-cockpit-when-creating-e-document-for-france/qaa-p/14270678#M4931765"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:34:12.161000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/overview-of-background-job-in-the-system/qaa-p/14270681#M4931766</id>
    <title>Re: Overview of background job in the system</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:37:32.657000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vaishnavi_R_Kamble</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1813960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you so much. I am working on your latest comment.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/overview-of-background-job-in-the-system/qaa-p/14270681#M4931766"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:37:32.657000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/data-migration-from-sap-c4c-to-zoho-crm-system/qaa-p/14270683#M458191</id>
    <title>Re: Data migration from SAP C4C to ZOHO CRM system</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:40:32.685000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dsolanki007</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/889491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Sijin,&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I need your help in Current migration activity where we are going to migrate SAP C4C to ZOHO CRM system. I am going to transfer Opportunities BO data through excel sheet in .xlms format. Now i am stuck in how do i transfer attachments(Pdf files) of each opportunities to ZOHO CRM? We have opportunities where customer attached pdf of POs and excel sheet as well in each opportunities, now i want to transfer that attachments as well in ZOHO CRM in respective opportunities. C&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Can you please guide me on this ASAP?? Thank you!! Find below screenshot.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dsolanki007_0-1763362365655.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341774i8B9D513EE27C6EAC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dsolanki007_0-1763362365655.png" alt="dsolanki007_0-1763362365655.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Dhaval Solanki&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;***REMOVED BY MODERATION***&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/data-migration-from-sap-c4c-to-zoho-crm-system/qaa-p/14270683#M458191"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:40:32.685000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/when-using-sap-hana-cloud-for-advanced-analytics-what-are-best-practices/qaq-p/14270685</id>
    <title>When using SAP HANA Cloud for advanced analytics, what are best practices for data modeling and part</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:45:43.442000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Suheb</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1558812</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If we store very large amounts of fast-coming data (like IoT or sensor data) in SAP HANA Cloud and we want to analyze it, how should we structure (model) and divide (partition) the database so the system stays fast and efficient?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/when-using-sap-hana-cloud-for-advanced-analytics-what-are-best-practices/qaq-p/14270685"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:45:43.442000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/customer-master-data-updation-in-sap-s-4-hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14270692#M4931768</id>
    <title>Re: Customer Master Data - Updation in SAP S/4 Hana Publi...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:48:16.264000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tehreem_Fatima1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1486433</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121" target="_blank"&gt;Chris1973&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope you are doing well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP Public Cloud, the Migration Cockpit is often misunderstood when it comes to data changes. The Migration Cockpit only allows you to upload data.&lt;BR /&gt;You cannot update or change existing data using the Migration Cockpit (I’ll try after your suggestion). This tool is strictly meant for initial data migration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, I am trying to use “Manage Mass Maintenance – Business Partner”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To update Business Partner data, you need to use the Manage Mass Maintenance – Business Partner application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;However, you can only perform updates when the Mass Update Template is available within the app and that is where the real catch was. This was the point I had been missing during the entire process.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before the Mass Update Template appears in the app, you must first enable the related activity in the system (from Implementation activity).&lt;BR /&gt;Once this activity is activated, the template becomes visible and you can successfully perform mass updates on Business Partner data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have now resolved the issue, and everything is working correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Thank you for your support, and thank you as well for your helpful suggestions throughout the process.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tehreem Fatima&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/customer-master-data-updation-in-sap-s-4-hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14270692#M4931768"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:48:16.264000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/how-to-transfer-each-opportunities-attachments-data-from-sap-c4c-to-zoho/qaq-p/14270696</id>
    <title>How to transfer each opportunities attachments data from SAP C4C to ZOHO C4M?/</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:51:42.625000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dsolanki007</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/889491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I need your help in Current migration activity where we are going to migrate SAP C4C to ZOHO CRM system. I am going to transfer Opportunities BO data through excel sheet in .xlms format. Now i am stuck in how do i transfer attachments(Pdf files) of each opportunities to ZOHO CRM? We have opportunities where customer attached pdf of POs and excel sheet as well in each opportunities, now i want to transfer that attachments as well in ZOHO CRM in respective opportunities. Find below screenshot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dsolanki007_0-1763362289978.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341773i7EED025AE512BB86/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dsolanki007_0-1763362289978.png" alt="dsolanki007_0-1763362289978.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dhaval Solanki&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;+91 9898712915&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/how-to-transfer-each-opportunities-attachments-data-from-sap-c4c-to-zoho/qaq-p/14270696"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:51:42.625000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/%E9%94%80%E5%94%AE%E8%AE%A2%E5%8D%95%E7%9A%84%E7%A8%8E%E9%A2%9D%E5%B7%AE%E5%BC%82%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%A4%84%E7%90%86/qaa-p/14270701#M208162</id>
    <title>Re: 销售订单的税额差异如何处理</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:54:26.111000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ethan_wang04</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/828403</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;You can refer the sloution. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/s-4-hana-cloud-workaround-%E9%94%80%E5%94%AE%E5%90%AB%E7%A8%8E%E4%BB%B7/ba-p/13509670" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/s-4-hana-cloud-workaround-%E9%94%80%E5%94%AE%E5%90%AB%E7%A8%8E%E4%BB%B7/ba-p/13509670&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've just verified the solution. You can comment if you have any questions about it.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;你可以参考这个解决方案。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/s-4-hana-cloud-workaround-%E9%94%80%E5%94%AE%E5%90%AB%E7%A8%8E%E4%BB%B7/ba-p/13509670" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/s-4-hana-cloud-workaround-%E9%94%80%E5%94%AE%E5%90%AB%E7%A8%8E%E4%BB%B7/ba-p/13509670&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;我刚刚验证过这个方案没有问题。如果你有什么问题，你可以留言。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/%E9%94%80%E5%94%AE%E8%AE%A2%E5%8D%95%E7%9A%84%E7%A8%8E%E9%A2%9D%E5%B7%AE%E5%BC%82%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%A4%84%E7%90%86/qaa-p/14270701#M208162"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:54:26.111000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-start-btp-abap-environment-via-landscape-portal-quot-system/qaq-p/14270702</id>
    <title>Unable to start BTP ABAP Environment via Landscape Portal – "System expected element 'object'"</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:54:58.682000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jreimann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163508</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;this morning I tried to start my BTP ABAP Environment using the Landscape Portal, the same way I have done several times before. However, the environment no longer starts and instead shows the error message:&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;System expected element 'object'.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="msh_error.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341771iC392DBC92739622B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="msh_error.png" alt="msh_error.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;When clicking Start, the portal triggers a batch request that fails with 400 Bad Request. The response payload looks like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
   "error":{
      "code":"/A4CLP/MSH_MSG/000",
      "message":"System expected element 'object'",
      "@SAP__common.ExceptionCategory":"Provider_Application_Error",
      "innererror":{
         "ErrorDetails":{
            "@SAP__common.Application":{
               "ComponentId":"BC-ESI-ESF-GW",
               "ServiceRepository":"SRVD",
               "ServiceId":"/A4CLP/MNG_SYS_HIBERNATE_SRV",
               "ServiceVersion":"0001"
            },
            "@SAP__common.TransactionId":"61D0A68A790F482F85DBC57866695E9A",
            "@SAP__common.Timestamp":"20251117064124.696085",
            "@SAP__common.ErrorResolution":{
               "Analysis":"Use ADT feed reader \"SAP Gateway Error Log\" or run transaction /IWFND/ERROR_LOG on SAP Gateway hub system and search for entries with the timestamp above for more details",
               "Note":"See SAP Note 1797736 for error analysis (https://service.sap.com/sap/support/notes/1797736)"
            }
         }
      }
   }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The instance used to start without issues. Now the start operation consistently fails with this error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone seen this issue before or knows what might cause this error? Is this related to Free-Tier environments, or is there any known outage or workaround?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for any insights!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+BTP+ABAP+environment/pd-p/73555000100800001164" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="11-1"&gt;SAP BTP ABAP environment&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-start-btp-abap-environment-via-landscape-portal-quot-system/qaq-p/14270702"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:54:58.682000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-guidelines-showing-decimal-places/qaa-p/14270703#M49374</id>
    <title>Re: Variable Pay - Guidelines showing decimal places</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:56:41.204000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StefM</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1490642</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks Dorota, unfortunately have tried this but no joy!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-guidelines-showing-decimal-places/qaa-p/14270703#M49374"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:56:41.204000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-guidelines-showing-decimal-places/qaa-p/14270704#M49375</id>
    <title>Re: Variable Pay - Guidelines showing decimal places</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:56:59.092000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StefM</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1490642</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Xavier</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-guidelines-showing-decimal-places/qaa-p/14270704#M49375"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:56:59.092000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-guidelines-showing-decimal-places/qaa-p/14270705#M49376</id>
    <title>Re: Variable Pay - Guidelines showing decimal places</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:57:00.168000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StefM</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1490642</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi XavierT</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-guidelines-showing-decimal-places/qaa-p/14270705#M49376"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:57:00.168000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/india-export-with-payment-of-tax-einvoicing/qaa-p/14270707#M4231566</id>
    <title>Re: India: Export with Payment of Tax - eInvoicing</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T07:57:44.939000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ravivarma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1668552</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Annika,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;EXPWP (Export with Pay) is determined automatically for export invoices when taxes are calculated in the invoice. No special configuration is needed solely to set EXPWP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If taxes are calculated in the invoice but are missing from the e-invoice XML:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify that “Classify Condition Types for Goods and Services Tax for India” is correctly maintained for the relevant pricing procedure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure all GST-relevant condition types used in pricing are properly classified so the tax amounts flow into the XML payload.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the issue persists, raise an SAP incident under component CA-GTF-CSC-EDO-IN-IV and include sample invoice numbers, pricing/tax screenshots, and the generated XML payload.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ravivarma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/india-export-with-payment-of-tax-einvoicing/qaa-p/14270707#M4231566"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T07:57:44.939000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-guidelines-showing-decimal-places/qaa-p/14270710#M49378</id>
    <title>Re: Variable Pay - Guidelines showing decimal places</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:00:13.650000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StefM</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1490642</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Xavier, thanks for your response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have tried changing the money format to a new format like you have suggested here but unfortunately there is no change. The only money format it is responding to is defMoneyFormat (even though this is not assigned to the column) it is respecting whatever format is being used there. Issue is that I am using defMoneyFormat for Prorated Target Incentive Amount which needs to have 2 decimal places and similarly, does not work unless using defMoneyFormat, I have raised a ticket with SAP to investigate. Cheers!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-guidelines-showing-decimal-places/qaa-p/14270710#M49378"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:00:13.650000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-logistics-management/bc-p/14270711#M7890</id>
    <title>Re: What's new in SAP Logistics Management</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:00:19.565000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LaurinPS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/777685</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1508012"&gt;@NadineRied&lt;/a&gt;, is SAP LGM on the technical basis of SAP TM and SAP EWM? For example, if I create a warehouse Task in SAP LGM, is it a SAP EWM warehouse Task and could be seen in table /scwm/ordim_o? Could it also be seen in the Warehouse Monitor?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-logistics-management/bc-p/14270711#M7890"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:00:19.565000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fixed-quantity-indicator-in-standard-costing-estimate/qaq-p/14270713</id>
    <title>fixed quantity indicator in standard costing estimate</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:01:52.160000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gavin_ZOUFENG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1426327</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Currently, in our BOM, the fixed quantity flag is checked. When calculating MRP and creating production orders, the quantity remains fixed (regardless of the production quantities). &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, during standard costing, the fixed quantity does not take effect. In the standard cost estimate for the finished product, although the usage of a raw material under a semi-finished product is set as fixed, CK11N calculates the raw material usage based on the quantity of the semi-finished product, leading to an inflated standard cost. What methods can be used to avoid this issue?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fixed-quantity-indicator-in-standard-costing-estimate/qaq-p/14270713"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:01:52.160000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/output-tax-field-in-the-customer-master/qaq-p/14270714</id>
    <title>Output tax field in the customer master.</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:02:07.986000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yKim</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1486100</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Community,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I have a question about output tax field in the customer master.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yKim_0-1763362757918.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341778i2D99FE608D3CFE1E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yKim_0-1763362757918.png" alt="yKim_0-1763362757918.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is our partner system, I want to add another Dep City/Reg for tax determination for customer side.&lt;BR /&gt;(For example, Dep City/Reg in US)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;But I can't find which data affects this field in the SAP Public Cloud system.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Kindly explain what do I need to do add new country column in the output tax field in the customer master?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/output-tax-field-in-the-customer-master/qaq-p/14270714"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:02:07.986000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-conditionally-hide-attributes-and-sections-in-sap-commerce/ba-p/14270462</id>
    <title>How to Conditionally Hide Attributes and Sections in SAP Commerce Backoffice Using Dynamic Forms</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:02:51.204000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Karthi_Murugan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1444361</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Background:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Commerce Backoffice introduced &lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic Forms&lt;/STRONG&gt; to make the Editor Area and wizard UI more flexible and context-aware. Instead of showing all fields statically, Dynamic Forms allow you to &lt;STRONG&gt;show/hide fields, sections, or tabs&lt;/STRONG&gt; based on the current model values, without any Java customization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature improves Backoffice usability and allows developers to control the UI using simple XML rules.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/FONT&gt; :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We want to achieve two requirements in the Product Editor Area:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hide a specific attribute&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., saturatedFat and unSaturatedFat) based on a condition.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hide an entire section&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., nutrition or manufacturing section) unless certain product properties are available.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;How can this be implemented using Dynamic Forms?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is a working configuration example that demonstrates:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to define the editor area for the Product.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to hide an entire section using &lt;CODE&gt;df:section&lt;/CODE&gt; with &lt;CODE&gt;visibleIf&lt;/CODE&gt; conditions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to hide a specific attribute using &lt;CODE&gt;df:attribute&lt;/CODE&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1894535847"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Editor Area Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following XML defines multiple sections in the Product editor area:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;context merge-by="type" parent="GenericItem" type="Product"&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;context component="base"&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;y:base&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;y:labels&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;y:label&amp;gt;code&amp;lt;/y:label&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;/y:labels&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;/y:base&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;/context&amp;gt;

	&amp;lt;context component="editor-area"&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;editorArea:editorArea xmlns:editorArea="http://www.hybris.com/cockpitng/component/editorArea"&amp;gt;

			&amp;lt;editorArea:tab name="hmc.tab.Product.detail"&amp;gt;

				&amp;lt;!-- Product Basic Details --&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;editorArea:section name="hmc.section.product.detail"&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="code"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="name"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="catalogVersion" readonly="true"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="approvalStatus"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="minOrderQuantity"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="maxOrderQuantity"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="showNutrition"/&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;/editorArea:section&amp;gt;

				&amp;lt;!-- Nutrition Section --&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;editorArea:section name="hmc.section.product.nutrition.detail"&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="calories"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="protein"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="carbohydrate"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="cholesterol"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="totalFat"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="saturatedFat"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="unSaturatedFat"/&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;/editorArea:section&amp;gt;

				&amp;lt;!-- Manufacturing Details --&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;editorArea:section name="hmc.section.product.mfg.detail"&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="manufacturer"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="dateOfManufacture"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="dateOfExipry"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="countryOfOrigin"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="seller"/&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;editorArea:attribute qualifier="soldToCountries"/&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;/editorArea:section&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;/editorArea:tab&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;/editorArea:editorArea&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;/context&amp;gt;
​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698022342"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Applying Dynamic Forms for Conditional Visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1630591556"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hide a Section Based on a Condition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hide Nutrition Section if &lt;STRONG&gt;showNutrition = false&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Hide Manufacturing Section if &lt;STRONG&gt;manufacturer is null&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;context component="editorAreaDynamicForms" merge-by="module"&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;df:dynamicForms xmlns:df="http://www.hybris.com/cockpitng/component/dynamicForms"&amp;gt;

		&amp;lt;df:section id="nutritionSection"
			triggeredOn="showNutrition"
			qualifier="hmc.section.product.nutrition.detail"
			visibleIf="showNutrition==true"/&amp;gt;

		&amp;lt;df:section id="manufacturerSection"
			triggeredOn="manufacturer"
			qualifier="hmc.section.product.mfg.detail"
			visibleIf="manufacturer!=null"/&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;/df:dynamicForms&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/context&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1434078051"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Hide a Specific Attribute Dynamically&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example: Show &lt;STRONG&gt;saturatedFat&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;unSaturatedFat&lt;/STRONG&gt; only when &lt;STRONG&gt;totalFat &amp;gt; 10&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;context component="editorAreaDynamicForms"&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;df:dynamicForms&amp;gt;

		&amp;lt;df:attribute id="ProductSaturatedFat"
			qualifier="saturatedFat"
			triggeredOn="totalFat"
			visibleIf="totalFat &amp;gt; 10"/&amp;gt;

		&amp;lt;df:attribute id="ProductUnSaturatedFat"
			qualifier="unSaturatedFat"
			triggeredOn="totalFat"
			visibleIf="totalFat &amp;gt; 10"/&amp;gt;

	&amp;lt;/df:dynamicForms&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/context&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979399108"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dynamic Forms provide a powerful and flexible mechanism to build &lt;STRONG&gt;context-aware&lt;/STRONG&gt;, data-driven screens in SAP Commerce Backoffice. By leveraging &lt;CODE&gt;df:section&lt;/CODE&gt; and &lt;CODE&gt;df:attribute&lt;/CODE&gt;, you can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hide or show entire sections&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hide or show specific attributes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create responsive editor areas that adapt to model values&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve Backoffice usability and reduce clutter for business users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach eliminates the need for custom Java implementations and keeps the Backoffice configuration clean and maintainable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your project requires conditional UI behavior in Backoffice, &lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic Forms should be your first choice&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-conditionally-hide-attributes-and-sections-in-sap-commerce/ba-p/14270462"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:02:51.204000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/emarsys-order-sales-data-upload-fails-with-missing-header/qaq-p/14270716</id>
    <title>Emarsys Order/Sales Data Upload Fails with “Missing header”</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:07:52.825000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ram6453</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I’m integrating &lt;SPAN&gt;sales-data/api&lt;/SPAN&gt; data into Emarsys and one of my uploads is consistently failing with the following message.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Upload failed due to errors — Missing header&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have already another service in azure that calls this api which is running successfully,&amp;nbsp;when reusing this api we are facing this issue,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we have checked headers of api and csv header&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please to suggest any other ways to debug&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/emarsys-order-sales-data-upload-fails-with-missing-header/qaq-p/14270716"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:07:52.825000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/can-i-select-multiple-items-or-partners-in-sap-b1-web-client-2508/qaq-p/14270720</id>
    <title>Can i select multiple items or partners in SAP B1 Web Client 2508 ?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:13:58.254000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>antoine55</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265977</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Can I select multiple entries, such as items or business partners, directly within a form in SAP Business One 10.0 FP 2508 (Web Client)? If this isn’t supported natively, is it possible to implement a custom selection interface using the Web Client Extension Framework or the Service Layer?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/can-i-select-multiple-items-or-partners-in-sap-b1-web-client-2508/qaq-p/14270720"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:13:58.254000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/udm-enablement-job-location-field-is-not-appearing-to-create-business-rule/qaa-p/14270721#M49379</id>
    <title>Re: UDM Enablement - Job Location field is not appearing...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:15:38.883000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ssindhuja</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/142709</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;udaymahobia,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The field is not visible in the business rule because you do not have permission for this object. Please provide yourself with this field permission from RBP and then try!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sindhuja R&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/udm-enablement-job-location-field-is-not-appearing-to-create-business-rule/qaa-p/14270721#M49379"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:15:38.883000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/fields-in-api-for-bnl-consumer-api-for-freight-subcontracting/qaq-p/14270723</id>
    <title>Fields in API for BNL - Consumer API for Freight Subcontracting</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:17:23.143000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PingZhang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1766069</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Greetings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I have some questions regarding specification details about some fields in&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/FreightOrderForSubcontracting_Consumer/path/post_LbnFreightOrderForSubcontracting" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumer API for Freight Subcontracting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;transportMeansTypeCode : Does is mean standard code defined by SAP here ? (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/business-network-freight-collaboration/code-lists/means-of-transport" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Means of Transport&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) ? There is no clarification about this field in API model.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;transportationServiceLevel: Does it managed and pre-defined by shipper in TM system? Is mapping in BNL required? What is applicable value for this?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;vendorId : Does this information have anything to do with carrier? Or does it mean something regarding purchase order? What is data source of this information?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;transportationCharges--itemChargeElements--chargeLineNumber，referenceFromLine，referenceToLine: Does chargeLineNubmer refer to other fields or doc in order to set value? What's mean of refereFromLine and refereneToLine?&amp;nbsp; Does it mean 1 cahrgeLineNumber may include multiple items? I'm grateful very much if you could give example.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;lbnTrackingReference: I can see clarification for this field is "A unique reference that contains the technical id for tracking freight forwarder specific scenario",but this field in this API is optional,what does it first used in&amp;nbsp;subsequent transact?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Items--item-- &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Service--carrierServiceCode: Does this have to be pre-defined in TM and mapping required in BNL?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;transportationCommodityClassifications--type code and code : Do they have to be pre-defined by shipper in TM, does SAP have standard code or do these code refer to other standard?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/fields-in-api-for-bnl-consumer-api-for-freight-subcontracting/qaq-p/14270723"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:17:23.143000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/customer-confirmation-on-proof-of-delivery/qaa-p/14270724#M4231569</id>
    <title>Re: Customer Confirmation on Proof of Delivery</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:17:37.595000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;You cannot store customer confirmation numbers in the standard PoD transaction out-of-the-box. The solution is to extend the delivery document with custom fields (via extensibility apps) and integrate them into the PoD process. This ensures the customer’s PoD reference and date are captured consistently and available for invoicing and dispute resolution&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/customer-confirmation-on-proof-of-delivery/qaa-p/14270724#M4231569"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:17:37.595000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-b1/qaa-p/14270726#M4931772</id>
    <title>Re: SAP B1</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:19:07.067000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>antoine55</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265977</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you very helpful</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-b1/qaa-p/14270726#M4931772"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:19:07.067000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-auth-and-security-project-work-implementation/qaq-p/14270728</id>
    <title>SAP Auth and Security Project work / Implementation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:20:27.729000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ECONRADIE</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1401836</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Security Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’ve been working as an SAP Authorizations &amp;amp; Security Consultant for the past nine years, primarily supporting ECC environments and managing day-to-day user access operations. I’m now looking to broaden my expertise beyond BAU activities and deepen my knowledge in areas such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP GRC implementation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rule set design and optimization&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP role-build methodologies and best-practice frameworks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Overall project-based security design and governance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If anyone could recommend tools, materials, frameworks, or learning paths that would help strengthen my understanding of these project-focused areas, I would really appreciate it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-auth-and-security-project-work-implementation/qaq-p/14270728"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:20:27.729000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/integrate-github-copilot-with-sap-cloud-application-studio/ba-p/14269045</id>
    <title>Integrate GitHub Copilot with SAP Cloud Application Studio</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:21:16.388000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Poovi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1761043</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#003366"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Requirement:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;To integrate GitHub Copilot with SAP Cloud Application Studio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;FONT color="#003366"&gt;Introduction:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;GitHub Copilot integration in Visual Studio Code offers powerful AI assistance for SAP Cloud Application Studio developers working on SAP C4C. It helps transform natural language prompts into ABSL scripts, automates repetitive coding tasks, and enhances logic building with intelligent suggestions. By streamlining development and reducing manual effort, Copilot boosts productivity and supports faster delivery of high-quality solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#003366"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Benefits of GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio/Cloud Application Studio&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports complex logic building by offering real-time suggestions for conditional flows, loops, and data manipulations in ABSL.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Boosts productivity by reducing time spent on boilerplate code, allowing developers to focus on business-specific requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improves accuracy by minimizing syntax errors and offering context-aware completions based on SAP C4C development patterns.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Encourages collaboration by making code easier to understand and maintain, especially for teams working across different modules or geographies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#003366"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Sign In with GitHub Account:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;U&gt;STEP 1:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Click on GitHub Copilot -&amp;gt; Open Chat Window to Sign In&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_0-1763109633765.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340472i43C317AD5422D055/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_0-1763109633765.png" alt="Poovi_0-1763109633765.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;U&gt;STEP 2:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;GitHub Copilot login page will be opened. Click on “Sign up for Copilot Free”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_1-1763109633770.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340473iD480D26840C85AA2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_1-1763109633770.png" alt="Poovi_1-1763109633770.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;U&gt;STEP 3:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Signup page will be opened. Click on “Create an account”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_2-1763109633774.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340474iEF91FBC8A9AD0E2D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_2-1763109633774.png" alt="Poovi_2-1763109633774.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;U&gt;STEP 4:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Enter user details and create an account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_3-1763109633789.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340476i20142C65813B54C3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_3-1763109633789.png" alt="Poovi_3-1763109633789.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;U&gt;STEP 5:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Open SDK and click on “Sign In”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_4-1763109633799.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340475iE5F23F0227203EC0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_4-1763109633799.png" alt="Poovi_4-1763109633799.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;U&gt;STEP 6:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Click on “Authorize github”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_5-1763109633809.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340477i913DCD8CB9B3E5DF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_5-1763109633809.png" alt="Poovi_5-1763109633809.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;U&gt;STEP 7:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;User can access GitHub copilot now in SAP Cloud Application studio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_6-1763109633815.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340478iB5CC52EC03AA366A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_6-1763109633815.png" alt="Poovi_6-1763109633815.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#003366"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Open GitHub Chat:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;GitHub copilot can be opened in two ways,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Separate Chat window.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Copilot assistant in script file.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;1)Separate chat window.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/U&gt;Click on GitHub Copilot -&amp;gt; Open Chat Window&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_7-1763109633824.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340479i5B5E59316F2A5839/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_7-1763109633824.png" alt="Poovi_7-1763109633824.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;A copilot chat window will be open separately as shown below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_8-1763109633838.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340480i218B08E55A26AC9A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_8-1763109633838.png" alt="Poovi_8-1763109633838.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;U&gt;2)Copilot assistant in script file.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/U&gt;Open script file and click on “Ask Copilot” from the menu option&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_9-1763109633872.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340482iF49CFE62BFAC58EA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_9-1763109633872.png" alt="Poovi_9-1763109633872.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Copilot chat option will be opened inside the script file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_10-1763109633884.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340483i6E30A51F3FF3D0ED/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_10-1763109633884.png" alt="Poovi_10-1763109633884.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#003366"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Start Typing with Comments or Partial Code:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CASE 1: ABSL Scripting Assistance&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Copilot helps generate ABSL (Advanced Business Scripting Language) code by interpreting natural language prompts. Whether you're writing BeforeSave, AfterModify, or ValidationOnSave scripts, Copilot can suggest logic structures, syntax, and even error handling patterns, reducing development time and minimizing syntax errors.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Example:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt; “write code to raise an error message, if the email ID is &lt;A href="mailto:testmail@gmail.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;testmail@gmail.com&lt;/A&gt;”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_11-1763109633893.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340481i9A65E61B014B3973/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_11-1763109633893.png" alt="Poovi_11-1763109633893.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Prompt response:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_12-1763109633901.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340485iB386C910486DD1DD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_12-1763109633901.png" alt="Poovi_12-1763109633901.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CASE 2 : Review and refine code&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;If you're working with legacy or repetitive code, Copilot can help refactor loops, simplify conditions, and remove redundancy. It acts like a virtual reviewer, offering cleaner alternatives and improving overall code quality.&lt;BR /&gt;Example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt;” Identify the lines of code which has dump issues and fix it.”&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In below screen shot Copilot Identified the inconsistent lines in red and provided fix/suggestions in green color.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prompt response:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_13-1763109633913.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340484i5218B1D4A324C80A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_13-1763109633913.png" alt="Poovi_13-1763109633913.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CASE 3: To Explain the code&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;GitHub Copilot uses AI to understand the context of your code and comments, offering real-time suggestions and explanations. It would help the developers in understanding the code quickly, there by saving the time and efforts for analysis.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Example:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Explain me the selected lines of code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_14-1763109633925.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340486i55A1B9601AADD8D6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_14-1763109633925.png" alt="Poovi_14-1763109633925.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Prompt response:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_15-1763109633937.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340489iC107DB9B94AAF66D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_15-1763109633937.png" alt="Poovi_15-1763109633937.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_16-1763109633949.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340488i9933811209851EFF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_16-1763109633949.png" alt="Poovi_16-1763109633949.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Explain me the code in the script file&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_17-1763109633961.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340487i5C8D5D6A03283274/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_17-1763109633961.png" alt="Poovi_17-1763109633961.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Prompt response:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_18-1763109633972.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340492i55A4EFAEEA18B58D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_18-1763109633972.png" alt="Poovi_18-1763109633972.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_19-1763109633976.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340490i6851C588426E0CBD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_19-1763109633976.png" alt="Poovi_19-1763109633976.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_20-1763109633979.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340491iD24796AE9DA5D728/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_20-1763109633979.png" alt="Poovi_20-1763109633979.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_21-1763109633984.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340493i165B929A7334CBC2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_21-1763109633984.png" alt="Poovi_21-1763109633984.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CASE 4: Basic syntax generation&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;GitHub Copilot can help developers working in SAP Cloud Application Studio by generating basic ABSL (Advanced Business Scripting Language) syntax. It understands the context of business objects and actions, offering ready-to-use code snippets like variable declarations, loops, and conditional statements. This accelerates development and reduces errors, especially for those new to ABSL.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Poovi_22-1763109633990.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340494iE036768DFACBCC47/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Poovi_22-1763109633990.png" alt="Poovi_22-1763109633990.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;FONT color="#003366"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/U&gt;Using GitHub Copilot in SAP C4C development streamlines coding by offering intelligent suggestions tailored to the platform’s scripting and extension needs. It boosts developer productivity by reducing repetitive tasks and helping maintain clean, consistent code. Copilot also serves as a valuable learning aid for those new to SAP C4C, guiding them through SDK usage and integration patterns.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/integrate-github-copilot-with-sap-cloud-application-studio/ba-p/14269045"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:21:16.388000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/transport-of-g-l-accounts-in-3sl/qaa-p/14270729#M4231571</id>
    <title>Re: Transport of G/L accounts in 3SL</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:22:09.992000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>khanhlynx99</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/854654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/37844"&gt;@Ernesto_Cepeda&lt;/a&gt;, I am encountering the same problem to Niklas's but I cannot find where the custom G/L a/c transport request is saved according to your instruction. In case you have any idea why it was not saved there or where else it could be saved, I will highly appreciate it if you can share with me. Thank you very much.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/transport-of-g-l-accounts-in-3sl/qaa-p/14270729#M4231571"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:22:09.992000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-start-btp-abap-environment-via-landscape-portal-quot-system/qaa-p/14270730#M4931773</id>
    <title>Re: Unable to start BTP ABAP Environment via Landscape Po...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:23:33.224000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jreimann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163508</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;After waiting another 20 minutes and trying again, our ABAP Environment instance has now started successfully.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-start-btp-abap-environment-via-landscape-portal-quot-system/qaa-p/14270730#M4931773"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:23:33.224000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/odata-service-no-system-alias-found-for-service-after-transport-to-qa-why/qaq-p/14270732</id>
    <title>OData Service: “No system alias found for service” after transport to QA – why is “LOCAL” missing?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:27:44.907000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vds</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/708214</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’ve created an OData service that reads data from a custom table and provides PDF downloads. Everything is fully implemented and working in our development system (DEV). The service also runs fine in the Gateway Client (/IWFND/GW_CLIENT).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After transporting it to QA, I’m getting the following error in the Gateway Client:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;500 – No system alias found for service&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I checked the service in QA via /IWFND/MAINT_SERVICE, I noticed that there is no system alias “LOCAL” defined at all.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This confused me because in DEV the service is assigned to the alias “LOCAL”, but in QA it doesn’t exist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What also makes it strange:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other OData services in QA and PROD are working fine—even though they also don’t have any system alias assigned. So the system somehow works without explicitly having “LOCAL” configured.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why does “LOCAL” exist in DEV but not in QA/PROD?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shouldn’t this be consistent?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How is it possible that other OData services work without any system alias at all?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is the system using some kind of implicit local alias?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is the correct way to fix this issue for my new OData service?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do I need to create the alias manually in QA, or is there a better approach?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How can I make sure that existing productive OData services won’t be affected by this configuration?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/odata-service-no-system-alias-found-for-service-after-transport-to-qa-why/qaq-p/14270732"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:27:44.907000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/user-exit-for-fb02/qaa-p/14270733#M4231572</id>
    <title>Re: user Exit for FB02</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:27:52.771000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mahil</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1735104</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello Sir, As per the requirement, users should not be allowed to change the payment block key to ‘V’ in FB02, except for the authorized user USER01. I have configured this restriction in GGB0 under: Financial Accounting → Line Item → Validation. The prerequisite is set as: BSEG-ZLSPR = 'V' . The check is defined as: SYST-TCODE = 'FB02' AND SYST-UNAME = 'USER01'. However, the validation is not working as expected. Currently, all users are still able to change the payment block key to ‘V’, which should not happen. Kindly check and advise on the correct approach to ensure that only USER01 is permitted to change the payment block key value to ‘V’. Thank you.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/user-exit-for-fb02/qaa-p/14270733#M4231572"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:27:52.771000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-logistics-management/bc-p/14270734#M7891</id>
    <title>Re: What's new in SAP Logistics Management</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:28:24.121000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NadineRied</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1508012</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/777685"&gt;@LaurinPS&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, SAP Logistics Management is a separate, completely new product built on SAP BTP with a micro services based architecture. It currently connects with SAP S/4HANA Cloud, private edition via purchase orders and outbound deliveries. In SAP Logistics Management, we also have warehouse tasks in order to execute for example putaway movements. These warehouse tasks are within SAP Logistics Management and not transferred externally, also not to SAP EWM. So no, they are not visible in /scwm/ordim_o or via the warehouse management monitor but you can see them in SAP Logistics Management for example via the app &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/e5980ac94ccb478882691811d1d1730a.html?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Process Warehouse Tasks.&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps. Kind Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nadine&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-logistics-management/bc-p/14270734#M7891"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:28:24.121000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/how-s-4hana-finance-improves-working-capital-and-cash-flow-forecasting/bc-p/14270736#M5884</id>
    <title>Re: How S/4HANA Finance Improves Working Capital and Cash Flow Forecasting</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:37:19.066000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>antoine55</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265977</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the detailed explanation. If I understand correctly, S/4HANA Finance mainly improves working capital and liquidity forecasting by unifying all financial and operational data in real time through the Universal Journal, and by using embedded analytics and machine learning. This removes the manual reconciliations and delays seen in traditional ERPs, allowing AR, AP, inventory, and liquidity forecasts to be analyzed instantly and more accurately. It also seems that the integration with Treasury and predictive tools makes forecasting more strategic and reliable.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/how-s-4hana-finance-improves-working-capital-and-cash-flow-forecasting/bc-p/14270736#M5884"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:37:19.066000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-innovations-in-sap-cloud-erp-private-2025/bc-p/14270737#M62466</id>
    <title>Re: AI innovations in SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:37:34.574000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bernhard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/298</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great to see!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-innovations-in-sap-cloud-erp-private-2025/bc-p/14270737#M62466"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:37:34.574000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/supercharge-sap-automate-new-hire-events-with-sap-build-process-automation/bc-p/14270739#M186393</id>
    <title>Re: Supercharge SAP: Automate New Hire Events with SAP Build Process Automation and SuccessFactors</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:40:58.135000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gopinath_Murugaiyan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17956</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Much appreciated on detailed blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/151637"&gt;@acharyaw&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/supercharge-sap-automate-new-hire-events-with-sap-build-process-automation/bc-p/14270739#M186393"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:40:58.135000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/simplifying-aws-ec2-with-cloud-connector-installation-amp-sap-dp-agent/bc-p/14270740#M186394</id>
    <title>Re: Simplifying AWS EC2 with Cloud Connector installation &amp; SAP DP Agent Integration with BTP</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:42:10.905000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ubaid_Khan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1553270</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great write-up, Utkarsh !&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":clapping_hands:"&gt;👏&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The steps on setting up AWS EC2 Instance with Cloud Connector and DP Agent is really clear.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Loved how you covered the mount point creation and BTP Trial integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This has made it super helpful for hands-on learners.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kudos !&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/simplifying-aws-ec2-with-cloud-connector-installation-amp-sap-dp-agent/bc-p/14270740#M186394"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:42:10.905000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/extending-form-templates-for-sales-document-output/ba-p/14256735</id>
    <title>Extending Form Templates for Sales Document Output</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:53:05.633000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>califf</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/678787</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In Sales, you often need to create output for sales documents (for example, printed sales orders) or share document output via email. To meet these requirements, SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud provides the Output Management Framework, which enables documents to be printed as PDFs or sent electronically. SAP delivers preconfigured form templates and gateway services for each type of sales document.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, the fields available in the predelivered form templates may not always fulfill specific customer needs. In such cases, you can enhance the services to include additional fields and customize form templates accordingly. Before implementing any enhancement, check whether the desired field already exists in the predelivered form templates in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Maintain Form Templates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; app.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here are some examples of form template customization:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extend predelivered forms with additional partner functions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extend predelivered forms with additional condition types&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extend predelivered forms with additional standard fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extend predelivered forms with custom fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--2143931514"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extend Predelivered Forms with Additional Partner Functions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The predelivered form templates support four partner functions:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AG&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Sold-to party&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;WE&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Ship-to party&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;RE&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Bill-to party&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;RG&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Payer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Output data includes the country, address, language of correspondence for the address, and the partner's full name.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can include additional partner functions (e.g., sales employee) in your custom form templates (that is, copies of the predelivered form templates). For more information, see &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-enable-printing-of-partner-function-specific-data-in-output-for/ba-p/13491999" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to Enable Printing of Partner Function-Specific Information&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note: The fields available for the output are hardcoded and fixed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1954522277"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extend Predelivered Forms with Additional Condition Types&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can enable additional condition types in your custom form templates. Complete the following steps:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Identify the relevant pricing procedure used in the sales document.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Open the sales document and check the information in the document header.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="califf_0-1763362395178.png" style="width: 699px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341775iA079F78C2814C9BA/image-dimensions/699x165/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="699" height="165" role="button" title="califf_0-1763362395178.png" alt="califf_0-1763362395178.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In your configuration environment, open the configuration activity Set Pricing Procedures (101117) and make settings for the target condition types in "Procedures-Control Data".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example: For condition type PPR0, enter a or A in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Print Type&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; column.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lowercase (a): &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Item-Level &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;condition data is relevant.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Uppercase (A): &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Header-Level &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;condition data is relevant.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="califf_1-1763362395180.png" style="width: 671px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341777iC0EC109B012B9FD2/image-dimensions/671x255/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="671" height="255" role="button" title="califf_1-1763362395180.png" alt="califf_1-1763362395180.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;(Optional) Add calculation logic in the form template using scripting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For example, to get a subtotal of two condition types, you can add a script to perform this calculation within the custom form template. This allows for dynamic adjustments and tailored outputs based on specific business needs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1758008772"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extend Predelivered Forms with Additional Standard Fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some standard fields (for example, customer group) are not available in the predelivered form templates by default. You can enable these standard fields in your custom form templates via data source extension in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom Fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; app.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For example, for sales orders, you can create a data source extension for the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sales: Sales Order Confirmation Form&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FDP_V1_ORDER_CONFIRM_SRV)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; form service in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom Fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; app. As shown below, you can select fields from the list.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="califf_2-1763362395181.png" style="width: 739px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341776iE42F9F1216951822/image-dimensions/739x244/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="739" height="244" role="button" title="califf_2-1763362395181.png" alt="califf_2-1763362395181.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This extension approach does not support the fields on schedule line level.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some fields added via data source extension may not appear in PDF preview but will show in the final output.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information, see &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a376cd9ea00d476b96f18dea1247e6a5/579920be820f45969e061197aca34484.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to Extend a Custom Form Template with Standard Fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1561495267"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extend Predelivered Forms with Custom Fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can extend your custom forms templates (that is, copies of the predelivered form templates) with custom fields created in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom Fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; app.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Complete the following steps in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom Fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; app:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create custom fields in the following business contexts:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sales: Sales Document&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sales: Sales Document Item&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable usage of the custom fields under Form Templates for the respective form templates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note: When you use the following&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; BAdIs to set or change values of custom fields in sales documents, do not use CDS views as input data in your custom logic:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Modification of Header Custom Fields in Sales Documents&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SD_SLS_MODIFY_ITEM)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Modification of Header Custom Fields in Sales Documents&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SD_SLS_MODIFY_HEAD)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Instead, you should use the input parameters of the BAdIs in your custom logic. This ensures real-time transactional data in document output.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information, see &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a376cd9ea00d476b96f18dea1247e6a5/eb15c4e53dcc4671837800e2894d5b45.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to Extend a Custom Form Template with Custom Fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/extending-form-templates-for-sales-document-output/ba-p/14256735"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:53:05.633000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/rehire-process-with-onb-2-0-and-mini-ec/qaa-p/14270746#M49380</id>
    <title>Re: Rehire process with ONB 2.0 and mini EC</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:55:47.488000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gopinath_Murugaiyan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17956</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/22028"&gt;@Amol1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;it is must to have EC Full license to support rehire and with mini EC, rehire is not supported&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Gopi&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/rehire-process-with-onb-2-0-and-mini-ec/qaa-p/14270746#M49380"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:55:47.488000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/custom-fields-in-monitor-purchase-requisition-report/qaq-p/14270747</id>
    <title>Custom Fields in Monitor Purchase Requisition Report</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:58:30.481000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;B&gt;Monitor Purchase Requisition Items&lt;/B&gt; application, the client requires a few additional columns to be displayed, including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PR Approver Name&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PR Approval Date&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PR Approval Time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Purchase Order&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Purchase Order Item&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PO Approver Name&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PO Approval Date&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PO Approval Time (Days)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have checked for available BADIs related to this report but could not find any suitable options to add these custom fields.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly suggest an appropriate &lt;B&gt;BADI&lt;/B&gt; to add the custom fields to the &lt;B&gt;Monitor Purchase Requisition Items&lt;/B&gt; application or advise how to develop a new &lt;B&gt;custom report&lt;/B&gt; by copying the existing Monitor Purchase Requisition Items report to add mentioned custom fields.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please provide a solution at the earliest&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/custom-fields-in-monitor-purchase-requisition-report/qaq-p/14270747"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:58:30.481000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/custom-fields-in-monitor-purchase-requisition-report/qaa-p/14270748#M208165</id>
    <title>Re: Custom Fields in Monitor Purchase Requisition Report</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T08:58:38.573000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your query.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We reviewed the Monitor Purchase Requisition Items application and confirmed that, in the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, the system does not provide any BADI or extensibility option to add additional fields such as PR/PO approver details, approval timestamps, or PO references directly into this standard app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This application is built on a standard analytical data model that cannot be modified through enhancements or UI extensions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommended and Supported Approach&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly explore the CDS views : &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;Summary&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since the standard app cannot be enhanced, the custom analytical report approach is the recommended method to deliver all required additional fields in a compliant and upgrade-safe way.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following cases are classified as consulting requests and should not be raised via a Support incident. This includes inquiries concerning:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Advice or assistance relating to configuration, business process analysis, or implementation specific to the customer’s unique environment or already documented in Product Guides.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;‘How-To’ questions seeking assistance with documented features.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assistance with customization of the core product, core functionality and/or problems or errors caused by customization that has been implemented or completed by customers or partners.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Aishwarya&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/custom-fields-in-monitor-purchase-requisition-report/qaa-p/14270748#M208165"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T08:58:38.573000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-solution-architect-certification-essential-prep-and-expert-tips/ba-p/14270127</id>
    <title>SAP BTP Solution Architect certification: Essential prep and expert tips</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:00:00.076000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoseBastidas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP BTP Solution Architect certification.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341430i6B377CC51B13207D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP BTP Solution Architect certification.png" alt="SAP BTP Solution Architect certification.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stepping into the SAP BTP Solution Architect role can feel like a big milestone — and honestly, it should. &amp;nbsp;It’s a role that shapes strategy, guides architecture, and helps customers bring real innovation to life.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re preparing for the &lt;STRONG&gt;new scenario-based SAP BTP Solution Architect certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we’re hosting a focused, 30-minute webinar designed to help you walk in with confidence.&amp;nbsp; We’ll break down the updated exam structure released at SAP TechEd, share practical guidance from certified experts, and even demo the &lt;STRONG&gt;new AI roleplay experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; that many candidates find surprisingly eye-opening.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Plus, if you’ve been following the &lt;EM&gt;Becoming an SAP BTP Solution Architect&lt;/EM&gt; learning journey, this session will help you connect the dots and move from “I think I’m ready” to “I know I’m ready.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt; and give yourself the advantage of arriving fully prepared.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/nov/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012116.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/nov/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00012116.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPBTP #SAPPartners #SolutionArchitect #CertificationPrep #TechSkills&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-solution-architect-certification-essential-prep-and-expert-tips/ba-p/14270127"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:00:00.076000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-a-beginner-s-guide-part-1/bc-p/14270749#M176381</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC): A Beginner's Guide - Part 1</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:00:48.030000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>zfiori</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1829</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;It’s where users actually interact with data through dashboards, reports, and planning models. SAC is tightly integrated with BDC.&amp;nbsp; It provides both out-of-the-box analytical stories and flexible tools for ad-hoc analysis. It even supports AI-driven features like predictive insights and chat-based data exploration, helping users move seamlessly from insight to action. "&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks for your selfless sharing, it really help us a lot.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ZFiori.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-a-beginner-s-guide-part-1/bc-p/14270749#M176381"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:00:48.030000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-rpt-1-a-revolutionary-tabular-ml-model-and-owasp-ml-top-10-compliance/ba-p/14270750</id>
    <title>SAP-RPT-1: A Revolutionary Tabular ML Model and OWASP ML Top 10 Compliance</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:01:48.703000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AlexDevassy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2158816</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Note: This blog discusses &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;model, the enterprise version of the ConTextTab / SAP-RPT-1-OSS model architecture. The underlying technology is detailed in the &lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.10707" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ConTextTab research paper&lt;/A&gt; published by SAP, with an open-source implementation available as ConTextTab on &lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/SAP/contexttab" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Hugging Face&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/contexttab/tree/main" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765455978"&gt;The Challenge: Traditional Tabular ML's Security Dilemma&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the world of enterprise machine learning, tabular data represents the backbone of business intelligence from customer analytics to financial forecasting. However, traditional tabular ML approaches have long faced a fundamental security challenge: the need for extensive fine-tuning on customer data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When organisations deploy conventional ML models, they must:&lt;BR /&gt;- Fine-tune models using sensitive customer data, permanently modifying model weights&lt;BR /&gt;- Store customer information within model parameters, creating privacy risks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Manage complex security frameworks to protect against data poisoning, model inversion, and membership inference attacks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Navigate compliance requirements while maintaining model performance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This creates a paradox: the more effective the model becomes through fine-tuning, the greater the security risks it introduces.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568942473"&gt;Enter SAP-RPT-1: Redefining Tabular Machine Learning&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501511687"&gt;The Breakthrough: In-Context Learning for Tabular Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1&lt;/A&gt; represents a paradigm shift in tabular machine learning, introducing a revolutionary approach that eliminates the security-performance trade-off entirely. Built on the principle of In-Context Learning (ICL), SAP-RPT-1 achieves state-of-the-art performance without ever modifying its core model weights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304998182"&gt;How SAP-RPT-1 Works: A Security-First Architecture&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unlike traditional models that require fine-tuning, SAP-RPT-1 operates through a fundamentally different mechanism:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer provides data (tables) examples as context&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Model processes examples in real-time without storing or learning from them&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Predictions are made based on patterns identified in the provided context&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer data is immediately discarded after prediction completion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach delivers two critical advantages:&lt;BR /&gt;- Superior performance through semantic understanding of tabular relationships&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Inherent security advantages through its ephemeral processing approach, addressing several traditional ML vulnerability categories. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979401958"&gt;The Technical Innovation: Seven Pillars of Security-by-Design&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 revolutionary approach is built on seven fundamental characteristics that naturally eliminate most machine learning security risks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911971172"&gt;1. Specialized Architecture for Tabular Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 is fundamentally a classification and regression model designed specifically for structured data, not a Large Language Model. This focus makes it subject to the OWASP ML Top 10 security framework rather than LLM-specific vulnerabilities, providing a clearer security assessment pathway.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715457667"&gt;2. In-Context Learning vs. Traditional Fine-Tuning&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The core innovation lies in SAP-RPT-1 learning approach:&lt;BR /&gt;- Traditional Fine-tuning: Permanently modifies model weights using customer data, creating persistent security risks&lt;BR /&gt;- SAP-RPT-1 ICL: Uses customer data as contextual examples within the input, without modifying any model parameters&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Security Advantage: Eliminates risks associated with model weight manipulation and data persistence&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518944162"&gt;3. Enterprise API-First Security Model&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Fully managed API service: SAP handles all infrastructure, security, and model management while customers interact exclusively through secure, authenticated API endpoints&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Enterprise-grade security: Leverages SAP's proven security frameworks and compliance standards to safeguard SAP-RPT-1, while the base architecture remains transparently published through the open-source SAP-RPT-1-OSS version&lt;BR /&gt;- Controlled environment: All predictions occur within SAP's secure infrastructure&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-322430657"&gt;4. Customer Data Dependency as a Security Feature&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 ICL architecture creates an inherent security advantage:&lt;BR /&gt;- No standalone inference: Model requires customer-provided historical examples for every prediction&lt;BR /&gt;- Customer data control: Prediction quality directly depends on customer-provided context&lt;BR /&gt;- Reduced poisoning risk: Traditional attacks like model poisoning and data poisoning become significantly limited&lt;BR /&gt;- Contextual relevance: Model can only make predictions within the scope of provided examples&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-125917152"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;5. Ephemeral Processing Architecture&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every SAP-RPT-1 inference follows a secure, temporary processing model:&lt;BR /&gt;- Memory-only processing: Customer data exists solely during the inference request&lt;BR /&gt;- No weight updates: Model parameters remain completely unchanged throughout operation&lt;BR /&gt;- Zero persistence: No traces of customer information remain in the model&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--145827722"&gt;6. Enterprise-Grade SAP Management&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a SAP-provided service, SAP-RPT-1 &lt;/SPAN&gt;benefits from comprehensive enterprise security controls:&lt;BR /&gt;- Supply chain security: Direct SAP control over model development, training, and distribution&lt;BR /&gt;- Model integrity: Protection against unauthorised modifications and tampering&lt;BR /&gt;- Data governance &amp;amp; compliance: &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt; SAP ensures that all data used to train its Foundation Model follows strict regulations to protect privacy and meet legal standards. SAP has robust security policies to manage data safely when developing its applications.&lt;BR /&gt;- Quality assurance: Professional model validation and continuous security testing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--342341227"&gt;7. Secure Semantic Processing Pipeline&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 employs a mathematically based data processing approach that eliminates code execution risks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All inputs (strings, numbers, dates, etc.) are transformed into embeddings (vector representations of the data), and these embeddings undergo pure mathematical transformations within the model with no code execution occurring during data processing, only mathematical operations on numerical vectors: Inputs (e.g., strings, numbers, dates) → Vector Embeddings → Mathematical Operations → Prediction Result.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Security guarantees:&lt;BR /&gt;- No code execution pathways in data processing&lt;BR /&gt;- Pure mathematical tensor operations throughout the pipeline&lt;BR /&gt;- Semantic understanding without security vulnerabilities&lt;BR /&gt;- Input sanitization through numerical conversion&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--245451725"&gt;SAP-RPT-1 &amp;amp; OWASP ML Top 10 Compliance&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With SAP-RPT-1 architecture established, we can now examine how these design principles address the industry-standard OWASP ML Top 10 security framework. This assessment demonstrates that SAP-RPT-1 innovative approach doesn't just match traditional security measures, it fundamentally eliminates most attack vectors entirely.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--735368237"&gt;SAP RPT-1 &amp;amp; OWASP ML Top 10 Compliance Overview&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;OWASP ML Top 10&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Risk &lt;SPAN&gt;Applicability&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to SAP RPT-1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;Risk Assessment&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;Technical Rationale&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Security Status&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML01: Input Manipulation Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="212px"&gt;Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Minimal exposure due to customer-controlled data model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers provide their own contextual examples, significantly reducing adversarial input scenarios. Risk limited to compromised customer environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="212px"&gt;Customer Managed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML02: Data Poisoning Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="212px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Architecture prevents traditional data poisoning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;In-Context Learning does not modify model weights. Customer data serves only as contextual input during inference, with no persistent model updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="212px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="165px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML03: Model Inversion Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="165px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="165px"&gt;No sensitive training data to extract&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="165px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer data is ephemeral and not embedded in model weights. No gradient information exposed through API.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="165px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="111px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML04: Membership Inference Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="111px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="111px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP regulated training data eliminates attack vector&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="111px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;No customer data persists in model, eliminating membership inference opportunities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="111px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML05: Model Theft&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP-managed infrastructure prevents model parameter access&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP-RPT-1 is provided and managed within SAP's secure infrastructure. Customers access only the API endpoint, never the model parameters &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Further since customer provided context is not saved in model due to ICL, model theft has no impact on customers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML06: AI Supply Chain Attacks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP as trusted model provider eliminates supply chain risk&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is the official model provider with direct control over development, training, and distribution. No third-party supply chain vulnerabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML07: Transfer Learning Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;No transfer learning in deployment architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In-Context Learning eliminates transfer learning attack vectors entirely..&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML08: Model Skewing &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer data quality responsibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Potential for unintentional bias in customer-provided data. Model leverages &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;patterns present in contextual examples, requiring customer awareness and data curation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Customer Managed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML09: Output Integrity Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Standard API security controls apply&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Risk can be mitigated through conventional authentication and authorization mechanisms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Customer Managed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML10: Model Poisoning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Immutable model architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pre-trained model weights remain completely unchanged during operation. Customer data cannot modify base model behaviour or parameters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--638478735"&gt;The Results: A New Standard for Secure ML&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1128395247"&gt;SAP-RPT-1 Security Achievement&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The OWASP ML Top 10 compliance reveals SAP-RPT-1 remarkable security profile:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Inherent Protection Against 7 out of 10 Major Threats&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP-RPT-1 In-Context Learning architecture provides built-in protection against most ML security risks. Unlike traditional systems that require extensive security hardening, SAP-RPT-1 design reduces the likelihood of most attack vectors by default.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Standard Controls for Remaining Risks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The three-remaining low-risk areas (Input Manipulation, Model Skewing, and Output Integrity) are addressed through conventional security measures that organisations typically already have in place:&lt;BR /&gt;- Input validation and API security controls&lt;BR /&gt;- Customer data governance&lt;BR /&gt;- Standard authentication and authorization mechanisms&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Empowerment Through Data Control&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Rather than creating security burdens, SAP-RPT-1 empowers customers by giving them direct control over model behaviour through their own data, while eliminating the risks associated with traditional model training.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://owasp.org/www-project-machine-learning-security-top-10/)" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;OWASP ML Security Top 10&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.10707" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1-OSS / ConTextTab Paper&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/SAP/contexttab" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1-OSS / ConTextTab Model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/contexttab/tree/main" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1-OSS / ConTextTab Github&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/tuH8Fj5?h=&amp;amp;ltr=a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1 Model FAQ&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;- Know more on SAP-RPT-1 Model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-rpt-1-a-revolutionary-tabular-ml-model-and-owasp-ml-top-10-compliance/ba-p/14270750"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:01:48.703000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14270751#M14523</id>
    <title>Re: Reimagining Certification for the Way We Work Today</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:02:54.342000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S_0019191663</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1891280</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hey, I passed the BTPA exam yesterday. I was surprised that it was an active, 24-hour exam, in a scenario format. I wanted to register for the exam, but I was surprised by the new approach. I took the exam in Polish. I feel like the AI ​​didn't understand my answers, even though I spoke clearly. The entire application froze, and the AI ​​asked illogical questions. This meant I lost my attempt at passing the exam. I would appreciate it if you could verify my exam attempts. I provided all the required information and scored 54%. I would appreciate your help and re-verification. Where can I contact you regarding this matter?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Patrycja&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14270751#M14523"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:02:54.342000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/the-netherlands-events/sitnl-sap-inside-track-netherlands-2025/ec-p/14270753#M26</id>
    <title>Re: sitNL - SAP Inside Track Netherlands 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:04:00.465000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tbroek</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/717</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks Jim for explaining. You are right, click 'Yes' to register.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/the-netherlands-events/sitnl-sap-inside-track-netherlands-2025/ec-p/14270753#M26"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:04:00.465000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/third-party-for-material-with-product-type-2-lean-service/qaa-p/14270754#M4231573</id>
    <title>Re: third party for material with product type 2 (lean se...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:04:54.177000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Check SAP Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;3236870.&amp;nbsp; One option is to go with whatever SAP suggested under Resolution or the other alternate is, via In‑App Extensibility, add custom fields for Validity Start Date and Validity End Date in the sales order item. Map these fields to the PR creation process so they flow into the service PR automatically. If extensibility is not possible, you may need to manually maintain the validity dates in the PR after it is created. This is less ideal but ensures compliance with SAP’s requirement.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/third-party-for-material-with-product-type-2-lean-service/qaa-p/14270754#M4231573"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:04:54.177000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/new-mrp-controller-values-invisible-on-planned-orders-apps/qaa-p/14270755#M4231574</id>
    <title>回复： New MRP Controller values invisible on Planned Orders...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:06:07.002000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adrien_delanoe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/621351</uri>
    </author>
    <content>That was it, thank you very much Matt !</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/new-mrp-controller-values-invisible-on-planned-orders-apps/qaa-p/14270755#M4231574"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:06:07.002000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/user-exit-for-fb02/qaa-p/14270758#M4231575</id>
    <title>Re: user Exit for FB02</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:12:31.406000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaymondGiuseppi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/185148</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Two suggestions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;BTE 00001136 to prevent change of the field when not allowed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use an exit in validation rule to perform authority checl when the field is changed (delta between BSEG-ZLSPR in memory and database)&amp;nbsp;You should also check transaction code FB09 in the rule&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/user-exit-for-fb02/qaa-p/14270758#M4231575"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:12:31.406000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/dm-is-release-of-stack-2300-still-planned/qaq-p/14270759</id>
    <title>DM - is release of stack 2300 still planned?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:13:47.006000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>a_migliore</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/391539</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;is it still planned released of SAP Disclosure Management's new stack like showed in Road Map?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="a_migliore_0-1763366965930.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341782iD301FB8378BA6503/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="a_migliore_0-1763366965930.png" alt="a_migliore_0-1763366965930.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Activities for Annual Report are starting everywhere and it is hard to plan an upgrade now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Andrea&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/dm-is-release-of-stack-2300-still-planned/qaq-p/14270759"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:13:47.006000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/odata-service-no-system-alias-found-for-service-after-transport-to-qa-why/qaa-p/14270762#M4931781</id>
    <title>Re: OData Service: “No system alias found for service” af...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:15:57.194000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>qwertie</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7496</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;it depends if you have transported the system alias in your next system. you can check System alias in table&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;/IWFND/V_DFSYAL&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;you can also maintain the system aliases with SPRO &amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="qwertie_0-1763367291620.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341783i12C57173C6C2E462/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="qwertie_0-1763367291620.png" alt="qwertie_0-1763367291620.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;also you can transport current alias entries&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="qwertie_1-1763367350035.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341784i7595FB734233B94A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="qwertie_1-1763367350035.png" alt="qwertie_1-1763367350035.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;br&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/odata-service-no-system-alias-found-for-service-after-transport-to-qa-why/qaa-p/14270762#M4931781"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:15:57.194000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/output-tax-field-in-the-customer-master/qaa-p/14270766#M4231576</id>
    <title>Re: Output tax field in the customer master.</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:20:25.351000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;For information, tax determination is not controlled directly by fields in the customer master. Instead, it is driven by Tax Departure Country/Region (Dep. Country/Region) → taken from the supplying plant or company code, Customer’s destination country/region → taken from the customer master (address data) and Tax condition records → maintained in Manage Tax Records app. The “Output Tax” field you see in the customer master is essentially a tax classification indicator, not a place to add new countries.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In order to add another Country/Region, in your case, it is US, Go to Manage Your Solution → Configure Tax on Sales and Purchases. Add the US as a departure country/region for tax determination. In the Business Partner (Customer Master), under Sales and Distribution → Billing → Output Tax, you can assign tax classifications per country/region. If you want to see “US” appear here, you must first configure the tax departure country/region in SSCUI. Use the Manage Tax Records app to define tax codes for the US. Link them to the departure country/region and customer tax classification.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/output-tax-field-in-the-customer-master/qaa-p/14270766#M4231576"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:20:25.351000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/rap-event-additional-save-gt-raise-event-gt-insert-generates-shortdump/qaa-p/14270767#M4931782</id>
    <title>Re: RAP event - Additional save &gt; Raise Event &gt; INSERT ge...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:20:33.639000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EgbertVenema</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/499608</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the quick reply! I do understand German, so let's give the webinar a go &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Setting the phase to SAVE manually right before the method that performs the INSERT, does fix that specific command. Unfortunately, a little further down the line (still in the standard SAP method) a WAIT command is issued, which is apparently not allowed in the SAVE phase. *sigh*&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;A "CALL &amp;lt;save&amp;gt;" call is active with "CL_PRINT_QUEUE_UTILS". The current statement "WAIT" is therefore forbidden.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;But good to know we can (and probably should) set the phase manually, thanks for that insight!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/rap-event-additional-save-gt-raise-event-gt-insert-generates-shortdump/qaa-p/14270767#M4931782"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:20:33.639000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/demystifying-document-management-service-on-btp/bc-p/14270769#M176383</id>
    <title>Re: Demystifying Document Management Service on BTP</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:22:28.556000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tly</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135255</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks so much for the blog, it is very helpful.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One question, we have a weird scenario, where we setup linkage between S/4HANA private cloud and DMS content repository, and it was working fine.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But then we did a client copy to the S/4HANA private cloud, and then somehow the linkage to DMS content repository is gone, where run&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;CMIS_REPOSITORY_SETUP report again, it mention 'it is already linked before', and we are not able to link the DMS to S/4HANA private cloud (after client copy) anymore.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Any idea on the resolution for it? tried to search from SAP notes, but no luck here.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/demystifying-document-management-service-on-btp/bc-p/14270769#M176383"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:22:28.556000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/boost-your-developer-efficiency-with-ide-actions/ec-p/14270771#M1244</id>
    <title>Re: 🟢 Boost Your Developer Efficiency with IDE Actions</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:24:44.018000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BMEIJS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5671</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Is there a way to debug these IDE Actions. I have set a breakpoint in my IDE method but the debugger doesn't stop?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/boost-your-developer-efficiency-with-ide-actions/ec-p/14270771#M1244"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:24:44.018000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/picking-list-and-packing-list-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-ewm/qaq-p/14270773</id>
    <title>Picking list and packing list in s/4hana public cloud EWM</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:29:02.058000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;How to print Picking list and packing list in s/4hana public cloud EWM.&amp;nbsp;Is it possible to print picking list and packing list in SAP S/4hana public cloud EWM?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Detail configuration please.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/picking-list-and-packing-list-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-ewm/qaq-p/14270773"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:29:02.058000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/picking-list-and-packing-list-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-ewm/qaa-p/14270774#M208167</id>
    <title>Re: Picking list and packing list in s/4hana public cloud...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:29:09.026000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Picking List&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You may consider print warehouse order with Form Template EWM_PICK_LIST_2. Attached SAP Help Portal page as below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/87f9b54f9c4f4e75aff0061860a6589a/82cf810979654983b2c505f1f3154987.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/87f9b54f9c4f4e75aff0061860a6589a/82cf810979654983b2c505f1f3154987.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Packing List&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is no packing list form template at WM public cloud, but you may print loading list instead. "The loading instruction includes information from the header level of the outbound delivery order, such as recipient, weight, and volume. It also includes information about the handling units (HUs) and unpacked products assigned to the outbound delivery order. "&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Attached the SAP Help Portal page as below for detail:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/87f9b54f9c4f4e75aff0061860a6589a/6025c866f085435a87cd2fd27b8824c4.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/87f9b54f9c4f4e75aff0061860a6589a/6025c866f085435a87cd2fd27b8824c4.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/picking-list-and-packing-list-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-ewm/qaa-p/14270774#M208167"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:29:09.026000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fixed-quantity-indicator-in-standard-costing-estimate/qaa-p/14270776#M4231578</id>
    <title>Re: fixed quantity indicator in standard costing estimate</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:30:43.340000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Yes why this happens is because, Costing explosion in CK11N follows the quantity structure of BOMs and routings. For fixed‑quantity components, costing only respects the flag if the component is directly under the costed material’s BOM. When the fixed‑quantity component is under a lower‑level semi‑finished BOM, the system multiplies it by the semi‑finished quantity, because the costing run treats the semi‑finished product as a proportional input.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Options to avoid this issue are&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Place the raw material directly in the finished product BOM (instead of under the semi‑finished). This way, CK11N will correctly treat it as fixed and not scale it with the semi‑finished quantity.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Run CK11N with a costing lot size = 1 for the semi‑finished product. This ensures the fixed quantity is applied once, not multiplied by the semi‑finished lot size. You can set costing lot sizes in the material master (Costing view).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Model the semi‑finished product as a phantom assembly (special BOM usage). Phantom assemblies explode into the parent BOM during costing, so the fixed‑quantity component is treated as if it belongs to the finished product BOM.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fixed-quantity-indicator-in-standard-costing-estimate/qaa-p/14270776#M4231578"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:30:43.340000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/payroll-eg-issue-need-to-process-salaries-in-non-egp-currencies-for-foreign/qaa-p/14270777#M4231579</id>
    <title>Re: Payroll EG Issue – Need to Process Salaries in Non-EG...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:32:11.773000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mohamed_Aly</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/56040</uri>
    </author>
    <content>very thanks Ahmed,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/payroll-eg-issue-need-to-process-salaries-in-non-egp-currencies-for-foreign/qaa-p/14270777#M4231579"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:32:11.773000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/s4hana-public-cloud-ex-rate-diff-acc-incomplete/qaq-p/14270779</id>
    <title>S4Hana Public cloud - Ex. rate diff. acc. incomplete</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:34:20.776000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rekafulop</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1944157</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear All,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We are implementing S4 hana Public cloud version.&lt;BR /&gt;In bank statement transaction&amp;nbsp; for Romania we receive the error that Ex rate diff.&amp;nbsp; acct. are incomplete for account 0011001020.&lt;BR /&gt;Could you please advise how to solve this issue.&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/s4hana-public-cloud-ex-rate-diff-acc-incomplete/qaq-p/14270779"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:34:20.776000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/do-we-have-quot-disassembly-bom-quot-and-production-orders-processing-in/qaa-p/14270780#M4231580</id>
    <title>Re: Do we have "Disassembly BOM" and Production Orders Pr...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:35:03.039000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ashisherplogic873</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124782</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello , Thankyou Dominik. Let me look into the link and if something more I have I will revert to this post.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your time &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/do-we-have-quot-disassembly-bom-quot-and-production-orders-processing-in/qaa-p/14270780#M4231580"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:35:03.039000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-bas-simulate-rest-api-with-oauth/qaa-p/14270781#M4931784</id>
    <title>Re: SAP BAS - Simulate REST API with Oauth</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:36:07.888000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MioYasutake</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/789</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1658853"&gt;@RomnickJohn&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You need to add the following configuration to package.json:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  "cds": {
    "requires": {
      "TES_CWT_H_DEST": {
        "kind": "rest",
        "credentials": {
          "destination": "TES_CWT_H_DEST"
        }
      }
    }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, execute the following command to bind the destination service:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;cds bind 2 &amp;lt;destinationServiceInstance&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then, execute the service in hybrid mode:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;cds watch --profile hybrid&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-bas-simulate-rest-api-with-oauth/qaa-p/14270781#M4931784"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:36:07.888000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/step-6-enable-draft-with-odata-draft-enabled-issue/qaa-p/14270785#M4931785</id>
    <title>Re: step 6: enable draft with @odata.draft.enabled issue</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:40:02.394000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MioYasutake</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/789</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2107948"&gt;@Shivanshu-prasad&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are using the local SQLite DB, execute the following command to reflect necessary changes associated with draft:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;cds deploy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/step-6-enable-draft-with-odata-draft-enabled-issue/qaa-p/14270785#M4931785"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:40:02.394000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/the-netherlands-events/sitnl-sap-inside-track-netherlands-2025/ec-p/14270790#M27</id>
    <title>Re: sitNL - SAP Inside Track Netherlands 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:41:35.762000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abinaya05</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1949642</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your reply.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have selected Yes there but I haven't got any email confirmation so will there be any entrance check to show any confirmation.And since I have to travel 2.5 hrs for this, it shouldn't be like I'm not registered after I reach there. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/the-netherlands-events/sitnl-sap-inside-track-netherlands-2025/ec-p/14270790#M27"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:41:35.762000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-innovations-in-sap-cloud-erp-private-2025/bc-p/14270791#M62467</id>
    <title>Re: AI innovations in SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:42:34.150000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yannick_PTT</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40565</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks Bernhard!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-innovations-in-sap-cloud-erp-private-2025/bc-p/14270791#M62467"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:42:34.150000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-existing-stock-items-from-non-batch-to-batch-management/qaa-p/14270796#M4231581</id>
    <title>Re: Change existing stock items from Non-Batch to Batch M...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:51:55.088000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hasancangunal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2264864</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you, I will consider the tool</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-existing-stock-items-from-non-batch-to-batch-management/qaa-p/14270796#M4231581"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:51:55.088000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaa-p/14270798#M4231582</id>
    <title>Re: What does "Price Category HF" mean?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:54:05.790000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The item “Price Category HF” in the BCPricingChanges sheet refers to Hotfix (HF) price category changes in SAP S/4HANA Cloud. It is not a new functional field in the customer master or pricing itself, but rather an internal classification used by SAP to indicate that a Business Catalog (BC) or pricing‑related change is delivered as part of a Hotfix Collection (HF). In other words, “Price Category HF” is a marker that the pricing change is tied to a hotfix release cycle, not a notice of future price category changes for customers. Have a look at this blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-the-price-category-information/ba-p/13544146?form=MG0AV3" target="_blank"&gt;Understanding the Price Category information&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143549"&gt;@Tayane&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaa-p/14270798#M4231582"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:54:05.790000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-tile-visualization-amp-navigation-in-sap-build-workzone-cloud/bc-p/14270799#M186398</id>
    <title>Re: Custom Tile Visualization &amp; Navigation in SAP Build Workzone - Cloud foundry launchpad: Solv</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:55:09.572000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KM55</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1553591</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Ransome, I did my deployment differently, not in BAS. So cannot tell you ,sorry.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-tile-visualization-amp-navigation-in-sap-build-workzone-cloud/bc-p/14270799#M186398"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:55:09.572000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-dynamically-split-comma-separated-values-into-multiple-rows-in-sap/qaa-p/14270800#M4931786</id>
    <title>Re: How to dynamically split comma-separated values into...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:55:24.238000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sivaramakrishnan_Manickam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/874631</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I just tired this in SQL console in SAP HANA , you can try it in SQL View data sphere&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265823"&gt;@archanareddy_2511&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;wrote:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I am working in SAP Datasphere (Data Builder – Graphical View) and I have a column that contains comma-separated values inside a single row. Example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ID&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Observee(s)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;19195&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0039270, 0040932, 00051689&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;43400&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;00055233&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;121461&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;NULL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My requirement is to dynamically split these comma-separated values into individual rows, like this:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ID&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Observee&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;19195&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0039270&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;19195&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0040932&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;19195&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;00051689&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;43400&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;00055233&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I need a solution that is&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dynamic (not limited to a fixed number of values like 5 or 10)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Works in SAP Datasphere (Graphical View OR HANA SQL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Works even when:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;number of comma-separated values varies per row&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;values sometimes contain spaces&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;column type is NVARCHAR&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;JSON_TABLE or STRING_TO_TABLE are not supported&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recursion is not enabled in Datasphere SQL View&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So far, I tried:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;JSON_TABLE() → not supported&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;STRING_TO_TABLE() → not supported&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recursive CTE → not allowed inside Data Builder SQL View&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regular expression functions → no REGEXP_SUBSTR in Graphical View&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Calculated Columns → no built-in SPLIT or explode function&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Is there any recommended Datasphere pattern for splitting CSV string fields into multiple records?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Is this possible in:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Graphical View (Projection, Aggregation, Calculated Column, etc.)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;or&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SQL View using functions supported by SAP HANA Cloud?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If someone can provide either:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A working SQL example&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;or&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A correct modeling approach in Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;WITH source_data AS (&lt;BR /&gt;SELECT 19195 AS id, '0039270,0040932,00051689' AS observees FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL&lt;BR /&gt;SELECT 43400, '00055233' FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL&lt;BR /&gt;SELECT 121461, NULL FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL&lt;BR /&gt;SELECT 55555, '12345,67890' FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL&lt;BR /&gt;SELECT 88888, '0001,0002,0003,0004' FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;),&lt;BR /&gt;numbers AS (&lt;BR /&gt;SELECT 1 AS n FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL SELECT 2 FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL SELECT 3 FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL SELECT 4 FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL SELECT 5 FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL SELECT 6 FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL SELECT 7 FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL SELECT 8 FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL SELECT 9 FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;UNION ALL SELECT 10 FROM DUMMY&lt;BR /&gt;)&lt;BR /&gt;SELECT&lt;BR /&gt;s.id,&lt;BR /&gt;TRIM(&lt;BR /&gt;CASE&lt;BR /&gt;WHEN INSTR(s.observees, ',', 1, n.n) = 0 THEN&lt;BR /&gt;SUBSTRING(s.observees,&lt;BR /&gt;CASE WHEN n.n = 1 THEN 1 ELSE INSTR(s.observees, ',', 1, n.n - 1) + 1 END,&lt;BR /&gt;1000)&lt;BR /&gt;ELSE&lt;BR /&gt;SUBSTRING(s.observees,&lt;BR /&gt;CASE WHEN n.n = 1 THEN 1 ELSE INSTR(s.observees, ',', 1, n.n - 1) + 1 END,&lt;BR /&gt;INSTR(s.observees, ',', 1, n.n) -&lt;BR /&gt;CASE WHEN n.n = 1 THEN 1 ELSE INSTR(s.observees, ',', 1, n.n - 1) + 1 END&lt;BR /&gt;)&lt;BR /&gt;END&lt;BR /&gt;) AS observee&lt;BR /&gt;FROM source_data s&lt;BR /&gt;JOIN numbers n&lt;BR /&gt;ON n.n &amp;lt;= LENGTH(s.observees) - LENGTH(REPLACE(s.observees, ',', '')) + 1&lt;BR /&gt;WHERE s.observees IS NOT NULL&lt;BR /&gt;ORDER BY s.id, observee;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265823"&gt;@archanareddy_2511&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;wrote:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I am working in SAP Datasphere (Data Builder – Graphical View) and I have a column that contains comma-separated values inside a single row. Example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ID&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Observee(s)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;19195&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0039270, 0040932, 00051689&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;43400&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;00055233&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;121461&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;NULL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My requirement is to dynamically split these comma-separated values into individual rows, like this:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ID&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Observee&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;19195&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0039270&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;19195&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0040932&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;19195&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;00051689&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;43400&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;00055233&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I need a solution that is&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dynamic (not limited to a fixed number of values like 5 or 10)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Works in SAP Datasphere (Graphical View OR HANA SQL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Works even when:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;number of comma-separated values varies per row&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;values sometimes contain spaces&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;column type is NVARCHAR&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;JSON_TABLE or STRING_TO_TABLE are not supported&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recursion is not enabled in Datasphere SQL View&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So far, I tried:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;JSON_TABLE() → not supported&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;STRING_TO_TABLE() → not supported&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recursive CTE → not allowed inside Data Builder SQL View&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regular expression functions → no REGEXP_SUBSTR in Graphical View&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Calculated Columns → no built-in SPLIT or explode function&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Is there any recommended Datasphere pattern for splitting CSV string fields into multiple records?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Is this possible in:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Graphical View (Projection, Aggregation, Calculated Column, etc.)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;or&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SQL View using functions supported by SAP HANA Cloud?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If someone can provide either:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A working SQL example&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;or&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A correct modeling approach in Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="oUTPUT.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341795i533A9337369D68E0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="oUTPUT.png" alt="oUTPUT.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-dynamically-split-comma-separated-values-into-multiple-rows-in-sap/qaa-p/14270800#M4931786"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:55:24.238000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaa-p/14270802#M4231583</id>
    <title>Re: What does "Price Category HF" mean?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:56:48.085000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Please avoid creating multiple discussions for the same requirement. You already created and got response here - &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaq-p/14270663" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaq-p/14270663&lt;/A&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaa-p/14270802#M4231583"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:56:48.085000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-when-querying-a-sac-story-that-consumes-data-from-an-analytical-model/qaq-p/14270827</id>
    <title>Error when querying a SAC story that consumes data from an analytical model in SAP Datasphere</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T10:00:26.512000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>miquelfornieles</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/151594</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are currently experiencing issues running SAC stories that consume SAP Datasphere analytical models. This issue has arisen during this summer. We have already created a SAP CASE, but we haven’t received any solution yet . For now, expanding the SAP Datasphere parameters is ruled out due to its extra cost.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We would appreciate any help to unblock this problem. The issue is that the execution time of SAC stories has increased significantly (there hasn’t been any notable increase in data), and in the worst cases, the report execution ends with a timeout (we are aware of the 3-minute limitation).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What concerns us is that the &lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAC report only displays a table with about 20,000 records.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt; The analytical model consumes a view that is persisted. Furthermore, there are no other processes running in parallel, and the number of SAC executions is minimal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The error message is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;"code":"inaTimeout","details":{"stack":"See correlation id ada620af-5346-439b-5037-5292cab57589","message":"execution aborted by timeout, Code: 613, SQL State: HY000","code":613,"sqlState":"HY000","name":"HanaError","originalMessage":"execution aborted by timeout"}}&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The note related to SAC Timeout is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003584795" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;0003584795&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Timeout Issue with Analytic Model in SAP Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Miquel&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-when-querying-a-sac-story-that-consumes-data-from-an-analytical-model/qaq-p/14270827"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T10:00:26.512000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/the-extensibility-wizard-one-tool-to-rule-them-all/bc-p/14270833#M62468</id>
    <title>Re: The Extensibility Wizard: One Tool to Rule Them All?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T10:05:10.266000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Karthik-Thiru</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/130244</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44721"&gt;@srekapalli&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Extensibility Wizard is expected to be made available for the S/4HANA 2025 Private cloud release but it is not yet released. An update would be shared once it is available.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/the-extensibility-wizard-one-tool-to-rule-them-all/bc-p/14270833#M62468"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T10:05:10.266000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaa-p/14270835#M4231585</id>
    <title>Re: What does "Price Category HF" mean?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T10:06:41.447000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As already mentioned in the comment, the question has been answered already here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaq-p/14270663" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaq-p/14270663&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've also forwarded your feedback to the expert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards, Henrike&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/what-does-quot-price-category-hf-quot-mean/qaa-p/14270835#M4231585"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T10:06:41.447000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/build-ai-services-using-the-sap-cloud-application-programming-model-and/ev-p/14270837</id>
    <title>🇩🇪 Build AI services using the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model and Generative AI Hub</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T10:08:53.445000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KevinR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423549</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/codejam-cap-llm/tree/main" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CodeJam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;event is on the topic of&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build AI services using the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model, SAP AI Core and Generative AI Hub.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;It is beneficial if you have some basic knowledge about JavaScript as we're using the SAP Cloud SDK for AI with the JavaScript variant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This CodeJam introduces attendees to aspects of exposing generative artificial intelligence (genAI) capabilities to execute tasks using a given business context.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During this event, you'll become acquainted with the theory behind genAI, SAP AI Core, SAP AI Launchpad, and learn how to use the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model to expose AI capabilities through your own OData service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While working through the exercises, you'll become comfortable creating CDS-based service definitions and integrating them into the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) and SAP AI Core Foundation Models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is an&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;in-person event only&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;(not virtual) and is planned for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tuesday January 20th, 2026 in Bielefeld, Germany&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":germany:"&gt;🇩🇪&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;from 10:00 am - 04:00 pm. The workshop site will be the Steigenberger Hotel Bielefelder Hof in Bielefeld.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The event will be held in english.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The instructor is the Developer Advocate&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/70"&gt;@KRiedelsheimer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prerequisites: Any Chromium-based web browser, such as Google Chrome.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that seating is limited -&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;we can only accomodate 25 attendees&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Register here in the Community Event using the RSVP functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;For more information on SAP CodeJam events, to ask questions, and to chat with your fellow attendees, head over to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CodeJam group&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/build-ai-services-using-the-sap-cloud-application-programming-model-and/ev-p/14270837"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T10:08:53.445000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/asset-accounting-fi-aa-insurance-values-in-sap-s-4hana/bc-p/14270838#M72253</id>
    <title>Re: Asset Accounting (FI-AA) – Insurance values in SAP S/4HANA</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T10:11:07.090000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>agalal1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/12355</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This blog is awesome! Thanks a lot&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/804095"&gt;@felixhuether58&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The reasons this blog is awesome: 1) the context is introduced, 2) the concept is explaine and 3) the step-by-step configuration is complete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keep it up!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/asset-accounting-fi-aa-insurance-values-in-sap-s-4hana/bc-p/14270838#M72253"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T10:11:07.090000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14270840#M14524</id>
    <title>Re: Reimagining Certification for the Way We Work Today</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T10:13:11.912000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kasithunuguntla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/129345</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10529"&gt;@DianaRoesner&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;BR /&gt;You mentioned that the new version of the exam is expected to open on Nov. 25. Our team of five members has registered for this exam as part of TechEd, Bangalore.&lt;BR /&gt;Would it be possible to keep the old exam pattern available until the new system is fully stabilized? There seem to be several teething issues that may not be resolved in such a short timeframe.&lt;BR /&gt;We have a target to complete this certification by the end of November and would greatly appreciate if the old exam pattern could remain accessible in the interim as that’s what we’ve prepared for.&lt;BR /&gt;Also, please let us know if registrants will get another opportunity in case the exam system is not ready in time for TechEd.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your prompt attention to this matter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kasi&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14270840#M14524"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T10:13:11.912000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
