<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-08-05T13:44:01.442863+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/component-consumption-in-a-multilevel-bom-in-an-order/qaa-p/14172053#M4221890</id>
    <title>Re: component consumption in a multilevel BOM in an order</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:08:12.535000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rohan_Hire74</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2143457</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I am quite new to SAP. Could you please guide me on what inputs and outputs I should provide to the ABAP developer, and which fields from the relevant tables should be used to develop the Functional Specification (FS)? Additionally, do I need to provide a mathematical formula to capture the step-by-step calculation of low-level material quantity, since my material is located at a lower level in the Bill of Materials (BOM)?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/component-consumption-in-a-multilevel-bom-in-an-order/qaa-p/14172053#M4221890"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:08:12.535000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/project-systems-clear-information-on-boqs/qaa-p/14172054#M4221891</id>
    <title>Re: Project Systems, Clear information on BoQs</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:10:58.778000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;SAP Best Practice is&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Use Document Info Records (DIRs) to attach BoQ documents to WBS.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Maintain BoQ versions for change tracking.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Integrate with SAP MM and SAP SD for full procurement and billing flows.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Use Network Activities for detailed scheduling and resource planning.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;BoQ Process in SAP PS is Create the project using CJ01 or Project Builder. Define WBS elements to represent project phases or deliverables. Prepare BoQ items manually or import from external systems. Link BoQ items to WBS elements. Use BoQ to plan costs in SAP PS. Assign planned costs to WBS elements using:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Easy Cost Planning&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Unit Costing&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Activity-Based Costing&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Convert BoQ items into Purchase Requisitions or RFQs via MM integration. Vendor BoQ drives subcontractor selection and pricing. Monitor actual consumption vs. BoQ quantities. Use confirmations and goods receipts to track progress.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;For Customer BoQ, generate billing based on milestones or progress. Use DP91 or Resource-Related Billing.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;For Vendor BoQ, process vendor invoices and match against BoQ quantities.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Compare planned vs. actual costs and quantities. Analyze deviations in scope, rate, or execution.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/project-systems-clear-information-on-boqs/qaa-p/14172054#M4221891"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:10:58.778000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/selective-data-migration-approach/qaa-p/14172055#M4921976</id>
    <title>Re: Selective data migration approach</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:11:23.436000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VenkatSriram</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1392419</uri>
    </author>
    <content>KBA 3018442 is deleted any other availble</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/selective-data-migration-approach/qaa-p/14172055#M4921976"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:11:23.436000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/why-we-created-open-resource-discovery/ba-p/14172057</id>
    <title>Why we created Open Resource Discovery</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:17:39.776000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SimonHeimler</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172928</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1736879689"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is Open Resource Discovery?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://open-resource-discovery.github.io/specification/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Open Resource Discovery&lt;/A&gt; (ORD) is a protocol for application / service metadata publishing and discovery. It can be used as a foundation for &lt;STRONG&gt;metadata catalogs / marketplaces &lt;/STRONG&gt;and runtime introspection of&lt;STRONG&gt; system landscape resources. &lt;/STRONG&gt;For more information, have a look at the &lt;A href="https://open-resource-discovery.github.io/specification/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ORD Introduction&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="2025-07-30 17_44_01-Open Resource Discovery Introduction.pptx - PowerPoint.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296469iAF178F1322D5675A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-07-30 17_44_01-Open Resource Discovery Introduction.pptx - PowerPoint.png" alt="2025-07-30 17_44_01-Open Resource Discovery Introduction.pptx - PowerPoint.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1540366184"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Building a static API &amp;amp; Event Catalog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The origin of ORD was as a publishing channel to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Accelerator+Hub/pd-p/73555000100800001091" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1214-1"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- formerly known as SAP API Hub - the centralized catalog for the public APIs and events offered by SAP products and SAP’s partners.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP aspires to offer one central place where developers can browse and explore existing APIs and get the API contracts as opposed to a proliferation of disconnected API portals and catalogs per product. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From the beginning, we needed to support multiple protocols like OData, plain REST and SOAP. Early in this project, we established the use of open industry standards, most notably &lt;A href="https://spec.openapis.org/oas/latest.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;OpenAPI&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;as the common denominator to describe all REST-based APIs (incl. OData). &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When putting many different protocols and metadata description formats into one catalog, it quickly becomes obvious that the catalog needs some reliably consistent information across them: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Description: Titles, (short) descriptions, links, tags, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lifecycle: Version, lifecycle status and timelines (beta, active, deprecated), successors for deprecated, changelog, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Taxonomy: Assignment to vendors, products, industry taxonomy, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Grouping: Which resources belong together, can be discovered together&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The second challenge was to provide an easy, automated way to publish the API &amp;amp; Event metadata, including the shared information listed above.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In 2018-2019, this led to the first drafts of the ORD protocol, driven by the Business Accelerator Hub team. The idea was to define a Service Provider Interface (SPI) enabling applications to expose their metadata by describing themselves, as an application is the only reliable source of information about itself. ORD is entirely complementary to the metadata industry standards we were already using; it merely provides a discovery wrapper around them and adds some common shared information, taxonomy, and relationships to build a single catalog from many individual sources.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the ORD API implemented, an application can now register itself on Business Accelerator Hub and the metadata can be crawled and published without manual intervention, thus streamlining the publishing process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1343852679"&gt;Understanding&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Customer System Landscapes (Runtime Introspection)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In 2020, the Open Resource Discovery specification moved ownership to SAP’s Cross-Product Alignment (CPA) team. We quickly realized the potential in this idea, also beyond publishing static metadata to Business Accelerator Hub.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Technology+Platform/pd-p/73555000100700000172" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1215-1"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(BTP), we needed a better understanding of the runtime (customer) system landscapes, including API and event resources. Since many of SAP’s larger solutions are highly customizable and extensible, the challenge is that each tenant can be different: some APIs may not be activated, some may have field extensions, some may have been added by the customer. Since the metadata in Business Accelerator Hub is static, it can only document a generic baseline of what a customer&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;could&lt;/STRONG&gt; look like. To find out what has changed since the snapshot taken in Business Accelerator Hub, it has become necessary to inspect the metadata of the systems at runtime. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This runtime metadata can be very useful – for example, when creating side-by-side extensions in BTP or &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Build/pd-p/73555000100700001491" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1181-1"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/a&gt;, the developers benefit from knowing the actual state of interfaces, so they can find them more quickly and safely build against them&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We realized that the same protocol and interfaces can be used to do both: describe the static baseline metadata and its current state. Therefore, we generalized the ORD specification to work for both static and runtime metadata discovery and integrate it with the Unified Customer Landscape (UCL). &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When generalizing the ORD standard, we defined some design goals – one of which was that the standard should work not only for SAP but be more general-purpose, so that it can be adopted and used by other companies once we open-sourced it. After verifying that ORD works well in SAP production environments, we released v1.0 to general availability in 2021.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1147339174"&gt;Support Adoption and Validation with Tooling&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Developers and integrations rely on machine-readable, well documented API interfaces. To improve the overall experience, we need to ensure that we have 1) wide coverage of metadata existing resources and 2) decent quality, so that API metadata is useful, consistent, and reliable for human developers and machines alike. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To scale this across a large company like SAP, it’s essential to not only provide guidelines and specs – we also need to make it easy to adopt the metadata approach and have a quick validation / feedback loop.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For the ease of adoption, the obvious solution is to build ORD support right into the frameworks, like the ABAP Platform or the CAP Framework and provide a &lt;A href="https://github.com/open-resource-discovery/provider-server" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;generic provider server&lt;/A&gt; to easily provide static metadata.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The quality and validation aspect turned out to be a big topic of its own – we invested in creating a metadata validator that can not only validate ORD, but also the most important metadata formats we transport along inside of it. Quality is also a gradual and moving goal, so we created a concept of “policy levels” in which we distinguish between various degrees or goals of quality – and can validate which level the published content has achieved. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To increase the quality of the metadata, we realized that we need to come to the validation step early in the process (“shift left”), so we don’t identify issues too late, in the worst case not before publishing. Validation ideally happens in the CI/CD of the local application development. The central publishing targets then act as quality gates to ensure at least a baseline for quality. Therefore, we made sure that our validation runs in the central quality gates and at the same time made it easy for product teams to run the same validations locally.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By continuously validating already published metadata according to old and new rules, we have a data-driven approach to identify where we need to increase quality and which validation rules are realistic to enforce. With this loop, we were already able to improve the metadata and documentation quality of SAP software and can grow it continuously.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-950825669"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrating Data Products into ORD&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In 2022-2023, when we started the work on &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Data+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100700003531" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1249-1"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(BDC), the Data Mesh and Data Product topic become very relevant to us as a company. We quickly realized the potential of reusing the ORD specification and the infrastructure for metadata discovery, validation, and cataloging. Even better, by integrating data products into ORD, we were able to ensure that data products are not a silo for data scientists but are interconnected with the existing, more developer-oriented concepts of APIs and Event&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We enabled the description of Data Products in ORD to make them describable and discoverable just like other resources. For Data Products, some specialized API protocols like &lt;A href="https://delta.io/sharing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Delta Sharing&lt;/A&gt; became relevant to add. At this stage, we also had to extend ORD to describe integration dependencies to indicate input ports (potential data lineage) and we further invested into connecting all ORD concepts with business and domain concepts, like Business Objects (Entity Types). For more background, have a look at the blog post: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-metadata-behind-sap-data-products-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14016947" target="_blank"&gt;The Metadata behind SAP Data Products in SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We have now started to connect APIs, Events, and Data Products to business processes, as this connects the concepts of various personas (developers, data scientists, business experts). By interlinking the concepts, we help discovery, search and make it easier to understand what belongs together.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-754312164"&gt;Extend with AI and Knowledge Graph&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are currently seeing a rise in specialized AI agent protocols like MCP and A2A. With this comes a need to build registries / catalogs so consumers or agents can discover them. From the ORD perspective, agent or tools are just a special &amp;nbsp;type of API protocol we could put in the same API catalog - just like Delta Sharing was a new API Protocol geared towards Data Products. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Current efforts on MCP and A2A seem to solve the discovery problem for a single protocol in isolation. However, we see value in having a combined catalog that can include both &lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/overview" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;MCP&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://a2a-protocol.org/latest/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;A2A&lt;/A&gt; – and it is likely there will be more agent protocols to follow. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI agents will benefit from knowledge graphs for further grounding, for helping to avoid AI hallucinations, for storing knowledge explicitly, to reduce the cost and compute of agentic planning, and to provide explain-ability of reasoning. Building an MCP API / proxy around every existing API is costly, so we see potential in bringing in the huge, existing ecosystem of APIs, Events, and Data Products into knowledge graphs. We also see value in having AI to assist with understanding often very complex, customized system landscapes and what they offer, how they can be integrated, and extended.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-557798659"&gt;Establishing ORD as a Linux Foundation Standard&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In 2023, ORD was &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/open-resource-discovery-a-protocol-for-decentralized-metadata-discovery-is/ba-p/13579190" target="_blank"&gt;released as an SAP open-source standard&lt;/A&gt;, accessible for industry-wide adoption. In 2025 we changed ORD's ownership model, contributing it to the Linux Foundation via the publicly funded &lt;A href="https://apeirora.eu/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;ApeiroRA / IPCEI-CIS program&lt;/A&gt;. With this we ensure vendor-neutral governance and long-term independence from SAP. The standard is now open to contributions and ownership of other companies as well. Thus, ORD has laid the foundation to potentially become an accepted industry standard. ORD received the &lt;A href="https://apiworld.co/awards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;2025 API award&lt;/A&gt; in the category “Best in API standards and specification”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-361285154"&gt;Our Vision&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We believe that we have created something special with ORD: We are not aware of any stable, open-source standard that can handle the metadata discovery of applications / services across different protocols and types of resources, tailored to the requirements of various personas and products. There are a few projects with similar goals – some redundant, some complementary – as ORD. A detailed comparison would require at least one more blog post, which may come at a different time.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Many years of SAP experience across multiple products, use cases, and stakeholders went into the standard. With ORD, it’s possible to break up metadata silos and create a well-connected metadata graph of the technical resources in your IT landscape. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We believe that a good metadata integration architecture is an important pillar to achieve transparency in a well-integrated IT landscape and benefits developers, applications and AI alike.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you have questions, feedback, or interest in collaboration, feel free to create &lt;A href="https://github.com/open-resource-discovery/specification/issues" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;a GitHub issue&lt;/A&gt; or reach out to &lt;A href="mailto:simon.heimler@sap.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Simon Heimler&lt;/A&gt; directly. We are looking forward to collaborating with other companies on the future of ORD. Collaboration with the &lt;A href="https://github.com/open-resource-discovery/steering" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Technical Steering Committee&lt;/A&gt; is very welcome.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/why-we-created-open-resource-discovery/ba-p/14172057"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:17:39.776000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-to-transfer-the-planned-order-from-sap-public-cloud-to-sap-digital/qaa-p/14172060#M205972</id>
    <title>Re: How to transfer the Planned order from SAP PUBLIC CLO...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:20:02.773000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;As of now, planned order integration from SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition to SAP DMC is not fully supported out-of-the-box. This limitation is confirmed in SAP’s Digital Manufacturing Integration Guide&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/f6b2ab2222794bebad4c0dcd33138e71/latest/en-US/SAP_DMC_Integration_Guide_enUS.pdf?form=MG0AV3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;So what you can do is build a custom iFlow in SAP Cloud Integration to extract planned orders from S/4HANA Cloud via API. Transform and send them to SAP DMC using supported endpoints. SAP provides integration packages like SAP S/4HANA Integration with SAP Digital Manufacturing. These contain predefined iFlows that can be adapted for REM scenarios&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Ensure the following are correctly configured. Communication Arrangement for the relevant API (e.g., Planned Order Integration), Communication User with appropriate roles and Manage Business Settings in DMC where plant must be mapped and integration mode set&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-to-transfer-the-planned-order-from-sap-public-cloud-to-sap-digital/qaa-p/14172060#M205972"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:20:02.773000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/http-403-forbidden-error-when-posting-a-https-url-from-postman-to-cpi/qaa-p/14172061#M4921977</id>
    <title>Re: HTTP 403 Forbidden error when posting a https url from postman to CPI</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:20:11.630000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AmanJain</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1465680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks a lot Priyanks, this is a essential step. This helped me get around 403 error.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/http-403-forbidden-error-when-posting-a-https-url-from-postman-to-cpi/qaa-p/14172061#M4921977"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:20:11.630000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/change-si-unit/qaa-p/14172066#M205973</id>
    <title>Re: Change SI Unit</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:22:22.266000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Yes you cannot change the standard. If this answered your query, close the discussion by clicking "Accept as Solution"</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/change-si-unit/qaa-p/14172066#M205973"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:22:22.266000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/looking-forward-to-connect-and-learn/td-p/14172067</id>
    <title>Looking forward to connect and learn!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:23:00.115000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sugam_Rijal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2140878</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi SAP community,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My name is Sugam, and I am a postgraduate in ERP systems, specialized in SAP, and I do not have professional experience; however, I am keen to explore opportunities and learn from experienced professionals.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are new to SAP or are a veteran and willing to help a fellow enthusiast, I'd love to connect on LinkedIn and learn more here:&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sugamrijal1" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sugam R.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/looking-forward-to-connect-and-learn/td-p/14172067"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:23:00.115000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-dynamic-value-help-cds-views-for-domain-value/qaq-p/14172068</id>
    <title>How to create dynamic value help cds views for domain value?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:23:03.908000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>UI5_DEV1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1487023</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I create my domain value help like this.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;define view entity x
    as select from dd07t
{
    @ObjectModel.text.element: ['ddtext']
    key domvalue_l as domvalue,
    ddtext
}
where 
    domname = 'x'
    and as4local = 'A'
    and ddlanguage = $session.system_language

"Then use this value help like this 
@Consumption: { valueHelpDefinition: [{ entity: {name: 'X', element: 'domvalue'}}]}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 'Problem' with this solution is i have to create a new cds view for each domain. I am looking for a more generic approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a way to define one value help cds view and use this for all domains? Like the following idea. (Syntax is false, just want to show what i mean)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;define view entity GENERIC_DOMAIN_VH
    as select from dd07t
{
    @ObjectModel.text.element: ['ddtext'] 
    key domvalue_l as domvalue,
    ddtext
}
where 
    domname = @parameter
    and as4local = 'A'
    and ddlanguage = $session.system_language

@Consumption: { valueHelpDefinition: [{ entity: {name: 'GENERIC_VALUE_HELP', element: &amp;lt;domainname&amp;gt;}}], filter: { multipleSelections: false} }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;I tried it with association inside my cds view and parameter in the value help but without success.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-dynamic-value-help-cds-views-for-domain-value/qaq-p/14172068"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:23:03.908000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-sap-community/m-p/14172069#M10258</id>
    <title>Re: Hello SAP Community!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:25:33.662000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sugam_Rijal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2140878</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Ashutosh,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You seem to have a lot of experience within this domain and am looking for mentors whom I can connect with and learn from their experiences. I would love to connect with you: &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sugamrijal1" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sugam R.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-sap-community/m-p/14172069#M10258"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:25:33.662000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/change-si-unit/qaq-p/14172074</id>
    <title>Change SI Unit</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:27:44.696000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>khan_786</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/883894</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If we create New Dimension then can we change the SI Unit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/change-si-unit/qaq-p/14172074"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:27:44.696000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/best-learning-content-marketplace-to-integrate-with-sf-as-per-your/qaa-p/14172078#M45479</id>
    <title>Re: Best learning content marketplace to integrate with S...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:29:10.041000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marjoriep</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1438352</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Heather,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot for your answer, it's very helpful.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm surprised about the localization part because there is an import template for a locale and we use it when creating curriculums for example. We mentioned it to SkillSoft but they couldn't maintain that locale file for all the items and we know that if we manually populate those filed (title and description) it will get scrapped with a new content synchronization. So really, it's not an alternative.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As for the data, I meant that it's quite limited and basic. We do not get any data on skills progression for example. We use the LMS reports so it would mean that we will have to somehow extract or analyze data in SkillSoft (or another marketplace) as well, adding work and steps....&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Harvard Manage Mentor, do you send employees on the plateform directly or do you import the catalogue?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thnaks again for your insight &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/best-learning-content-marketplace-to-integrate-with-sf-as-per-your/qaa-p/14172078#M45479"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:29:10.041000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/hands-on-statt-theorie-effektives-learnen-direkt-im-system/ba-p/14172086</id>
    <title>Hands-on statt Theorie: Effektives Learnen direkt im System</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:32:09.101000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JenniferHauck</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14191</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Willkommen in der nächsten Generation des praxisnahen Lernens – noch einfacher, direkter, effizienter.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Auf Basis Ihres Feedbacks haben wir unsere Übungssysteme gezielt weiterentwickelt – für ein noch besseres Lernerlebnis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Profitieren Sie von einem optimierten Zugang, klaren Strukturen und zur eigenständigen praxisnahen Weiterbildung.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finden sie die für sie relevanten Practice Systeme hier: &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/practice-systems" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/practice-systems&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Das ist neu.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kursmaterialien: Relevante Unterlagen wie Übungshandbücher sind nun direkt über die SAP Learning Plattform verfügbar&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Kursmaterialien" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296536iBD3771A086996F1B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="JenniferHauck_0-1754392936525.png" alt="Kursmaterialien" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Kursmaterialien&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Verbesserte Navigation: Ein klar strukturierter Ablauf führt Sie intuitiv durch Ihre Lernumgebung.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Neue Navigation" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296538iA3D3ECE31334EA57/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="JenniferHauck_1-1754392936548.png" alt="Neue Navigation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Neue Navigation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Im Bereich „My Learning“ auf der SAP Learning Plattform finden Sie alle wichtigen Informationen zu Ihrem Übungssystem übersichtlich gebündelt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="My Learning" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296537i27D8DF31711C506B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="JenniferHauck_2-1754392936552.png" alt="My Learning" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;My Learning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kurze Onboarding-Videos erleichtern den Einstieg: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/onboarding-videos" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Kickstart your learning with bite-sized onboarding videos&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Erfahren Sie Schritt für Schritt, wie Sie auf Ihr Übungssystem zugreifen und diese effizient nutzen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Neu: Generative KI mit Joule in den SAP Übungssystemen&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Noch praxisnäher – mit künstlicher Intelligenz.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mit Joule, wird Ihr Lernprozess intelligenter und effizienter. Ab sofort verfügbar in der &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/practice-systems/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-sandbox" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Sandbox&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;lesen sie mehr &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/introducing-joule-on-hands-on-practice-sandbox/ba-p/13989061" target="_self"&gt;hier&lt;/A&gt; und den &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/introducing-generative-ai-in-sap-successfactors-hands-on-practice-systems/ba-p/14065612" target="_blank"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Practice Systemen.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mit einer gültigen &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/training-certification/learning-hub.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning Hub Lizenz&lt;/A&gt; können Sie direkt loslegen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Weitere nützliche Informationen finden sie hier:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/training-certification" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Learning Services&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;Topic Page&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Ask questions about&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://answers.sap.com/tags/676305042803066886656318788802663" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Training&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;and follow&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Read other&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/tags/676305042803066886656318788802663/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Training&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;blog posts and follow&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Happy Learning!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/hands-on-statt-theorie-effektives-learnen-direkt-im-system/ba-p/14172086"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:32:09.101000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-see-in-html5-application-in-sap-btp-cockpit-subaccount/qaq-p/14172094</id>
    <title>unable to see in HTML5 Application in SAP BTP COCKPIT Subaccount</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:32:52.972000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Govind1010</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2129069</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Can you please share what are the steps you have followed for the above Issue?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm also facing the same issue/error.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-see-in-html5-application-in-sap-btp-cockpit-subaccount/qaq-p/14172094"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:32:52.972000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-unable-to-deactivate-quot-create/qaa-p/14172095#M4921980</id>
    <title>Re: In SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public edition unable to deactiv...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:33:14.801000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rohit0909</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2142819</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Chuma,&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks for your reply&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;1)We checked that Create inbound delivery app exist only in one catalog which is&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_LE_BC_ID_PROC_MC.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;2) we checked that Catalog&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_LE_BC_ID_PROC_MC &lt;/STRONG&gt;includes the app Create inbound delivery app, and It supports IAM apps&lt;BR /&gt;3)we removed and reassign the roles in "Maintain business user'' to trigger IAM refresh.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;still, we are unable to deactivate "Create inbound delivery " app.&lt;BR /&gt;can you please suggest?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-unable-to-deactivate-quot-create/qaa-p/14172095#M4921980"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:33:14.801000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-replication-flow-logs-monitoring-amp-insights/bc-p/14172096#M174778</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Datasphere Replication Flow Logs: Monitoring &amp; Insights</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:33:44.386000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>17827729</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/644099</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks so much — this is really helpful, and your blog came at the perfect time! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I just have two quick questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I create a DB User Group, I don’t have the necessary privileges to import the remote table. However, if I use a DB Analysis user, it works — but that user can only be active for a maximum of 5 days.&lt;BR /&gt;Is there a way to grant the DB User Group the right authorizations to import remote tables without running into authorization errors?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, do you know if there is any table or location where we can see the Delta Load Operations?&lt;BR /&gt;We'd be very interested in tracking the number of objects replicated during each delta load.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Again, thanks a lot for sharing — super helpful!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Marisa&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-replication-flow-logs-monitoring-amp-insights/bc-p/14172096#M174778"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:33:44.386000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/compatibility-scope-what-happens-after-2025-2030/bc-p/14172102#M61365</id>
    <title>Re: Compatibility Scope: What Happens after 2025/2030</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:38:19.837000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Prinya40</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150199</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Expert,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In case customer is using the SAP S/4HANA 1909 on&amp;nbsp; Azure with Project System and the EWA indicates the issues on CP e.g., t-code: CJ20N for Project Builder.&amp;nbsp; So my question is if customer chooses to upgrade to version 2023 (or 2025 to be released soon) on Azure, will the CP still be detected? Now I heard that only the choice of system migration to RISE, will allow users with the use rights to comply in this case.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prinya&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/compatibility-scope-what-happens-after-2025-2030/bc-p/14172102#M61365"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:38:19.837000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/view-s-field-is-empty-although-it-isn-t-empty-in-its-table/qaa-p/14172103#M4921981</id>
    <title>Re: View's field is empty although it isn't empty in its...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:38:36.168000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If your Z-table is meant to store language-dependent texts (like descriptions), and SPRAS is part of the key, SAP expects a text table relationship. If this isn’t defined properly, the maintenance view might not display the language field correctly. To fix this, go to SE11 → your Z-table → Extras → Language-Dependent Texts. Define the text table relationship properly. Ensure SPRAS is marked as a key field in the text table&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If your maintenance view is joining multiple tables (e.g., a base table and a text table), and SPRAS is part of the key, the join condition must explicitly include SPRAS. To fix this, check in SE11 → maintenance view → check the Join Conditions. Make sure SPRAS is included in the join between base and text table. Without this, the system might not be able to match the correct language entry.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If the Z-table is not set up correctly as a text table, SAP might not treat SPRAS as a language key in views. To fix this, go to SE11 → Z-table → check Delivery Class. For text tables, use A (Application Table) or L (Text Table). Also check Table Category; it should be Transparent Table&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/view-s-field-is-empty-although-it-isn-t-empty-in-its-table/qaa-p/14172103#M4921981"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:38:36.168000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-replication-flow-logs-monitoring-amp-insights/bc-p/14172107#M174779</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Datasphere Replication Flow Logs: Monitoring &amp; Insights</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:42:53.388000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shubham521</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/845865</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/644099"&gt;@17827729&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While creating the DB User Analysis there is an option "&lt;SPAN&gt;Database analysis user expires in". The value can be set from 1day, 3 days, 5 days or never. Its better to set the value as never so that it does not get expire.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regarding the second points, i am also trying to get this info in any technical table, however i am not sure if we get this value in any table. However you can get this value in the runtime jSON of the replication flow, but this will be a manual task.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shubham&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-replication-flow-logs-monitoring-amp-insights/bc-p/14172107#M174779"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:42:53.388000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/reporting-daily-material-stocks-using-cds-views/bc-p/14172109#M174780</id>
    <title>Re: Reporting daily material stocks using CDS views</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:43:23.022000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Matthias_BW</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/174540</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/869783"&gt;@atriquellc&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Multiplying price by the quantity is a possible solution, when the value is needed on a monthly base. For a daily consideration i suggest to combine values from material movements in MATDOC enriched by price adjustment postings from ACDOCA.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/reporting-daily-material-stocks-using-cds-views/bc-p/14172109#M174780"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:43:23.022000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/bw-true-impact-of-build-statistics-in-cubes/qaq-p/14172110</id>
    <title>BW: True impact of build statistics in cubes.</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:44:36.862000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>luisaguilar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1141824</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm wondering about the impact of building statistics on InfoCubes in process chains after loading requests (BW 7.5); specially in query performance.&lt;BR /&gt;I've searched for information regarding &lt;EM&gt;when&lt;/EM&gt; (frequency) and &lt;EM&gt;how&lt;/EM&gt; (percentage of data), but most sources seem rather vague.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks in advance,&lt;BR /&gt;luis.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/bw-true-impact-of-build-statistics-in-cubes/qaq-p/14172110"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:44:36.862000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/transporting-content-in-sap-build-process-automation/bc-p/14172111#M174781</id>
    <title>Re: Transporting content in SAP BUILD Process Automation</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:44:57.495000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TS12</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1619673</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;vbalko-claimate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;thanks for the blog, but i have some open questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For the Export CAS Instance i assume to use Plan Standard and for the Target System then Application, is that correct ? Or if there would be a need to also import something to D then all over Application.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Also open for me the type of the Node in ctms, would it be Application oder Multi Target as i got from an BPA team that they downloaded files from BPA inside file with mtar extension.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thorsten&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/transporting-content-in-sap-build-process-automation/bc-p/14172111#M174781"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:44:57.495000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/encryption-using-public-key-and-rsa-algorithm/m-p/14172113#M2042249</id>
    <title>Re: Encryption using public key and RSA algorithm</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:48:18.660000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Suravee</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1632442</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;there is no parameter&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;strustcab in&amp;nbsp;SSFW_KRN_ENVELOPE . Can throw some light on this i am stuck with this issue.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/encryption-using-public-key-and-rsa-algorithm/m-p/14172113#M2042249"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:48:18.660000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/oss-note-for-changes-sepa-in-october-2025/qaq-p/14172126</id>
    <title>OSS note for changes SEPA in October 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:54:01.196000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crislefe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/990086</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Starting in November 2025, there will be changes to SEPA transfer files in Spain. Could someone please tell us which SAP notes will reflect these changes?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/oss-note-for-changes-sepa-in-october-2025/qaq-p/14172126"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:54:01.196000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/automation-on-convert-batch-input-to-bapi/qaq-p/14172127</id>
    <title>automation on convert batch input to bapi</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:54:18.256000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>koby99940</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1122453</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello ,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;upgrade to s\hana from ecc involve (not mandotery) , overwrite batch-inputs with bapi.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have an idea and like to check with you , experts , if its a good one ...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The main idea is to convert the bdcdata internal table to the tables used as an input to the bapi .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;i'll build a generic function\method with input params: transaction,bdcdata[] .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using there&amp;nbsp; z table with mapping of screen\fields from bdcdata to table\field on the bapi input data .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we'll insert the generic function\method instead of command&amp;nbsp; "call transacrion fb01... using bdcdata" that will convert the bdcdata&amp;nbsp; to bapi tables and run the bapi instead .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;that's the idea. do you find in usefull ? is there other automation instead of rewrite the code in all the&amp;nbsp; programs involve batch-input?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Koby&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/automation-on-convert-batch-input-to-bapi/qaq-p/14172127"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:54:18.256000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/user-type-fw-is-not-active-in-sap/qaa-p/14172130#M4921984</id>
    <title>Re: User Type FW is Not Active in SAP?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:57:13.464000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;You must take the tutorial &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/community-2024.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/community-2024.html&lt;/A&gt; referred by &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/help/faqpage/title/can_write_publish_own_blog_post" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/help/faqpage/title/can_write_publish_own_blog_post&lt;/A&gt;. The question has been already asked in the forum.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/user-type-fw-is-not-active-in-sap/qaa-p/14172130#M4921984"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:57:13.464000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/empowering-business-users-with-personalized-news-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud/ba-p/14153055</id>
    <title>Empowering Business Users with Personalized News in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Release</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T13:58:33.724000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CarolineWelsh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/178433</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keeping business users informed about system and company news is essential for organizational success. When users are aware of changes that could impact their daily tasks, they can make better decisions, adapt more quickly, and boost overall productivity. Staying up to date—especially with updates on processes, departments, or system changes—helps eliminate confusion and ensures alignment across teams.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While our existing news feed provides valuable updates on SAP system changes, we’ve listened closely to customer feedback and enhanced communication and user experience on &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;My Home&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; even further. In the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release, we now offer the ability to customize and manage the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;My Home&lt;/I&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;news feed through the new &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage News&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;application.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Manage News Application" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287518iA590C4614F2B974A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ManageNews1.png" alt="Manage News Application" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Manage News Application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Introducing the Manage News Application&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The Manage News application empowers news administrators to deliver timely, targeted information updates directly to business users via a centralized news feed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Key capabilities for news administrators include:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create, manage, and publish news articles:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Administrators can compose news posts to be displayed on My Home, controlling the flow of critical company and system updates.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Control visibility and importance:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; News items can be marked as &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;critical&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, ensuring essential information is highlighted and receives appropriate attention from business users.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Plan and schedule communications:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Administrators can organize when specific news should be published, enabling timely and organized delivery of updates.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Language adaptation:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Messages can be tailored in all company-supported languages, ensuring effective communication across diverse user groups.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Targeted audience assignment:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; News can be assigned to specific App Transaction codes, so only users with access to the corresponding Fiori apps or transaction codes will see relevant news items.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Organize news by groups or categories:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; News articles can be grouped into categories such as Finance or Human Resources, making it easy for users to find pertinent information.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Visual enhancements:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Administrators can upload images aligned with news topics to make posts more engaging and visually informative.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="News article creation in Manage News Application" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287519i19967DFA20797924/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ManageNews2.png" alt="News article creation in Manage News Application" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;News article creation in Manage News Application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Business Users Will Experience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;My Home&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; news feed now displays articles created by news administrators, neatly organized into designated categories. Critical updates are clearly marked with an eye-catching critical marker to ensure users notice and prioritize these messages.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This personalized news feature centralizes essential communications in one place, tailored to the needs of each user based on their system app access. By delivering relevant, timely information directly to business users, organizations can foster a more informed and agile workforce.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Critical News displayed in My Home News Feed" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287520iD66E68569B57ED1D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ManageNews3.png" alt="Critical News displayed in My Home News Feed" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Critical News displayed in My Home News Feed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Critical News Article in My Home News dialog" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287521iF52C4F99B2E9E53F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ManageNews4.png" alt="Critical News Article in My Home News dialog" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Critical News Article in My Home News dialog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefits for Your Organization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the Manage News application, administrators can tailor the news feed to reflect the specific needs of your company or organization, enabling more effective communication with business users. This streamlined and targeted approach to information sharing helps:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Improve user awareness and decision-making&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Minimize confusion and misalignment across teams&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Increase adaptability to system or process changes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhance overall company performance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To access the Manage News application users or administrators will have to be assigned to the SAP_CORE_BC_CUX_NWS_MNG_PC &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;business catalogue. For business users to view the news feed on My Home they will have to be assigned SAP_CORE_BC_CUX_NWS_DSP_PC catalogue. The SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP_BR_EMPLOYEE role will already have &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP_CORE_BC_CUX_NWS_DSP_PC business catalogue assigned.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;With the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&amp;nbsp;2508 release, news maintained in the Manage News application will be displayed by default for all customers who have not configured a RSS feed or SAP Custom System News. To display the news from the Manage News application the 'Manage News App' setting needs to be enabled via UI Adaptation mode (&lt;EM&gt;Adapt UI&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the User Actions menu). Users or administrator must have the catalog SAP_CORE_BC_EXT_FLEX&amp;nbsp;attached to their role to access the UI Adaptation key user capabilities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="My Home UI Adaptation Mode News Feed Settings" style="width: 567px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296541i632C46786BCF145E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-05 at 12.26.23.png" alt="My Home UI Adaptation Mode News Feed Settings" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;My Home UI Adaptation Mode News Feed Settings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’re excited to bring this powerful new communication feature to you with the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and look forward to seeing how it helps your business stay connected and informed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are interested in hearing about the latest innovations in SAP Cloud ERP, please &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://tinyurl.com/public-cloud-prac-forum" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;join our Public Cloud Practitioner Forum&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in which SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition customers share best practices and provide feedback to the SAP development teams about new functionality.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/public-cloud-means-continuous-innovation-and-continuous-learning-new-user/ba-p/14017362" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/public-cloud-means-continuous-innovation-and-continuous-learning-new-user/ba-p/14017362&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(Open to SAP Cloud ERP customers, including partners running SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://people.sap.com/caroline.welsh" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Caroline Welsh&lt;/A&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://anna-marie%20freitag/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Suneet Agarwal&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; on behalf of the SAP UX Foundations responsible for&amp;nbsp;&lt;I&gt;My Home&amp;nbsp;&lt;/I&gt;in SAP S/4HANA.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/empowering-business-users-with-personalized-news-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud/ba-p/14153055"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T13:58:33.724000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/which-development-installation-should-i-choose/qaa-p/14172133#M83210</id>
    <title>Re: Which development installation should I choose?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:01:04.871000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jameswood32</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2202180</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choosing the right development installation depends a lot on your project requirements, your development environment, and your goals. Here are a few things to consider:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Project Type: Are you working on web development, mobile apps, backend services, or something else? Different installations and tools cater better to specific types of projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Platform Compatibility: Make sure the installation supports your operating system (Windows, macOS, Linux) and any frameworks or languages you plan to use.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Features and Tools: Some installations come bundled with extra tools like debuggers, emulators, or integrated package managers. Think about what features you need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Resource Usage: Lightweight installations might be better if you’re on limited hardware, while full IDEs offer more comprehensive features.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Community and Support: Consider popular and well-supported options, as they tend to have more tutorials, plugins, and troubleshooting help available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you share more about your development goals and environment, the community can provide more tailored recommendations!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/which-development-installation-should-i-choose/qaa-p/14172133#M83210"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:01:04.871000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/automation-on-convert-batch-input-to-bapi/qaa-p/14172135#M4921985</id>
    <title>Re: automation on convert batch input to bapi</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:01:53.959000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>It's a nice idea but it will take double time. Is there a reason why you want to replace Batch Input with BAPI? First, I would test if the legacy Batch Input works identically in S/4HANA.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/automation-on-convert-batch-input-to-bapi/qaa-p/14172135#M4921985"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:01:53.959000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/oss-note-for-changes-sepa-in-october-2025/qaa-p/14172137#M4221893</id>
    <title>Re: OSS note for changes SEPA in October 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:02:15.971000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;While SAP has not yet published a dedicated note specifically titled for Spain’s SEPA changes in November 2025, the following notes and resources are expected to be relevant:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Lakshmipathi_0-1754395311784.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296581i10102F815AC4AB34/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Lakshmipathi_0-1754395311784.png" alt="Lakshmipathi_0-1754395311784.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;These notes are updated periodically to reflect regulatory changes.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What you can do is Monitor the SAP Support Portal and engage with your banking partners to confirm their readiness and format expectations.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/oss-note-for-changes-sepa-in-october-2025/qaa-p/14172137#M4221893"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:02:15.971000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/currency-and-unit-conversion-in-sap-datasphere-analytic-model-with-variable/ba-p/14161044</id>
    <title>Currency and unit conversion in SAP Datasphere Analytic Model with variable and value help</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:02:39.769000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Katharina_Markon</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2043392</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Currency conversion is the act of changing financial information from one currency into another. This process is especially crucial for global businesses that conduct operations across various countries and handle transactions in multiple currencies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unit conversion is also important because it ensures consistency, accuracy, and clarity when working with different measurement systems. Unit conversion enables accurate, effective communication and operations across systems, industries, and borders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The following steps are carried out for currency / unit conversion in SAP Datasphere:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;Create currency / unit conversion tables and views&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Create a task chain and schedule it&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Determine the semantic type and the associated unit in the fact view&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;Create input parameters with input help&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5. Add conversion measure in analytical model&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For currency conversion these tables must be available in your SAP S/4 HANA system:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;TCURV&amp;nbsp;- Exchange rate types&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;TCURW&amp;nbsp;- Exchange rate type text&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;TCURX&amp;nbsp;- Decimal places in currencies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;TCURN&amp;nbsp;- Quotations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;TCURR&amp;nbsp;- Exchange rates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;TCURF&amp;nbsp;- Conversion factors&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;TCURC&amp;nbsp;- Currency codes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;TCURT&amp;nbsp;- Currency text&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For unit conversion these tables must be available in your SAP S/4 HANA system:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;T006 -&amp;nbsp;Units of Measurement&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;T006D - Dimensions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;T006A -&amp;nbsp;Assign Internal to Language-Dependent Unit&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;!--          ScriptorStartFragment          --&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;!--          ScriptorEndFragment          --&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;Create currency / unit conversion tables and views&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;a) Start the creation of the corresponding tables and views in the correct space in the Data Builder via Create and Currency / Unit Conversion Views&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_0-1753340331542.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290659iC952785786A584F7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_0-1753340331542.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_0-1753340331542.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;b) Choose source system and check objects.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_0-1753345009021.png" style="width: 473px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290710iCF7DA9987B17D0D0/image-dimensions/473x355?v=v2" width="473" height="355" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_0-1753345009021.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_0-1753345009021.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;c)&amp;nbsp;After clicking on “Create”, all objects are created automatically.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_4-1753340991268.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290667iF5CAC16C2418A172/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_4-1753340991268.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_4-1753340991268.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;Create a task chain and schedule it&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Create a task chain and include all relevant data flows to upload data into the required&amp;nbsp;tables. To keep the data up to date, it is advisable to schedule the task chain.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_3-1753340833475.png" style="width: 328px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290665i4B93C5288E0C07F2/image-dimensions/328x759?v=v2" width="328" height="759" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_3-1753340833475.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_3-1753340833475.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;3. Determine the semantic type and the associated unit in the fact view&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the fact view, which is located under the analytical model, you must maintain the semantic types of the key figures and the associated units.&amp;nbsp;Conversion in the analytical model can only take place through this step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_5-1753341174694.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290670i85C3B4FC5039582B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_5-1753341174694.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_5-1753341174694.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;Create input parameters with input help&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the user is to be provided with a value aid when calling up variables, one or more input parameters must be created in the fact view.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_6-1753341312982.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290671i03CA653380AED878/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_6-1753341312982.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_6-1753341312982.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you only want to provide users with a narrow list with a few units, you can build a view on the unit table and enter it here as value help. You can also set a default value here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_8-1753341568601.png" style="width: 729px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290676i37C897C06D9DFE34/image-dimensions/729x330?v=v2" width="729" height="330" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_8-1753341568601.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_8-1753341568601.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Attention: You may have to set the field length of WAERS to 3 in the view.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;5. Add conversion measure in analytical model&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;a) You can now create conversion measures in the analytical model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_9-1753341835959.png" style="width: 402px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290678iCA45D1198C12CBA3/image-dimensions/402x652?v=v2" width="402" height="652" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_9-1753341835959.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_9-1753341835959.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;b) Enter business name and technical name for your new measure. Select source measure.&amp;nbsp;SAP Datasphere uses the source key figure to recognize whether a unit or currency conversion needs to be carried out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_12-1753342607548.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290684iDC03D14862BCD42A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_12-1753342607548.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_12-1753342607548.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;c) Select the date to which you want to convert and the appropriate exchange rate type (only for currency translation).&amp;nbsp;Then click on the selection help for Target Currency and select “Variable”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_13-1753342653376.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290685i84CBE16974B8E734/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_13-1753342653376.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_13-1753342653376.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on "Use existing Source Variable" and choose the correct one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_11-1753342559001.png" style="width: 557px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290683i443EC7BF26664C04/image-dimensions/557x400?v=v2" width="557" height="400" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_11-1753342559001.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_11-1753342559001.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;d) Under “Advanced”, select the client that is maintained in the TCURR table and what should happen if an error occurs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_14-1753342870004.png" style="width: 345px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290691i3035E1F82A1BFC16/image-dimensions/345x151?v=v2" width="345" height="151" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_14-1753342870004.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_14-1753342870004.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;TCURR:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_15-1753342992940.png" style="width: 265px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290693i94EC5C7A8527CB0D/image-dimensions/265x211?v=v2" width="265" height="211" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_15-1753342992940.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_15-1753342992940.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;e) Go back to main Analytic Model Properties and check error messages or test the new measure in preview.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Tip:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the analytical model existed before the input parameters were created in the fact view below, they must be mapped manually to new or existing variables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KatharinaMarkon1_16-1753343479000.png" style="width: 667px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290696iDE622CBD1930DA0B/image-dimensions/667x356?v=v2" width="667" height="356" role="button" title="KatharinaMarkon1_16-1753343479000.png" alt="KatharinaMarkon1_16-1753343479000.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735926343"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currency and unit conversions are foundational components in ensuring data integrity, consistency, and meaningful analysis in multinational environments. SAP Datasphere offers a structured and streamlined approach to managing these conversions by leveraging integrated tables from SAP S/4HANA and guided steps within the Data Builder and analytical model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By systematically creating conversion views, automating data flows through task chains, assigning semantic types, configuring input parameters, and defining conversion measures, users can implement robust, scalable conversion logic. This ensures that financial and operational data across diverse units and currencies are harmonized and ready for accurate reporting and decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/currency-and-unit-conversion-in-sap-datasphere-analytic-model-with-variable/ba-p/14161044"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:02:39.769000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/abapgit-how-to-use-practical-step-by-step-sap-btp-sap-logon-on-premise/ba-p/14172141</id>
    <title>abapGit: How to use ? Practical Step by step - SAP BTP, SAP Logon - On Premise</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:04:06.968000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sandeep_suggu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11644</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;HI SCN Folks,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope you guys are doing great &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;In this blog, covers only scenarios which i actually worked on &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is abapGit?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;abapGit is&amp;nbsp;an open-source Git client designed specifically for SAP's ABAP development environment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It allows ABAP developers to manage their code using Git, enabling features like version control, collaboration, and code transport alternatives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Essentially, it bridges the gap between the SAP world and the popular Git version control system.&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;abapGit Official SIte:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://abapgit.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://abapgit.org/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;More Blog Posts for more info.:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/abapgit-so-easy/ba-p/13321892" target="_blank"&gt;abapGit - so easy&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/7-ways-abapgit-can-transform-your-development-approach-for-internal/ba-p/13565976" target="_blank"&gt;7 ways abapGit can transform your development approach for internal development&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;amp; Many More...in SAP Community: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/forums/searchpage/tab/message?filter=includeBlogs&amp;amp;q=abapgit&amp;amp;sort_by=-topicPostDate&amp;amp;collapse_discussion=true&amp;amp;include_blogs=true" target="_blank"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Below is the list of practical videos &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP :&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" title="SAP BTP: How to Connect SAP BAS (Business Application Studio) x GitHub | 2024" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QducczbY-vk" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP: How to Connect SAP BAS (Business Application Studio) x GitHub&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Logon (On Premise):&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;TABLE width="727"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="347"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="380"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Video url&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;abapGit: Gist Setup &amp;amp; Usage&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6laKjoC1Jeo" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6laKjoC1Jeo&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;abapGit: Remove &amp;amp; Uninstall&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xh-xQXCeZHM" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xh-xQXCeZHM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;abapGit: Subpackage &amp;amp; Folder Logic&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-Jb1So9M9ik" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-Jb1So9M9ik&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;abapGit: Tracking Of Changes (Online)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e9hIwxeh4lU" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e9hIwxeh4lU&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;abapGit: Offline Pull&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zrgRppW81_4" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zrgRppW81_4&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;abapGit: Offline Push&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yy8baStu_DY" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yy8baStu_DY&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;abapGit: Online Pull&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rX44UJN6Ny0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rX44UJN6Ny0&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;abapGit: Online Push&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sTxdfG_EeeY" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sTxdfG_EeeY&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;abapGit: GitHub Repository Setup&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JDR-n9PxkOM" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JDR-n9PxkOM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;abapGit: GitHub Setup &amp;amp; Token Generation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i8panMg2XNc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i8panMg2XNc&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+BTP+ABAP+environment/pd-p/73555000100800001164" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="11-1"&gt;SAP BTP ABAP environment&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/development+tools+for+SAP+BTP%25252C+Neo+environment/pd-p/67838200100800004383" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="362-1"&gt;development tools for SAP BTP, Neo environment&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+BTP+cockpit/pd-p/e6ab964e-18d4-49a1-b26b-46827aa6ca66" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1245-1"&gt;SAP BTP cockpit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Thank You,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sandeep Suggu.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11644" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community Profile&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://profile.sap.com/u/sandeep_suggu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Profile&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://in.linkedin.com/in/suggu-sandeep" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/abapgit-how-to-use-practical-step-by-step-sap-btp-sap-logon-on-premise/ba-p/14172141"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:04:06.968000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-adjust-the-outbound-delivery-quantity-to-zero-in-case-of-delivery/qaa-p/14172145#M4921986</id>
    <title>Re: How to adjust the outbound delivery quantity to zero in case of delivery cancellation in EWM</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:06:52.383000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FredLobo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1792361</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I have a similar requirement. Were you able to resolve the issue ?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-adjust-the-outbound-delivery-quantity-to-zero-in-case-of-delivery/qaa-p/14172145#M4921986"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:06:52.383000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/ctms-setup-for-sap-build-work-zone/ba-p/14136121</id>
    <title>cTMS Setup for SAP Build Work Zone</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:07:20.160000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Padmanabula</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171881</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;cTMS Architecture – SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Padmanabula_0-1753190360601.png" style="width: 549px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289865i1C9F91BDA51F84AF/image-dimensions/549x247?v=v2" width="549" height="247" role="button" title="Padmanabula_0-1753190360601.png" alt="Padmanabula_0-1753190360601.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Here we have four environments Dev, QA, UAT, and Prod, each corresponding to a separate&amp;nbsp;BTP subaccount. We have provisioned the Cloud Transport Management Service (cTMS) in a separate subaccount.&amp;nbsp;The development team develops their content and export the same from the Dev subaccount using&amp;nbsp;Cloud Transport Management Service (cTMS), which then adds the transport to the&amp;nbsp;QA&amp;nbsp;node.&amp;nbsp;From there, it is imported into QA and the subsequent environments (UAT, Prod) through&amp;nbsp;Solution Manager (SolMan), leveraging&amp;nbsp;Focused Build (FB)&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;Charm status transitions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Additionally, this setup can be&amp;nbsp;integrated with SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Setup Steps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Since several of these SaaS applications share common setup steps, please begin by following the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;initial setup steps&amp;nbsp;outlined here&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blogs/blogworkflowpage/blog-id/technology-blog-members/article-id/174058" target="_self"&gt;Setting Up Cloud TMS for Various SAP SaaS Solutions&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step1: Create Service Instance for SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need to subscribe to SAP Build work zone, standard edition, with Application Plan, which you might have already subscribed when you are setting up SAP Build Work Zone.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are the plans available, for cTMS setup, we need a service instance and key as well for setting up destinations to target subaccount for moving the transports.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Padmanabula_2-1753191028786.png" style="width: 574px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289872i9A783BF2A0F9BD33/image-dimensions/574x280?v=v2" width="574" height="280" role="button" title="Padmanabula_2-1753191028786.png" alt="Padmanabula_2-1753191028786.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For creating Service Instance/key, you should already setup a space in your Cloud Foundry, if you did not setup yet.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to corresponding space and create the Service Instance, chose the SAP Build Work Zone, standard edition and chose the standard plan, then create the Service Key.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; you need to do this in all subaccounts including Dev.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Padmanabula_0-1753971420905.png" style="width: 620px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/294643i6138C297288C6277/image-dimensions/620x245?v=v2" width="620" height="245" role="button" title="Padmanabula_0-1753971420905.png" alt="Padmanabula_0-1753971420905.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step2: Create Destination to cTMS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need to setup a destination with name "ctms_destination" in source subaccount, this is required for integrating with cTMS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Padmanabula_3-1753192192815.png" style="width: 642px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289887i12C136A58851B7D5/image-dimensions/642x201?v=v2" width="642" height="201" role="button" title="Padmanabula_3-1753192192815.png" alt="Padmanabula_3-1753192192815.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Name:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;should be "ctms_destination"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;URL:&lt;/STRONG&gt; uri found in the cTMS service key&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authentication:&lt;/STRONG&gt; OAuth2ClientCredentials&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Token Service URL:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;uaa → url&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;from the cTMS service key&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please use Client ID &amp;amp; Secret from cTMS Service Key.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step3: Create Destinations to CF Subaccounts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;In the subaccount where the&amp;nbsp;Cloud Transport Management&amp;nbsp;(cTMS) service is subscribed, create a&amp;nbsp;destination&amp;nbsp;to each target&amp;nbsp;SAP&amp;nbsp;Build Work Zone subaccount.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Padmanabula_4-1753192337458.png" style="width: 653px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289888iFC6734C2014BDCF8/image-dimensions/653x204?v=v2" width="653" height="204" role="button" title="Padmanabula_4-1753192337458.png" alt="Padmanabula_4-1753192337458.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Name:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Give appropriate name to resemble your CTMS Node&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;URL:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://portal-service.cfapps.us10.hana.ondemand.com/cdm_import_service" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://portal-service.cfapps.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://my-subdomain.authentication.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/token" href="https://my-subdomain.authentication.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/token" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&amp;lt;region&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://portal-service.cfapps.us10.hana.ondemand.com/cdm_import_service" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;.com/cdm_import_service&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authentication:&lt;/STRONG&gt; OAuth2ClientCredentials&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Token Service URL:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://my-subdomain.authentication.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/token" href="https://my-subdomain.authentication.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/token" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://&amp;lt;subdomain&amp;gt;.authentication.&amp;lt;region&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Please use the client id, secret, from the SAP Build Work Zone service key created in step1 above.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step4: Configure Transport Nodes in cTMS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1862388288" id="toc-hId-1862388350"&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;You have been assigned one of the following roles: Administrator or LandscapeOperator.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;From the cTMS UI, you can define transport nodes to represent your system landscape. There are multiple ways to create a node:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;You can either Create a node on the Landscape Visualization screen or from Transport Nodes screen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1862388288" id="toc-hId-1665874845"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Padmanabula_5-1753194993458.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289895i3EADF2C8070C379F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Padmanabula_5-1753194993458.png" alt="Padmanabula_5-1753194993458.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Allow Upload to Node:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Enable this checkbox to allow file uploads to the node. E&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;nabled for the Dev node only.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Forward Mode:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Default value is Auto,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can change this setting based on your landscape and transport flow requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Controlled by SAP Solution Manager:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select this checkbox only if you plan to integrate with SAP Solution Manager (e.g., Charm or Focused Build). We will only enable this for QA and upper environments.&amp;nbsp; When you enable this, it will not allow manual imports from cTMS UI, only through Charm/FB status change.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;If you plan to integrate with Cloud ALM, do not check this option.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content Type:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;For SAP BWZ, select Application Content.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Destination:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Select the appropriate target destination you previously configured in your cTMS subaccount in Step3.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step5:&amp;nbsp;Create Transport routes in cTMS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;In SAP Cloud Transport Management, transport routes are used to connect transport nodes.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Padmanabula_6-1753194993623.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289897i4182ABBF61CE4FDB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Padmanabula_6-1753194993623.png" alt="Padmanabula_6-1753194993623.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Name: Provide the appropriate name&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Chose the Source node &amp;amp; Target node and click on OK.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;After setting up Transport Nodes and routes, your landscape looks something like this based on the number of environments you have.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Padmanabula_7-1753194993630.png" style="width: 648px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289898iE534EBC17D90261A/image-dimensions/648x115?v=v2" width="648" height="115" role="button" title="Padmanabula_7-1753194993630.png" alt="Padmanabula_7-1753194993630.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;You can also use Transport Landscape Wizard, with which you can setup the all your landscape nodes &amp;amp; routes at a time.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step6: Integrate with Solution Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;To integrate Cloud Transport Management (cTMS) with SAP Solution Manager (Charm / Focused Build), follow the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;step6&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;from below article.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;If you want to integrate with Cloud ALM, follow the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;step7&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;from below article.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blogs/blogworkflowpage/blog-id/technology-blog-members/article-id/174058" target="_self"&gt;Setting Up Cloud TMS for Various SAP SaaS Solutions&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope you learned, how to setup cTMS for SAP Build Work Zone. Now the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;setup is complete and ready for transporting the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;content using cTMS either integrated with SAP Solution Manager or Cloud ALM.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Thank you for reading&amp;nbsp; my article, feel free to provide any feedback or comment for any questions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Thanks,&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="verdana,geneva" size="3"&gt;Raghu&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/ctms-setup-for-sap-build-work-zone/ba-p/14136121"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:07:20.160000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-welcome/bc-p/14172156#M740</id>
    <title>Re: Devtoberfest 2025 Welcome!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:11:34.142000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SandipAgarwalla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14164</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to the 2025 Edition.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-welcome/bc-p/14172156#M740"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:11:34.142000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ci-just-started-talking-to-ai-introducing-the-new-ai-adapter-for-sap/bc-p/14172160#M174783</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CI Just Started Talking to AI : Introducing the new AI Adapter for SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:11:59.300000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ashwini21</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1825095</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Amazing Blog Punith!!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ci-just-started-talking-to-ai-introducing-the-new-ai-adapter-for-sap/bc-p/14172160#M174783"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:11:59.300000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/vendor-returns-amp-subsequent-delivery-process-in-purchasing/ba-p/14160012</id>
    <title>Vendor Returns &amp; Subsequent Delivery Process in Purchasing</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:12:36.611000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sagnikch</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1436202</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vendor Returns &amp;amp; Subsequent Delivery Process in Purchasing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Return of goods helps us to return damaged or unwanted goods to the Vendor. A subsequent delivery is an additional delivery of Goods to meet the demand or fulfill the previous defective delivery.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are situations when an order cannot be fulfilled with just one delivery due to lack of available stock.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prerequisites –&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Creation of Material Master.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_26-1753259492328.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290172i1608379D86F3F9DC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_26-1753259492328.png" alt="sagnikch_26-1753259492328.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Creation of Suppliers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_27-1753259608665.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290173iE9797B58973CF754/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_27-1753259608665.png" alt="sagnikch_27-1753259608665.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Case 1: &amp;nbsp;Return to vendor when Purchase Order Available.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Purchase Order to be created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_28-1753259765845.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290174iED297294D7AD431E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_28-1753259765845.png" alt="sagnikch_28-1753259765845.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Goods Receipt:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We would perform GRN of the PO Quantity with Movement Type 101.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_29-1753259900064.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290175iEF74934E17507256/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_29-1753259900064.png" alt="sagnikch_29-1753259900064.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Purchase Order History gets updated in the Purchase Order:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_30-1753259976862.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290176i547AE697B167BB5D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_30-1753259976862.png" alt="sagnikch_30-1753259976862.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After GRN we find that 200 Kgs are defective and cannot be used so we have to return 200Kgs to the Supplier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;TCode: MIGO with Return Delivery with the previously posted GRN Material Document number (5000000041 in our case)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_31-1753260010614.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290179i552B7431A95C60F5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_31-1753260010614.png" alt="sagnikch_31-1753260010614.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Movement type 122 is automatically selected by the system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_32-1753260102062.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290181iE1DE943184262EB3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_32-1753260102062.png" alt="sagnikch_32-1753260102062.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter the Reason of the Movement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_33-1753260231758.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290182iEEE059B646F989AB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_33-1753260231758.png" alt="sagnikch_33-1753260231758.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The reason can be configured in Transaction OMJJ for the Movement type &lt;STRONG&gt;122&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_34-1753260270214.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290184i8EFA72A072ED32A2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_34-1753260270214.png" alt="sagnikch_34-1753260270214.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_35-1753260291539.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290186i8312111D597BA172/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_35-1753260291539.png" alt="sagnikch_35-1753260291539.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_36-1753260325371.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290188iA4C9CDF5CEF95092/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_36-1753260325371.png" alt="sagnikch_36-1753260325371.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Accounting Document After posting:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_37-1753260362163.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290189i47EB49B48E4AF25E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_37-1753260362163.png" alt="sagnikch_37-1753260362163.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_38-1753260391269.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290190iCC6FE9A2DD7EECFB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_38-1753260391269.png" alt="sagnikch_38-1753260391269.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BSX Cr –&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;WRX Dr +&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Purchase Order History updates after Return.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_39-1753260490320.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290192i4CDAC0C3A76FE3E4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_39-1753260490320.png" alt="sagnikch_39-1753260490320.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The vendor sends the material as a subsequent replenishment of the damaged quantity as the subsequent delivery and we have to perform the GRN of the material.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Subsequent Delivery: The system prepopulate the return material document number, otherwise we can also locate the return delivery document number from the Purchase Order History.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_40-1753260537798.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290194i5C8915809EAF6E43/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_40-1753260537798.png" alt="sagnikch_40-1753260537798.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_41-1753260566826.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290199iEB59D159F302E281/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_41-1753260566826.png" alt="sagnikch_41-1753260566826.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Accounting Document after Vendor Return:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_42-1753260596874.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290200iAC1D6F238E7B1F8C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_42-1753260596874.png" alt="sagnikch_42-1753260596874.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Updated PO History after GRN and MIRO:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_43-1753260667040.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290203i6FD3A2E6625A86F6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_43-1753260667040.png" alt="sagnikch_43-1753260667040.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Case 2: Return Process when Purchase Order not available&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scenario: When a buyer procures books on a daily basis for a week and some of his books are not sold and the buyer wants to return the unsold books to the vendor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 1:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this case we have to create a Return Purchase Order. The Return Quantity &amp;amp; the &lt;STRONG&gt;Returns Item indicator&lt;/STRONG&gt; has to be ticked.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_44-1753260756883.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290205i163E07EEAD9001E0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_44-1753260756883.png" alt="sagnikch_44-1753260756883.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 2: MIGO has to be performed. Choose Goods Receipt -&amp;gt; Purchase Order -&amp;gt; Enter the Purchase Order Number.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_45-1753260811233.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290206i7B31F705F82B0CC9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_45-1753260811233.png" alt="sagnikch_45-1753260811233.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;System automatically fetches the Movement Type &lt;STRONG&gt;161&lt;/STRONG&gt; as Goods Return.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_46-1753260842740.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290207i771889566EBF626F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_46-1753260842740.png" alt="sagnikch_46-1753260842740.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter the Quantity and Post.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Accounting Entries after Returns Posted -&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_47-1753260868718.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290208i0C3EB318748C0D86/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_47-1753260868718.png" alt="sagnikch_47-1753260868718.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BSX Cr-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;WRX Dr+&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 3: Issue of Credit Memo, Goto Transaction MIRO and enter the PO number as shown below, select Transaction- Credit memo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_48-1753260916656.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290209iE9FC2EB84E680738/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_48-1753260916656.png" alt="sagnikch_48-1753260916656.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_49-1753260962921.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290210iFC85E422EDDE85CD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_49-1753260962921.png" alt="sagnikch_49-1753260962921.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Credit Memo Posted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_50-1753260993744.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290211i4E0460532B423DC2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_50-1753260993744.png" alt="sagnikch_50-1753260993744.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Updated Purchase Order History-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sagnikch_51-1753261032008.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/290212i227CB6605CFA4397/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sagnikch_51-1753261032008.png" alt="sagnikch_51-1753261032008.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conclusion:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vendor Returns can be done for goods received against a particular Purchase Order or for the extra stock that has to be returned to the supplier as excess supply.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sagnik.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/vendor-returns-amp-subsequent-delivery-process-in-purchasing/ba-p/14160012"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:12:36.611000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/compatibility-scope-what-happens-after-2025-2030/bc-p/14172166#M61367</id>
    <title>Re: Compatibility Scope: What Happens after 2025/2030</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:13:40.816000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stefan_berndt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/288656</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Prinya,&lt;BR /&gt;CJ20N itself is not part of compatibility packages, but only&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;some sub-feature of CJ20N, such as hierachy graphics and others. Unfortunately, it is not possible to exactly check for the usage of these sub-features.&lt;BR /&gt;Therefore, we decided for CJ20N and similar other cases to check for the main transactions as indicator for possible feature usage in our tools such as Early Watch and Simplification Item Check even if these leads to false positives.&lt;BR /&gt;Generally, the outcome of these reports should be considered as indicators for compatibility package usage that must be double-checked with&amp;nbsp;the affected business departments.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Stefan&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/compatibility-scope-what-happens-after-2025-2030/bc-p/14172166#M61367"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:13:40.816000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-load-mdc-source-tables/qaa-p/14172175#M4921987</id>
    <title>Re: How to load MDC Source tables?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:15:57.308000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ThomasLu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/561653</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can directly use BP webervice or a pure custom program to load data from other ecc system into MDC source tables and then trigger the MDC process automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please have a look at MDC standard BP save source table method: &lt;STRONG&gt;CL_MDC_BP_2_CONSOLIDATION~WRITE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;and BP trigger MDC Process method: &lt;STRONG&gt;CL_MDC_BP_2_CONSOLIDATION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;~START_PROCESS&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;as a reference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can create a custom program to extract data from other ECC systems and then using above methods to save into MDC source tables and then trigger process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Br.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thomas&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-load-mdc-source-tables/qaa-p/14172175#M4921987"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:15:57.308000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ehs-environment-management-process-outlining-amp-workflow/ba-p/14169622</id>
    <title>SAP EHS Environment Management Process Outlining &amp; Workflow</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:19:21.814000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>gourav2209</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2211332</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP EHS Environment Management Process Outlining&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The environment management application component helps companies to stay compliant with emissions-related environmental regulations. The solution covers the processes and sub-processes of managing compliance scenario activities to ensure compliance. These processes enable you to create and incorporate a strategy of managing environmentally related data from data collection, sampling, calculation, and aggregation of emissions into the daily operations within your companies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage air and water emissions to fulfil legal requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Calculate and aggregate emissions while fostering proactive data transparency and monitoring.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Detect and communicate deviations, manage investigations, and track follow-up activities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How SAP EHS: Environment Management Helps Industry’s Today:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP's Environment Management product supports customers in the following ways:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leverages prebuilt emission factor library and equations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collects activity data like fuel used, or electricity used.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Proactively flags data issues with data collection or emission calculations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitors thresholds of greenhouse gas emissions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Emission Management Process Steps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The environment management application component helps companies to stay compliant with emissions-related environmental regulations (air and water emissions.) The solution covers the processes and sub-processes of managing compliance scenario activities to ensure compliance. These processes enable you to create and incorporate a strategy of managing environmentally relevant data from data collection, sampling, calculation, and aggregation of emissions into the daily operations within your company.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="gourav2209_0-1754057921450.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295329iE7E5FC382895966E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="gourav2209_0-1754057921450.png" alt="gourav2209_0-1754057921450.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Identify Compliance Requirements: &lt;/STRONG&gt;The first step in the process is to identify and prepare the&amp;nbsp;compliance requirements&amp;nbsp;in the system. This is the task for the environment manager in the company. Inside a compliance requirement, its structure and content are modelled in a hierarchy of paragraphs with environmental limits, regulatory lists, and equations. They can be used later in the compliance scenario.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plan &amp;amp; Monitor Emissions: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Once the compliance requirements are identified and created in the system, the environment manager can document all emissions-related activities into a compliance requirement. The next step in the process is that the environmental manager starts planning the emissions by creating and setting up the activities in the required compliance scenarios. The&amp;nbsp;compliance scenario&amp;nbsp;is the object that supports the execution of one or more compliance requirements. The main goal of a compliance scenario is to define and plan various types of activities, such as: Data collections (most of all emission data), Samplings (determining properties and compositions of used materials), Calculations (determining emissions from used materials), Location-based data aggregations, Execution of tasks.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Collect &amp;amp; Sample Data:&lt;/STRONG&gt; In the process steps Collect and Sample Data and Calculate and Aggregate Data, the environmental manager must perform the required steps to complete the planning. The respective compliance scenarios for the relevant locations must have been created beforehand.&lt;BR /&gt;The Data Collection activity inside a Compliance Scenario defines the responsible persons who collect the emissions data. Also, the schedule of the data collection can be maintained.&lt;BR /&gt;The Sampling activity inside a Compliance Scenario defines which substances or components to analyze (= analytes) and what sampling method to use for it.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculate &amp;amp; Aggregate Data: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Calculations determine amounts of gas emissions by using the amounts of incinerated materials (like coal or oil) collected earlier together with the emission factors that apply for those materials. More complicated calculations also exist. The environmental limits can optionally be referenced in a calculation&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The environment manager can use this activity to acquire aggregated values for the environmental data; this aggregated data can be used for environmental assessments and for reporting to the authorities. The aggregation of data is done based on the location structure. These location-based aggregations use as input data collections, sampled data, and calculated data stored for your locations.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitor Data &amp;amp; Identify Data Issues: &lt;/STRONG&gt;In the process step, Monitor Data and Identify Data Issues, the environment manager can check the environmentally related data and identify if there are any issues with the data.&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The app can also be used to approve, replace, invalidate, and create&amp;nbsp;deviations&amp;nbsp;for data with warnings or for exceeded data.&lt;BR /&gt;Collected and calculated data is automatically compared to associated limits in a compliance scenario and flagged, if exceeded.&lt;BR /&gt;Limit warnings and exceedances are displayed in the Data Issues - Exceedances and Warning app.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Identify Deviation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In the process step, Identify Deviations, the environmental manager starts monitoring the data on a plant level and performs checks against company goals about compliance with applicable environmental limits.&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;A&amp;nbsp;deviation&amp;nbsp;record is an event that indicates the violation of specific environmental requirements.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Record Deviation &amp;amp; Start Investigation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Once deviations have been identified, they can be created as records in the system, and a proper investigation can be performed and documented. The environmental manager can use this procedure to review and complete deviation records that have been created for inconsistent environmentally related data. During the review and completion process, you can check the information that is already available for the deviation and change it if necessary.&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The environment management application component helps companies to stay compliant with emissions-related environmental regulations. The solution covers the processes and sub-processes of managing compliance scenario activities to ensure compliance. These processes enable you to create and incorporate a strategy of managing environmentally related data from data collection, sampling, calculation, and aggregation of emissions into the daily operations within your companies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thankyou!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rampem Gourav&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ehs-environment-management-process-outlining-amp-workflow/ba-p/14169622"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:19:21.814000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-reverse-ers-related-goods-receipt-documents/qaq-p/14172184</id>
    <title>How to reverse ERS related goods receipt documents</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:19:24.615000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grace_Li1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2073639</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dears,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We met a ERS related problem. We used ERS Evaluated Receipt Settlement function, post goods receipt, and through APP "schedule supplier invoice jobs", to schedule ERS jobs, post invoice automatically by job.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But today, we found the purchase order is incorrect, need to reverse the invoice and goods receipt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we tried to reverse the invoice, we found the error message "M8.414", the message said, if you want invoice creation completely using ERS, then you must cancel the goods receipt and not the invoice document. ERS will then create the relevant cancellation invoice document for the cancelled goods movement".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, when we use APP "post goods movement" to cancel the goods receipt document, system also generated the error message "M7021 Deficit PU IR Quantity&amp;nbsp; XXXXX".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you please guide how to reverse ERS related goods movement document? Is it another APP?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you very much.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Grace&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-reverse-ers-related-goods-receipt-documents/qaq-p/14172184"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:19:24.615000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/leveraging-sap-successfactors-compensation-for-salary-benchmarking/ba-p/14153700</id>
    <title>Leveraging SAP SuccessFactors Compensation for Salary Benchmarking</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:24:39.677000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hrajkumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1625060</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Though SAP has brought in several enhancements in compensation module, there isn't a direct solution to capture external salary benchmarking data and use it for comparison against existing pay ranges during annual compensation planning activity. However for one of my recent client who is into new-gen technology product development, wanted to have their top talents (some even hold individual patents to their names)&amp;nbsp; paid as per market.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Client does have subscription tie-up with an external vendor who provides market salary data which the management would like to leverage during their annual compensation planning exercise. After understanding their business nuances, I did try to auto update EC custom MDF through an integration but it did not materialize due to platform differences and firewall incidents. So, I resorted to import the data to SuccessFactors until technical handshake happens between two platforms. Let me share the solution here, so that the tech savvy HR's can think of incorporating.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;How SuccessFactors Compensation Supports Market Benchmarking&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SuccessFactors does not provide market data, however supports in creating placeholder for utilizing market benchmarking data and comparing it with existing pay ranges in Employee Central&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Importing Market Data:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;M&lt;/SPAN&gt;arket benchmark data can be obtained from vendors such as Mercer, Aon, etc. and imported into SuccessFactors. It can be either imported directly in Employee Central leveraging custom fields or can be imported in a specific lookup table in compensation module with Country and Pay Grade being the key fields against which 'Min', 'Mid' &amp;amp; 'Max' values are maintained.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Salary Pay Matrix:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Direct EC Pay Matrix can be used in order to compare with market data for a specific pay grade of a specific country. This enables the planner to consider the market pay data while making compensation decision for the employee.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Technical briefing from SuccessFactors standpoint:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A placeholder will be created for the market data to be imported into SF system. Could be custom fields in EC or through compensation lookup tables (preferred for non-EC system)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a section on the worksheet which populates the min-mid-max of market pay for the pay grade/country which helps the planner to compare current pay versus market pay for the employee and make compensation recommendations accordingly&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the prospective market data provider (external vendor) can connect SF system, using their end point URL we can build a custom integration where the data is extracted automatically though a scheduled job and stored in custom MDF in Employee Central.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Companies are always reinventing and so do our clients, hence&amp;nbsp;organizations to remain competitive in the talent market always go the extra mile to persuade. We shall support them in implementing such cost effective solutions and realize true value of their SAP investments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+SuccessFactors+Compensation/pd-p/73555000100800000771" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="159-1"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Compensation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+SuccessFactors+Employee+Central/pd-p/73555000100800000773" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="160-1"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/leveraging-sap-successfactors-compensation-for-salary-benchmarking/ba-p/14153700"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:24:39.677000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/digital-signature-in-sap-qm-result-recording/bc-p/14172208#M71809</id>
    <title>Re: Digital Signature in SAP QM Result Recording</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:27:23.128000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>msamiullah68</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/878655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5565"&gt;@swapson&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;2nd&amp;nbsp;What is the purpose of maintaining SSF and entering an email address in the Communication section? The document only shows how to maintain it but does not explain its purpose. If we maintain an email address here, will the system automatically send emails? I have maintained my email and selected the SSF method, but no email was sent.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/digital-signature-in-sap-qm-result-recording/bc-p/14172208#M71809"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:27:23.128000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/prt-details-not-coming-from-erp-to-dm/qaa-p/14172211#M83211</id>
    <title>Re: PRT details not coming from ERP to DM</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:27:57.875000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>antoniomasseretti</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/821859</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/175657"&gt;@ManoelCosta&lt;/a&gt; in our scenario we have correctly download the PRT for order specific routing but can't find a way to download them in MASTER ROUTING. Have you any way to do it ?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/prt-details-not-coming-from-erp-to-dm/qaa-p/14172211#M83211"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:27:57.875000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/trial-accounts-retirement-of-sap-intelligent-rpa-end-of-january-2023-and/bc-p/14172215#M183464</id>
    <title>Re: Trial Accounts: Retirement of SAP Intelligent RPA end of January 2023 and the move forward</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:28:33.325000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Beeple</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1703917</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The link to a video how to create a free tier account is dead, as it leads to a &lt;STRONG&gt;blocked page (private video)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. So where is a working instruction?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/trial-accounts-retirement-of-sap-intelligent-rpa-end-of-january-2023-and/bc-p/14172215#M183464"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:28:33.325000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/form-processing-s-4hana-public-cloud/qaq-p/14172235</id>
    <title>Form processing - S/4HANA Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:30:14.923000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sonja_Trapp</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1970764</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am currently working on form processing with Adobe Livecycle Designer in conjunction with SAP Fiori in the public cloud.&lt;BR /&gt;Unfortunately, I am having problems with the data connection and am not sure how exactly it works.&lt;BR /&gt;Perhaps some of you have already had experience with this or can provide me with links to instructions or tips?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/form-processing-s-4hana-public-cloud/qaq-p/14172235"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:30:14.923000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-configuring-flexible-workflow-item-to-return-to-workflow-initatior/qaq-p/14172248</id>
    <title>Error: configuring Flexible Workflow item to return to workflow initatior when rejected, Public Clou</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:32:45.998000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TS01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1628811</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to implement different Flexible Workflow scenarios for procurement in SAP Public Cloud.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While creating a workflow for purchasing contract, I ran accross an error message. I wanted to create a scenario in which the workflow item (in this case Purchasing Contract) is sent back to the creater (/workflow initiator) in case it has been rejected by the approver. When I try to activate the workflow, the following message appears:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="TS01_0-1754375145036.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296393i2965061FFCB257DB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="TS01_0-1754375145036.png" alt="TS01_0-1754375145036.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In detail it says:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"An error occurred while activating the workflow. The operation has been canceled. Cause: Agent rule '/RULE/WF_INITIATOR' for step 'ReworkCTR' is not defined in scenario&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;{
	"message": "HTTP request failed",
	"statusCode": "400",
	"statusText": "Bad Request",
	"headers": {
		"Content-Type": "application/json;charset=utf-8",
		"Content-Length": "1083",
		"DataServiceVersion": "1.0"
	},
	"responseText": "{\"error\":{\"code\":\"SWF_FLEX_DEF/042\",\"message\":{\"lang\":\"en\",\"value\":\"Agent rule '/RULE/WF_INITIATOR' for step 'ReworkCTR' is not defined in scenario\"},\"innererror\":{\"application\":{\"component_id\":\"BC-BMT-WFM-DEF\",\"service_namespace\":\"/SAP/\",\"service_id\":\"SWF_FLEX_DEF_SRV\",\"service_version\":\"0001\"},\"transactionid\":\"AFCDEB7C2BF44DEDB294560DBFFDDB7A\",\"timestamp\":\"20250805063009.9170550\",\"Error_Resolution\":{\"SAP_Transaction\":\"For backend administrators: use ADT feed reader \\\"SAP Gateway Error Log\\\" or run transaction /IWFND/ERROR_LOG on SAP Gateway hub system and search for entries with the timestamp above for more details\",\"SAP_Note\":\"See SAP Note 1797736 for error analysis (https://service.sap.com/sap/support/notes/1797736)\",\"Batch_SAP_Note\":\"See SAP Note 1869434 for details about working with $batch (https://service.sap.com/sap/support/notes/1869434)\"},\"errordetails\":[{\"ContentID\":\"\",\"code\":\"SWF_FLEX_DEF/042\",\"message\":\"Agent rule '/RULE/WF_INITIATOR' for step 'ReworkCTR' is not defined in scenario\",\"propertyref\":\"\",\"severity\":\"error\",\"transition\":false,\"target\":\"\"}]}}}"
}&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have found a SAP note to a similar issue:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3597159/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3597159 - Error raises when activating workflow content in Manage Workflows for Group Journal Entries app. - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;However, the linked resolution (&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Note 3372372)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;seems to be only applicable for private cloud, as the needed transaction cannot be found via the launchpad and I'm not entirely sure it would even resolve my issue specifically.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can anyone help?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to hearing your responses, thank you in advance!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-configuring-flexible-workflow-item-to-return-to-workflow-initatior/qaq-p/14172248"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:32:45.998000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/modules-drag-and-relate-menu-dislocated/qaa-p/14172259#M4221897</id>
    <title>Re: Modules Drag and Relate Menu Dislocated</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:38:19.589000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>williamwachholz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1957665</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do you want to rearrange the "Modules" tab to the top? I think you cannot reorder these tabs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/modules-drag-and-relate-menu-dislocated/qaa-p/14172259#M4221897"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:38:19.589000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-reverse-ers-related-goods-receipt-documents/qaa-p/14172262#M4221898</id>
    <title>Re: How to reverse ERS related goods receipt documents</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:38:42.840000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Couple of ways are there to reverse ERS document&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;ERS invoices must be reversed by reversing the GR, not by canceling the invoice directly. Use the Post Goods Movement app or transaction MIGO. Select Movement Type 102 (Reversal of GR), Reference the original GR document, Ensure the quantity matches exactly. If you get M7021 Deficit PU IR Quantity, it means the invoice quantity has already been settled and the system blocks reversal.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;To allow GR reversal even after invoice creation, you need to adjust customizing SPRO → Materials Management → Inventory Management → Goods Receipt → Set “Reversal of GR Despite Invoice” for Movement Type 102. This setting allows reversal of GR even if an ERS invoice exists. Check &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Note 497178&lt;/STRONG&gt; explains this configuration.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Once the GR is successfully reversed, the ERS job will automatically create a cancellation invoice for the reversed GR. You do not need to manually reverse the invoice in MR8M.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-reverse-ers-related-goods-receipt-documents/qaa-p/14172262#M4221898"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:38:42.840000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-dynamic-value-help-cds-views-for-domain-value/qaa-p/14172264#M4921988</id>
    <title>Re: How to create dynamic value help cds views for domain...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:38:55.533000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rb</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9848</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As you tought you can create a CDS view for the values:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Get domain fix values'
@ObjectModel.resultSet.sizeCategory: #XS
@ObjectModel.dataCategory: #TEXT
define view entity ZIDomainFixValues 
  as select from    dd07l as FixedValue
    left outer join dd07t as ValueText on  FixedValue.domname    = ValueText.domname
                                       and FixedValue.domvalue_l = ValueText.domvalue_l
                                       and FixedValue.as4local   = ValueText.as4local

{
@UI.lineItem: [
  {
    importance: #LOW,
    value: 'DomainName',
    type: #STANDARD,
    position: 100,
    cssDefault.width: '1px'
  }
]
 @Consumption.valueHelpDefault.display:false 
key FixedValue.domname as DomainName,
@UI.hidden: true
key FixedValue.valpos as Valpos,
@UI.hidden: true
@Semantics.language: true
key  ValueText.ddlanguage as Language,
@UI.lineItem: [
  {
    importance: #HIGH,
    value: 'DomvalueL',
    type: #STANDARD,
    position: 20
  }
]
@Consumption.valueHelpDefault.display:true 
 FixedValue.domvalue_l as DomvalueL,

@UI.lineItem: [
  {
    importance: #HIGH,
    value: 'DomvalueH',
    type: #STANDARD,
    position: 30
  }
]
 FixedValue.domvalue_h as DomvalueH,
 .hidden: true
 FixedValue.appval as Appval,
@UI.lineItem: [
  {
    importance: #HIGH,
    value: 'DomeValueText',
    type: #STANDARD,
    position: 50
  }
]
@Consumption.valueHelpDefault.display:true 
@Semantics.text: true
 ValueText.ddtext as DomeValueText
}

where
      FixedValue.as4local  = 'A' --Active
  and ValueText.ddlanguage = $session.system_language
  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;and then use it in other CDS views:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  @Consumption.valueHelpDefinition: [{
  entity: {name: 'ZIDomainFixValues' , element: 'DomvalueL' },

  additionalBinding: [{ element: 'DomainName',
                           localConstant: 'ZSD_OUT_NP_FUNCTION', usage: #FILTER }],
                           distinctValues: true
                           }]
  &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1692417"&gt;@search&lt;/a&gt;.defaultSearchElement
  Function;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-create-dynamic-value-help-cds-views-for-domain-value/qaa-p/14172264#M4921988"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:38:55.533000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/bas-connection-to-on-premises-system-failing-with-request-failed-with/qaq-p/14172268</id>
    <title>BAS Connection to On-Premises System Failing with 'Request failed with status code 503'</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:40:38.495000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>s_sudhirkumar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/368509</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm getting a &lt;STRONG&gt;The server returned an error. Request failed with status code 503&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt; when trying to connect to an &lt;STRONG&gt;on-premise system&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system is connected successfully in &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Destination is valid&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and connection works in &lt;STRONG&gt;Build Apps , Business Automation Process&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;BAS is the only place it's failing.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_ALL access&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and all required services are accessible as confirmed by&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;BASIS &amp;amp; SECURITY&lt;/STRONG&gt; Team.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Did I miss any configuration on the on-premise system or in BAS?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Also, is there a way to debug or trace this kind of issue from the BAS or backend side?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="s_sudhirkumar_0-1754396668446.png" style="width: 585px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296632i4768889027E65FFD/image-dimensions/585x281/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="585" height="281" role="button" title="s_sudhirkumar_0-1754396668446.png" alt="s_sudhirkumar_0-1754396668446.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/bas-connection-to-on-premises-system-failing-with-request-failed-with/qaq-p/14172268"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:40:38.495000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/need-help-converting-functional-specification-to-cds-views-in-sap-s-4hana/qaq-p/14172277</id>
    <title>Need Help Converting Functional Specification to CDS Views in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:43:34.269000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pavankumar1127</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1616345</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’ve prepared a Functional Specification Document (FSD) based on a requirement in SAP S/4HANA &lt;STRONG&gt;Private Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and I’ve shared it with our ABAPer. However, the ABAP team is requesting the same FSD in terms of &lt;STRONG&gt;CDS Views&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but I’m not experienced with CDS Views in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Public Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you all know, CDS development and extensibility differ between &lt;STRONG&gt;Private Cloud (on-premise-like)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Public Cloud (restricted, key-user-based)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, so I’m a bit confused on how to approach this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am attaching/sharing my FSD here – kindly go through it and help me understand:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can this requirement be fulfilled via standard released CDS views?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If not, how to approach building a custom CDS view in Public Cloud?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any step-by-step guidance or sample CDS logic would be highly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to suggestions and help from the community!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavankumar1127_0-1754397249562.png" style="width: 467px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296680i55EC93D68025A3AF/image-dimensions/467x350/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="467" height="350" role="button" title="pavankumar1127_0-1754397249562.png" alt="pavankumar1127_0-1754397249562.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavankumar1127_1-1754397278699.png" style="width: 457px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296681iB699F7C11FE46EE2/image-dimensions/457x335/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="457" height="335" role="button" title="pavankumar1127_1-1754397278699.png" alt="pavankumar1127_1-1754397278699.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="pavankumar1127_2-1754397309213.png" style="width: 461px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296682i82C036751FB2B4ED/image-dimensions/461x316/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="461" height="316" role="button" title="pavankumar1127_2-1754397309213.png" alt="pavankumar1127_2-1754397309213.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2108029"&gt;@pavanKolla&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3763"&gt;@PriyankaChak&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance,&lt;BR /&gt;Pavan Kumar&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/need-help-converting-functional-specification-to-cds-views-in-sap-s-4hana/qaq-p/14172277"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:43:34.269000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/trigger-a-warning-message-in-va02-in-s-4-hana-public-cloud/qaq-p/14172281</id>
    <title>trigger a warning message in VA02 in s/4 hana public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:45:56.284000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>habeeb_unissa</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1420976</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In S/4 Hana Public Cloud, user wants to trigger a warning message in VA02(Change of sales Order) whenever Price list type is changed . I got a BADI , but in that Price list type is not available&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="habeeb_unissa_0-1754397813215.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296701i5C591F1DBE1E6374/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="habeeb_unissa_0-1754397813215.png" alt="habeeb_unissa_0-1754397813215.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="habeeb_unissa_1-1754397866463.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296704iB55BDB22CE8EE0FB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="habeeb_unissa_1-1754397866463.png" alt="habeeb_unissa_1-1754397866463.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks &amp;amp; Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Habeeb Unissa&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/trigger-a-warning-message-in-va02-in-s-4-hana-public-cloud/qaq-p/14172281"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:45:56.284000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/static-factory-action-for-child-nodes-no-access-to-parent-key/qaa-p/14172284#M4921990</id>
    <title>Re: Static factory action for child nodes - no access to...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:47:42.943000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cmartin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1739014</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi, did you find any solution?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/static-factory-action-for-child-nodes-no-access-to-parent-key/qaa-p/14172284#M4921990"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:47:42.943000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/solved-an-error-occurred-while-installing-sap-s-4hana-2023-fps03-fully/qaa-p/14172286#M4921991</id>
    <title>Re: 【solved 】An error occurred while installing SAP S/4HA...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:50:07.761000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>i806184</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143795</uri>
    </author>
    <content>How did you solve the problem. I am facing similar issue</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/solved-an-error-occurred-while-installing-sap-s-4hana-2023-fps03-fully/qaa-p/14172286#M4921991"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:50:07.761000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-calculate-depreciation-for-multiple-capitalizations-across-years-in/qaq-p/14172287</id>
    <title>How to calculate depreciation for multiple capitalizations across years in SAC?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:51:45.766000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nasser_itani</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/795238</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm working on a &lt;STRONG&gt;CAPEX planning model in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and doing&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;depreciation logic&lt;/STRONG&gt; where &lt;STRONG&gt;multiple capitalizations happen in different years&lt;/STRONG&gt;, each with their own timeline, but they all &lt;STRONG&gt;sum up into the fixed asset value&lt;/STRONG&gt; and depreciate based on their own start date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I don’t have a dedicated "capitalization year" field, only the date dimension (e.g., FY, period). I’m looking to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Accumulate the &lt;STRONG&gt;Fixed Asset value&lt;/STRONG&gt; based on the total capitalized until that year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Calculate &lt;STRONG&gt;depreciation per year&lt;/STRONG&gt; for each capitalized amount based on the &lt;STRONG&gt;useful life&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., straight-line method).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure that the depreciation logic &lt;STRONG&gt;respects the start year&lt;/STRONG&gt; of each capitalized amount and stops after its life ends.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Below is the code I am having and results attached in screenshot. Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;FOREACH.BOOKED [d/DIM_WBS_PROJECT]&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;//get the total budget&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@TOTALBUDGET = RESULTLOOKUP([d/Measures] = "Amount", [d/Account] = "CAPEX_003", [d/Date] = PERIOD([d/DIM_WBS_PROJECT].[p/BUDGETEDYEAR]))&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;//get the previous year spending&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@PYSPENDING = RESULTLOOKUP([d/Measures] = "Amount", [d/Account] = "CAPEX_012", [d/Date] = "2022")&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;//calculate remaining budget&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@REMAININGBUDGET = ROUND(@TOTALBUDGET - @PYSPENDING, 3)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;//calculate the annual depreciation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@ANNUALDEPR = ROUND(@REMAININGBUDGET / @USEFULLIFE, 2)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@ENERGIZEDYEAR = ATTRIBUTE([d/DIM_WBS_PROJECT].[p/ENERGIZEDYEAR])&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@YEAR_COUNT = 0&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1726201"&gt;@count&lt;/a&gt; = INT(@USEFULLIFE)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FOREACH [d/Date]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;//get the energized year&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;//DATA([d/Account] = #ENERGYEAR_VAL, [d/DIM_AUDIT] = "#", [d/DIM_BUDGETYEAR] = "#", [d/DIM_FLOW] = "#", [d/DIM_SCENARIO] = "#", [d/Measures] = "Amount") = ATTRIBUTE([d/DIM_WBS_PROJECT].[p/ENERGIZEDYEAR])&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;// Read year of this Date member&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2081647"&gt;@Number&lt;/a&gt; = @ENERGIZEDYEAR - @BUDEGTYEAR + 1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@CURRYEAR = YEAR([d/Date])&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;IF @CURRYEAR &amp;lt;= @ENERGIZEDYEAR AND @REMAININGBUDGET &amp;gt; 0 THEN&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;//BOOK the annual spending&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DATA([d/Account] = "CAPEX_001") = ROUND(@REMAININGBUDGET / &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2081647"&gt;@Number&lt;/a&gt;, 6)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;//BOOK CWIP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DATA([d/Account] = "CAPEX_012") = RESULTLOOKUP([d/Account] = "CAPEX_012",[d/Date]=PREVIOUS(1)) + RESULTLOOKUP([d/Account] = "CAPEX_001")&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;//Fixed Assets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DATA([d/Account] = "CAPEX_007") = RESULTLOOKUP([d/Account] = "CAPEX_007",[d/Date]=PREVIOUS(1))+RESULTLOOKUP([d/Account] = "CAPEX_002")&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;//CWIP Final&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DATA( [d/Account] = "CAPEX_013") = RESULTLOOKUP( [d/Account] = "CAPEX_013",[d/Date]=PREVIOUS(1))+ RESULTLOOKUP([d/Account] = "CAPEX_001")-RESULTLOOKUP( [d/Account] = "CAPEX_002")&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ENDIF&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@CAPITALIZED = RESULTLOOKUP([d/Account] = "CAPEX_002")&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FOR &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1834271"&gt;@start&lt;/a&gt;_COUNT = 1 TO &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1726201"&gt;@count&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DATA([d/Account] = "CAPEX_004",[d/Date] = NEXT(@START_COUNT)) = RESULTLOOKUP([d/Account] = "CAPEX_007") /@USEFULLIFE&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ENDFOR&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nasser_itani_0-1754398041832.png" style="width: 693px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296705i840C9E9763AC3BA0/image-dimensions/693x151/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="693" height="151" role="button" title="nasser_itani_0-1754398041832.png" alt="nasser_itani_0-1754398041832.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-calculate-depreciation-for-multiple-capitalizations-across-years-in/qaq-p/14172287"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:51:45.766000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-automate-multi-action-execution-via-rest-api-server-side-without/qaq-p/14172288</id>
    <title>How to Automate Multi Action Execution via REST API (Server-Side) without User Interaction?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:52:38.509000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>noseUD</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1528897</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a question regarding the automation of processes using the SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) REST API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What I want to achieve:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to call the SAC REST API from a server-side application (e.g., Python, Node.js) to execute a specific Multi Action in a fully automated manner. The target API endpoint is: /api/v1/multiActions/{multiActionId}/execute&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current Situation and Challenges:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To handle authentication for the API call, I have created an OAuth 2.0 client from the SAC administration menu (System &amp;gt; Administration).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My first attempt was to create a client with the "Interactive Usage" purpose. However, based on the documentation, I understand that this purpose requires a redirect URI for user authentication and consent. This approach seems designed for scenarios where a web application acts on behalf of a user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This has led to the following challenge:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because user interaction (logging in and clicking the consent screen in a browser) is required, it is difficult to create a completely automated, server-to-server batch process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Questions:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is there a recommended solution for calling the Multi Action execution API from a server-side application as a batch process, without any user interaction?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;I also tried creating an OAuth client with the "API Access" purpose, but I could not get it to work. If this is the correct approach, could you please provide guidance on the proper configuration or point out potential reasons for failure (e.g., missing permissions)?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alternatively, is there a fundamental misunderstanding in my approach to automating SAC API calls?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have managed to successfully obtain an OAuth token using the "API Access" purpose. However, when I use this token to call the API in my execute_multi_action method, the request fails with a&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt; 500 Internal Server Error.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is the sample Python code that demonstrates the issue. The &lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;get_oauth_token and&amp;nbsp;get_csrf_token&lt;/FONT&gt; function works correctly, but the &lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;execute_multi_action&lt;/FONT&gt; function receives the 500 error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import requests
import json

# Constants for authentication and API endpoints (masked for security)
TOKEN_URL = "https://&amp;lt;MASKED&amp;gt;.authentication.&amp;lt;MASKED&amp;gt;.ondemand.com/oauth/token"
SAC_BASE = "https://&amp;lt;MASKED&amp;gt;.analytics.cloud.sap"
CLIENT_ID = '&amp;lt;MASKED_CLIENT_ID&amp;gt;'
CLIENT_SECRET = '&amp;lt;MASKED_CLIENT_SECRET&amp;gt;'
MULTI_ACTION_ID = '&amp;lt;MASKED_MULTI_ACTION_ID&amp;gt;'

def get_bearer_token():
    """
    Obtain OAuth2 bearer token using client credentials grant.
    """
    resp = requests.post(
        TOKEN_URL,
        auth=(CLIENT_ID, CLIENT_SECRET),
        data={'grant_type': 'client_credentials'}
    )
    resp.raise_for_status()  # Raise an error for HTTP error codes
    return resp.json()['access_token']

def get_csrf_token(session, bearer_token):
    """
    Retrieve CSRF token required for subsequent API requests.
    """
    url = f"{SAC_BASE}/api/v1/csrf"
    headers = {
        'x-csrf-token': 'fetch',                # Request to fetch CSRF token
        'x-sap-sac-custom-auth': 'true',
        'Authorization': f"Bearer {bearer_token}",
    }
    # Send GET request to retrieve CSRF token
    resp = session.get(url, headers=headers)
    resp.raise_for_status()
    csrf_token = resp.headers.get('x-csrf-token')
    print(f"CSRF Token: {csrf_token}")
    return csrf_token

def execute_multi_action(session, bearer_token, csrf_token):
    """
    Execute a multi-action via SAC API with required parameters.
    """
    url = f"{SAC_BASE}/api/v1/multiActions/{MULTI_ACTION_ID}/executions"
    headers = {
        'x-csrf-token': csrf_token,
        'Content-Type': 'application/json',
        'x-sap-sac-custom-auth': 'true',
        'Authorization': f"Bearer {bearer_token}",
    }
    payload = {
        "parameterValues": [
            {
                "parameterId": "TargetVersion",
                "value": {
                    "memberIds": ["public.Plan_TEST"],
                    "hierarchyId": None
                }
            },
            {
                "parameterId": "SourceVersion",
                "value": {
                    "memberIds": ["public.Actual"],
                    "hierarchyId": None
                }
            }
        ]
    }
    # Send POST request to execute the multi-action
    resp = session.post(url, headers=headers, data=json.dumps(payload))
    resp.raise_for_status()
    return resp.json()["executionId"]

def get_execution_result(session, execution_id):
    """
    Retrieve the result or status of the executed multi-action.
    """
    url = f"{SAC_BASE}/api/v1/multiActions/{MULTI_ACTION_ID}/executions/{execution_id}"
    # Send GET request to get execution result
    resp = session.get(url)
    resp.raise_for_status()
    return resp.json()

def main():
    # Step 1: Obtain bearer token for authentication
    bearer_token = get_bearer_token()
    with requests.Session() as session:
        # Step 2: Get CSRF token for secure API requests
        csrf_token = get_csrf_token(session, bearer_token)
        print("Current cookies in session:")
        for cookie in session.cookies:
            print(f"{cookie.name} = {cookie.value}")

        # Prepare cookie string for use in headers (if needed)
        cookie_string = "; ".join([f"{c.name}={c.value}" for c in session.cookies])
        print("Cookie string for headers:")
        print(cookie_string)

        # Step 3: Execute the multi-action and get its execution ID
        execution_id = execute_multi_action(session, bearer_token, csrf_token)
        # Step 4: Retrieve and print the execution result
        result = get_execution_result(session, execution_id)
        print(json.dumps(result, indent=2, ensure_ascii=False))

if __name__ == "__main__":
    main()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your time and assistance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-automate-multi-action-execution-via-rest-api-server-side-without/qaq-p/14172288"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:52:38.509000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-generate-purchase-order-output-on-change-of-a-purchase-order/bc-p/14172290#M61368</id>
    <title>Re: How to generate purchase order output on change of a purchase order?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:53:28.556000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jrosenhauer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44324</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;when I enter the entry like mentioned in step iv and change the quantity after generating the output nothing happens. Do I need an additional step in OPD as well?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And very funny that there is no table and no field values for the mentioned "table" in onPrem. So the question from above is very relevant. Where to get that information from?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-generate-purchase-order-output-on-change-of-a-purchase-order/bc-p/14172290#M61368"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:53:28.556000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/change-si-unit/qaa-p/14172292#M205976</id>
    <title>Re: Change SI Unit</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:54:59.647000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MariusSiegel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132208</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/883894"&gt;@khan_786&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;no you can't change the SI Unit during creation but you can copy an existing dimension together with the assigned SI Unit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;best regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/change-si-unit/qaa-p/14172292#M205976"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:54:59.647000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-there-any-way-to-trigger-the-data-update-in-tables-s021-s022-s023-on/qaa-p/14172294#M4221900</id>
    <title>Re: Is there any way to trigger the data update in tables...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:58:19.374000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaghavanKathamuthu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17050</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Its not updating in realtime. Is it possible to update in real time</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-there-any-way-to-trigger-the-data-update-in-tables-s021-s022-s023-on/qaa-p/14172294#M4221900"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:58:19.374000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/defining-key-figures-at-different-planning-levels/qaa-p/14172295#M205977</id>
    <title>Re: defining key figures at different planning levels</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:59:17.183000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1899640"&gt;@Mritunjay_Deo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on the information you provided, you can view the Sales History key figure (currently at WK-PRD-LOC-CUST level) at the WK-PRD-LOC-LOCFR level, I suggest take first, define a new key figure at WK-PRD-LOC-LOCFR, then reference Sales History in the key figure expression, after that, apply disaggregation using a driver for example “location” and finally ensure proper planning levels and master data relationships exist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this helps provide clarity for your customer. I am happy to help if you have further questions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you find my response helpful, kindly accept the answer and award a Kudos to this post. Your support is appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/defining-key-figures-at-different-planning-levels/qaa-p/14172295#M205977"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:59:17.183000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/trigger-a-warning-message-in-va02-in-s-4-hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14172296#M4221901</id>
    <title>Re: trigger a warning message in VA02 in s/4 hana public...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T14:59:26.458000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If the Price List Type is not exposed in the BAdI you're using then, go to the Custom Fields and Logic app., check if Price List Type can be added as an extension field to the relevant business context (e.g., Sales Document Header or Item). If available, you can then use it in your custom logic.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Some BAdIs are tied to specific business contexts. For VA02, try these:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Sales Document Change (Header)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Sales Document Change (Item)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;These contexts may expose more fields than the BAdI you initially found.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/trigger-a-warning-message-in-va02-in-s-4-hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14172296#M4221901"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T14:59:26.458000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-replication-flow-delta-functionality/bc-p/14172298#M174784</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Datasphere - Replication Flow (Delta Functionality)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:00:59.810000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnuragPakhidde</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1611438</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;HI&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2128390"&gt;@RAviraj3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;BR /&gt;If you have following annotations on your CDS view that you created on S4 systems, the system will use automatic delta capture using CDC once you create replication flow in SAP Datasphere with "initial and delta" settings for the CDS view.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@Analytics.dataExtraction.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;enabled:true&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@Analytics.dataExtraction.delta.changeDataCapture.automatic:&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;true&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that you need all SAP DI related TCI Notes implemented on your S4 system to support this. Also, if you have a very complex logic in your CDS views the CDC automatic delta will not work. Hope this helps!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-replication-flow-delta-functionality/bc-p/14172298#M174784"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:00:59.810000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/comparison-scripting/qaq-p/14172301</id>
    <title>comparison scripting</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:03:12.838000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>saikiransripathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2036607</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;#created 10versions and taken 2dropdowns in table .imported 10 versions in both dropdowns,&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Created filter between them.----this is done&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;but i should only see variance on the report When I next change version from drop down. it should reflect the changes in the table.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;I have done until here but i want to see only one column that&amp;nbsp; shows comparison between versions.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="photo_6093789167269040355_w (1).jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296708iC4C1C1568F2A908F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="photo_6093789167269040355_w (1).jpg" alt="photo_6093789167269040355_w (1).jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/comparison-scripting/qaq-p/14172301"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:03:12.838000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/effective-way-of-doing-an-update-with-inner-join-in-abap/qaa-p/14172300#M4921994</id>
    <title>Re: Effective way of doing an UPDATE with INNER JOIN in ABAP?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:03:14.433000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vincent8</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/726328</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Yes sorry I forgot to mention I have ABAP 7.50</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/effective-way-of-doing-an-update-with-inner-join-in-abap/qaa-p/14172300#M4921994"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:03:14.433000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-replication-flow-delta-functionality/bc-p/14172302#M174785</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Datasphere - Replication Flow (Delta Functionality)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:03:41.882000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnuragPakhidde</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1611438</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/880828"&gt;@Lokesh_Kumar_Pothapola&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Is automatic CDC delta supported also for SAP BW systems, if we would like to extract certain HCPRs using SAP Datasphere's Replication Flow?&lt;BR /&gt;Idea is to create a CDS view using external HANA view of the HCPR and then extract it using replication flows in SAP Datasphere.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-replication-flow-delta-functionality/bc-p/14172302#M174785"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:03:41.882000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-unable-to-deactivate-quot-create/qaa-p/14172305#M4921996</id>
    <title>Re: In SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public edition unable to deactiv...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:05:45.127000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2142819"&gt;@Rohit0909&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the detailed update.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You've confirmed that:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Create Inbound Delivery app is included only in catalog SAP_LE_BC_ID_PROC_MC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The catalog supports IAM-based app control&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You’ve removed and reassigned roles to trigger a refresh&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, the app is still visible, which typically means the catalog is still indirectly assigned through another role.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommended Next Steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review all assigned roles for the user IAM permissions are cumulative. The app may still be exposed via another role containing the same catalog.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Refresh IAM Authorizations&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; action in the Maintain Business Roles app to re-sync backend assignments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clear cache or use Incognito Mode to eliminate tile caching issues.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the issue persists, raise an SAP incident under CA-IAM-ABA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-unable-to-deactivate-quot-create/qaa-p/14172305#M4921996"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:05:45.127000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-there-any-way-to-trigger-the-data-update-in-tables-s021-s022-s023-on/qaa-p/14172306#M4221902</id>
    <title>Re: Is there any way to trigger the data update in tables...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:06:18.335000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Even with correct settings, if it is not working as expected, it could be due to:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Update program not triggered immediately&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Missing update rules or routines&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Background job dependencies&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In such cases, consider running program RMCBNEUA to force update, checking update rules in MC24, verifying update groups in MC26&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-there-any-way-to-trigger-the-data-update-in-tables-s021-s022-s023-on/qaa-p/14172306#M4221902"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:06:18.335000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-bw-odp-delta-via-replication-flow/bc-p/14172307#M174786</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Datasphere - BW ODP Delta via Replication Flow</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:06:28.995000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnuragPakhidde</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1611438</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/275733"&gt;@Martin_Kuma&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks for sharing really cool insights in terms of Replication Flow capabilities for SAP BW systems.&lt;BR /&gt;Question - Is it possible to use "Pass-Through" option of replication flows in case of SAP BW to directly extract the data to Azure Data Lake instead of local DSP tables?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-bw-odp-delta-via-replication-flow/bc-p/14172307#M174786"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:06:28.995000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/quot-check-in-as-new-version-not-possible-quot-error-in-manage-change/qaa-p/14172308#M83212</id>
    <title>Re: "Check In as New Version Not Possible" Error in Manag...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:07:14.329000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mbrewer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1505530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Chuma,&lt;BR /&gt;Appreciate the response. As instructed by the note, I have tried to complete the same action via the Manage Documents app and I receive the same error.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mbrewer_0-1754399897941.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296721iF7470D531622C52F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="mbrewer_0-1754399897941.png" alt="mbrewer_0-1754399897941.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mbrewer_2-1754399428328.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296717i4D230CA6D678447E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="mbrewer_2-1754399428328.png" alt="mbrewer_2-1754399428328.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mbrewer_3-1754399444798.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296718iB4652F87B838894A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="mbrewer_3-1754399444798.png" alt="mbrewer_3-1754399444798.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you saying that the only way to create a new version is to select the "Create New Version" button here in the Manage Documents list? The goal is that we'd be able to check out the document from the "Manage Change Records" app, make changes, then upload the new document as a new version.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mbrewer_4-1754399708573.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296719iE815C9D2999A7C80/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="mbrewer_4-1754399708573.png" alt="mbrewer_4-1754399708573.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/quot-check-in-as-new-version-not-possible-quot-error-in-manage-change/qaa-p/14172308#M83212"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:07:14.329000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/not-able-to-fetch-routing-args-in-onroutematched-from-semantic-object-and/qaq-p/14172310</id>
    <title>Not able to fetch routing args in onRouteMatched() from semantic object and navigation from Workzone</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:08:41.506000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madhav15</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140075</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Greeting Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to develop UI5 app where First page routing parameter will come from SAP Build Work zone, standard edition application navigation parameters. But when I am defining route patterns in manifest.json file for first page It is showing blank on output screen. Here is code for manifest.json.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt; "routes": [
        {
          "name": "RouteDashboard",
          "pattern": "Employee/{role}",
          "target": [
            "TargetDashboard"
          ]
        }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; In workzone, standard edition I am giving navigation parameters like this.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="madhav15_0-1754399026076.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296712i564F075F253574A1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="madhav15_0-1754399026076.png" alt="madhav15_0-1754399026076.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dashboard controller:-&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="madhav15_1-1754399064116.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296713i98DAE6C962BF1960/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="madhav15_1-1754399064116.png" alt="madhav15_1-1754399064116.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can anybody help me on this, while passing parameter in manifest file I am not able to see anything and if I remove this I can see the output of app but can't fetch argument from onRouteMatched in this case. Any help would be appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/not-able-to-fetch-routing-args-in-onroutematched-from-semantic-object-and/qaq-p/14172310"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:08:41.506000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fb60-duplicate-invoices-are-not-checked-anymore/qaq-p/14172311</id>
    <title>FB60 Duplicate invoices are not checked anymore</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:08:49.746000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>medkhaled</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/624175</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my system S4, FB60 Duplicate invoices are not checked anymore. before the check was working fine.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now I checked, if the fields relevants for this check have been updated or changer, but it seems that there no way to change them, it's the standard behavior of SAP :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the Reference Document Number field (BKPF-XBLNR) is filled up the following fields will be checked to idnetify duplicate invoices:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Company Code(BUKRS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Vendor(LIFNR)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Currency(WAERS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Invoice/Document Date(BLDAT)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reference document number(XBLNR)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the Reference Document Number field (BKPF-XBLNR) is not filled up the following fields will be checked to idnetify duplicate invoices:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Company Code(BUKRS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Vendor(LIFNR)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Currency(WAERS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Invoice/Document Date(BLDAT)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Amount in document currency(WRBTR)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you please confirm this ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, what other points can I check ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;May be make a debug with a developer to make to check if there is a specific ABAP that bypass this check ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your help&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fb60-duplicate-invoices-are-not-checked-anymore/qaq-p/14172311"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:08:49.746000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/webinar-brazilian-tax-reform-with-sap/ec-p/14172315#M141</id>
    <title>Re: 🇧🇷 Webinar: Brazilian Tax Reform with SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:10:32.138000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>WilsonMantovani</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1682515</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Olá!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Não consigo me conectar e parece que o Webinar já está acontecendo. Podem me enviar um novo link, por favor?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Obrigado!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wilson J. Mantovani&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/webinar-brazilian-tax-reform-with-sap/ec-p/14172315#M141"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:10:32.138000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-community-escape-house-for-august-fiori-element-with-flexible/bc-p/14172317#M50191</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community Escape House for August - Fiori Element with Flexible Programming Model</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:11:13.566000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aakash_06</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2104719</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Successfully &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":party_popper:"&gt;🎉&lt;/span&gt;escaped from the &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Fiori/pd-p/73554900100700000977" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="18-1"&gt;SAP Fiori&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;room, I enjoyed the entire Developer challenge. Thank you&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163102"&gt;@AmarUbhe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for this particular escape room challenge. I got an opportunity to learn SAP&amp;nbsp;Fiori Element with Flexible Programming Model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Aakash_06_0-1754399274884.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296714iAD2737DCE8755DC5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Aakash_06_0-1754399274884.png" alt="Aakash_06_0-1754399274884.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-community-escape-house-for-august-fiori-element-with-flexible/bc-p/14172317#M50191"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:11:13.566000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-community-escape-house-for-august-fiori-element-with-flexible/bc-p/14172319#M50192</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community Escape House for August - Fiori Element with Flexible Programming Model</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:11:49.709000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruthiel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/120859</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you very much for this challenge &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163102"&gt;@AmarUbhe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;!!&lt;BR /&gt;I am feeling much more confident with FPM now!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The best challenge this year!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAPUI5/pd-p/500983881501772639608291559920477" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="325-1"&gt;SAPUI5&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-community-escape-house-for-august-fiori-element-with-flexible/bc-p/14172319#M50192"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:11:49.709000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-configuring-flexible-workflow-item-to-return-to-workflow-initatior/qaa-p/14172320#M4221904</id>
    <title>Re: Error: configuring Flexible Workflow item to return to workflow initatior when rejected, Public</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:12:12.432000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MariusSiegel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132208</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Could you please provide more information on the details of the workflow you want to create?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-configuring-flexible-workflow-item-to-return-to-workflow-initatior/qaa-p/14172320#M4221904"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:12:12.432000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/webinar-brazilian-tax-reform-with-sap/ec-p/14172321#M142</id>
    <title>Re: 🇧🇷 Webinar: Brazilian Tax Reform with SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:12:15.449000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GFVConsulting24</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1922608</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Parece que o evento de hoje foi cancelado&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/webinar-brazilian-tax-reform-with-sap/ec-p/14172321#M142"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:12:15.449000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/source-of-data-for-settlement-doc-pricing/qaa-p/14172322#M4221905</id>
    <title>Re: Source of data for Settlement Doc Pricing</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:12:33.795000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichaelWerner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/519</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1474620"&gt;@Dforway1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition to what&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348"&gt;@Lakshmipathi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/155910"&gt;@GauthierVictor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;wrote.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/settlement-management-transfer-manager-and-split-criteria-for-settlement/ba-p/13522028" target="_blank"&gt;Settlement Management – Transfer Manager and Split... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;provides some insight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"&lt;SPAN&gt;reference doc (Sales Order) and reference item as split criteria&lt;/SPAN&gt;" could result in a large number of items within a settlement document. Therefore I recommend the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test the worst case scenario (Largest number of items) early. Some years ago we tested settlement documents with about 200000 items. It worked. But every solution is different. The only way to find out if performance and usability are sufficient is testing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid the derivation of fields from the reference document / item.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Michael&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/source-of-data-for-settlement-doc-pricing/qaa-p/14172322#M4221905"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:12:33.795000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/form-processing-s-4hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14172324#M4221906</id>
    <title>Re: Form processing - S/4HANA Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:15:16.436000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Check this&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/adobe-form-development-in-rise-with-sap-public-cloud-2208/ba-p/13539970?form=MG0AV3" target="_blank"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39712"&gt;@BijeshRB98&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Also check this&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/forms-service-by-adobe/sap-forms-service-neo/using-adobe-livecycle-designer?form=MG0AV3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/form-processing-s-4hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14172324#M4221906"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:15:16.436000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/badi-to-pick-user-name-from-the-user-id-in-count-list-output-form/qaq-p/14172325</id>
    <title>BADI to pick user name from the user ID in COUNT_LIST output form</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:15:21.628000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruwani_Abeysinghe1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1540749</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have a requirement to display the username in the PI count output format rather than the username which is given in the standard form. We have created a custom field, assigned it to the custom layout and tried using the BADI-&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;INV10_LIST_OF_STOCKS_FORM_I. However, we are unable to get the username.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please advise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ruwani&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/badi-to-pick-user-name-from-the-user-id-in-count-list-output-form/qaq-p/14172325"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:15:21.628000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-community-escape-house-for-august-fiori-element-with-flexible/bc-p/14172327#M50193</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community Escape House for August - Fiori Element with Flexible Programming Model</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:15:36.901000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GauravPhadnis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2095063</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163102"&gt;@AmarUbhe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; for exciting challenge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GauravPhadnis_0-1754399729047.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296720i800EA40CAA5398B0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="GauravPhadnis_0-1754399729047.png" alt="GauravPhadnis_0-1754399729047.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-community-escape-house-for-august-fiori-element-with-flexible/bc-p/14172327#M50193"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:15:36.901000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ind-percent-value-is-resetting-to-default-value-in-variable-pay/qaq-p/14172328</id>
    <title>IND Percent value is resetting to default value in Variable Pay</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:16:43.755000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>satnaik18</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/137299</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am facing one issue where Ind Percent field value is resetting default value after manager is changing the value. I have checked the permission in design worksheet, Configure label names &amp;amp; Visibility &amp;amp; in Guideline. All three editable permission is given.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you please provide your inputs how to resolve the issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879"&gt;@xavierlegarrec&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721"&gt;@DavidSomelofske&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Satish Naik&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ind-percent-value-is-resetting-to-default-value-in-variable-pay/qaq-p/14172328"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:16:43.755000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/multiattachment-field-on-offer-approval-details/qaq-p/14172331</id>
    <title>Multiattachment field on Offer Approval Details</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:21:22.278000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FabioFerreira91</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/117845</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Team,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We would like to add a multiattachment field to the Offer Approval Template as custom field, however after checking some KBAs I have some doubts:&lt;BR /&gt;- From this KBA I can see that multiattachment is possible, also multiattachmentselection: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-recruiting/setting-up-and-maintaining-sap-successfactors-recruiting/supported-field-types-for-offer-approvals?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supported Field Types for Offer Approvals | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;, however no information regarding which custom field type should I choose.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Is this something you can help with?&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks a lot,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/multiattachment-field-on-offer-approval-details/qaq-p/14172331"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:21:22.278000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-see-list-data-when-i-run-the-app/qaa-p/14172332#M4921998</id>
    <title>Re: Unable to see list data when I run the app</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:22:21.565000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ankita_Mundhra</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2120777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Chuma,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My query is already being run in the Integrations tab where I am calling Salesforce and fetching the data. Data is being successfully fetched there.&lt;BR /&gt;Similar to what I did for the single query.&lt;BR /&gt;I am then creating a data variable of collection of records and then trying to display the data variable here.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Should I again call the query in the page logic?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Ankita Mundhra&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-see-list-data-when-i-run-the-app/qaa-p/14172332#M4921998"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:22:21.565000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ind-percent-value-is-resetting-to-default-value-in-variable-pay/qaa-p/14172333#M45482</id>
    <title>Re: IND Percent value is resetting to default value in Variable Pay</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:22:42.145000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DavidSomelofske</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I need more information, screenshots, etc. There is no way anyone could help you without context.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ind-percent-value-is-resetting-to-default-value-in-variable-pay/qaa-p/14172333#M45482"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:22:42.145000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/webinar-brazilian-tax-reform-with-sap/ec-p/14172334#M143</id>
    <title>Re: 🇧🇷 Webinar: Brazilian Tax Reform with SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:25:46.527000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>andressajulioNA</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2166964</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13377"&gt;@RosanaErnzen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;wrote:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join us for an exclusive session exploring the impact of Brazil’s tax reform on SAP solutions. Discover the latest digital deliverables for logistics, gain insights into upcoming plans for industry, finance, and tax calculation solutions, and learn more about Split Payment and Assisted Tax Determination. The session will conclude with a live Q&amp;amp;A with SAP experts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_sNzaVfdDSbicZB-9mzOvzA#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: The session will be delivered in Brazilian Portuguese.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Bom dia!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Evento cancelado:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SAP Webinar&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Panorama das Entregas Digitais&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;para a Reforma Tributária e Planos Futuros&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Link inscrição:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_sNzaVfdDSbicZB-9mzOvzA" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_sNzaVfdDSbicZB-9mzOvzA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Event canceled, we will inform you soon of a new date.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/webinar-brazilian-tax-reform-with-sap/ec-p/14172334#M143"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:25:46.527000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/issue-related-to-stock-becoming-negative-during-goods-movements/qaa-p/14172335#M4221907</id>
    <title>Re: Issue related to stock becoming negative during goods...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:26:09.602000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Not sure what exactly your issue as you have not shared any screen shot. But in general, ensure your S-user ID has the correct authorizations to create incidents. You're using the SAP for Me portal: SAP Support Portal. If you're blocked at submission try using a different browser or clearing cache. Use the “Report an Incident” tile from SAP Launchpad.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If the portal still fails call SAP Support directly via your regional support center. Use the SAP ONE Support Launchpad to raise the issue with the portal itself&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/issue-related-to-stock-becoming-negative-during-goods-movements/qaa-p/14172335#M4221907"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:26:09.602000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/temse-management-getting-error-in-background-job/qaa-p/14172337#M4921999</id>
    <title>Re: TEMSE management - Getting error in Background Job</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:29:06.498000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S_Sriram</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/816</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Shah, Is it possible to check the number of spools in your system? and are you getting any Spool I/O error dumps in the transaction code ST22?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/temse-management-getting-error-in-background-job/qaa-p/14172337#M4921999"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:29:06.498000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-vc-hide-multiple-characteristics-invisible/qaa-p/14172338#M4221908</id>
    <title>Re: SAP VC - Hide multiple characteristics (invisible)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:29:48.228000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Clemens_Schmid</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1472297</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Man you made my day, TX!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-vc-hide-multiple-characteristics-invisible/qaa-p/14172338#M4221908"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:29:48.228000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/portugal-reversal-documents-vs-credit-notes-key-differences-explained/bc-p/14172340#M183466</id>
    <title>Re: Portugal Reversal Documents vs. Credit Notes: Key Differences Explained</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:30:31.709000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>syedfairoz49</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/816029</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you, Elsa. This is a really helpful topic.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/portugal-reversal-documents-vs-credit-notes-key-differences-explained/bc-p/14172340#M183466"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:30:31.709000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-ckeditor-content-sanitization-and-formatting-issues-in-sap/ba-p/14170594</id>
    <title>Handling CKEditor Content Sanitization and Formatting Issues in SAP Commerce SmartEdit</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:31:42.265000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>priti_mittal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/471799</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1994990471"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Background&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Commerce SmartEdit uses &lt;STRONG&gt;CKEditor for editing CMSParagraphComponent content. CKEditor includes &lt;STRONG&gt;sanitization logic that strips or modifies HTML tags it considers unsafe. If HTML is not well-formatted during in imported impex file&amp;nbsp; , SmartEdit may:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remove content completely.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alter the layout unintentionally.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Break visual rendering inside the editing UI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1798476966"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Common Issues Observed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Special tags like &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;style&amp;gt;, or &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; disappear when editing a paragraph component.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;HTML imported via impex with malformed tags (e.g., missing closing tags, extra &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; or &amp;amp;nbsp;) leads to distortion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Changes made in SmartEdit on top of malformed HTML worsen the structure and cause further rendering issues.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1601963461"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CKEditor Sanitization Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Commerce allows limited control over this behavior using the following property:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;cms.components.allowUnsafeJavaScript=&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;true&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enabling this property allows SmartEdit to preserve certain script or inline JavaScript blocks, but &lt;STRONG&gt;this alone is not enough. If the underlying HTML is inconsistent or dirty, CKEditor still might misinterpret it.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1405449956"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution – Groovy Script to Clean and Beautify HTML&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;If a significant amount of CMSParagraphComponent content has already been maintained in a higher environment via Impex imports, issues may arise when a business user opens and edits that content through the SmartEdit editor. In such cases, saving the changes can distort the view of the content. This often happens because the imported HTML may contain formatting issues, such as unnecessary line breaks or improperly structured tags.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To address this, one option is to manually clean up the HTML formatting in each Impex file. However, a more efficient solution is to use the Groovy script provided below. This script exports all CMSParagraphComponent content from the higher environment, cleans up the HTML formatting, and prepares a clean Impex file that can be re-imported into the target catalog. Once the Impex is imported and the sync process is completed, the display issues in SmartEdit should be resolved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1079853732"&gt;Groovy Script :&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import de.hybris.platform.core.Registry
import de.hybris.platform.catalog.CatalogVersionService
import de.hybris.platform.cms2.model.contents.components.CMSParagraphComponentModel
import de.hybris.platform.servicelayer.model.ModelService
import de.hybris.platform.servicelayer.search.FlexibleSearchService

// Initialize required services
def modelService = spring.getBean("modelService", ModelService)
def searchService = spring.getBean("flexibleSearchService", FlexibleSearchService)
def catalogVersionService = spring.getBean("catalogVersionService", CatalogVersionService)
def commonI18NService = spring.getBean("commonI18NService")

// Define language and catalog context
def languageIso = "en" // Replace with desired language ISO
def catalogId = "abcContentCatalog" // Replace with your catalog ID
def catalogVersion = "Staged" // Replace with your catalog version

// Set the current language
def lang = commonI18NService.getLanguage(languageIso)
commonI18NService.setCurrentLanguage(lang)

// Get catalog version model
def catalogVersionModel = catalogVersionService.getCatalogVersion(catalogId, catalogVersion)

// Query CMSParagraphComponent items
def query = """
    SELECT {pk} FROM {CMSParagraphComponent}
    WHERE {catalogVersion} = ?catalogVersion
"""
def params = ["catalogVersion": catalogVersionModel]
def result = searchService.search(query, params)

// Print Impex header
println "INSERT_UPDATE CMSParagraphComponent;uid[unique=true];catalogVersion(catalog(id),version)[unique=true];content[lang=${languageIso}]"

// Process each component and beautify content
result.result.each { CMSParagraphComponentModel component -&amp;gt;
    def content = component.getContent()
    if (content != null) {
        def beautifiedContent = beautifyHtml(content)
        println ";${component.uid};${catalogId}:${catalogVersion};\"${beautifiedContent}\""
    }
}

// HTML Beautification Helper
def beautifyHtml(String html) {
    if (!html) return ""

    // Step 1: Normalize tag breaks
    html = html.replaceAll("&amp;gt;&amp;lt;", "&amp;gt;\n&amp;lt;")

    // Step 2: Remove leading spaces on each line
    html = html.replaceAll("(?m)^\\s+", "")

    // Step 3: Clean up attributes inside tags
    html = html.replaceAll(/&amp;lt;([^&amp;gt;]+)&amp;gt;/) { full, inner -&amp;gt;
        def cleaned = inner.replaceAll(/[\n\r]+/, " ") // Remove newlines
                           .replaceAll(/\s+/, " ")     // Collapse extra spaces
                           .trim()
        return "&amp;lt;${cleaned}&amp;gt;"
    }

    // Step 4: Normalize inner text between tags
    html = html.replaceAll(/&amp;gt;([^&amp;lt;]+)&amp;lt;/) { full, inner -&amp;gt;
        def cleaned = inner.replaceAll(/[\n\r]+/, " ")
                           .replaceAll(/\s+/, " ")
                           .trim()
        return "&amp;gt;" + cleaned + "&amp;lt;"
    }

    // Step 5: Re-indent HTML
    def indent = 0
    def lines = html.split("\n")
    def indented = lines.collect { line -&amp;gt;
        if (line =~ /^&amp;lt;\/.+&amp;gt;/) indent--
        def result = "  " * Math.max(indent, 0) + line.trim()
        if (line =~ /^&amp;lt;[^\/!][^&amp;gt;]*[^\/]&amp;gt;$/ &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !(line =~ /&amp;lt;.*&amp;lt;\/.*&amp;gt;/)) indent++
        return result
    }

    // Step 6: Escape double quotes for Impex
    return indented.join("\n").replaceAll('"', '""')
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-883340227"&gt;What the Script Does:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cleans malformed HTML tags and unnecessary line breaks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fixes spacing and re-indents the content for improved readability and structure&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Escapes double quotes to ensure compatibility with Impex format&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-815909441"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sample Output:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s a sample output generated by the script in Impex format:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;INSERT_UPDATE CMSParagraphComponent;uid[unique=true];catalogVersion(catalog(id),version)[unique=true];content[lang=en]
;AboutUsPageParagraphComponent;abcContentCatalog:Staged;"&amp;lt;div class=""container""&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div class=""row small-health-container""&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div class=""main__text-container header-text mt-10""&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3 class=""title mb-20""&amp;gt;Wherever you are on your health journey!&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=""description""&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;Dis-Chem goes beyond being just a pharmacy and retail store;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;we deliver healthcare in various ways, extending our services, products, and initiatives to encompass community clinics, feeding programs the Dis-Chem Foundation, and health insurance products. With the momentum of initiatives like these driving Dis-Chem forward, we hope to lead a movement in South Africa, becoming the champions of better health for all. This shift in perspective allows us to see the bigger picture and take a more holistic view of health and wellness in today’s world. It aligns with the growth of our offerings, which we have developed and implemented over the years.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=""description mt-20""&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;Continuing to prioritize the bigger picture and adopting a holistic view of health and wellness will undoubtedly have a positive impact on our customers and the communities we serve. We are inspired by the opportunity to make a difference in people’s lives beyond the traditional role of a pharmacy and retail store.&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;hr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-619395936"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;CKEditor’s sanitization, while important for security, can interfere with business HTML requirements if the input content is malformed. Combining SmartEdit configuration (cms.components.allowUnsafeJavaScript=true) with Groovy-based content cleanup ensures your CMS content is resilient, editable, and production-ready.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-ckeditor-content-sanitization-and-formatting-issues-in-sap/ba-p/14170594"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:31:42.265000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/key-user-custom-fields-maximum-number-of-fields-and-characters/bc-p/14172348#M183467</id>
    <title>Re: Key User Custom Fields: Maximum number of fields and characters</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:34:04.650000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MarcusP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1420720</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thx to Georg and team for the very helpful information!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/key-user-custom-fields-maximum-number-of-fields-and-characters/bc-p/14172348#M183467"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:34:04.650000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/modules-drag-and-relate-menu-dislocated/qaa-p/14172351#M4221909</id>
    <title>Re: Modules Drag and Relate Menu Dislocated</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:35:10.869000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe_Lima</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83237"&gt;@kedalenechong&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assuming you have enabled the Cockpit, this will be your main menu layout while such a function is active. You can return to the standard shape, at the cost of not having the Cockpit feature available though.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I hope it helps.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;BR,&lt;BR /&gt;Felipe&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/modules-drag-and-relate-menu-dislocated/qaa-p/14172351#M4221909"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:35:10.869000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/non-nettable-warehouse-inventory-calculated-in-atp/qaa-p/14172353#M205979</id>
    <title>Re: Non-Nettable Warehouse Inventory Calculated in ATP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:35:34.034000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;ATP in SAP ECC/S4HANA by default ignores the “nettable” indicator on warehouses and sums all unrestricted stock at plant level. MRP runs honor the nettable flag, but classic ATP doesn’t. In SPRO (or the equivalent SSCUI in S/4HANA Cloud) under Sales and Distribution &amp;gt; Basic Functions &amp;gt; Availability Check you can create/modify your Scope of Check, assign it to your Checking Rule/Checking Group, tick “No storage location inspection”. This tells the ATP engine to ignore storage-location stock entirely and only consider slocs entered on the sales order. Limitation: if no sloc is entered on the order, ATP still returns total plant stock (including sloc 04).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If you prefer a purely configuration-only approach, then, define an MRP Area type 02 for storage location 04. Assign sloc 04 to that MRP Area. In your ATP scope, restrict checks to all MRP Areas except the one for sloc 04. This isolates non-nettable stock but adds overhead on master-data maintenance and MRP runs.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The below comparison table will give a better idea&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Lakshmipathi_0-1754400888924.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296730iC59806066375FE58/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Lakshmipathi_0-1754400888924.png" alt="Lakshmipathi_0-1754400888924.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/non-nettable-warehouse-inventory-calculated-in-atp/qaa-p/14172353#M205979"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:35:34.034000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/quot-check-in-as-new-version-not-possible-quot-error-in-manage-change/qaa-p/14172358#M83213</id>
    <title>Re: "Check In as New Version Not Possible" Error in Manag...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:40:32.809000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1505530"&gt;@mbrewer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the update and screenshots.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, uploading a new version is only supported via &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create New Version&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;in the Manage Documents app. The Manage Change Records app doesn’t allow versioning due to status and version control rules.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I thought you mentioned you’re working on release S4 Private cloud 2023? Just checking, as the behavior should be consistent, but version-specific fixes may apply.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/quot-check-in-as-new-version-not-possible-quot-error-in-manage-change/qaa-p/14172358#M83213"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:40:32.809000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-activate-the-alert-management-and-job-automation-monitoring-in-sap/qaq-p/14172359</id>
    <title>How to Activate the Alert Management and Job &amp; Automation Monitoring in SAP Cloud ALM?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:40:43.365000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to we change the settings in the "Supported Use Cases" section of a system entry in the SAP Cloud ALM Landscape Management app? The "Job &amp;amp; Automation Monitoring" entry has configuration status "Inactive", and the "Alert Management" has status "Not Configured". How do we enable these settings?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-activate-the-alert-management-and-job-automation-monitoring-in-sap/qaq-p/14172359"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:40:43.365000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-activate-the-alert-management-and-job-automation-monitoring-in-sap/qaa-p/14172360#M4922001</id>
    <title>Re: How to Activate the Alert Management and Job &amp; Automa...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:40:51.064000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If a system in the SAP Cloud ALM Landscape Management app has Configuration Status value "Inactive", it means that data collection was enabled at one point, but has been disabled and the SAP Cloud ALM backend still has collected data for that system. If you wish to move the status to "Active", you simply must enable data collection again for that system. More information can be found in KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3616000" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3616000&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The "Alerting Management" statuses are dependent on the settings in the SAP Cloud ALM for Operations use cases. In order for "Alert Management" to show Active statuses, at least 1 Operations use case must have an event that generates alerts for the specified system. If no alerting has been enabled for a system, the use case "Alerting Management" will continue to show status "Not Configured". You spoke about Job &amp;amp; Automation Monitoring, so you can follow KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3111904" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3111904&lt;/A&gt; to help configure Alerting for that use case.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-activate-the-alert-management-and-job-automation-monitoring-in-sap/qaa-p/14172360#M4922001"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:40:51.064000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/recife-discussions/devtoberfest-29-de-setembro-a-24-de-outubro/td-p/14172363</id>
    <title>Devtoberfest - 29 de setembro a 24 de outubro</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:42:42.671000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marssel700</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11741</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Olá,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Desenvolvedores, marquem na agenda!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;O Devtoberfest 2025 acontece de 29 de setembro a 24 de outubro. Uma experiência imperdível!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thumbnail_Devtoberfest 2025.png" style="width: 250px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296732iC2E789DED0E4F7AD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="thumbnail_Devtoberfest 2025.png" alt="thumbnail_Devtoberfest 2025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prepare-se para mergulhar em trilhas como ABAP | Ferramentas &amp;amp; Frontend | Integração | Dados &amp;amp; IA | CAP, além de conteúdos divertidos e prêmios incríveis para os vencedores.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Não fique de fora!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fiquem à vontade para participar e também para compartilhar em suas redes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Links úteis abaixo:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-welcome/ba-p/9358" target="_self"&gt;O concurso 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/gh-p/Devtoberfest" target="_self"&gt;Participe do grupo Devtoberfest&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/katherinekenneally_devtoberfest-sapteched-activity-7358428751925313537-2HtR?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;amp;rcm=ACoAAA3FNtUBKdH0zYsQASFwVjb5SrQM6-ngqjY" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Post no LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Abraço a todos&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/recife-discussions/devtoberfest-29-de-setembro-a-24-de-outubro/td-p/14172363"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:42:42.671000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-error-error-server-error-no-json-root-element-in-response/qaa-p/14172364#M4922002</id>
    <title>Re: SAC error Error: Server Error No json root element in response...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:43:13.901000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cardoso</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/248387</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Alex,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-error-error-server-error-no-json-root-element-in-response/qaa-p/14172364#M4922002"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:43:13.901000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sending-of-order-and-invoice-output-to-multiple-email-ids-maintained-in/qaa-p/14172366#M4221910</id>
    <title>Re: Sending of Order and Invoice output to multiple email Ids maintained in customer in Public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:43:40.944000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>luizapereira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1394837</uri>
    </author>
    <content>We helped you to accept the answer since there were no updates after 7 days. You can unaccept it anytime if you have further questions.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sending-of-order-and-invoice-output-to-multiple-email-ids-maintained-in/qaa-p/14172366#M4221910"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:43:40.944000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
