<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-11-12T07:59:01.184192+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-npp-sap-capabilities-for-faster-smarter-payments/ba-p/14266032</id>
    <title>Unlocking the NPP: SAP Capabilities for Faster, Smarter Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T03:57:00.839000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>michael_davies</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7744</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The payments landscape is rapidly changing and in Australia the New Payments Platform ("NPP") is providing new infrastructure and capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our customers want to understand more about what the NPP offers and how SAP is enabling the adoption of the new innovations, as well as the implications for data and payment processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This Blog series is the result of close collaboration between SAP and the Australian Payments Plus team, who are responsible for the NPP. It is a combined effort with the SAP ANZ localization team, notably my colleague&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131740"&gt;@Bino_Philip&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;who has done much of the heavy lifting in defining the SAP response. Any errors are mine alone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is an evolving topic and whilst we’ll try to keep it current, please ensure you check the latest SAP documentation. Also bear in mind that until we publish a Development Roadmap, any comments on plans, intentions or other forward looking statements are personal views and not the official SAP position.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The series is planned as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unlocking the NPP: SAP Capabilities for Faster, Smarter Payments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unlocking the NPP: Payments overview&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unlocking the NPP: PayID&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unlocking the NPP: PayTo&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764704416"&gt;When will SAP be NPP ready?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the number one question we get on this topic, with a mass of confusion on the changes required for NPP and opportunities it presents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The simple answer is that SAP is already NPP capable with many customers benefiting from real time payments and the additional capabilities available now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, to understand the full picture of what is available in SAP across the range of NPP capabilities, how we are delivering innovation and plans for the future, please read on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568190911"&gt;So what is the NPP?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The New Payments Platform is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Infrastructure which enables real time payments across Australia&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Additional capabilities to improve security and simplify payments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Operated by Australian Payments Plus, whose members include the largest Banks, payment processors and businesses in Australia&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The eventual replacement for the Bulk Electronic Clearing System (“BECS”) overseen by the Reserve Bank of Australia which will be decommissioned by June 2030&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is a mass of additional information at &lt;A href="https://www.auspayplus.com.au/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.auspayplus.com.au/&lt;/A&gt;, including technical documentation and file mapping guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The NPP is particularly relevant for payments where Payer and Payee use different Banks and the funds need to be transferred between them, for example from a Westpac account to an NAB account. The current BECS cross bank clearing is a periodic batch process on business days only whereas NPP is a real-time process available 24/7.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The NPP is already available and is being widely used for personal banking. NPP is the technology behind the Osko brand which enables real time payments using the PayID function, removing the need to share Bank details (BSB and Account number).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that NPP is currently only relevant to payments within Australia where the Sending and Receiving Banks and other Financial Institutions are connected to the NPP. They can connect directly as an “NPP Participants” which requires them to meet strict criteria and is largely limited to major Financial Institutions. Other entities who wish to provide NPP services (“Identified Institutions”) cannot connect directly and must have an agreement with a sponsoring NPP Participant. Where the Payer and Payee use the same Bank, the additional capabilities of NPP such as PayID, PayTo (see below) are still relevant, even though clearing of payments is handled within the Bank.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371677406"&gt;Architecture&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Individuals and Corporates will continue to transact though their Bank which for simplicity we will assume is connected directly to the NPP as a “Participant”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="michael_davies_0-1762849582451.png" style="width: 617px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338464iEBAB0D18357064F8/image-dimensions/617x182/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="617" height="182" role="button" title="michael_davies_0-1762849582451.png" alt="michael_davies_0-1762849582451.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The role of SAP does not change: it will create the payment instructions, receive status updates and bank statements and enable the Bank integration. Additional message types such as for intraday bank statements and APIs may also be relevant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We do not currently envisage any requirement for SAP systems to connect directly to the NPP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175163901"&gt;NPP capabilities&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The NPP is not just a change in technology or a new platform. It is designed and built to deliver significant business benefits and opportunities to innovate new business models. By sending payments using the NPP, SAP customers can start to leverage these current capabilities and investigate the benefits and opportunities they provide:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Real time payment clearing. This means that funds reach the payee in seconds not hours or days, improving cash flow. This has benefits in scenarios such as Public Sector benefits payments where recipients may have an urgent need, for example Bush fire related Disaster Recovery Payments. Similarly real time payments and their related status messages enable immediate execution of follow-on processes such as order credit unblock, sales order processing or delivery release with confidence that the funds have transferred.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Real time payment status messages. This means errors can be corrected faster and more payments reach the Payee on time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;24/7 operations, 365 days a year. This provides additional flexibility in payment processing, from processing urgent payments to making payments precisely on the due date, even where this falls on a public holiday. It also assists with meeting compliance obligations, especially around payroll and superannuation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PayID enables payments to be made using the Payee’s email, phone number, ABN or other identifier, without requiring their BSB and Bank Account details&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PayTo agreements provide a greater degree of control and transparency for Direct Debit arrangements. The agreement or mandate is stored within the NPP and the Payer can approve, vary, end and define conditions (such as maximum amounts). The Payee needs to quote the agreement number rather than the BSB and Bank Account in the Direct Debit payment file.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confirmation of Payee. This service reduces fraud by checking the name on the Bank Account with the name of the intended Payee recipient.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978650396"&gt;NPP payment files&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will go into more detail in the next Blog on the requirements around making a payment using NPP. The main point to be aware of is that whilst the NPP has specific requirements for payment file format and field mapping, the Bank determines what is required from SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each Bank will provide documentation on:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Payment file format - this is usually based on ISO20022 standard&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;NPP relevant fields, i.e. what is required to ensure processing by NPP rather than BECS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the file is created with the required format and fields, it can be sent to the Bank for processing using standard integration. We’ll discuss integration impacts and the challenge for SAP to&amp;nbsp;create a standard NPP compliant solution in the next Blog.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782136891"&gt;SAP Approach for NPP&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whilst the official SAP Roadmap is still being developed internally, our general approach can be understood as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP solutions will be developed and delivered incrementally over future years, rather than as a single release.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP solutions will be based around a single common standard, such as the ISO standard format and not numerous variations such as for Bank specific formats.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP will focus on solutions for S/4HANA Cloud, both Public and Private Editions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-npp-sap-capabilities-for-faster-smarter-payments/ba-p/14266032"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T03:57:00.839000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/requirement-date-of-components-in-production-order-related-to-different/qaa-p/14266062#M4231221</id>
    <title>Re: Requirement date of components in production order re...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T04:02:06.565000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kota_Miyakita1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1979488</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Hakan, thanks for your comment. current we face the issue that componnet requirement date is not calculated based on assigned operation 0200, but based on planned order start date(even included setup time). however in process order, it works fine. Issue only happen in planned order.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/requirement-date-of-components-in-production-order-related-to-different/qaa-p/14266062#M4231221"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T04:02:06.565000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/transparent-table-comparison/ba-p/14266075</id>
    <title>Transparent Table Comparison</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T04:19:47.452000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>abhyarthana</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/731998</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635621824"&gt;Table Comparison in DTV 1.7&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the newest release of the Data Transition Validation tool, DTV 1.7, transparent tables can now be validated. The tool has been enhanced to support the validation of both standard and custom transparent tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This recent feature expands the tool's validation capabilities, enabling it to support validation for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Reports and transactions (70+)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Custom reports of ALV output type&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Custom namespace reports of ALV output type&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Standard and custom transparent tables&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog will demonstrate how you can utilize this new feature to compare transparent tables and view the validation results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439108319"&gt;Table comparison&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on “Define Test Specification” of the DTV project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339000i60D73F5B21CFD892/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS1.png" alt="SS1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And then click on “Table”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339001iD200CE0A33D93641/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS2.png" alt="SS2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on Insert Row&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS3.1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339002i7213B64D8AF90ED9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS3.1.png" alt="SS3.1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide the table information as below&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transparent table name&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Description&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Functional Area&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Functional Group&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can add multiple tables here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS3.2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339004iF5B3D2F9392E5573/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS3.2.png" alt="SS3.2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can use the Variant if you have any, and/or also provide split and condition parameter as per the requirement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS5.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339006iE7918BF081213808/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS5.png" alt="SS5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can then perform &lt;STRONG&gt;Simulation &lt;/STRONG&gt;(Not mandatory) and extract the result in the source system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS6.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339007i1CFB95D4CD42463C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS6.png" alt="SS6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once source extraction is done, similar process can be followed to extract the data in the target system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS7.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339008i55EBBF6FBB7F257B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS7.png" alt="SS7.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Use “Import Simulation Results” functionality to reuse the extraction result in “Data Extraction” step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS8.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339009i1BF93CBE2B16954F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS8.png" alt="SS8.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once extraction is complete for both source and target systems, Data Evaluation can be triggered by selecting the tables and clicking on &lt;STRONG&gt;“Run Selected”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS9.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339010iB637D5267E82A769/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS9.png" alt="SS9.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can then check the evaluation result in the result tab.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS10.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339011i045F0D4FF20CD1CC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS10.png" alt="SS10.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the addition of the table comparison feature, the scope of DTV validation has significantly broadened, making it more valuable in transition scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/transparent-table-comparison/ba-p/14266075"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T04:19:47.452000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-re-fx-reversal-process-of-asset-retirement/qaq-p/14266089</id>
    <title>SAP RE-FX Reversal process of Asset Retirement</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T04:31:29.301000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lainec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1970285</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dear Gurus,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please assist me on the reversal of an ROU asset retirement from a terminated contract.&lt;BR /&gt;Our scenario is as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. The IFRS16 lease contract was created and given notice June 30, 2025&lt;BR /&gt;2. Time slice was created for valuation (termination date +1 day) and proceeded with generation of cashflow as follows:&lt;BR /&gt;asset adjustment, depreciation and all postings ended as of June 29, 2025.&lt;BR /&gt;3. Receep has been posted Aug 2025 wherein Leasing retirement also posted.&lt;BR /&gt;Note that asset has not been deactivated.&lt;BR /&gt;4. Come November 2025, we need to reverse the asset retirement since termination did not pushed through and we have to continue the contract.&lt;BR /&gt;5. We now performed RECEEPRV to reverse valuation postings. However we are now encountering an error:&lt;BR /&gt;Errors occurred for asset XXXX XXXXXXXXXX in fiscal year 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have tried removing the given notice and reversing the RECEEP but we still encountered the same error when reversing the receep postings in November 2025.&lt;BR /&gt;We cannot reverse in the same period used in posting asset retirement as FI posting period is already closed for Aug 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How do we reverse the asset retirement from SAP RE-FX after the lease termination has been cancelled?&lt;BR /&gt;What is the process for this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Lained33&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-re-fx-reversal-process-of-asset-retirement/qaq-p/14266089"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T04:31:29.301000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/predicting-cycling-performance-sap-rpt-1-vs-ai-chat-models-and-strava/bc-p/14266114#M176307</id>
    <title>Re: Predicting Cycling Performance: SAP RPT-1 vs AI Chat Models and Strava</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T04:50:37.943000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>zfiori</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1829</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;"&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The comparison highlights clear patterns:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strava&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;remains the most accurate overall, with minimal deviation in both time and speed. Its specialized algorithm and access to large datasets give it a strong advantage.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;stands out as a powerful alternative. It delivered deterministic predictions, handled structured data effectively, and achieved results very close to reality. This shows its potential for numeric forecasting beyond sports—think production planning or predictive maintenance.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gemini&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;produced fast responses and understood units correctly, but its speed prediction was less precise.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Copilot&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;struggled with numeric interpretation. Copilot showed inconsistent outputs, while ChatGPT had the largest error in time prediction, likely due to misunderstanding units."&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your selfless sharing, it really help us a lot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ZFiori.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/predicting-cycling-performance-sap-rpt-1-vs-ai-chat-models-and-strava/bc-p/14266114#M176307"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T04:50:37.943000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/navigating-the-sap-learning-help-center-your-gateway-to-seamless-learning/bc-p/14266115#M579</id>
    <title>Re: Navigating the SAP Learning Help Center: Your Gateway to Seamless Learning Support!</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T04:57:52.713000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pradeeprajan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/115285</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Amazing and well explained Sandeep.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/navigating-the-sap-learning-help-center-your-gateway-to-seamless-learning/bc-p/14266115#M579"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T04:57:52.713000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-to-track-a-freight-order-in-gtt-without-using-dock-scheduling-and/qaq-p/14266116</id>
    <title>How to track a freight order in GTT without using dock scheduling and gatehouse operations?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:00:48.266000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sidbansal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265082</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can we track a Freight order in GTT without having a licence plate entered either in dock scheduling or at gate house operations?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Context: We are thinking of turning off LBN dock appointments/gatehouse operations app but still would continue to use GTT, therefore need to understand if there are any impacts?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-to-track-a-freight-order-in-gtt-without-using-dock-scheduling-and/qaq-p/14266116"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:00:48.266000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-customize-push-notification-payload-to-send-additional-data-from-s4/qaq-p/14266117</id>
    <title>How to customize push notification payload to send additional data from S4 to SSAM</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:03:16.846000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>daniyal_dolare</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1426435</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Currently in the standard push notification feature for SAP Service and Asset Manager, only the object key of particular object like Notification number for Notification and Order Id for Work Order is sent to mobile device in push notification payload. Sample payload:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;{"notification":{"alert":"{\"title-loc-key\":\"NOTIF_TITLE_KEY\",\"title-loc-args\": [\"1000000000\"],\"loc-key\":\"NOTIF_BODY_KEY\",\"loc-args\": [\"1000000000\"]}","data":"{\"ObjectType\":\"Notification\",\"ObjectID\":\"1000000000\"}"}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But we want to show additional details in the push notification message like notification description and technical object description. We found the exact method which generates the payload. Class&amp;nbsp;/MFND/CL_CORE_OTRIG_CPMS_PUSH&amp;nbsp; and method is&amp;nbsp;BUILD_JSON_DATA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But in this method, we are only able to get Object Key (Notification Number) and no other data. Also we are not able to fetch relevant data from table as notification is not yet saved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does anyone knows how can we handle this situation and how to send additional data like Technical object description in this payload. Any BAdI available for this or how to achieve this?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-customize-push-notification-payload-to-send-additional-data-from-s4/qaq-p/14266117"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:03:16.846000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-sap-enterprise-support-day-and-elevate-your-business/bc-p/14266118#M186239</id>
    <title>Re: Join the SAP Enterprise Support Day and Elevate Your Business Transformation!</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:03:58.312000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>viswanathappa</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36014</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The same issue as&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2009552"&gt;@DorotaTuo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;. Unable to Register&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-sap-enterprise-support-day-and-elevate-your-business/bc-p/14266118#M186239"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:03:58.312000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/dear-sap-support-i-want-ask-one-question-how-to-rename-change-log-ctrl/qaq-p/14266121</id>
    <title>Dear SAP Support  I want ask one Question How to Rename Change Log ? Ctrl Double click Can't Rename</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:06:58.991000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nitmanet168</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/869105</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dear SAP&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Support&amp;nbsp; I&lt;/STRONG&gt; want&lt;STRONG&gt; ask one Question How to Rename Change Log ? Ctrl Double click Can't Rename ? i ask again&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nitmanet168_1-1762920282236.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339046iEC6A0D9D594D42D6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nitmanet168_1-1762920282236.png" alt="nitmanet168_1-1762920282236.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/dear-sap-support-i-want-ask-one-question-how-to-rename-change-log-ctrl/qaq-p/14266121"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:06:58.991000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/dynamic-alv-column-creates-default-excel-column-col/m-p/14266122#M195</id>
    <title>Re: Dynamic ALV column creates default excel column col:</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:09:31.449000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jeff_broodwar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/188779</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I tried to debug, found that the excel writer class appends the 'col:' in the beginning of the dynamic column if no fieldcatalog was passed. TO avoid this, fill the field catalog like below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;data(lt_field_catalog) = zcl_excel_common=&amp;gt;get_fieldcatalog( ip_table = &amp;lt;fs_table&amp;gt; ).

"Loop through the catalog, fill scrtext_s,scrtext_m,scrtext_l here.

"Pass when binding table

lo_worksheet-&amp;gt;bind_table(
  EXPORTING
    ip_table         = &amp;lt;fs_table&amp;gt;
    it_field_catalog = lt_field_catalog&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The generated excel should use the text you passed to your field catalog. The class doesn't automatically use the contents of your alv field catalog. Solved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps someone in the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Geoff&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/dynamic-alv-column-creates-default-excel-column-col/m-p/14266122#M195"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:09:31.449000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/dynamic-alv-column-creates-default-excel-column-col/m-p/14266124#M196</id>
    <title>Re: Dynamic ALV column creates default excel column col:</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:11:01.636000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jeff_broodwar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/188779</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks Sandra, it didn't use the ALV field catalog, it should pass a different field catalog defined in the excel writer class. Appreciate your feedback.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/dynamic-alv-column-creates-default-excel-column-col/m-p/14266124#M196"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:11:01.636000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/verify-database-accessing/qaa-p/14266125#M4931448</id>
    <title>Re: Verify database accessing</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:15:58.603000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JamesZ</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163948</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Pitichai,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SSFS meants to store username&amp;amp;password in file system, but 10g should not able to use SSFS.&lt;BR /&gt;And you should able to always connet database like:&lt;BR /&gt;conn /as sysdba&lt;BR /&gt;conn sapsr3/password etc.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;normaly to connet database, and query table, you should able to query table normaly.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;And about encryption, the only encryption is told in SAP note 974876 , but this is not often used.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;So do normal login to your database, and do query the database table, and if there is any error, let us see what kind of error/&lt;BR /&gt;Probably it is permission error, instead of encryption.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;James&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Support&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/verify-database-accessing/qaa-p/14266125#M4931448"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:15:58.603000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/bc-p/14266128#M186240</id>
    <title>Re: BTP Trial Update: CF Runtime Availability</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:30:30.212000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alrdh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2233258</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44516"&gt;@CarolinBoeke&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;BR /&gt;I'm new here and I know this is causing deployment problem in cloud foundry environment, but does it also affect deployment on kyma environment ? Please confirm about this, deployment on kyma environment might be a temporary solution for this. Thank you so much.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Alrdh&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/bc-p/14266128#M186240"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:30:30.212000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/report-related-to-stock-retained-period/qaa-p/14266136#M4231225</id>
    <title>Re: Report related to stock retained period.</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:41:16.542000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yKim</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1486100</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121"&gt;@Chris1973&lt;/a&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks for kind response.&lt;BR /&gt;The only way to realize based on report type is using custom analytical query.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I really appreciate for finding CDS table for handling my issue&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best Regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/report-related-to-stock-retained-period/qaa-p/14266136#M4231225"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:41:16.542000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/va01-va02-va03-overview-screen-enhancement-options/qaa-p/14266137#M4231226</id>
    <title>Re: VA01/VA02/VA03 Overview Screen Enhancement Options</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:41:32.910000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Samar_05</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1424167</uri>
    </author>
    <content>HELPFULL</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/va01-va02-va03-overview-screen-enhancement-options/qaa-p/14266137#M4231226"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:41:32.910000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/swpm-distributed-sap-system-database-instance-gt-no-connection-to-ms-sql/qaa-p/14266138#M4931449</id>
    <title>Re: SWPM - Distributed SAP system - Database Instance --&gt; no connection to MS SQL Server Database</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:41:52.912000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HRaj5</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1539487</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Mamartins,wlourens2,&lt;BR /&gt;I have a requirement where the database host is separate from the host where the NWAS needs to be installed, needing a distributed installation.&lt;BR /&gt;Does SWPM need to be launched in the DB host to install the database instance? Or can it is be done remotely via the host where i am going to install ASCS and PAS, with ODBC connection to the Database on the separate server?&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/swpm-distributed-sap-system-database-instance-gt-no-connection-to-ms-sql/qaa-p/14266138#M4931449"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:41:52.912000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/va01-va02-va03-overview-screen-enhancement-options/qaa-p/14266139#M4231227</id>
    <title>Re: VA01/VA02/VA03 Overview Screen Enhancement Options</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:42:49.227000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Samar_05</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1424167</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BADI NAME - BADI_SLS_HEAD_SCR_CUS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/va01-va02-va03-overview-screen-enhancement-options/qaa-p/14266139#M4231227"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:42:49.227000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-service-amp-asset-manager-2405-work-order-list-screen-search-bar-not/qaq-p/14266142</id>
    <title>SAP Service &amp; Asset Manager 2405 Work Order list Screen Search bar not working as Expected</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:44:02.634000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DivanWellalage</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1441667</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello experts,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We’ve customized the Work Order List screen in our SAP Service and Asset Manager (SSAM) 2405 application for our customer, and we’re facing a search issue.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Here’s what we’ve done:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We modified the WorkOrderObjectCell.fragment for the Work Order list.&lt;BR /&gt;In the fragment, we updated the Subhead property as follows:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;"Subhead": "{{#Property:HeaderFunctionLocation}} - {{#Property:FunctionalLocation/#Property:FuncLocDesc}} - {{#Property:FunctionalLocation/#Property:Address/#Property:Name}}"&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;After this change, the subhead correctly displays the desired values on the UI (as shown in the attached imge.jpg).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;However, when we use the search bar on the Work Order List screen, the search does not return results based on the HeaderFunctionLocation value.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For example, if we search for a value like 23651 (which is visible in the Subhead for one of the work orders), no results are shown.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What could be the issue here?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Is there any limitation or restriction beyond searching on this property?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Divan Wellalage&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-service-amp-asset-manager-2405-work-order-list-screen-search-bar-not/qaq-p/14266142"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:44:02.634000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/swpm-distributed-sap-system-database-instance-gt-no-connection-to-ms-sql/qaa-p/14266143#M4931451</id>
    <title>Re: SWPM - Distributed SAP system - Database Instance --&gt; no connection to MS SQL Server Database</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:44:49.641000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HRaj5</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1539487</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Mamartins,wlourens2, I have a requirement where the database host is separate from the host where the NWAS needs to be installed, needing a distributed installation. Does SWPM need to be launched in the DB host to install the database instance? Or can it is be done remotely via the host where i am going to install ASCS and PAS, with ODBC connection to the Database on the separate server? Thank you in advance!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/swpm-distributed-sap-system-database-instance-gt-no-connection-to-ms-sql/qaa-p/14266143#M4931451"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:44:49.641000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-rap-custom-action-print-pdf/qaa-p/14266146#M4931452</id>
    <title>Re: SAP public cloud RAP Custom action Print pdf</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:49:01.335000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OwenLiu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14130</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121"&gt;@Chris1973&lt;/a&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-rap-custom-action-print-pdf/qaa-p/14266146#M4931452"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:49:01.335000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/down-payments-for-non-trade-supplier-are-not-applicable-in-manage-down/qaa-p/14266147#M4231228</id>
    <title>Re: Down payments for Non-Trade Supplier are not applicable in Manage Down Payment Request Applicati</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:49:59.057000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OwenLiu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14130</uri>
    </author>
    <content>We helped you to accept the answer as solution. You can un-accept it anytime if you have further questions.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/down-payments-for-non-trade-supplier-are-not-applicable-in-manage-down/qaa-p/14266147#M4231228"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:49:59.057000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/distribution-of-avc-objects/qaa-p/14266148#M84534</id>
    <title>Re: Distribution of AVC-objects</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:52:11.247000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OwenLiu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14130</uri>
    </author>
    <content>We helped you to accept the answer as solution. You can un-accept it anytime if you have further questions.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/distribution-of-avc-objects/qaa-p/14266148#M84534"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:52:11.247000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-no-agents-determined-after-execution-of-responsibility-determination/qaa-p/14266149#M4931453</id>
    <title>Re: Error-No agents determined after execution of responsibility determination rule' Flexible Workfl</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:52:35.322000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OwenLiu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14130</uri>
    </author>
    <content>We helped you to accept the answer as solution. You can un-accept it anytime if you have further questions.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-no-agents-determined-after-execution-of-responsibility-determination/qaa-p/14266149#M4931453"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:52:35.322000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/duplicates-in-draft-on-test-tenant-public-cloud/qaa-p/14266150#M4931454</id>
    <title>Re: Duplicates in draft on test tenant - public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:53:19.381000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OwenLiu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14130</uri>
    </author>
    <content>We helped you to accept the answer as solution. You can un-accept it anytime if you have further questions.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/duplicates-in-draft-on-test-tenant-public-cloud/qaa-p/14266150#M4931454"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:53:19.381000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/delta-statistical-depreciation-areas-missing-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14266151#M256340</id>
    <title>Re: Delta (statistical) depreciation areas missing in SAP...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:54:20.498000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OwenLiu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14130</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121"&gt;@Chris1973&lt;/a&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/delta-statistical-depreciation-areas-missing-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14266151#M256340"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:54:20.498000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/deploy-scope-and-organizational-structure-activities-missing/qaa-p/14266153#M4231229</id>
    <title>Re: Deploy Scope and Organizational Structure - activities missing</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:55:37.463000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OwenLiu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14130</uri>
    </author>
    <content>We helped you to accept the answer as solution. You can un-accept it anytime if you have further questions.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/deploy-scope-and-organizational-structure-activities-missing/qaa-p/14266153#M4231229"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:55:37.463000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-creating-badi-enhancement-implementation-quot-sap-object-enhs-cannot/qaa-p/14266155#M4931455</id>
    <title>Re: Error creating BAdI Enhancement Implementation: "SAP...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:56:40.166000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OwenLiu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14130</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960"&gt;@Chuma&lt;/a&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-creating-badi-enhancement-implementation-quot-sap-object-enhs-cannot/qaa-p/14266155#M4931455"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T05:56:40.166000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/excited-to-join-the-sap-community-exploring-ai-seo-and-digital-growth/td-p/14266160</id>
    <title>Excited to Join the SAP Community – Exploring AI SEO and Digital Growth Strategies</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:09:26.217000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rathoreseo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265092</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;BR /&gt;I’m Mahesh Chand, founder of RathoreSEO, where we focus on AI-powered SEO strategies that align with evolving digital search trends. With over 19 years of experience in #SEO and digital marketing, I’m passionate about understanding how AI, analytics, and automation are shaping the future of organic visibility&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I joined the SAP Community to learn, share insights, and connect with professionals who are equally passionate about the intersection of AI, digital transformation, and intelligent data systems. My current focus is on #AI SEO# — using generative AI models and semantic data to improve search performance and online business growth&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m looking forward to engaging in meaningful discussions, learning from experts here, and contributing wherever my experience adds value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re exploring AI in digital marketing, search optimization, or automation, I’d love to exchange ideas!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warm regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Mahesh Chand&lt;BR /&gt;Founder – RathoreSEO&lt;BR /&gt;(Community Member, AI SEO Practitioner)&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/excited-to-join-the-sap-community-exploring-ai-seo-and-digital-growth/td-p/14266160"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:09:26.217000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/successfactors-learning-and-linkedlin-integration/qaa-p/14266162#M49276</id>
    <title>Re: Successfactors learning and Linkedlin integration</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:16:19.626000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SunnyZ</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/19145</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello there, we normally suggest option 1 if the customer is using Microsoft Suite that includes Azure AD already. If not, then only opption 2 is feasible. Suggest discussing with the IT team from the customer and confirm if they are happy with the solution too. Thanks!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/successfactors-learning-and-linkedlin-integration/qaa-p/14266162#M49276"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:16:19.626000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/category-synchronization-in-product-catalog-online-version/qaa-p/14266180#M458171</id>
    <title>Re: Category synchronization in Product Catalog Online ve...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:23:59.066000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>david_jiang01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/834744</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The order of categories should be determined by the columns &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SequenceNumber&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RSequenceNumber&lt;/STRONG&gt; in table &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;cat2prodrel&lt;/STRONG&gt;. So please kindly check if these 2 values are synced for the target product:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;select * from cat2prodrel where targetpk = {product pk}.&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;In your case, the values are mostly kept to be the same value, so the order will be random.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also check below related questions for more details:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/what-determines-category-order/qaq-p/12026141" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/what-determines-category-order/qaq-p/12026141&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/category-synchronization-in-product-catalog-online-version/qaa-p/14266180#M458171"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:23:59.066000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/automating-invoice-processing-using-sap-btp-capm-and-document-information/qaq-p/14266190</id>
    <title>Automating Invoice Processing Using SAP BTP, CAPM, and Document Information Extraction AI</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:27:06.263000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shrenath</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1630696</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In today’s business world, automating repetitive back-office tasks can greatly enhance efficiency and accuracy. One such task is invoice verification and processing. In this blog, I’ll share how I built an end-to-end automated invoice processing system using SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), CAP (Cloud Application Programming Model), and SAP Document Information Extraction (DOX) AI — leveraging OCR for intelligent data extraction and reporting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business Scenario:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many organizations receive vendor invoices via email in different formats — PDFs, scanned images, or photos. Manually verifying and uploading these invoices into systems like SAP S/4HANA or SAP Business ByDesign can be time-consuming and error-prone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My goal was to automate this entire process:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Read incoming emails&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validate invoice templates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extract invoice details intelligently&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Store structured data in JSON format&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Generate a daily summary report (Excel)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Architecture Overview&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tools &amp;amp; Services Used:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP CAPM (Cloud Application Programming Model): For building backend logic and APIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Document Information Extraction (DOX) AI: For intelligent extraction of invoice content&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP Object Store / Document Repository: For storing extracted documents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Email Listener / Node.js service: For reading and parsing incoming emails&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ExcelJS (or CAP plugin): For generating daily invoice reports&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;End-to-End Flow&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Email Monitoring:&lt;BR /&gt;A CAP service listens to a configured mailbox using IMAP or MS Graph API. When a new mail arrives, it checks the subject and body for invoice-related keywords.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Template Validation:&lt;BR /&gt;The email content is validated against a predefined invoice template format to ensure that only legitimate invoices proceed further.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Attachment Check:&lt;BR /&gt;If an attachment exists:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If it’s a PDF, it’s sent directly to Document Extraction AI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If it’s an image (JPEG, PNG, etc.), it’s first converted to PDF using an OCR library (like PDFKit), and then sent to DOX AI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Document Information Extraction:&lt;BR /&gt;The Document Extraction AI service processes the document and extracts key invoice fields like:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Vendor Name&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Invoice Number&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Invoice Date&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Total Amount&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tax Details&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The extracted content is then stored as a JSON object in an SAP HANA database (or another data persistence layer in CAP).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data Storage and Reporting:&lt;BR /&gt;At the end of the day, the system aggregates all processed invoices and generates a daily Excel report summarizing:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Number of invoices processed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Success vs. failure count&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Vendor-wise totals&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Any anomalies or mismatches&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This report is made available for download or automatically emailed to the finance team.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Technical Highlights&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CAPM Backend Logic:&lt;BR /&gt;Built a CAP service that handles mail events, document extraction calls, and report generation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration with DOX AI:&lt;BR /&gt;Used the Document Information Extraction API from SAP AI Business Services for content parsing.&lt;BR /&gt;API endpoint example:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;POST /document-information-extraction/v1/document/jobs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;OCR Enhancement:&lt;BR /&gt;For image attachments, OCR ensures that even scanned documents are converted into machine-readable text before extraction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;JSON Storage:&lt;BR /&gt;Extracted content is saved in a structured JSON format in the CAP model, making it easy to query, audit, or feed into analytics dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Excel Generation:&lt;BR /&gt;Used Node.js-based Excel generation via libraries like exceljs to automate daily reporting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Results &amp;amp; Benefits&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="619"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feature&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automated Email Monitoring&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Eliminates manual mail checking&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;OCR + DOX Integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Handles multiple file types (PDF/Image)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;JSON Storage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enables structured and reusable data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Excel Reporting&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provides end-of-day insights for finance teams&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BTP-based&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="310"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scalable, secure, and easy to extend&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Final report&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shrenath_0-1762924805389.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339073iD66D0561BC49DF04/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shrenath_0-1762924805389.png" alt="shrenath_0-1762924805389.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Possible Enhancements&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate with SAP Workflow Management for approvals&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add error notification service for failed invoices&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use SAP Build Apps for a visual dashboard of daily processing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable multi-language OCR for international invoice formats&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/automating-invoice-processing-using-sap-btp-capm-and-document-information/qaq-p/14266190"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:27:06.263000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-adt-package-deleted/qaa-p/14266191#M4931457</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud ADT Package deleted</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:28:35.667000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aarnavpant</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1544342</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Adnan,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you please elaborate on the issue a little more. Do different project means to a different system. If yes, then on which step actually it happened.&lt;BR /&gt;Did it happened on the linking step or pulling or pushing?&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Aarnav&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-adt-package-deleted/qaa-p/14266191#M4931457"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:28:35.667000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-use-g-l-a-c-tolerance-group-in-sap-public-cloud/qaq-p/14266194</id>
    <title>How to use G/L a/c tolerance group in SAP public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:32:17.620000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>khanhlynx99</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/854654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi experts,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am testing the operations of G/L account tolerance group in SAP public cloud, but the differences within the tolerance limit were not automatically written off as expected. I suppose there was something wrong with how I ran the operations. Please kindly tell me out.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following is how I ran the test and the detailed problem.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1:&amp;nbsp;Define Tolerance Groups for G/L Accounts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In CBC app: "&lt;SPAN&gt;Define Tolerance Groups for G/L Accounts" (SSCUI: 102323), I defined a G/L a/c tolerance group 10JP for a company code.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_1-1762914571876.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338996i8DE8095CAF91FC13/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_1-1762914571876.png" alt="khanhlynx99_1-1762914571876.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Assign the tolerance group to a G/L a/c&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In app "&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage G/L Account Master Data", copy the existing account 1256200&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;SPAN&gt;Deferred Income&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) into a new a/c :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;12562002&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;with the tolerance group (defined in step 1) and OIM.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_3-1762922390243.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339053i1D2C8EF91C8829C0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_3-1762922390243.png" alt="khanhlynx99_3-1762922390243.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Post journal entries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I chose the following conceptual transactions to test&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;・Post an outstanding expenses transaction then make payment on it with a difference within tolerance limit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="700"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="111"&gt;Step&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="119"&gt;Document type&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="165"&gt;Debit&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="71"&gt;　&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="165"&gt;Credit&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="69"&gt;　&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;3.1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SA/KR&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Salary&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;10000&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Deferred expenses&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;10000&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;3.2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SA/KZ&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Deferred expenses&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;10000&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Cash/bank account&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;9900&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why don't I simply create an invoice and make payment on payables account?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The answer is that you cannot assign a G/L a/c tolerance group to a vendor reconciliation account. In SAP public cloud, each account group has pre-defined and non-editable field status, accordingly the account group of AR/AP reconciliation accounts has the field "tolerance group" suppressed. Check them in CBC app "&lt;SPAN&gt;Define Account Group" (SSCUI&amp;nbsp;103508).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_2-1762921320959.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339048iA371BA4985C59476/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_2-1762921320959.png" alt="khanhlynx99_2-1762921320959.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;3.1&amp;nbsp;Post an outstanding expenses transaction&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In app "&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage Journal Entries" post the following journal entry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_6-1762923513611.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339061iAC3EB3AD6377640C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_6-1762923513611.png" alt="khanhlynx99_6-1762923513611.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;3.2 Make a payment and clear open items&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use app "&lt;SPAN&gt;Clear G/L Accounts", choose the open item created in step 3.1 and post payment to clear.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_8-1762924915626.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339075i6147C435CB049FBF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_8-1762924915626.png" alt="khanhlynx99_8-1762924915626.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In tab "Post to G/L account", enter the account and amount for credit, using 10010000 (petty cash) and leaving 100 JPY difference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_9-1762925030398.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339077i5E12AF194C694C89/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_9-1762925030398.png" alt="khanhlynx99_9-1762925030398.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When pressing "Simulate", the following error happens whereas the difference is within tolerance limit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_10-1762925126378.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339078i136DEDAAA32253F8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_10-1762925126378.png" alt="khanhlynx99_10-1762925126378.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-use-g-l-a-c-tolerance-group-in-sap-public-cloud/qaq-p/14266194"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:32:17.620000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ewm-repacking-hu-into-allowed-handling-unit-types-in-replenishment/ba-p/14265877</id>
    <title>SAP EWM - Repacking HU into Allowed Handling Unit Types in Replenishment</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:35:32.959000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vedant_Gunde</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1975131</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; High Rack can store different Handling unit types such as A1, A2, A3 and B1. Stock will be Replenished to Fix bins; however, Fix bins can store only HUs with B1 Handling unit type. Before pushing stock to fixed bins HUs with same HU type as B1 should directly move to fix bins and HU type other than B1 need to repack in a WorkCentre.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1) Define Handling Unit Types &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; Integration with Other SAP Components &amp;gt;Extended Warehouse Management &amp;gt; Additional Material Attributes &amp;gt;Attribute Values for Additional Material Master Fields &amp;gt;Define Handling Unit Type&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_0-1762878779310.png" style="width: 601px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338818i3C0578EAD1D4D85B/image-dimensions/601x315/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="601" height="315" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_0-1762878779310.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_0-1762878779310.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2) Define HU Type Groups and Assign HU Types&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Cross-Process Settings &amp;gt; Handling Units &amp;gt; Define HU Type Groups&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_6-1762879999163.png" style="width: 603px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338827iEE2D377B9BAD1CFC/image-dimensions/603x205/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="603" height="205" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_6-1762879999163.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_6-1762879999163.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Cross-Process Settings &amp;gt; Handling Units &amp;gt; Define HU Types for Each Warehouse Number and Assign HU Type Group&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_7-1762880013297.png" style="width: 619px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338828i52AF55E8ABD678A9/image-dimensions/619x257/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="619" height="257" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_7-1762880013297.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_7-1762880013297.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3) Define Storage Types&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Master Data&amp;gt; Define Storage Types&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;a) High Rack Storage&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_17-1762882133621.png" style="width: 558px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338855i72184302DB87346C/image-dimensions/558x399/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="558" height="399" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_17-1762882133621.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_17-1762882133621.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;b) Work Center Storage&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_2-1762878978359.png" style="width: 555px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338821i372F82EB0A971F67/image-dimensions/555x298/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="555" height="298" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_2-1762878978359.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_2-1762878978359.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;c) Fix Bin Storage&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_3-1762878986315.png" style="width: 564px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338822i97707916F1104D44/image-dimensions/564x345/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="564" height="345" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_3-1762878986315.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_3-1762878986315.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4) Define Activity Area&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Master Data&amp;gt; Activity Areas &amp;gt; Define Sort Sequence for Activity Areas&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_4-1762879732854.png" style="width: 719px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338825i96E0426D4ADB4D9B/image-dimensions/719x159/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="719" height="159" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_4-1762879732854.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_4-1762879732854.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5) Define POSC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Cross-Process Settings &amp;gt; Warehouse Task &amp;gt; Define Process-Oriented Storage Control&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Storage Process – Definition&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_14-1762881344242.png" style="width: 613px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338849iAED9B658F4FA9958/image-dimensions/613x147/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="613" height="147" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_14-1762881344242.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_14-1762881344242.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Assign Storage Process steps&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_15-1762881344246.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338850i65017D9DDF7FE03A/image-dimensions/592x203/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="592" height="203" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_15-1762881344246.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_15-1762881344246.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Process-Oriented Storage Control&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_16-1762881344250.png" style="width: 609px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338851i45DD51DFE9BC0618/image-dimensions/609x137/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="609" height="137" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_16-1762881344250.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_16-1762881344250.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;- IB03 step is maintained here to move products from Workcenter which will be repacked in OB02 step. In OB02 only HU Types maintained under PALL HU type group will be repacked.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Define Work Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Master Data&amp;gt; Work Center &amp;gt; Define Work Center&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_5-1762879797975.png" style="width: 791px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338826i8B03677976684558/image-dimensions/791x123/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="791" height="123" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_5-1762879797975.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_5-1762879797975.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7) Define Warehouse Order Creation rule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Cross-Process Settings &amp;gt; Warehouse Order &amp;gt; Define Limit Values for the Size of a Warehouse Order&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_8-1762880354491.png" style="width: 449px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338834i93FB9FC27DAD2219/image-dimensions/449x475/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="449" height="475" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_8-1762880354491.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_8-1762880354491.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Field Activity area used to limit the creation of warehouse order where products of different HU types are stored in High Rack&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Cross-Process Settings &amp;gt; Warehouse Order &amp;gt; Define Packing Profile for Warehouse Order Creation&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_9-1762881054343.png" style="width: 575px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338840i57F4B77C59BF0C03/image-dimensions/575x284/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="575" height="284" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_9-1762881054343.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_9-1762881054343.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Cross-Process Settings &amp;gt; Warehouse Order &amp;gt; Define Creation Rules for Warehouse Orders&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_10-1762881095511.png" style="width: 416px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338842iF91DEAA4949CF592/image-dimensions/416x418/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="416" height="418" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_10-1762881095511.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_10-1762881095511.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_11-1762881102946.png" style="width: 404px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338843i879755336CCA0887/image-dimensions/404x416/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="404" height="416" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_11-1762881102946.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_11-1762881102946.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Define Search Sequence of Creation Rules for Activity Areas&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_12-1762881233484.png" style="width: 620px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338847i4821DFB73CF8C451/image-dimensions/620x155/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="620" height="155" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_12-1762881233484.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_12-1762881233484.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8)Picking Strategies &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Goods Issue Process &amp;gt; Strategies &amp;gt; Specify Storage Type Search Sequence&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_18-1762882223325.png" style="width: 597px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338856i55CFAA9A97274E3D/image-dimensions/597x185/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="597" height="185" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_18-1762882223325.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_18-1762882223325.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Determine Storage Type Search Sequence for Stock Removal&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_19-1762882223329.png" style="width: 609px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338857iB3EB96A6948EFCB4/image-dimensions/609x168/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="609" height="168" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_19-1762882223329.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_19-1762882223329.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;9) Activate Replenishment&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; SCM EWM &amp;gt; EWM &amp;gt; Internal Warehouse Processes &amp;gt; Replenishment Control &amp;gt; Activate Replenishment Strategies in Storage Types&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_20-1762882223333.png" style="width: 582px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338858iC77F637B16D049A9/image-dimensions/582x332/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="582" height="332" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_20-1762882223333.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_20-1762882223333.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Master Data:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1) Create material Master&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;a) Materials&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_21-1762882536908.png" style="width: 449px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338860i3513AD6D33234920/image-dimensions/449x188/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="449" height="188" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_21-1762882536908.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_21-1762882536908.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;b) Packaging materials&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_22-1762882536911.png" style="width: 487px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338861i26C81B44BD0DB80E/image-dimensions/487x151/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="487" height="151" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_22-1762882536911.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_22-1762882536911.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2) Packaging specification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_23-1762882536917.png" style="width: 657px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338862i5589BA8ACDD57316/image-dimensions/657x189/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="657" height="189" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_23-1762882536917.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_23-1762882536917.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_24-1762882536924.png" style="width: 655px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338864i41E1459F59506F22/image-dimensions/655x295/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="655" height="295" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_24-1762882536924.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_24-1762882536924.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3) Additional Attributes for activity area /N/SCWM/SEBA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_25-1762882536927.png" style="width: 672px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338863i563ECFFF6FD17F5B/image-dimensions/672x167/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="672" height="167" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_25-1762882536927.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_25-1762882536927.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4) Assign Fixed Bins /N/SCWM/BINMAT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_26-1762882536932.png" style="width: 711px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338865iFDB036DBD37E410C/image-dimensions/711x185/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="711" height="185" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_26-1762882536932.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_26-1762882536932.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5) Create Bins and Assign Storage Section&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_27-1762882536936.png" style="width: 761px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338867iEAD24C38FC743E54/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_27-1762882536936.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_27-1762882536936.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6)&amp;nbsp; Load Storage bin sorting&amp;nbsp;/N/SCWM/SRTUP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_28-1762882536939.png" style="width: 624px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338866iE062DEE6E64DE662/image-dimensions/624x153/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="624" height="153" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_28-1762882536939.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_28-1762882536939.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Testing:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;1) Replenish Stock /N/SCWM/REPL&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_29-1762883074541.png" style="width: 530px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338868i7DD7DA1B4E9681FA/image-dimensions/530x281/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="530" height="281" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_29-1762883074541.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_29-1762883074541.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Enter Mandatory parameters such as warehouse number and PED and execute.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_30-1762883074544.png" style="width: 551px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338870iDFCAB086BE837DF7/image-dimensions/551x266/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="551" height="266" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_30-1762883074544.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_30-1762883074544.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Select line item to Replenish and click on execute&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_31-1762883074547.png" style="width: 561px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338869i43BF8B85BAEB72D9/image-dimensions/561x332/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="561" height="332" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_31-1762883074547.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_31-1762883074547.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;We can observe WT are created for Fix bins.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_32-1762883074554.png" style="width: 814px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338872iF8BC3116DE217D88/image-dimensions/814x182/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="814" height="182" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_32-1762883074554.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_32-1762883074554.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_33-1762883074561.png" style="width: 801px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338873i688CAC41ACD111EF/image-dimensions/801x204/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="801" height="204" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_33-1762883074561.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_33-1762883074561.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;2) Confirm Warehouse Order&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Products stored in AA CART with HU type B1 packaging are grouped in WO02 warehouse order. Whereas Products stored in AA PALL with HU types A1, A2 and A3 packaging are grouped in WO01 warehouse order and this help us to direct products with other HU type to repack into Pick HU of Hu type B1 using packaging specification.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_35-1762883074571.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338875iDCFC693E1015F30F/image-dimensions/592x273/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="592" height="273" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_35-1762883074571.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_35-1762883074571.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;We can observe Multiple Pick HUs are created with HU type B1.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_36-1762883074576.png" style="width: 621px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338876iE69E7D18169DE202/image-dimensions/621x292/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="621" height="292" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_36-1762883074576.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_36-1762883074576.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Click on Confirm in Foreground, Pick HU will be updated as Destination HU while Source Hu is still blank, hence user can scan/pick any available Handling unit to confirm WT/WO. Here 1st step OB01 is completed.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_48-1762884345898.png" style="width: 649px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338893iD2960F7BA1C72EF6/image-dimensions/649x240/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="649" height="240" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_48-1762884345898.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_48-1762884345898.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;We can observe here once the order is confirmed, Destination bin is updated in WO as workcenter bin.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Confirm other order&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_39-1762883074590.png" style="width: 630px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338879i6D1B019EEEC62409/image-dimensions/630x342/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="630" height="342" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_39-1762883074590.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_39-1762883074590.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_40-1762883074591.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338878i7DCAF286CEB72396/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_40-1762883074591.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_40-1762883074591.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_41-1762883074596.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338881i794239EC62FDFB57/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_41-1762883074596.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_41-1762883074596.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;For Warehouse order WO02, destination is Fix bin as no repacking needed.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;3) Pack Products in Workcenter /N/SCWM/PACK&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_42-1762883074599.png" style="width: 535px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338883i278C1C1873784E67/image-dimensions/535x212/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="535" height="212" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_42-1762883074599.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_42-1762883074599.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_44-1762883074605.png" style="width: 593px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338884i18BB560EF48C6890/image-dimensions/593x236/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="593" height="236" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_44-1762883074605.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_44-1762883074605.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;As control for picking HU is&amp;nbsp;3 Only adopt content (mat. + lower-level HUs) into pick HU at warehouse process type, qty moved directly into pick HU. We can select Pick HU and print them in workcenter. Once all the activities completed, click on Complete process step for HU.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_45-1762883074611.png" style="width: 558px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338885iBAC042D4813FB4EC/image-dimensions/558x392/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="558" height="392" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_45-1762883074611.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_45-1762883074611.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;New WT will be created on refresh to move repacked HUs to fix bins&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vedant_Gunde_46-1762883074620.png" style="width: 861px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338886i4BD371F23675180D/image-dimensions/861x287/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="861" height="287" role="button" title="Vedant_Gunde_46-1762883074620.png" alt="Vedant_Gunde_46-1762883074620.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Step IB03 to move products to fix bin storage with HU type B1. Products will automatically pick their destination bin from Fix bin assignment (/SCWM/BINMAT).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ewm-repacking-hu-into-allowed-handling-unit-types-in-replenishment/ba-p/14265877"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:35:32.959000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unified-destination-setup-for-accessing-multiple-odata-services-in-bas/qaq-p/14266195</id>
    <title>Unified Destination Setup for Accessing Multiple OData Services in BAS</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:36:12.151000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sawa-tomoki</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1393121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP Support,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to ask a question regarding how to manage Destinations on SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So far, we have been using the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Extensibility service to create Destinations for each individual communication scenario (e.g., one for sales order integration, another for purchase order integration).&lt;BR /&gt;As a result, we are ending up with multiple Destinations—one per communication scenario—that correspond to each OData service we wish to use.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the other hand, when connecting BTP with an SAP on-premise system, it has been possible to access various OData services through a single Destination.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our current objective is to enable a development flow where we can build a Fiori application in BAS and, at the initial data source selection step, choose from various OData services (e.g., purchase, sales, or custom OData) via a single Destination.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, as it stands, only the OData services associated with the specific communication scenario used when the Destination was created are selectable during BAS development. This limits flexibility in application development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there any recommended configuration or best practice that would allow us to create a single Destination that can be used to access multiple communication scenarios or OData services?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would greatly appreciate your guidance on this matter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unified-destination-setup-for-accessing-multiple-odata-services-in-bas/qaq-p/14266195"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:36:12.151000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14265198</id>
    <title>What's new in SAP Logistics Management</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:37:44.523000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NadineRied</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1508012</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Logistics Management is our new solution in Supply Chain Management that combines&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;warehousing and transportation management to streamline your operations with network-centric collaboration. As mentioned in the previous &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14254200" target="_self"&gt;What's new article&lt;/A&gt;,&amp;nbsp;we are committed to delivering innovations continuously on a bi-weekly basis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, you will learn about the new features in SAP Logistics Management that have been released this week.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764675778"&gt;Print loading list&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now print the loading list for a pickup in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/af5d4e528a2646709ce1bd7e5d288b91.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=SAP+Logistics+Management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Manage Pickups and Deliveries&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; app. The loading list contains general information like carrier and ship-to party. Depending on when you print the loading list, it shows the goods that are planned to be loaded onto the truck or are already loaded.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Exemplary loading list:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="loio02fe4a655b374207a8eea0604472ad5f_LowRes.png" style="width: 445px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338454iD9C8F829832BE744/image-dimensions/445x576/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="445" height="576" role="button" title="loio02fe4a655b374207a8eea0604472ad5f_LowRes.png" alt="loio02fe4a655b374207a8eea0604472ad5f_LowRes.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568162273"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Upload stock&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the setup section, you may find a new app where you can upload a spreadsheet file containing stock data to be posted into the system. Y&lt;/SPAN&gt;ou can perform the following actions:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Download a spreadsheet template file to define the initial stock&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Import the initial stock by uploading the spreadsheet file&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validate the data errors in the uploaded data before posting the stock&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Post stock into specified storage bins&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="upload1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338905i6ACF8201BAEF37A7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="upload1.jpg" alt="upload1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="upload2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338906i57643A7B8807FF54/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="upload2.jpg" alt="upload2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371648768"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175135263"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sites in organizational model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With this feature, you can import sites in your organizational models via the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/dfa040b3de5844a4b0ed5ebf866ae48c.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=SAP+Logistics+Management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Import Organizational Model&lt;/A&gt; app. A site acts as a higher-level organizational unit including shipping points and warehouses.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978621758"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Confirm warehouse tasks with changes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;With this feature, you can confirm warehouse tasks with changes, for example, the change of confirmed quantities and destination storage bins. You can also filter warehouse tasks using these changes in the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/e5980ac94ccb478882691811d1d1730a.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=SAP+Logistics+Management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Process Warehouse Tasks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; app. Currently, you can change confirmed quantities for ad-hoc and putaway warehouse tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;When you confirm putaway warehouse tasks by navigating from the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/681ac47d92a3452fa3a7ba20be65777b.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=SAP+Logistics+Management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Manage Inbound Warehouse Activities&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; app, you can also reduce the confirmed quantity and put away less quantity than the planned quantity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="confirmwithchanges.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338457i22BDCE77D529EB33/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="confirmwithchanges.jpg" alt="confirmwithchanges.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782108253"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create ad hoc warehouse tasks for stock with a reference to an outbound warehouse request&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With this feature, you can create ad hoc warehouse tasks in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/0f8f04bd83484699b67871827a87a44b.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=SAP+Logistics+Management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Manage Stock&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; app for stock that has already been reserved for an outbound warehouse request. This allows you to move already picked stock.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-585594748"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Related documents for inbound warehouse requests&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With this feature, you can view related documents for inbound warehouse requests in the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/681ac47d92a3452fa3a7ba20be65777b.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=SAP+Logistics+Management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Manage Inbound Warehouse Activities&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; app.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="relatedInbound.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338467iA40DE4EC14EB91AA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="relatedInbound.jpg" alt="relatedInbound.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-389081243"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration card for inbound warehouse request&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With this feature, when you access &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Logistics Management&lt;/SPAN&gt; via &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Build Work Zone, standard edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;, you can see an integration card showing the progress of inbound warehouse requests in each status after choosing a single date or a date range.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="iWHRcard.jpg" style="width: 305px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338474iF9A3ABFF234653E8/image-dimensions/305x281/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="305" height="281" role="button" title="iWHRcard.jpg" alt="iWHRcard.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;More information about integration cards in SAP Build Work Zone can be found &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/a407fadacc524298870f811f3c837a59/c25a11385302414483d92f6a541ae8a6.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=DRAFT&amp;amp;version=DEV" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-192567738"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New attributes for carrier determination&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Two new logistics attributes have been introduced to determine the appropriate carrier via the processing rule for a transportation request or a consignment order. They are:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Total Gross Weight&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Total Gross Weight Unit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The carrier determination can be found in the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/7e21ba1bf73241c180c4069fb776c52c.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=SAP+Logistics+Management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Define Processing Rules&lt;/A&gt; app.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--3945767"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Usability improvements for consignments and transportation requests&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/63235da662b6451c9b4ed08338ffff4a.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=SAP+Logistics+Management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Transportation Requests&lt;/A&gt; app you can now use a filter to search for errors and open tasks more easily:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="manageTR.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338781i8BD4F4D96866C64A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="manageTR.png" alt="manageTR.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/bdf2c17eab7842a195c349db389edaf9.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=SAP+Logistics+Management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Consignments&lt;/A&gt; app, the tag "BN4L" is displayed when a carrier is set up for use in SAP Business Network Freight Collaboration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ManageCons.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338782iFA59E57B1736E7B1/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ManageCons.png" alt="ManageCons.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT/7133b5f9c8924d549374db067bf45c8c/63235da662b6451c9b4ed08338ffff4a.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=SAP+Logistics+Management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Transportation Requests&lt;/A&gt; app, the popover for the warehouse processing status in the progress overview explains why a delivery isn't ready for warehouse processing yet.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="TRapp.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338794i08EB8155376E24FA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="TRapp.png" alt="TRapp.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-146795085"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All these features have been deployed this week and are available in the SAP Logistics Management tenants. We are happy to hear your feedback about the latest enhancements. Going forward you may find any information about new features also in our What's New Viewer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--640211573" id="toc-hId--49718420"&gt;Further Information&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_LOGISTICS_MANAGEMENT?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Logistics Management Product Page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-logistics-management/ba-p/14265198"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:37:44.523000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-index-creation-failure-in-sum-phase-eu-clone-mig-dt-run/ba-p/14266196</id>
    <title>Handling Index creation failure in SUM phase EU_CLONE_MIG_DT_RUN</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:38:30.199000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dinendra_Hijam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1792430</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;During an upgrade using the Software Update Manager (SUM) with the Database Migration Option (DMO) option, errors may occur in the phase EU_CLONE_MIG_DT_RUN with below error&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;***************************************************************************************************************************&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A3WEIMP 047 PRIMARY KEY&amp;nbsp; (&amp;nbsp; "MANDT" ,&amp;nbsp; "E_FINIS" ,&amp;nbsp; "EPN_PREFIX" ,&amp;nbsp; "EPN_BASE" ,&amp;nbsp; "EPN_SUFFIX" ,&amp;nbsp; "LOC_CODE" ,&amp;nbsp; "CREATED_ON" ,&amp;nbsp; "CREATED_TIME"&amp;nbsp; )'&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A3WEIMP 047 (HDB) dbrc = 26 'unique constraint violated'&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A3WEIMP 047 (HDB) SQL error = 349&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A3WEIMP 047 (HDB) cannot CREATE UNIQUE INDEX; duplicate key found:&amp;nbsp; [5] Several documents with the same ID exist in the index;SAPHANADB:/ &amp;lt;NAMESPACE&amp;gt;//BDL_NPSA.$trexexternalkey$ content not unique, cannot define unique constraint. rowCount != distinctCount&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A3WEIMP 047 (HDB) DBCreate failed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A2EEIMP 049 Index creation failed before - listing duplicate records for '/&amp;lt;NAMESPACE&amp;gt;/BDL_NPSA~0' with key fields: MANDT E_FINIS EPN_PREFIX EPN_BASE EPN_SUFFIX LOC_CODE CREATED_ON CREATED_TIME&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A4EEIMP 051 Duplicate record with key: '120' '1001713' '95VW' '5B489' 'AB' 'DE' '20230822' '000100' (occurs 3 times).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A3EEIMP 052 Found 1 duplicate keys in 3 records.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A1EEIMP 008 Task failed with error: (HDB) DbSlExecute failed for DDL statement 'ALTER TABLE "/&amp;lt;NAMESPACE&amp;gt;//BDL_NPSA"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A1EEIMP 008 ADD CONSTRAINT "/&amp;lt;NAMESPACE&amp;gt;/BDL_NPSA~0"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A1EEIMP 008 PRIMARY KEY&amp;nbsp; (&amp;nbsp; "MANDT" ,&amp;nbsp; "E_FINIS" ,&amp;nbsp; "EPN_PREFIX" ,&amp;nbsp; "EPN_BASE" ,&amp;nbsp; "EPN_SUFFIX" ,&amp;nbsp; "LOC_CODE" ,&amp;nbsp; "CREATED_ON" ,&amp;nbsp; "CREATED_TIME"&amp;nbsp; )'&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A1EEIMP 008 (HDB) dbrc = 26 'unique constraint violated'&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A1EEIMP 008 (HDB) SQL error = 349&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A1EEIMP 008 (HDB) cannot CREATE UNIQUE INDEX; duplicate key found:&amp;nbsp; [5] Several documents with the same ID exist in the index;SAPHANADB:/FORDEU/BDL_NPSA.$trexexternalkey$ content not unique, cannot define unique constraint. rowCount != distinctCount&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A1EEIMP 008 (HDB) DBCreate failed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A2EETSK 007 Finished create for object "/&amp;lt;NAMESPACE&amp;gt;/BDL_NPSA~0" of type "primary index" with error in 0.190 sec #20250922081128&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;***************************************************************************************************************************&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dinendra_Hijam_0-1762925142235.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339081iDFAA60C2C1E49296/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Dinendra_Hijam_0-1762925142235.png" alt="Dinendra_Hijam_0-1762925142235.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The error indicates that there are duplicate entries in the table of target DB. This is causing the creation of a unique index to fail, as there are multiple records with the same key. The duplicate entries come from the source DB as shown below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Source Database&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dinendra_Hijam_1-1762925142239.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339079iC547BE0C49C96A29/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Dinendra_Hijam_1-1762925142239.png" alt="Dinendra_Hijam_1-1762925142239.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Target&amp;nbsp; Database Table&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dinendra_Hijam_2-1762925142243.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339080iF5B61E19D569A618/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Dinendra_Hijam_2-1762925142243.png" alt="Dinendra_Hijam_2-1762925142243.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To fix/mitigate the issue, following actions can be taken:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Case 1: &lt;STRONG&gt;Duplicate entries can be deleted&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Identify the duplicate entries in the source database and delete them from the source database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If it is HANA database, please use the HANA scripts HANA_Data_DuplicateKeys_CommandGenerator_1.00.100+ and HANA_Data_DuplicateKeys_columnStore_Deletion_CommandGenerator attached in SAP Note 1969700.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the entries are deleted, retry the step in SUM tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Case 2: If customer is not allowing to delete the duplicate entries from Source database.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ignore the index creation in Target DB with below steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Identify the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;MIGRATE_DT_REPAIR_IMP.TSK&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; file under &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;../SUM/abap/load/migrate_dt_repair&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; directory.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Edit the index entry (which is having the issue) in the file as below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P &amp;lt;Index name &amp;gt; C ign&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dinendra_Hijam_3-1762925142245.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339082i6FC807A98FD5F5EF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Dinendra_Hijam_3-1762925142245.png" alt="Dinendra_Hijam_3-1762925142245.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this, SUM process will skip the index creation for this table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Repeat the SUM phase again.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: If the index is required later, it can be created manually after the target system is available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-index-creation-failure-in-sum-phase-eu-clone-mig-dt-run/ba-p/14266196"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:38:30.199000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-check-the-list-for-plan-settlement-for-internal-order-or-which-table-in/qaq-p/14266197</id>
    <title>how check the list for plan settlement for internal order, or which table in SE16N</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:48:48.710000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>zhangyi_draeger</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265103</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;how check the list for plan settlement for internal order, or which table in SE16N&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-check-the-list-for-plan-settlement-for-internal-order-or-which-table-in/qaq-p/14266197"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:48:48.710000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-members/configuration-settings-for-automatic-ps-project-creation-from-ppm-item/ba-p/14265007</id>
    <title>Configuration settings for automatic PS Project creation from PPM Item</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:49:46.138000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KrishnaPSingh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2252860</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this Blog Post we will explore key topics such as item types, utilizing PS Projects as templates, activating Project System integration, maintaining synchronization scenarios, and establishing object links. Additionally, we will highlight important configuration settings within the Project System that ensure a seamless transition from PPM to PS Projects. By understanding these configurations, project managers / consultants / users can streamline their processes, reduce manual errors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP PPM Configuration Objects Covered:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Item Types&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PS Project as Template&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activation of Project System integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maintenance of Synchronization scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Settings for Object Links&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Important setting in Project System&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Settings for Automatic creation of PS Project from PPM Item:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To automatically create a PS Project from a PPM Item, you need to configure the Item Type where the “Link to Project System” column is set to “PS Project System.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration Node:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Portfolio and Project Management – Global Customizing – Portfolio-Independent Settings – Define Portfolio Item Types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_0-1762841321764.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338384i727D5B03842F1E1B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_0-1762841321764.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_0-1762841321764.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You must have assigned SAP Project System Operative Project Object Number (Without “PD” as prefix) as Template at below mentioned configuration Node.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration Node:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Portfolio and Project Management – Global Customizing – Portfolio-Independent Settings – Map Item Type to Project or PS or Commercial Project&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select “Item Type to PS Project” and maintain the number in “Project ID” column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This task must be performed by opening the client, such as Test or Production, where you need to maintain the template.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_1-1762841321779.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338382i763CC732A0AA4424/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_1-1762841321779.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_1-1762841321779.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Operative PS Project used here as template is “CHEM-25-001” with Object ID Number (OBJNR) PD00000048:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_2-1762841321781.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338383i73EFF650CC8C9B4B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_2-1762841321781.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_2-1762841321781.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Project Structure:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_3-1762841321783.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338386i115F2F8AF14FF8D6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_3-1762841321783.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_3-1762841321783.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activation of Project System integration:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration Node:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Portfolio and Project Management – Portfolio Management – Base System Interfaces – Portfolio-Management-Specific Settings for Project Management Systems Integ – Enable Project Management Systems Integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_4-1762841321785.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338385i528845F2768EF0C3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_4-1762841321785.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_4-1762841321785.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maintenance of Synchronization scenarios:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration Node:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Portfolio and Project Management – Common Functions – Decision Flow Management Settings – Attribute Synchronization – Maintain Attributes for Synchronization Scenarios&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The attributes highlighted below must be maintained for the creation and updating of a PS Project from a PPM Item:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_5-1762841321789.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338387i8BD42B81DF50A37F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_5-1762841321789.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_5-1762841321789.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You can explore the remaining attributes if you wish to update the PPM Item Decision Point or the Item from the PS WBS, among other options, based on various business requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Settings for Object Links:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The configurations mentioned above are essential for the automatic creation of a PS Project from a PPM Item along with other very important configurations in PPM, as outlined below, where you need to define the Logical System, Destination, and Web Servers for each relevant object type.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration Node:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Portfolio and Project Management – Common Functions – Decision Flow Management Settings – Define DFM Object Link Types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; It is recommended to perform this configuration in the appropriate system by opening the client, such as the Test or Production system. Otherwise, the TR movement may override the settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_6-1762841321792.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338388i2E97342E85EB454E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_6-1762841321792.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_6-1762841321792.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_7-1762841321794.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338389i1EA7481CA0311EE3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_7-1762841321794.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_7-1762841321794.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Same way update for all the relevant Object Types, like PS Project Definition etc.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration Node:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Portfolio and Project Management – Portfolio Management – Base System Interfaces – Application Object Settings – Define Object Link Types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; It is recommended to perform this configuration in the appropriate system by opening the client, such as the Test or Production system. Otherwise, the TR movement may override the settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_8-1762841321797.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338390i85F400784F6976CB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_8-1762841321797.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_8-1762841321797.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_9-1762841321800.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338391i5E5E7894D186D342/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_9-1762841321800.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_9-1762841321800.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Same way update for all the relevant Object Types.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let’s execute the scenario:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Item created with ID TESTDEMO001:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_10-1762841321806.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338393iE9D7A1086029F588/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_10-1762841321806.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_10-1762841321806.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, create the project by selecting the checkbox. Here, we can see that the PS Project we assigned as a template in the configuration is available for selection to establish the PS Project structure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_11-1762841321810.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338392i173D94131D74A971/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_11-1762841321810.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_11-1762841321810.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Clicking on Save will automatically create the PS Project. After the project is created, the PS Project option will now be available in the Item.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_12-1762841321815.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338395i1023E183291DEE87/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_12-1762841321815.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_12-1762841321815.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Relationship tab under Related Objects, we can observe that the PS Project has been automatically assigned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_13-1762841321820.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338394i78F840FE6F6FE84A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_13-1762841321820.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_13-1762841321820.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Project Builder - CJ20N also we can see the PS Project is created:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_14-1762841321823.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338396iC2484535E270A19E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_14-1762841321823.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_14-1762841321823.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; One very important configuration needs to be considered in terms of automatic creation of PS project from PPM Item, The Edit checkbox in “Special Characters in Project Number” should not be checked: -&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transaction Code:&lt;/STRONG&gt; OPSK&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration Node:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Project System – Structures – Operative Structures – Work Breakdown Structure (WBS) – Project Coding Mask – Define Special Characters for Projects&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KrishnaPSingh_15-1762841321824.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338397i5F33E35D17ABB6D3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KrishnaPSingh_15-1762841321824.png" alt="KrishnaPSingh_15-1762841321824.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this checkbox is selected, the system will encounter issues when creating a PS Project due to restrictions of coded projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By carefully following the configuration settings mentioned in this article, you will be able to achieve the error free automatic PS Project creation from PPM Item.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Portfolio+and+Project+Management/pd-p/01200314690800000417" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="758-1"&gt;SAP Portfolio and Project Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Portfolio+and+Project+Management+for+SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/73555000100800000245" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="759-1"&gt;SAP Portfolio and Project Management for SAP S/4HANA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/PLM+Project+System+%252528PS%252529/pd-p/653310048283475313268757797580946" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1028-1"&gt;PLM Project System (PS)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-members/configuration-settings-for-automatic-ps-project-creation-from-ppm-item/ba-p/14265007"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:49:46.138000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/import-bulk-of-custom-fields-in-data-migration-modeler-ltmom-using-upload/qaa-p/14266198#M4931459</id>
    <title>Re: Import bulk of custom fields in Data Migration modeler (LTMOM) using Upload Structure Field List</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:51:28.300000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rahul0884</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2219627</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks for Sharing useful content.One Question ,Is it Limited to Semicolon as a delimiter or does this work with other Delimeters like tab or comma separated?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/import-bulk-of-custom-fields-in-data-migration-modeler-ltmom-using-upload/qaa-p/14266198#M4931459"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:51:28.300000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/adding-additional-field-in-mb51-report/qaa-p/14266199#M4231231</id>
    <title>Re: Adding Additional field in MB51 Report</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:54:15.696000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mahil</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1735104</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi sir,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In debug mode list have my zfields &amp;amp; and their respective values. Issues in catalog only. Herewith I attach my build_catalog values for reference.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;!--  StartFragment   --&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;if&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;rtt&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;fieldname&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;'ZZBRGEW'&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;fc_flat&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;seltext_m&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;'Gross&amp;nbsp;Weight'&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;fc_flat&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;tabname&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;'LIST'&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;fc_flat&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;ref_fieldname&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;'ZZBRGEW'&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;fc_flat&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;no_out&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;'X'&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ENDIF&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Advance Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/adding-additional-field-in-mb51-report/qaa-p/14266199#M4231231"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:54:15.696000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/intelliflow-manufacturing-with-sap-s-4hana-ux-and-collaboration-manager/ba-p/14266161</id>
    <title>IntelliFlow Manufacturing with SAP S/4HANA UX and Collaboration Manager</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:55:49.667000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mrinal_Chanda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146047</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In the ever-changing field of digital manufacturing, SAP continues to push the boundaries of innovation with its new release, SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Among the noteworthy features is the Review Progress Order—Multilevel View App, a game-changing tool for improving visibility, control, and cooperation across production and procurement processes. This strong pair, together with the newly released SAP Collaboration Manager, is redefining real-time communication and job execution for industrial teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing the Review Progress Order app&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Manufacturing procedures are complicated, with many levels of connections, components, and timelines. The Review Progress Order App handles this complexity by providing a multi-level view of production, sales, and processing orders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It allows users to&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp; Visualize component needs and receipt aspects throughout an order structure.&lt;BR /&gt;• Identify and analyze component shortages and delays to determine their root causes.&lt;BR /&gt;• Calculate total order delays depending on delivery and production time.&lt;BR /&gt;• Easily access associated apps, such as Manage Material Coverage, Display Material Stock, and Change Planned Order.&lt;BR /&gt;• Export data to Excel for offline analysis and reporting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Manufacturers frequently suffer with fragmented data and delayed insights. The Review Progress Order App combines crucial information into a single, simple interface. It enables planners and production managers to make educated decisions more rapidly, minimizing bottlenecks and boosting on-time delivery performance.&lt;BR /&gt;Collaboration Manager: A New Era of In-App Communication.&lt;BR /&gt;SAP has officially decommissioned the SAP CoPilot and introduced the SAP Collaboration Manager as a replacement for human-to-human collaboration within the SAP Fiori Launchpad. This innovation is currently available in both SAP S/4HANA Cloud and on-premise editions, providing a contextual, real-time communication layer directly within business applications&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features of Collaboration Manager:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• Set up individual or group discussions based on specific screens or business objects.&lt;BR /&gt;• Include attachments, screenshots, and video links in chats.&lt;BR /&gt;• Edit or remove messages quickly after posting.&lt;BR /&gt;• Convert private notes into collaborative threads as needed.&lt;BR /&gt;• Go straight to the screenshot or chat screen.&lt;BR /&gt;• Receive quick notifications for prompt answers and task completion&lt;BR /&gt;Collaboration in the Manufacturing Context&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's see a demo to understand it more clearly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To set the context, let's assume a sales representative has received a call from a customer about the delay of their order. The sales representative then contacts the production team to inquire about the delay.&amp;nbsp; Assume a production planner uses the Review Progress Order App to detect a delay in a vital component. Rather than switching systems or exchanging emails, users may start a discussion with the procurement team right away using Collaboration Manager. The discussion contains screenshots, order information, and direct links to the affected components. This in-house collaboration eliminates delays, improves clarity, and speeds up problem solving.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here in the demo, one of the customers contacted the sales representative, Dale Jones, who was asking for confirmation on the delayed sales order delivery. The sales representative sent a message through Collaboration Manager to the material planner or production planner regarding this matter. Here, the material planner, Michelle, replied with "acknowledge the message" by clicking on the sent icon to the sales representative through the Collaboration Manager.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fig 1 : In App communication - Collaboration Manager" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339047i241C5487CA97F43E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="UXCM Step-4.png" alt="Fig 1 : In App communication - Collaboration Manager" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fig 1 : In App communication - Collaboration Manager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fig 2 : Collaboration Manager - Acknowledgement" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339049i3DB0B3D3B1649582/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="UXCM Step-12.png" alt="Fig 2 : Collaboration Manager - Acknowledgement" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fig 2 : Collaboration Manager - Acknowledgement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then Michelle clicks on the "Review Order Progress" app in the Favorites section. After providing the sales order number in the app, she finds&amp;nbsp;the Issues column and finds two issues are present—one&amp;nbsp;of the required components has an uncovered quantity of 3 pieces for a planned product order. In this case, “PldOrd 4000002986.” The other one has a total delay of 1 day for the 10 pieces coming via a purchase requisition. In this case, “PurRqs 3000002513-10.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fig 3 : Review Progress Order app" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339050iFF986EA97D2D44F0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="UX Demo- Sh4.png" alt="Fig 3 : Review Progress Order app" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fig 3 : Review Progress Order app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fig 4: in app option to navigate" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339051iF154465263D854A5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="UX Demo- Sh6.png" alt="Fig 4: in app option to navigate" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fig 4: in app option to navigate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The app,&amp;nbsp;"Manage Material Coverage" option—Manage&amp;nbsp;the material coverage to resolve this issue. The "Reschedule" option for the Purchase Requisition provides a summary of the material coverage for this component, indicating that we are short by 10 pieces and need them within 9 days. The stock/requirements list provides an overview of what is coming in and going out when: Aug 12th I need 10 pieces, but I will be 10 short then.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fig 5: Resolving issue" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339052iD38D3DAB7D81332C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="UX Demo- Sh8.png" alt="Fig 5: Resolving issue" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fig 5: Resolving issue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system automatically proposes the new delivery date. It is now up to the user to accept it or reject it for an earlier or later date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fig 6 : Issue shown" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339054i6B0BC68DC6894DC4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="UX Demo- Sh13.png" alt="Fig 6 : Issue shown" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fig 6 : Issue shown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, the coverage issue for the material can be viewed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fig 7: In house navigation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339055i103A25C3F0C5F672/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="UX Demo- Sh15.png" alt="Fig 7: In house navigation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fig 7: In house navigation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fig 8: Resolving issue via Manage Monitor  Coverage" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339056i260E133F4B58C9B5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="UX Demo- Sh18.png" alt="Fig 8: Resolving issue via Manage Monitor  Coverage" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fig 8: Resolving issue via Manage Monitor  Coverage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fig 9: Issue Resolve" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339057i7A2D006C31E72134/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="UX Demo- Sh22.png" alt="Fig 9: Issue Resolve" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fig 9: Issue Resolve&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the issues are now resolved.&lt;BR /&gt;The Review Order Progress application makes it easy to obtain an overview of any issues an order may have and also makes it easy to resolve them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fig 10: Collaboration Manager - communication" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339058iF09BA904F46FDD9F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="UXCM Step-23.png" alt="Fig 10: Collaboration Manager - communication" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fig 10: Collaboration Manager - communication&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Benefits: Synergy of UX and Intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The combination of the Review Progress Order App and Collaboration Manager provides a comprehensive user experience that combines data transparency and real-time collaboration. This is how customers benefit:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Improved Decision-Making&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;With multilayer visibility of order progress and component delays, users can solve issues before they escalate. The ability to export data and navigate to connected apps ensures that decisions are based on thorough information.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Improved operational efficiency.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Collaboration Manager improves workflow efficiency by eliminating the need for external communication tools and enabling contextual discussions. Teams spend less time searching for information and more time carrying out tasks.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Faster issue resolution.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Real-time notifications and interactive threads help cross-functional teams address problems rapidly. The system immediately notifies the appropriate persons of any shortage, delay, or procurement problem.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. User-Centric Design.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Both tools are based on SAP Fiori, which ensures a uniform and straightforward user experience. The interface is dynamic, role-based, and geared for productivity, whether used on a desktop or a mobile device.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Scalability &amp;amp; Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;These elements are part of SAP's overall vision for building an intelligent, sustainable organization. They readily interact with other SAP apps and modules, allowing for scalability across sectors and geographies.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion: A New Standard for Manufacturing Excellence.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP's most recent developments in S/4HANA are more than just feature enhancements; they represent a paradigm shift in how industrial firms function. The Review Progress Order App clarifies complex order structures, and the Collaboration Manager encourages agile, informed teamwork.&lt;BR /&gt;They represent a strong blend of UX and enterprise intelligence, allowing businesses to respond faster, collaborate smarter, and provide better results. For consumers, their use implies more production, lower costs, and higher satisfaction—all hallmarks of a really intelligent manufacturing organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For more information on SAP S/4HANA Cloud, refer to the following links:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud release info&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud/product-releases" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Early Release Series Webinars&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2020/11/11/sap-s-4hana-cloud-early-release-series-watch-replays-on-demand/?preview_id=1218772" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Latest 2508 SAP S/4HANA Cloud Release Blogs&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/tag/pscc_enablement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product videos on our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLWV533hWWvDnnyN2j-CcUheNN-GaNCb3H" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLWV533hWWvDnmdq6Ps2LZLybNjZWy5A2b" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;YouTube playlist&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition Early Release Series&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/07/20/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2308-early-release-series/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud for User Experience and Cross Topics, Public Edition Continuous Influence Session&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1177" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inside SAP S/4HANA Podcast&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/inside-sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;openSAP microlearning for SAP S/4HANA&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://microlearning.opensap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inside SAP S/4HANA Podcast&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/inside-sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Best practices for SAP S/4HANA Cloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://rapid.sap.com/bp/#/browse/categories/sap_s%254hana/areas/cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Community:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Feature Scope Description&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/7c9e0bbbd1664c2581b2038a1c7ae4b3/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What’s New&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/ce01d82756b947a1a043a5d5a3204226/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Help Portal Product Page&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/p/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementation Portal&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/alm/sap-cloud-alm/implementation-portal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please refer to my latest blogs on SAP S/4HANA Cloud:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;All AI Blogs :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sales-innovation-with-sap-s-4hana-business-ai-and-user-experience-a/ba-p/14070623" target="_blank"&gt;Sales Innovation with SAP S/4HANA, Business AI, and User Experience: A Practical Approach&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/06/02/harnessing-artificial-intelligence-ai-for-sap-s-4hana-sales-order-extraction-from-pdf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Harnessing Artificial Intelligence (AI) for SAP S/4HANA Sales Order Extraction from PDF&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/06/05/optimizing-procurement-processes-with-artificial-intelligence-ai-in-sap-s-4hana-central-invoice-management-cim/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Optimizing Procurement Processes with Artificial Intelligence (AI) in SAP S/4HANA Central Invoice Ma...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/08/27/enhancing-sales-efficiency-ai-powered-sales-order-autocomplete-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2308-release-addressing-customer-challenges-and-driving-benefits/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhancing Sales Efficiency—AI-Powered Sales Order Autocomplete in SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/boost-sales-order-efficiency-with-joule-sap-s-ai-powered-copilot/ba-p/13609594" target="_blank"&gt;Boost Sales Order Efficiency with Joule, SAP’s AI-powered Copilot&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/forums/editpage/board-id/erp-blog-sap/message-id/56677/is-draft/true" target="_blank"&gt;Streamline Customer Return Management with SAP Business AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;All End-to-End Journey Blogs:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/01/25/s-4hana-cloud-end-to-end-logistics-journey-of-make-to-stock-mts-process-with-sales-procurement-manufacturing-transportation-ariba-network-dmc-integration./" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;E2E journey of Make to Stock (MTS) Logistics in SAP S/4HANA Cloud, public edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/08/04/sap-s-4hana-cloud-make-to-order-with-advanced-variant-configuration-process-with-embedded-analytics-driving-smart-decisions-on-custom-manufacturing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Make-to-Order (MTO) with Advanced Variant Configuration Process with Embedded **bl...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/11/07/revolutionizing-business-operations-a-deep-dive-into-sap-s-4hana-clouds-end-to-end-solution-for-service-orders-subscription-billing-and-entitlement-management/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;A Deep Dive into SAP S/4HANA Cloud’s End-to-End Solution for Service Orders, Subscription Billing, a...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Special Functionalities/Scenario Blogs:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/02/23/business-steps-capabilities-of-solution-order-management-as-per-sap-s-4hana-cloud-2302-public-edition-release-integration-with-field-service-management-fsm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Capabilities of Solution Order Management in S/4HANA Cloud, public edition 2302 release&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AATP Blogs:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/03/12/configuration-business-case-of-sap-s-4hana-advanced-atp-aatp-with-business-process-scheduling-bps-and-alternate-base-confirmation-abc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuration &amp;amp; Business Case of SAP S/4HANA Advanced ATP (AATP) with Business Process Scheduling (B...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow me on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://profile.sap.com/profile/id5b951ed7356cbbc794982e9186833423c9f327cdbb765611136e821f12041e2a?edit_avatar=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mrinal Kanti Chanda&amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/intelliflow-manufacturing-with-sap-s-4hana-ux-and-collaboration-manager/ba-p/14266161"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:55:49.667000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/error-while-transferring-asset-between-locations-in-same-state-sap-business/qaq-p/14266201</id>
    <title>Error While Transferring Asset Between Locations in Same State SAP Business one</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T06:57:34.163000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>IrfanTech</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1441539</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I’m facing an issue while trying to transfer an asset from one location to another within the same state in SAP. When attempting the transfer, the following error message appears:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Cannot add document; depreciation of source asset ‘HR01FA30040’ cannot be later than depreciation of target asset ‘HR04FA60112’.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you please help analyze and guide on how to resolve this issue?&lt;BR /&gt;I’ve verified that both assets belong to the same state, and depreciation has been run as per the schedule.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/error-while-transferring-asset-between-locations-in-same-state-sap-business/qaq-p/14266201"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T06:57:34.163000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/import-time-account-balances-from-3rd-party-systems/qaq-p/14266204</id>
    <title>Import time account balances from 3rd party systems</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:04:37.546000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pkvarma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2257508</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;iChris is our payroll system and we want to export balances from here and import to SuccessFactors on a regular basis using APIs. Is it possible to overwrite the balances in SF? I believe the Balances of a time account is not a database field and is calculated dynamically. Has anyone done this kind of integration? SF is also accruing (to enable viewing future projected balances) and hence the need to overwrite the balances as iChris is the source of truth. Appreciate any guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/import-time-account-balances-from-3rd-party-systems/qaq-p/14266204"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:04:37.546000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-monitor-outstanding-liabilities-pos-without-invoices-in-s-4hana/qaa-p/14266207#M4231232</id>
    <title>Re: How to Monitor Outstanding Liabilities (POs without I...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:07:03.725000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vallabhasatish90</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1771629</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Please check Fiori APP -&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Monitor GR/IR Account Reconciliation. There are many internal reports within the app that would give you some insights for PO GR and IR values.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-monitor-outstanding-liabilities-pos-without-invoices-in-s-4hana/qaa-p/14266207#M4231232"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:07:03.725000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/want-to-earn-more-badges-let-s-discuss/bc-p/14266209#M967</id>
    <title>Re: Want to Earn More Badges? Let’s Discuss!</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:08:55.513000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>zfiori</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1829</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keep learning, keep funning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ZFiori.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/want-to-earn-more-badges-let-s-discuss/bc-p/14266209#M967"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:08:55.513000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-find-an-easier-way-to-do-conditional-aggregation-in-sac/qaa-p/14266211#M4931460</id>
    <title>Re: Cannot find an easier way to do conditional aggregati...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:09:25.561000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/852123"&gt;@quincycheng1992&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I think you have done it correctly using multiple measures. 2 for Boolean evaluation, 2 for aggregation of these Booleans and finally the division. The default SAC behavior is Aggregation first, calculation next. But If you see you calculate first and aggregate next&amp;nbsp; and then calculate again given the nature of your calculation. Another thing is SAC separates different type of calculation namely Calculated, Restricted and Aggregation. SAC is more like Lego approach where you build the parts first and finally tie them together hence multiple kinds of measures. I agree to you that at times ( mostly) this is inefficient primarily due to increase in count of measures. Other BI tools allow you to merge different behavior in a single calculation as they do not differentiate between calculation/restriction and aggregation. Lets put it this way this differentiation of calculation is something flowing from historical SAP BI/BW tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps !&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nikhil&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-find-an-easier-way-to-do-conditional-aggregation-in-sac/qaa-p/14266211#M4931460"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:09:25.561000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-can-i-schedule-the-data-transfer-of-budget-forecast-from-sap-analytics/qaa-p/14266215#M4931461</id>
    <title>Re: How can I schedule the data transfer of Budget/Foreca...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:15:03.549000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2092597"&gt;@ElenaTheophili&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The below link covers and answers most of your queries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/1cbcff7ccd35405ab445b223c1ab1588/15447e5bda934be28f3b16cfb456fb23.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/1cbcff7ccd35405ab445b223c1ab1588/15447e5bda934be28f3b16cfb456fb23.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nikhil&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-can-i-schedule-the-data-transfer-of-budget-forecast-from-sap-analytics/qaa-p/14266215#M4931461"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:15:03.549000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/navigating-the-sap-learning-help-center-your-gateway-to-seamless-learning/bc-p/14266217#M580</id>
    <title>Re: Navigating the SAP Learning Help Center: Your Gateway to Seamless Learning Support!</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:15:44.396000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Siddique1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1453823</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Very well explained.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/navigating-the-sap-learning-help-center-your-gateway-to-seamless-learning/bc-p/14266217#M580"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:15:44.396000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-integrate-sap-btp-cloud-logging-service-with-sap-cloud-identity/bc-p/14266218#M186243</id>
    <title>Re: How to Integrate SAP BTP Cloud Logging Service with SAP Cloud Identity Services (IAS) Using SAML</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:15:44.493000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shusei_sekiya</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46547</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Wallace,&lt;BR /&gt;According to the note below, the current version does not support OIDC integration between SAP Cloud Logging and IAS. However, it indicates that this capability will be available after validation, likely during or after Phase 2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;What: We will be upgrading from OpenSearch 1.3 to 2.19. This upgrade brings:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;· Security &amp;amp; compliance hardenings&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;· Performance &amp;amp; stability improvements, including improved query performance, memory efficiency, and index handling&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;· Powerful new features including&amp;nbsp;Index management improvements, Enhanced anomaly detection, Better integration with SAML, OIDC (which we will enable shortly after validation), Improved Alerting, Shrink API, Support for additional SQL/DSL queries&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When: The upgrade will happen in 3 phases&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;·&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Phase 1 "Prepare"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(anytime): Prepare for the consumption of the upgrade by analyzing the adaptation guide&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;·&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Phase 2 "Explore"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(&lt;EM&gt;starting July 10&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":disappointed_face:"&gt;😞&lt;/span&gt; Opt-in to the upgrade version via feature flag for creating new or updating existing Cloud Logging instances to OpenSearch 2.19. Use this phase to validate integrations, explore features, verify custom dashboards &amp;amp; provide feedback, or to prepone the productive usage of OpenSearch 2.19.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;·&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Phase 3 "Adopt"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(&lt;STRONG&gt;starting November 27&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":disappointed_face:"&gt;😞&lt;/span&gt; All Cloud Logging instances will be force-upgraded to the new OpenSearch version 2.19&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-logging/cloud-logging/configuration-parameters" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuration Parameters | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3617458" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3617458 - SAP Cloud Logging: OpenSearch Stack Update Available - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-integrate-sap-btp-cloud-logging-service-with-sap-cloud-identity/bc-p/14266218#M186243"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:15:44.493000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/copy-and-paste-a-cell-from-sac-to-excel-cause-numbers-desconfiguration/qaa-p/14266219#M4931462</id>
    <title>Re: Copy and paste a cell from SAC to Excel cause numbers...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:21:42.023000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/884776"&gt;@priscilla_barbosa82&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you check if the excel user preference and SAC user preference for using comma and decimal separators are identical. This looks like a mismatch between excel settings and SAC settings. In SAC comma is the separator and may be in Excel the setting is something different.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps !&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nikhil&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/copy-and-paste-a-cell-from-sac-to-excel-cause-numbers-desconfiguration/qaa-p/14266219#M4931462"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:21:42.023000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/inconsistent-results-from-resource-amp-resource-recent-access-models/qaa-p/14266220#M4931463</id>
    <title>Re: inconsistent results from Resource &amp; Resource_Recent_...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:23:15.813000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Bingo, Resource_Recent_Access is driven by Activity.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/inconsistent-results-from-resource-amp-resource-recent-access-models/qaa-p/14266220#M4931463"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:23:15.813000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/target-was-not-found-fiori-app/qaa-p/14266224#M4931464</id>
    <title>Re: Target was not found-Fiori app</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:27:09.753000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Veeranna_Vyapari</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1884968</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, did you get any solution , i am facing the same issue for cost center budget report standard app</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/target-was-not-found-fiori-app/qaa-p/14266224#M4931464"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:27:09.753000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/standard-bank-file-format-quot-jp-zenginkyo-quot-does-not-output-data-in/qaq-p/14266225</id>
    <title>Standard bank file format "JP_ZENGINKYO" does not output data in SAP public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:28:15.070000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>khanhlynx99</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/854654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi experts,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I used the standard format&amp;nbsp;"JP_ZENGINKYO" to output a bank file, and although the CSV file was created, no data was displayed (except for Kind of record (constant) ).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_0-1762927047858.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339084iE654DB96DEB05DC8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_0-1762927047858.png" alt="khanhlynx99_0-1762927047858.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using a new format created by copying the standard one and changing the mapping source of some fields, I gained a bank file with some information corresponding to the edited fields.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I.e.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;・Standard format&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_1-1762927471195.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339086i54B8D2264EAF0103/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_1-1762927471195.png" alt="khanhlynx99_1-1762927471195.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;・Customized format&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_3-1762927546122.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339088iC7415E47B26E7325/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_3-1762927546122.png" alt="khanhlynx99_3-1762927546122.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And some other similarly edited fields.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The bank file&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_4-1762927633864.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339089i3DFE31E25EF14E2A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_4-1762927633864.png" alt="khanhlynx99_4-1762927633864.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Trace result shows that the edited fields received input values, meaning the system can still extract data from master data and payment, but&amp;nbsp;the unedited fields have blank input values, meaning the standard format's sources are not passed with data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_5-1762927740543.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339090iD65001FA06BE08B6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_5-1762927740543.png" alt="khanhlynx99_5-1762927740543.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I came up with an idea that we might need to customize the logic to pass values for these fields. However, in the app "Custom logic", the source of the standard format (table: FPAYHX) is not under CHANGING parameters but IMPORTING parameters, making it not customizable in Fiori launchpad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="khanhlynx99_6-1762928683449.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339095i6594978A2AC24209/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="khanhlynx99_6-1762928683449.png" alt="khanhlynx99_6-1762928683449.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do you have any idea why the sources of the standard format (FPAYHX-REFxx) cannot receive any values? Debugging is not supported in SAP public cloud, so we cannot determine the exact location of the problem.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you very much.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/standard-bank-file-format-quot-jp-zenginkyo-quot-does-not-output-data-in/qaq-p/14266225"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:28:15.070000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/financial-execution-amp-claims-for-trade-promotions-with-sap-revenue-growth/ba-p/14266226</id>
    <title>Financial Execution &amp; Claims for Trade Promotions with SAP Revenue Growth Management &amp; SAP Cloud ERP</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:29:05.659000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karenshentu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/887103</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635623592"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Bridging the Gap Between Promotion Planning and Financial Accuracy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Imagine you are a Key Account Manager (KAM) at a leading beverage manufacturer working with a large retail chain. You design various trade promotions (e.g., discounts, displays, rebates) to boost sales and market presence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Yet, managing associated trade spends, reconciling retailer claims, and ensuring precise financial settlements can be an operational heada&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;che for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;finance controllers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, who play a critical role in overseeing and validating all financial postings related to trade spend, ensuring accuracy, compliance, and accountability throughout the process. Supporting this effort is the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Order-to-Cash (O2C) specialist&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, responsible for managing the end-to-end order process, including order fulfillment, invoicing, and handling claims or disputes related to trade promotions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manual reconciliation, delayed financial clarity, and disconnected systems often hinder teams from accurately measuring promotion effectiveness and revenue impa&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ct, ultimately slowing the growth that KAMs and consumer packaged goods (CPG) companies depend on.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is where our solution steps in, with its Financial Execution and Claims capabilities that seamlessly bridge trade promotion planning and financial execution with the SAP S/4HANA ecosystem. By connecting promotions planned in SAP Revenue Growth Management directly to financial execution i&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;n S/4HANA and then to claims management, we off&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;er a fully automated end-to-end solution for financial posting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439110087"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. A Suite Designed to Integrate and Simplify Trade Spend Execution: SAP Revenue Growth Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/crm/revenue-growth-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Revenue Growth Management (REVENUE GROWTH MANAGEMENT)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; serves as a central platform enab&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ling CPG companies to create, plan, and monitor promotions with built-in integration into SAP S/4HANA’s finance and sales modules. Trade promotion tactics such as discounts, rebates, and display funding are transformed into condition contracts and&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;condition records for pricing within SAP S/4HANA, becoming the found&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ation for financial execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The execution phase uses these contracts and condition records for pricing during invoicing, ensuring promotions reflect correctly in accounting. Following execution, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;claims are submitted by retailers for reimbursements or deductions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in many different forms and methods. Once these documents and back-up materials are obtained, the claims&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; are matched against the condition contracts. Approved claims trigger settlements, creating credit memos or adjustments that close the loop for accurate revenue recognition. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This end-to-end integration reduces manual work, prevents errors like overpayments, and offers finance teams full visibility in&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to promotional trade &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;spend&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; obligations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. It also&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; empowers KAMs to achieve measurable revenue growth—all &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;operating&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; out-of-the-box within the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;B&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;usiness &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;S&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;uite&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Financial Execution and Claims 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339094iE2634B4483AB43F5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Financial Execution and Claims 1.png" alt="Financial Execution and Claims 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Target i&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ntegration &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;landscape &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;for financial execution and settlement of trade promotions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;For more information on our current capabilities, see &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blogs-by-sap/introducing-calendar-view-in-sap-revenue-growth-management-a-visual-leap/ba-p/14051325" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;An Overview of SAP Revenue Growth Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242596582"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Key Functionalities of Financial Execution and Claims in SAP Revenue Growth Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175165796"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3.1. Variable Discounts Explained&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Variable discounts, also known as OI discounts (can be called either on-invoice or off-invoice depending on the region), are discounts directly applied to the invoice. They happen only during the sell-in process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Effective Pricing Strategy Enablement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Variable discounts provide KAMs with the agility to implement pricing tactics such as a percentage off the list price or fixed amounts directly on sales invoices. This capability supports strategic selling, such as volume discounts or targeted discou&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;nts (e.g., for specific channels, customers, or timing), driving&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; retailer engagement without cumbersome manual interventions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Direct Invoice Application&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since variable discounts apply at invoice generation (sell-in phase), financial postings are immediate and precise. This direct connection between promotions and invoicing simplifies reconciliation and reduces disputes from the start.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The precision enabled by variable discounts not only ensures timely and precise financial postings but also guarantees that retailers receive precise invoices, leading to improved retailer satisfaction and stronger business partnerships.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Financial Execution and Claims 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339096iECC4DAA578869569/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Financial Execution and Claims 2.png" alt="Financial Execution and Claims 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Trade &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;pend&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;cenarios&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978652291"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3.2. Comprehensive Variable and Fixed Rebates Management&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accrual-Based Rebate Handling&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Revenue Growth Management allows setting aside accruals for both variable and fixed rebates. This ensures liabilities are reserved accurately in financial accounts, streamlining budget control.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Variable rebates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, also known as bill backs or retroactive rebates in the US, are rebates that vary based on sales or shipment volumes. Variable rebates can apply to all segments of the distribution chain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, including sell-in, sell-through, and sell-out.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fixed rebates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, also known as lump sums, such as display fees or feature costs, do not depend on product movements within the distribution chain but remain constant over a promotional period.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Su&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;pport for Rebate Payment Processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Revenue Growth Management facilitates various payment methods, such as credit memos against accounts receivable, and plans to support accounts payable processes for retailer invoice claims in 2026. This versatility aligns with varying corporate accounting practices and enhances transparency and efficiency in managing trade spend.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Proper accrual management ensures rebate liabilities are consistently and correctly recognized in financial accounts, enabling compliant and timely accounting postings. This approach builds confidence and efficiency within finance teams, supports KAMs by providing transparent visibility into trade spend, and facilitates appropriate sales revenue recognition.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782138786"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3.3. End-to-End Claims Management and Settlement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unified Claim Request Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All trade-related claims from retailers — whether deduction claims due to short pays or invoice claims requesting reimbursement — are consolidated within RGM Claims Management. This provides a single source of truth&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;with full visibility into claims status, approval workflows, and linkage to financial postings and settlements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Validation and Workflow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The system supports claim matching to corresponding promotions, with validation rules that reduce manual errors and allow multiple analysts to perfo&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;rm different validations in parallel, enhancing operational efficiency in complex accounts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Settlement and Financial Transparency (planned for 2026)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Settlement functionality, integrated with SAP S/4HANA condition contracts, will &lt;/SPAN&gt;automate&lt;SPAN&gt; the creation of settlement and accounting documents, ensuring accurate financial execution. This upcoming capability will enhance audit compliance and provide clearer visibility into trade spend.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ultimately, these capabilities help KAMs and CPG companies deliver smoother processes and have more satisfied retail customers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-456542562"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Co-Innovation: Advancing Financial Execution and Claims Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the Financial Execution and Claims capabilities of SAP Revenue Growth Management, CPG companies benefit from an integrated, fully automated end-to-end financial posting process that links key functions such as variable discounts, variable and fixed rebate management, and unified claims handling.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This seamless integration facilitates timely financial postings and enhances visibility into trade spending, empowering finance controllers and KAMs throughout the trade promotion lifecycle.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If you're a finance controller, O2C specialist, or a KAM&lt;/STRONG&gt; eager to innovate how promotions translate into accurate financial outcomes and tangible business results, cont&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;act us today at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:RGM_Engage@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;RGM_Engage@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to join our co-innovation program. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Together, let's shape financial execution and claims with SAP Revenue Growth Management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-513671221" id="toc-hId-518194495"&gt;More Information&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/rgm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Documentation on SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.api.community.sap.com/topics/revenue-growth-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Topic Page for&amp;nbsp;SAP Revenue Growth Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-calendar-view-in-sap-revenue-growth-management-a-visual-leap/ba-p/14051325" target="_blank"&gt;Introducing Calendar View in SAP Revenue Growth Management: A Visual Leap for Strategic Planning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/decoding-promotional-success-embedded-analytics-in-sap-revenue-growth/ba-p/14083999" target="_blank"&gt;Decoding Promotional Success: Embedded Analytics in SAP Revenue Growth Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-trade-spend-control-efficiency-with-funds-management-in-sap/ba-p/14106404" target="_blank"&gt;Unlocking Trade Spend Control Efficiency with Funds Management in SAP Revenue Growth Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/consolidating-customer-planning-unleash-growth-with-sap-revenue-growth/ba-p/14166630" target="_blank"&gt;Consolidating Customer Planning: Unleash Growth with SAP Revenue Growth Management’s Account Plan&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/elevate-your-promotion-strategy-baseline-management-with-sap-revenue-growth/ba-p/14183638" target="_blank"&gt;Elevate Your Promotion Strategy: Baseline Management with SAP Revenue Growth Management&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-promotion-excellence-streamlined-creation-and-copying-with-sap/ba-p/14219774" target="_blank"&gt;Driving Promotion Excellence: Streamlined Creation and Copying with SAP Revenue Growth Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/financial-execution-amp-claims-for-trade-promotions-with-sap-revenue-growth/ba-p/14266226" target="_blank"&gt;Financial Execution &amp;amp; Claims for Trade Promotions with SAP Revenue Growth Management &amp;amp; SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/financial-execution-amp-claims-for-trade-promotions-with-sap-revenue-growth/ba-p/14266226"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:29:05.659000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-data-import-automatically-email-rejected-error-rows-to-specific-users/qaa-p/14266227#M4931465</id>
    <title>Re: SAC Data Import – Automatically email rejected/error...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:29:35.019000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035488"&gt;@Eladtayarr&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can try your hands at the below API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/14cac91febef464dbb1efce20e3f1613/486aacd8e39d45209dd3702ad9da9eb8.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/14cac91febef464dbb1efce20e3f1613/486aacd8e39d45209dd3702ad9da9eb8.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635623593"&gt;/jobs/{jobID}/invalidRows&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This endpoint lists the rejected rows and the reason for failure after validation is completed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Hope this helps !&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Nikhil&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-data-import-automatically-email-rejected-error-rows-to-specific-users/qaa-p/14266227#M4931465"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:29:35.019000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-can-we-bundle-an-extension-to-submit-for-sap-commerce-cloud/qaa-p/14266230#M4931466</id>
    <title>Re: How can we bundle an extension to submit for SAP Comm...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:34:13.161000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pvadla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1532094</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1812388" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;RadhikaInugala&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please refer to the following link for information on the commerce extension for certification process . For further assistance, you may contact the SAP Integration and Certification Center (SAP ICC) as outlined in the link.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-premium-certification-for-hybris-commerce-extensions/ba-p/13323621" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-premium-certification-for-hybris-commerce-extensions/ba-p/13323621&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;kindly check if the above info is helpful.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-can-we-bundle-an-extension-to-submit-for-sap-commerce-cloud/qaa-p/14266230#M4931466"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:34:13.161000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sapb1-service-layer-error-while-connecting-to-database-server/qaa-p/14266231#M4931467</id>
    <title>Re: SAPB1 Service Layer Error while connecting to databas...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:36:30.636000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ANKIT_CHAUHAN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7756</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1983044"&gt;@PARAGMewada&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to rule out any underlying issue, could you try to reinstall Service Layer once and share the results with us?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ANKIT CHAUHAN&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sapb1-service-layer-error-while-connecting-to-database-server/qaa-p/14266231#M4931467"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:36:30.636000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-count-the-number-of-repeated-rows-in-story-table/qaa-p/14266232#M256344</id>
    <title>Re: How to count the number of repeated rows in story table</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:37:06.761000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2264248"&gt;@tara_shi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;May be you could try COUNTDIMENSION on category&amp;nbsp; in story calculation with calculation Type aggregation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nikhil&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-count-the-number-of-repeated-rows-in-story-table/qaa-p/14266232#M256344"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:37:06.761000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/inventory-multiple-counters-service-layer/qaa-p/14266233#M4231233</id>
    <title>Re: Inventory Multiple Counters Service Layer</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:40:28.083000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ANKIT_CHAUHAN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7756</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/970950"&gt;@byrongomez&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check if the following blog post helps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/inventory-counting-in-sap-business-sdk/ba-p/13322114" target="_blank"&gt;Inventory Counting in SAP Business SDK&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ANKIT CHAUHAN&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/inventory-multiple-counters-service-layer/qaa-p/14266233#M4231233"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:40:28.083000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/navigating-the-sap-learning-help-center-your-gateway-to-seamless-learning/bc-p/14266235#M581</id>
    <title>Re: Navigating the SAP Learning Help Center: Your Gateway to Seamless Learning Support!</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:44:18.767000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vaishnavir</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/823765</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Useful blog at right time to plan learning journey for upcoming year ! Good job Sandy !&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/navigating-the-sap-learning-help-center-your-gateway-to-seamless-learning/bc-p/14266235#M581"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:44:18.767000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/export-data-to-excel-in-sap-build-apps-using-javascript-and-flow-functions/bc-p/14266236#M176308</id>
    <title>Re: Export Data to Excel in SAP Build Apps Using JavaScript and Flow Functions</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:45:50.236000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>saplover</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1428636</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;hi interesting blog. Do you have any idea how to convert page variable type list of objects (table with data) to excel ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;User want to export table list in SAP Build app to excel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/export-data-to-excel-in-sap-build-apps-using-javascript-and-flow-functions/bc-p/14266236#M176308"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:45:50.236000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/vibe-coding-when-ai-writes-the-code-benefits-challenges-and-guardrails/ba-p/14266237</id>
    <title>Vibe Coding: When AI Writes the Code — Benefits, Challenges, and Guardrails</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:46:04.669000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>da_radix</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/703241</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From my experience leading engineering and delivery teams for high-value projects, I’ve understood that technology changes fast — and the way people leverage technology changes faster. Through the emerging rhythm of ‘Vibe coding’ developers &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;speed up each stage of the SDLC, minimize mundane work, and experiment while maintaining quality. It also helps programmers with intelligent code completions, pre-built templates, and l&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;everage AI suggestions, so thathey can &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;focus more on innovation, complex logic, and architecture. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://radixweb.com/blog/artificial-intelligence-statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;72% of global organizations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; use AI in at least one of their business domains. AI utilization is thrilling yet equally unnerving. The potential is remarkable, but it also comes with a huge responsibility.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, here’s my take on the opportunities, the risks, and the guidelines every organization needs to consider.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764706343"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why ‘Vibe Coding’ Matters Now&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;use cases of AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; have grown beyond its specific role to be a significant component of the dev team. Large language models, code generation tools, and specialized AI agents help draft modules, propose optimizations, and auto-generate tests. For enterprises prioritizing data sensitivity, integration, and complexity, this transformation is more than a strategic imperative. It helps change how we define value, delivery velocity, and team dynamics.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Speaking from my tech leadership experience, I’ve witnessed project schedules accelerate, and prototypes that took weeks to design are completed in a few days. This gave product owners and architects more time to think about long-term goals. However, speed without a structured approach is simply chaos. And that’s where expertise and experience are pressing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568192838"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Opportunities: Velocity, Innovation, and Scale&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are three big opportunities I often reflect on.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Velocity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; - AI-powered programming speeds up routine tasks like data-mapping code, unit tests, boilerplate, scaffolding, which further allows engineers to emphasize more on the challenging elements – business rules, edge-cases, and architecture. And for specific implementations, where orchestrations, BAPIs, and connector code are commonly used, code automation can drastically minimize time-to-value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Innovation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – When algorithms manage mundane activities, teams can innovate faster. You must ensure that your product teams improvise on &amp;nbsp;feature ideas with AI-enabled flow diagrams and mockups, streamlining the feedback process from stakeholders and clients. It’s seamless to experiment when testing a hypothesis becomes more cost-efficient.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scale &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– AI helps maintain standardization across extensive codebases and team structures. Trained models automatically recommend uniform code patterns; this keeps your enterprise's ‘coding vibe’ logical and seamless.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371679333"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Threat: Complacency, Drift, and Hidden Pitfalls&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, the flip side also demands attention.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Complacency&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – This drawback is real. If dev teams start accepting AI results on the surface, bugs emerge. I’ve observed that even the teams with good intentions might push out integration logic or autogenerated SQL that didn’t adhere to data sovereignty standards, edge inputs, and concurrency. These lapses might violate compliance or breach master data integrity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Drift &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Model drift and hallucinations are also the most significant concerns. AI sometimes might generate credible code or documentation that indirectly breaks security standards or business logic. If not checked early, these drifts enter production.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Human Risk &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– The biggest hidden pitfall is loss of skill. If engineers stop learning basic concepts, like debugging middleware, understanding BAPI contracts, or reading complex ABAP flows, it can erode the organization’s long-term strategic capability. This is a real issue that can be combatted only with a culture of continuous learning. Afterall, AI is here to compliment human abilities, but without human governance and intervention, it cannot make ethicll calls. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175165828"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Guidelines: Build for Trust, Not Just Speed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To experience the strengths while also managing the risks, development teams require an architecture of practice and governance. Drawing from our experience of working on specific projects, here are solid guardrails I would suggest.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define a ‘Trusted AI Baseline’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Refine&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; prompt libraries and train models using your organization’s secure patterns and best practices. I recommend managing a library of carefully designed model policies and prompt templates in line with your specific integration patterns, security controls, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://aws.amazon.com/what-is/service-level-agreement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;client SLAs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Default to Human Supervision &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Humans should first review every AI-generated modification&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. For design-based decisions, transfer outputs to product owners for verification against the business results. And for code, combine the AI’s recommendation tools with a named reviewer who has a good know-how of system invariants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Observability and Provenance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Maintain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; the record of suggestions made by AI, who approved it, and which version/model generated it. This traceability is non-negotiable for continuous improvements, debugging, and audits — particularly for businesses that majorly function under strict compliance demands.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ongoing Validation: Tests + Contracts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Go&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for automatic test generation alongside &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-based programming&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. For seamless integrations, you can design contract tests that help define throughput limits, expected error modes, and assert schemas. The automatic tests are like your safety net that lets you speed up while ensuring reliability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Talent Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keep your team members' skills honed by conducting frequent in-depth workshops on core topics, switching up team roles and responsibilities, and AI-based training for higher efficiency. We invest in resources for structured learning workflows that integrate AI-powered labs guided by experts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978652323"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How Can You Make it REAL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Try&amp;nbsp;implementing these principles across different initiatives and collaborations. Some proven strategies I advise using include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hybrid Pipelines -&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Incorporate AI into &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://about.gitlab.com/topics/ci-cd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CI/CD pipelines&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; so that AI-produced outputs prompt the same contract tests, security scans, and static analysis as human-generated code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Co-Created Models - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For long-term clients, continuously refine private models based on anonymized snippets of the code, architecture docs, and integration logs. This helps make AI-powered suggestions aligned to corporate frameworks and context-driven.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transparent Delivery -&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Every pull request AI assists or generates needs to be&amp;nbsp;identified, audited, and monitored, streamlining compliance and post-launch maintenance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Client Workshops - C&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;onduct governance and skills development training sessions that consist of red-team simulation exercises — deliberately coaxing AI toward risky results to train teams to identify and address potential issues.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782138818"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Human Equation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the race towards AI-led transformation, the human equation is of utmost importance. Cutting-edge technologies like AI help optimize decisions, analyze data at scale, and automate processes. Still, it is human perspective, ethical oversight, and creativity that unlock the real potential of AI. If you opt for AI-driven innovation, don’t just focus on deploying algorithms—keep your team members in the loop to ensure that teams guide, verify, and apply human context to machine outputs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, by focusing on seamless collaboration between AI and humans, businesses can align speed with responsibility, driving innovation while managing risks. Ultimately, it’s the amalgamation of human governance and AI capabilities that defines long-term evolution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-585625313"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Takeaway&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I’m optimistic! When powered by knowledge and structured by guardrails, Vibe Coding can revolutionize how dev teams build. It empowers humans to focus on things machines cannot - define objective, map out strategies, and employ critical thinking. The key for quick-moving businesses lies in striking the right balance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, if you’re considering integrating Vibe Coding, begin with pilot projects, capture all data, and keep humans in the loop. Well, the future isn’t humans vs. AI — it’s the seamless collaboration of AI with humans, vibing to design and develop more intelligent systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/vibe-coding-when-ai-writes-the-code-benefits-challenges-and-guardrails/ba-p/14266237"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:46:04.669000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-can-i-develop-an-add-on-that-needs-an-object-that-doesn-t-exist-in-the/qaa-p/14266238#M4931468</id>
    <title>Re: How can I develop an add-on that needs an object that...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:46:51.476000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ANKIT_CHAUHAN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7756</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2264682"&gt;@cssius&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The method you’re using is incorrect, particularly inserting data directly into system tables like OTFC or ONNM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This practice will void your SAP support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ANKIT CHAUHAN&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-can-i-develop-an-add-on-that-needs-an-object-that-doesn-t-exist-in-the/qaa-p/14266238#M4931468"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:46:51.476000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sapb1-service-layer-error-while-connecting-to-database-server/qaa-p/14266239#M4931469</id>
    <title>Re: SAPB1 Service Layer Error while connecting to databas...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:50:50.167000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PARAGMewada</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1983044</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Dear Ankit,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sapb1-service-layer-error-while-connecting-to-database-server/qaa-p/14266239#M4931469"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:50:50.167000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sap-ewm-posc-process-short-and-crisp/qaq-p/14266240</id>
    <title>SAP EWM POSC process (short and crisp)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:51:29.292000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>_Swapnil_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1465449</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Colleagues,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is a brief information about the setup of POSC process&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configuration - EWM&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Cross process setting&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Warehouse Task&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Define POSC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. External Storage Process steps - Here we assign the external storage process steps to already defined internal process steps. For example IB01 (unload) is assigned to UNLO&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Process Oriented Storage Control - Here we above defined external step is assigned to the warehouse. And the source storage type from where the step should be triggered, WPT and destination storage type are assigned. Additionally we can also define the section and bins of the destination storage type&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Storage Process Definition - Here we assign the storage process to the warehouse. In addition we aslo assign the direction to it (whether putaway, stock removal or internal process)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.1 Assign storage process step - In this we assign the external steps (above point 1) to the storage process and warehouse in a sequence as below&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="_Swapnil__0-1762929678792.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339099i41190D654CCCE8A7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="_Swapnil__0-1762929678792.png" alt="_Swapnil__0-1762929678792.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The additional columns are auto WT creation (this creates WT automatically once the preceding step is completed), prod/HU warehouse task and the duration in which the task should be completed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sap-ewm-posc-process-short-and-crisp/qaq-p/14266240"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:51:29.292000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sapb1-service-layer-error-while-connecting-to-database-server/qaa-p/14266241#M4931471</id>
    <title>Re: SAPB1 Service Layer Error while connecting to databas...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:51:58.084000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PARAGMewada</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1983044</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Dear Ankit, Thank you for Replay, and Inform You that last week we did same practice reinstall everything include service layer, but it works till yesterday accidentally what happen dont know, it shows error message</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sapb1-service-layer-error-while-connecting-to-database-server/qaa-p/14266241#M4931471"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:51:58.084000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/marketplace-app-deployment-amp-lifecycle-management-using-sap-devops-tools/qaa-p/14266242#M4931472</id>
    <title>Re: Marketplace App Deployment &amp; Lifecycle Management Usi...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:54:40.162000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Suheb</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1558812</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Deploying and managing a marketplace app using SAP DevOps tools involves streamlining the entire application lifecycle — from development to monitoring — through automation and continuous integration. SAP DevOps integrates tools like SAP Cloud ALM, CI/CD pipelines, and Transport Management System (TMS) to ensure smooth and consistent deployments across environments. Developers can build, test, and release marketplace apps faster using SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) and SAP Continuous Integration and Delivery Service, reducing manual intervention and errors. With built-in monitoring and analytics, teams can track performance, detect issues early, and ensure compliance with governance policies. Overall, SAP DevOps enables a reliable, automated, and scalable approach to marketplace app deployment and lifecycle management.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/marketplace-app-deployment-amp-lifecycle-management-using-sap-devops-tools/qaa-p/14266242#M4931472"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:54:40.162000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/di-api-price-assignment-invalid-after-changing-rdr1-itemcode/qaa-p/14266243#M4231234</id>
    <title>Re: DI API: Price Assignment Invalid After Changing Rdr1...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:54:41.182000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ANKIT_CHAUHAN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7756</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253026"&gt;@superpop&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the correct system behavior and it is required to update the document twice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly refer to SAP KBA&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3486918" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3486918&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3494796" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3494796&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;for similar scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP Business One client, calculations for Unit Price, Discount % and other fields are event-driven. The fields are calculated and pre-filled before the 'add' button is pressed. Unlike in DI-API or Service Layer, there are no event-driven actions. When changing the list of items and adjusting any price-related properties, the DI-API or Service Layer will execute specific sets of reverse calculation rules to determine linked properties.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ANKIT CHAUHAN&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/di-api-price-assignment-invalid-after-changing-rdr1-itemcode/qaa-p/14266243#M4231234"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:54:41.182000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/mrp-planning-issue/qaa-p/14266244#M208099</id>
    <title>Re: MRP Planning Issue</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:55:46.043000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>t_hemant</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/869115</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Caetano, In our business scenario, the header material is considered as a dummy material. It is not a physically manufactured or stocked item — its main purpose is to act as a structural element for BOM explosion so that the dependent components can be planned and procured as required. That’s why we have maintained MRP type “ND” (No Planning) for the header material — we don’t want the system to create any planned orders for it. However, we still want the dependent materials to be planned and generate planned orders (for in-house, procurement type “E”) or purchase requisitions (for external procurement, procurement type “F”). For this reason, all dependent components are maintained with MRP type “PD”, allowing the system to plan them automatically once the BOM is exploded. Essentially, the header material is only a technical structure to drive component planning — not a production or inventory-controlled item.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/mrp-planning-issue/qaa-p/14266244#M208099"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:55:46.043000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-landed-cost-works-in-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/qaa-p/14266245#M4231235</id>
    <title>Re: How Landed Cost works in S/4Hana Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:56:28.666000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Fernando,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, we use the term "Actual Costing".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please read the documentation on the SAP Help Portal: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/7f47a6d9441c46ac86c96fd27f6015f0/4cc57871cfca4755a96d3929f16d9e38.html?version=2508.VAL" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Actual Costing.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And here's the scope item information:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/2508/SolP/33Q?region=DE" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Actual Costing (33Q)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Henrike&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-landed-cost-works-in-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/qaa-p/14266245#M4231235"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:56:28.666000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-monitor-outstanding-liabilities-pos-without-invoices-in-s-4hana/qaa-p/14266246#M4231236</id>
    <title>Re: How to Monitor Outstanding Liabilities (POs without I...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:57:41.990000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>byd</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1424802</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you for the helpful suggestion! I've checked the "Monitor GR/IR Account Reconciliation" (F3302) app and confirmed it works well for tracking **goods received but not yet invoiced** (GR/IR clearing account balances). However, I noticed this app only shows items where **at least GR or IR has been posted**. It doesn't display **POs that haven't had any GR yet**. **My broader requirement is:** To monitor **total future cash outflow**, regardless of invoice registration status, across different procurement scenarios: **For inventory/stock items:** 1. PO issued → GR not posted → IR not posted (not visible in F3302) 2. PO issued → GR posted → IR not posted (visible in F3302) ✓ **For expense/non-stock items (e.g., services, consumables with cost center assignment):** 3. PO issued → No GR process → IR not posted 4. PO issued → No GR process → IR posted → Payment not executed **Follow-up questions:** - Is there a standard Fiori app to view **uninvoiced PO amounts before GR posting** (purchase order commitments) for both stock and non-stock items? - For non-stock purchases with cost center assignment, I understand scope item 2I3 (Predictive Commitment Management) can track commitments - does this also cover the scenario before invoice receipt? - Or is there a consolidated report/app that shows **total outstanding payables** (commitments + GR/IR + open AP) in one view? The business objective is to forecast cash requirements for the upcoming period, so we need visibility into all stages of the procurement-to-pay cycle. Thanks again for your help, and I appreciate any additional guidance!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-monitor-outstanding-liabilities-pos-without-invoices-in-s-4hana/qaa-p/14266246#M4231236"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:57:41.990000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-batch-upload-g-l-accounts-in-s-4-public-cloud-edition/qaa-p/14266247#M4231237</id>
    <title>Re: How to batch upload G/L accounts in S/4 Public Cloud Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:00:57.720000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, thank you for your question. It has been forwarded to the experts. Kind regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-batch-upload-g-l-accounts-in-s-4-public-cloud-edition/qaa-p/14266247#M4231237"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:00:57.720000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/question-about-di-server-license-compatibility-with-sap-business-one-10-0/qaa-p/14266249#M4231238</id>
    <title>Re: Question about DI Server License Compatibility with S...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:02:47.883000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ANKIT_CHAUHAN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7756</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2264000"&gt;@Sopida_Yotharit18&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Refer to SAP KBA &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3366480" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3366480&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/890591" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;890591&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the same.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ANKIT CHAUHAN&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/question-about-di-server-license-compatibility-with-sap-business-one-10-0/qaa-p/14266249#M4231238"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:02:47.883000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-api-odata-security-part-iii-oauth2-0-authorization-code-flow/bc-p/14266250#M176310</id>
    <title>Re: SAP API OData Security Part III – OAuth2.0 Authorization Code Flow</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:04:39.505000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vishal_Panda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265123</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Ravi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Great blog, Easy to understand and helpful.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a small question though, the OAuth example which you have given is used for a Non SAP Application updating data into SAP Table (POST Call) and due to security issues, we would require token and authentication.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a requirement that data from an SAP system is to be sent to a Non-SAP System. We want to enable OAuth2 for this activity. In This case we are using doing only Read operation and there is no Updation/Creation or Deletion of the data involved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So below are my queries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) What will be the steps for token exchange in that case?&amp;nbsp;Do I still need to access the X-CSRF token using Post Method&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) Is OAuth 2 required or suggested in such scenarios or the Base 64 encoding is enough.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-api-odata-security-part-iii-oauth2-0-authorization-code-flow/bc-p/14266250#M176310"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:04:39.505000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E5%88%A0%E9%99%A4%E9%85%8D%E7%BD%AE500043-102631/qaq-p/14266254</id>
    <title>删除配置500043-102631</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:06:00.879000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kongqi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1615844</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;管理您的解决方案（102631确定备选的统驭科目）有配置错误的地方，如何删除？&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E5%88%A0%E9%99%A4%E9%85%8D%E7%BD%AE500043-102631/qaq-p/14266254"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:06:00.879000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/mrp-planning-issue/qaa-p/14266255#M208100</id>
    <title>Re: MRP Planning Issue</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:15:33.401000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dominik_Tylczynski</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/141029</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Why don't you use sales BOM for your header material?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/mrp-planning-issue/qaa-p/14266255#M208100"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:15:33.401000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/assign-tolerance-groups-to-employees/qaa-p/14266256#M4231240</id>
    <title>Re: Assign tolerance groups to employees</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:16:19.225000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>khanhlynx99</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/854654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi NaveenP1,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/assign-tolerance-groups-to-employees/qaa-p/14266256#M4231240"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:16:19.225000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/qapp-cust-ip-f4-inspection-point-help/qaa-p/14266257#M4231241</id>
    <title>Re: QAPP_CUST_IP_F4 - inspection point help</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:18:09.227000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SriSanjay1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1619661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/qapp-cust-ip-f4-inspection-point-help/qaa-p/14266257#M4231241"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:18:09.227000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E5%A4%84%E7%90%86%E5%8F%91%E7%A5%A8%E7%9A%84%E4%BB%98%E6%AC%BE%E9%A1%B9%E7%9B%AE%E6%8A%A5%E9%94%99/qaa-p/14266258#M4231242</id>
    <title>Re: 处理发票的付款项目报错</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:19:06.566000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Machine Translation Portal translation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Error processing payment items for invoice&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Error processing payment item for invoice: No valid payment method found.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Payment method H has actually been selected in the journal entry voucher&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E5%A4%84%E7%90%86%E5%8F%91%E7%A5%A8%E7%9A%84%E4%BB%98%E6%AC%BE%E9%A1%B9%E7%9B%AE%E6%8A%A5%E9%94%99/qaa-p/14266258#M4231242"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:19:06.566000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/qapp-cust-ip-f4-inspection-point-help/qaa-p/14266259#M4231243</id>
    <title>Re: QAPP_CUST_IP_F4 - inspection point help</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:19:10.744000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SriSanjay1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1619661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi, Sumit</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/qapp-cust-ip-f4-inspection-point-help/qaa-p/14266259#M4231243"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:19:10.744000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/qapp-cust-ip-f4-inspection-point-help/qaa-p/14266262#M4231244</id>
    <title>Re: QAPP_CUST_IP_F4 - inspection point help</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:21:41.701000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SriSanjay1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1619661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Sumit, Can we make the value list as drop down for the user field? If yes, could you please suggest how we can make the value list as a drop down</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/qapp-cust-ip-f4-inspection-point-help/qaa-p/14266262#M4231244"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:21:41.701000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E5%A4%84%E7%90%86%E5%8F%91%E7%A5%A8%E7%9A%84%E4%BB%98%E6%AC%BE%E9%A1%B9%E7%9B%AE%E6%8A%A5%E9%94%99/qaa-p/14266263#M4231245</id>
    <title>Re: 处理发票的付款项目报错</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:21:53.837000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, thank you for your question. It has been forwarded to the experts. Kind regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E5%A4%84%E7%90%86%E5%8F%91%E7%A5%A8%E7%9A%84%E4%BB%98%E6%AC%BE%E9%A1%B9%E7%9B%AE%E6%8A%A5%E9%94%99/qaa-p/14266263#M4231245"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:21:53.837000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/in-group-reporting-data-monitor-is-used-for-preparation-of-consolidation/qaa-p/14266264#M256345</id>
    <title>Re: In Group Reporting , Data monitor is used for prepara...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:23:20.565000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MikeTjoeng</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135550</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Naga&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Group Reporting is used to consolidate all Entity Close data from various companies within the group, hence the term group closing or Consolidation. The Data Monitor is often referred as to Consolidation preparation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Steps in the Data Monitor contains:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;* The Data Entry Process ( Collecting the data from various Companies)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*&amp;nbsp; Calculation of Anual Net Income ( that does not come from the Entity Close)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*&amp;nbsp; Data Validation ( You have Corporate Standards on the Data Quality)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;* Adjustment Postings ( These contain correction postings from Entity Close or Standardized Postings to make adjustments to meet Corporate business guidelines)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;* Currency Conversion ( Entites deliver data in their reporting currencies, but for Group to Consolidate these data you need to translate it to the Group Currency)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consolidation Monitor&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is where after Consolidation Preparation the Consolidation process starts&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Interunit Elimination ( These are transactions that happen in between Companies ) They need to be neutralize cause they do not contribute to the Group Income as for an example and hence need to be taken off&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consolidation of Investment ( This is where according to the Ownership Structure the Investments get eliminated against Capital and where the Income generated is calculated according to the ownership shares you have in each of the Companies from Group Perspective.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The straight forward and easy case is if you own 100% of the company, but very likely this is not the case in a lot of large enterprises and hence not all profits are belonging to the group but also then to the minorities, that needs to be eliminated out.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is under the nutshell what Group Reporting does I hope this helps&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR Mike&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/in-group-reporting-data-monitor-is-used-for-preparation-of-consolidation/qaa-p/14266264#M256345"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:23:20.565000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/introduction-to-universal-revenue-recognition/bc-p/14266265#M62416</id>
    <title>Re: Introduction to Universal Revenue Recognition</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:24:09.532000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sellwerk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1940755</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Volkmar, very interesting scenario, in case of subscription are consumption models and rebates supported?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Frank&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/introduction-to-universal-revenue-recognition/bc-p/14266265#M62416"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:24:09.532000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-you-know-the-vendor-number-in-mdg-and-its-corresponding-vendor/qaq-p/14266273</id>
    <title>How do you know the vendor number in MDG and its corresponding vendor number in S4HANA?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:24:40.609000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>newguy_cloud</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1492327</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi MDG Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;May I know how do you check the mapping of a vendor in SAP MDG (source) versus its vendor code in SAP S4HANA (target)? Is there a configuration or SAP standard table that is being maintained?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If yes, please provide the path in IMG or the SAP standard table?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Newguycloud&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-you-know-the-vendor-number-in-mdg-and-its-corresponding-vendor/qaq-p/14266273"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:24:40.609000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unified-destination-setup-for-accessing-multiple-odata-services-in-bas/qaa-p/14266274#M4931477</id>
    <title>Re: Unified Destination Setup for Accessing Multiple OData Services in BAS</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:25:27.973000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, thank you for your question. It has been forwarded to the experts. Kind regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unified-destination-setup-for-accessing-multiple-odata-services-in-bas/qaa-p/14266274#M4931477"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:25:27.973000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-members/integrating-sap-ariba-slp-with-s-4hana-public-cloud-using-sap-master-data/bc-p/14266284#M1985</id>
    <title>Re: Integrating SAP Ariba SLP with S/4HANA Public Cloud Using SAP Master Data Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:26:14.120000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sarah_Ashour</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2226883</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;Karthikeyan_C,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for this blog it helps me a lot,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've a question regarding CIG Connection configuration,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;in basic data you mentioned&amp;nbsp;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;System ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subdomain ID,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;but in connection&lt;STRONG&gt; system id &lt;/STRONG&gt;is the &lt;STRONG&gt;identity zone &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;amp; there is no option to enter it manually so how can it be different.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I see the same in same documentation, but I couldn't apply it in my cig project connection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Much appreciate your support&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-members/integrating-sap-ariba-slp-with-s-4hana-public-cloud-using-sap-master-data/bc-p/14266284#M1985"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:26:14.120000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/control-parameter-for-instant-pr-creation-by-saving-the-sales-order/qaq-p/14266285</id>
    <title>Control parameter for instant PR creation by saving the Sales Order</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:28:23.660000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>reck</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/718955</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Experts,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;i have a doubt regarding PTO process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the combination of TAS as item category + CS as schedule line category, i can create an sales order with a material ( even without MRP view )&amp;nbsp; . By saving this order , a purchase requisite would be created immediately. Yes i know this is a typical 3rd party process. But i am curious, which parameter controls this automatic flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I know to enable the whole process we need quite a lot parameters in customizing and material master data, but i am more interested in the immediate action of creating PR. Is this because of the setting in CS (e.g. Ordert type NB ?) , or any setting in TAS,&amp;nbsp; or even the requirement type on position level in my sales order ( i checked the requirement type is empty ).&amp;nbsp; ?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The reason is we may need a similar process to create a one-on-one PR for sales without MRP run, and&amp;nbsp; we need to create Z category and types to enable that. Thus i need to know which parameter trigger this immdiate creation of PR, so that i can set them correctly at the correct place.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/control-parameter-for-instant-pr-creation-by-saving-the-sales-order/qaq-p/14266285"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:28:23.660000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-trm-daily-compounding-interest-calculation/qaa-p/14266287#M256346</id>
    <title>Re: SAP TRM Daily Compounding Interest Calculation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:29:14.395000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, thank you for your question. It has been forwarded to the experts. Kind regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-trm-daily-compounding-interest-calculation/qaa-p/14266287#M256346"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:29:14.395000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sales-order-bom-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-edition/qaa-p/14266288#M4231247</id>
    <title>Re: Sales Order BOM - SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:30:28.072000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, thank you for your question. It has been forwarded to the experts. Kind regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sales-order-bom-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-edition/qaa-p/14266288#M4231247"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:30:28.072000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/5le-data-protection-and-privacy-btp-connectivity/qaq-p/14266289</id>
    <title>5LE - Data Protection and Privacy. BTP Connectivity.</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:33:12.517000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Brooks1e</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1810723</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello - I am looking at the BTP side of scope item 5LE.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is not very clear whether I need to set up just a "proxy_connection" user or if I actually need to activate the service assignment "Data Privacy".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are no boosters for this scope item and the best practice PDF for this scope item isn't very clear.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any guidance would be appreciated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/5le-data-protection-and-privacy-btp-connectivity/qaq-p/14266289"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:33:12.517000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-index-creation-failure-in-sum-phase-eu-clone-mig-dt-run/bc-p/14266294#M186244</id>
    <title>Re: Handling Index creation failure in SUM phase EU_CLONE_MIG_DT_RUN</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:37:46.471000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NitinGupta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1615368</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great blog,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1792430"&gt;@Dinendra_Hijam&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-index-creation-failure-in-sum-phase-eu-clone-mig-dt-run/bc-p/14266294#M186244"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:37:46.471000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/in-group-reporting-data-monitor-is-used-for-preparation-of-consolidation/qaa-p/14266295#M256347</id>
    <title>Re: In Group Reporting , Data monitor is used for prepara...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:37:57.311000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MareikeBaudewig</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1469507</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Naga, hello Mike,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;you can also check out the following SAP Help Portal documentation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/90c07e91c7a64f328be3fd6b48955b13/7f023b8f3d00435b8973c5ba49b46e9f.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Monitor&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/90c07e91c7a64f328be3fd6b48955b13/4cd20a30dd35426a9a15e3e91d61acc4.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Consolidation Monitor&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/90c07e91c7a64f328be3fd6b48955b13/5eef55b0da37467287c52bf0ac1e8a0a.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Reclassification-Based Interunit Elimination&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this helps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Mareike&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/in-group-reporting-data-monitor-is-used-for-preparation-of-consolidation/qaa-p/14266295#M256347"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:37:57.311000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/smarter-quality-management-with-ai-assisted-processing-sap-s-4hana-cloud/bc-p/14266296#M62417</id>
    <title>Re: Smarter Quality Management with AI-Assisted Processing - SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:38:30.937000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Suresh-Eswaran</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2142883</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/271052"&gt;@chandra_reddy1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the detailed blog!!!&lt;BR /&gt;Could you please confirm whether the SAP Document AI license alone is sufficient, or we also need AI Units to test this functionality in the Public Cloud system (TDD)?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/smarter-quality-management-with-ai-assisted-processing-sap-s-4hana-cloud/bc-p/14266296#M62417"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:38:30.937000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-trm-daily-compounding-interest-calculation/qaa-p/14266297#M256348</id>
    <title>Re: SAP TRM Daily Compounding Interest Calculation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:43:51.975000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>william_cao</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/339742</uri>
    </author>
    <content>May I ask which financial product you are simulating?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-trm-daily-compounding-interest-calculation/qaa-p/14266297#M256348"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:43:51.975000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fiori-app-equivalent-to-transaction-mrn3-in-s-4hana-public-edition/qaq-p/14266299</id>
    <title>Fiori app equivalent to transaction MRN3 in S/4HANA Public Edition?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:47:31.734000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>byd</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1424802</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community,&lt;BR /&gt;Does SAP S/4HANA Public Edition have a Fiori app equivalent to transaction code MRN3?&lt;BR /&gt;If yes, please provide:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;・App name&lt;BR /&gt;・App ID&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fiori-app-equivalent-to-transaction-mrn3-in-s-4hana-public-edition/qaq-p/14266299"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:47:31.734000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/building-joule-skills-for-sales-order-queries-in-s-4hana-cloud-part-1/bc-p/14266300#M780</id>
    <title>Re: Building Joule Skills for Sales Order Queries in S/4HANA Cloud - Part 1: Environment Setup</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:58:01.792000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BharathKumarVaddepalli</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1989797</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2215539"&gt;@teng_teng69&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hi Teng&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for the clarification.&lt;BR /&gt;My actual question is — if we have different APIs, for example, one for Sales Orders and another for Purchase Orders, can we access both using a single destination, or do we need to create separate destinations for each?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank You&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bharath Kumar V&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/building-joule-skills-for-sales-order-queries-in-s-4hana-cloud-part-1/bc-p/14266300#M780"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:58:01.792000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/project-valuation-class-does-not-work/qaa-p/14266301#M4231250</id>
    <title>Re: project valuation class does not work</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T08:58:59.205000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bin_wu2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/585161</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi friend, thanks for your help. If I did not activate split valuation, then QKLAS does not work, right?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/project-valuation-class-does-not-work/qaa-p/14266301#M4231250"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T08:58:59.205000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
