<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-11-20T19:14:01.733404+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/project-progress-monitoring-tools/qaa-p/14273829#M208228</id>
    <title>Re: Project Progress Monitoring Tools</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T14:44:46.789000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>paul_wb</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2266586</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks Lakshmipathi! Regarding monitoring project supply chain progress using specialized reports and Fiori apps, I'm looking for a single report for the PM, Project Controller and Project Supply Chain Manager that displays all the supply chain progress information for project in one report (not several). Do you know of anything like this? If so, how should I find it in S4? Regarding multiple projects, I can't find the "Project Procurement Overview" in S4. I'm new to working with S4 and have still a lot to learn about this new version. What transaction would this be in ECC, if it exists in it? Thanks for the two links included, especially the blog link!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/project-progress-monitoring-tools/qaa-p/14273829#M208228"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T14:44:46.789000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/adobe-pdf-file-in-excel-format-with-same-layout/qaq-p/14273832</id>
    <title>Adobe PDF file in Excel format with same layout.</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T14:46:14.968000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mandeep_Rait1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2745</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi community,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;We have a requirement from the customer -&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;They want the Adobe PDF form to be displayed in an excel file. So, we are looking for a way to convert it programmatically/ any other tools.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Note: The layout should be the same.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/adobe-pdf-file-in-excel-format-with-same-layout/qaq-p/14273832"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T14:46:14.968000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-when-querying-a-sac-story-that-consumes-data-from-an-analytical-model/qaa-p/14273841#M4932095</id>
    <title>Re: Error when querying a SAC story that consumes data fr...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T14:50:04.519000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>miquelfornieles</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/151594</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi MArtin, thanks again for your comment. I forgot to mention that we did test creating the SAC report from scratch; however, the issue persists. To display a table with 200k records, it takes almost 3 minutes, and sometimes a timeout occurs. Regards. Miquel</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-when-querying-a-sac-story-that-consumes-data-from-an-analytical-model/qaa-p/14273841#M4932095"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T14:50:04.519000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-papm-the-role-of-business-calculation-engine-in-a-business-steering/ba-p/14271287</id>
    <title>SAP PAPM - the role of business calculation engine in a business steering</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T14:53:13.329000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>irinasheftelevich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/74514</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture 1. End-to-end profitability and performance management" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342720i33930AF9A100414D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="irinasheftelevich_3-1763562792885.png" alt="Picture 1. End-to-end profitability and performance management" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 1. End-to-end profitability and performance management&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MOTIVATION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;In today's fast-paced business world, the ability to effectively steer and lead an organization is fundamental for achieving strategic goals and maintaining a competitive edge. A key success criterion is the capacity to fully harness and derive value from organizational data. Many companies struggle with data problems, such as fragmented information, outdated systems, and the super important task of preparing data for emerging technologies like AI. Recognizing these challenges, we are excited to introduce a blog series dedicated to showcasing the substantial business value of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) in the context of planning and analytics.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;The motivation behind this initiative is to provide a comprehensive exploration of how SAP BDC capabilities as essential instruments, facilitating robust strategic alignment and guiding effective decision-making processes across diverse organizational requirements. We aim to illustrate how SAP BDC, equipped with powerful data management, planning, analytics and innovative AI capabilities, empowers organizations with enhanced business steering agility by providing real-time insights, streamlined data management, and automated decision support – going from insights to action, helps mainly leaders guide their businesses with precision.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Our blog series will provide valuable insights for decision-makers seeking to harness SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) to enhance operational efficiency, optimize resource allocation, and achieve long-term objectives. By featuring detailed planning &amp;amp; analytics topics, the series will illustrate the transformative impact of SAP BDC in addressing the operational complexities of today’s business environment. This first introductory blog post will spotlight the strategic advantages of SAP BDC, particularly in the context of Business Steering, setting the stage for a deeper exploration of its benefits throughout the blog series.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;There are several blog posts in the series that will cover advantages of SAP BDC in the context of business steering, so please stay tuned for the upcoming blogs:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-in-the-context-of-business/ba-p/14165827" target="_blank"&gt;The Value of SAP BDC in the context of business steering&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-amp-analytics-p-amp-a-is-an-essential-part-of-sap-business-data/ba-p/14223762" target="_blank"&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Analytics is an essential part of SAP BDC&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/key-planning-amp-analytics-components-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc/ba-p/14238066" target="_self"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Key Planning &amp;amp; Analytics components of SAP BDC&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Is AI going to “retire” a dashboard?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Simulations, a game changer in today’s volatile world&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extend-existing-planning-scenarios-of-sap-bpc-bw-ip-in-sap-bdc/ba-p/14234247" target="_self"&gt;Extend existing planning scenarios of SAP BPC/BW-IP in SAP BDC&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Real-time steering with LIVE planning&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;SAP PaPM - The role of business calculation engine in business steering &lt;STRONG&gt;(THIS BLOG POST)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Self – service analytics and real time business steering&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Business steering powered by AI agents&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Leverage data products in the context of planning &amp;amp; forecasting&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Introducing AI/ML capabilities by SAP Databricks&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In today’s fast-paced business environment, enterprises must be flexible and adaptable to evolving market conditions and customer expectations. As a result, companies are developing strategies focused on innovation, digital transformation, and sustainable growth. However, when it comes to execution, the benefits of these strategic initiatives often fall short of expectations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why the Gap?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Several factors contribute to the disconnect between strategy and execution:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Insufficient analysis and adaptation to business changes, making strategies difficult to execute in real-world conditions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Weak integration between financial and operational models, leading to misaligned decisions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lack of trust in the numbers due to data silos and overly complex reporting models.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Poor visibility into root causes of performance, whether underperformance or overachievement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is where the concept of &lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Performance Management (EPM)&lt;/STRONG&gt; becomes critical. EPM serves as the bridge between strategic goals and day-to-day execution. SAP offers a comprehensive, end-to-end EPM framework that spans planning, consolidation, tax, and sustainability management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Despite advancements, organizations still face hurdles in their EPM processes, that are highly connected to the reasons for the gap between strategy and execution:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New regulations &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;and market dynamics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data &amp;nbsp;silos&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and disconnected processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Limited business context in performance reporting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To address these, companies increasingly need a &lt;STRONG&gt;business semantics calculation engine &lt;/STRONG&gt;as an important part of their EPM framework —a solution that connects transactional and planning data to management reporting in real time. Such an engine should enable:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business-user-driven modeling&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; through a no-code/low-code environment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration of business semantics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (e.g., cost allocations, profitability logic) into real-time calculations, powered by solutions like SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Simulation and scenario analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; without IT dependency&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s explore how a business semantics calculation engine can bring value across different scenarios not only for actuals, but also for planning data:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regulatory reporting:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Ensure compliance with traceable, rule-based calculations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Profitability analysis:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Evaluate performance by customer segment, region, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;channel&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;or product line.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bill of Materials (BOM) simulation and explosion:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Assess the impact of changing prices or quantities on semi-finished and final products.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Operational transfer pricing:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Maintain compliance and transparency in cross-border pricing models.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Group cost calculations:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Enable unified and transparent cost modeling across entities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For instance, in a BOM simulation, users can assess how price or quantity changes at the component level affect the cost of the final product. This often involves recursive, high-volume calculations. By using SAP S/4HANA for transactional data, enriching it with SAP Profitability and Performance Management (SAP PaPM), and feeding the results into SAP Analytics Cloud, businesses can maintain full transparency, auditability, and planning granularity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Another example: planned profitability calculations at the SKU level. While this level of detail may be unnecessary in the core budgeting process, it's critical for management reporting. Rather than overburdening the core planning system, businesses can offload these complex calculations to a dedicated engine and integrate the results seamlessly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Last but not the least example to illustrate the need in business calculation engine is a group costing calculation. Let's say the company has many intercompany relationships, products and services are going through various steps between companies in this process. SAP PAPM delivers real-time insights into group margin, through segmented profit and loss reports according to key transfer pricing dimensions, providing needed data to manage and analyze tax costs and revenues, markups and markup costs, production and services costs and third-party revenues. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefits of Embedding a Calculation Engine into the Planning Process&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automate complex allocations and business logic&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ensure full transparency and auditability&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enable granular planning and analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;—by customer, product, channel, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Increase compliance by following new regulations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From the business user’s perspective, this process should be seamless. As a planner, you simply run the calculation and see results immediately integrated into your planning reports. This is precisely the kind of user-centric experience enabled by the SAP EPM framework—combining &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Profitability and Performance Management (SAP PaPM)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture 2. Detailed Profitability analysis powered by SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP PAPM" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342736i295E1ADECF68C368/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="irinasheftelevich_0-1763565536376.png" alt="Picture 2. Detailed Profitability analysis powered by SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP PAPM" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 2. Detailed Profitability analysis powered by SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP PAPM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;WHAT IS SAP PAPM?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP PaPM Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is a no-code calculation engine that empowers business users to model and execute complex logic without IT intervention. It processes large data volumes at high speed and supports a wide range of EPM scenarios.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key capabilities include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extending standardized processes in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA &lt;/STRONG&gt;with custom logic and allocations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enabling business users to model complex rules &lt;STRONG&gt;without coding&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Processing &lt;STRONG&gt;massive data sets&lt;/STRONG&gt; in-memory via &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrating data from &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP and non-SAP sources&lt;/STRONG&gt;, hosted on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Creating &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;financial documents&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;postings to general or group ledger&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and more in SAP S/4HANA enabling an end-to-end process, and not just running as a disconnected calculation engine&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ensuring &lt;STRONG&gt;full traceability&lt;/STRONG&gt; from results to source data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture 3. SAP Profitability and Performance Management" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342717i0F5CFE1461FBEA70/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="irinasheftelevich_1-1763562297031.png" alt="Picture 3. SAP Profitability and Performance Management" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 3. SAP Profitability and Performance Management&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP PAPM and SAP BUSINESS DATA CLOUD&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP PAPM can on top of BDC, in this case data persistency and processing happens on the SAP Datasphere level in SAP BDC. With SAP BDC Data products we can ensure context-rich data from SAP and non- SAP sources being available for PAPM calculations, building a foundation for detailed transparent analysis and also providing even more data for AI-powered insights.&amp;nbsp; Another benefit of placing SAP PAPM on top of SAP BDC is that with SAC being also part of the platform, we can really ensure end-to-end EPM processes without data replication, leveraging seamless planning and when needed extending calculations with SAP PAPM engine to achieve even greater transparency and performance.&amp;nbsp; Ream more about BDC components in our previous blog "&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/key-planning-amp-analytics-components-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc/ba-p/14238066" target="_blank"&gt;Key Planning &amp;amp; Analytics components of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/A&gt;"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture 4. SAP Business Data Cloud components" style="width: 939px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342718i63A13B36F4072892/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="irinasheftelevich_2-1763562362100.png" alt="Picture 4. SAP Business Data Cloud components" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 4. SAP Business Data Cloud components&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s take a look at the data flow for a corporate profitability analysis within an SAP landscape.&lt;BR /&gt;The initial data originates in the transactional system or system of record, SAP S/4HANA. While S/4HANA already provides capabilities for cost calculation and allocation, we can further enrich this data with performance results and details—such as customer segment, region, channel, or product line—and incorporate simulations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To achieve this, we introduce an additional BDC-based layer that leverages BDC data products and SAP Datasphere to connect to S/4HANA, as well as other potential data sources and prepare the data. SAP PaPM then performs the calculations, and SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) visualizes the results and provides a planning-process framework for end users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture 5. Corporate profitability analysis with SAP solutions" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343087iA27FCFC21D461CA5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="{C8969F89-2017-4C45-91EA-6B1C2ED42C7D&amp;amp;#125;.png" alt="Picture 5. Corporate profitability analysis with SAP solutions" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 5. Corporate profitability analysis with SAP solutions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A business semantics calculation engine is a powerful tool in enhancing the efficiency and effectiveness of EPM processes. Whether it’s for tax, transfer pricing, profitability modelling, or planning enhancements, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Profitability and Performance Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; plays an important role in bridging the gap between transactional data and reporting requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By embedding SAP PaPM within your EPM architecture, you can equip business users to act even faster, have greater insights, and align execution more closely with strategic intent. SAP Business Data cloud will provide a proven semantically reach data foundation and AI tools to simplify analysis, we will be giving more detailed examples in our next articles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking to take the next step? Connect with your SAP representative to register for an SAP BDC Discovery Workshop.&lt;BR /&gt;To expand your expertise in SAP PaPM, consider exploring the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/forums/searchpage/tab/message?filter=location&amp;amp;q=papm&amp;amp;location=blog-board:financial-management-blog-sap&amp;amp;collapse_discussion=true" target="_self"&gt;related blog series published within the SAP Community &amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;and stay tuned for more.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-papm-the-role-of-business-calculation-engine-in-a-business-steering/ba-p/14271287"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T14:53:13.329000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-proxy-generation-support-with-sap-integration-suite/bc-p/14273848#M186518</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP Proxy generation support with SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T14:54:15.166000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kamranbazmi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/119633</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/272095"&gt;@radhika_javvaji&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1582379"&gt;@KevinSong&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My issue is now resolved. The proxy objects were there but under a different bucket. I followed steps below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1- Run t-code SPROXY.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2- Goto menu Utilities --&amp;gt; Settings&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3- Scroll to the tab Proxy Generation and change the Enterprise Service Browser setting to "D Enterprise Service Browser"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4- Back out and re-run SPROXY.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5- Follow node Source --&amp;gt; ESR --&amp;gt; SWCs and you will see your custom integration packages there.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note:- Choose Re-usable option while migrating your SAP PO interfaces to integration suite. Otherwise, no objects will be created in the backend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope it helps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kamran&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-proxy-generation-support-with-sap-integration-suite/bc-p/14273848#M186518"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T14:54:15.166000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/pricing-report-in-mm/bc-p/14273861#M72262</id>
    <title>Re: Pricing Report in MM</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T14:58:38.632000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stedjo2000</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2264750</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot for this useful KT. I need to know how to delete an existing pricing report in MM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regard,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stéphane&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/pricing-report-in-mm/bc-p/14273861#M72262"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T14:58:38.632000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/s-4-hana-public-cloud-how-to-print-standard-text-in-custom-adobe-form/qaq-p/14273872</id>
    <title>S/4 HANA Public Cloud: How to print Standard Text in custom adobe form</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:03:57.268000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ramanjaneyareddy_p</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2254137</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am able to create the standard text, but unable to get the standard text details in S/4 HANA Public Cloud Adobe form.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ramanjaneyareddy_p_0-1763646787858.png" style="width: 280px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343236i10A4D1BBCB3EAD6C/image-dimensions/280x186/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="280" height="186" role="button" title="ramanjaneyareddy_p_0-1763646787858.png" alt="ramanjaneyareddy_p_0-1763646787858.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ramanjaneyareddy_p_1-1763647065620.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343245iDAF1C804CCF352E2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ramanjaneyareddy_p_1-1763647065620.png" alt="ramanjaneyareddy_p_1-1763647065620.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to print above text in adobe form, could you please provide the steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in Advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/s-4-hana-public-cloud-how-to-print-standard-text-in-custom-adobe-form/qaq-p/14273872"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:03:57.268000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/po-not-getting-creating-error-express-document-quot-update-was-cancelled/qaq-p/14273874</id>
    <title>PO not getting creating error EXPRESS DOCUMENT "UPDATE WAS CANCELLED"</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:04:49.756000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ANKITAPRAJAPATI1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2052868</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we are creating PO for a particular company code, while saving it says PO got created under number. but when viewing it pop-up comes EXPRESS DOCUMENT "UPDATE WAS CANCELLLED" by author.&lt;BR /&gt;Please find the SM13 screenshot,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-11-13 171450.png" style="width: 358px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343233i22CAA1CE08AD4B08/image-dimensions/358x182/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="358" height="182" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-11-13 171450.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-11-13 171450.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;also, I've checked the number range, but it's look fine.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you please help us to solve the issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks &amp;amp; regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ankita&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/po-not-getting-creating-error-express-document-quot-update-was-cancelled/qaq-p/14273874"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:04:49.756000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-process-automation-configuring-microsoft-365-email-provider-for/bc-p/14273877#M186519</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Build Process Automation – Configuring Microsoft 365 email provider for SMTP mail destinatio</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:08:25.510000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vincent00</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/773322</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1531465"&gt;@Erwan67&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thank you for your (very) quick response &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’ve checked it, and everything looks good to me.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So I’ve created a case at SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Vincent&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-process-automation-configuring-microsoft-365-email-provider-for/bc-p/14273877#M186519"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:08:25.510000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/vendor-automatically-changes-to-head-office-vendor-during-supplier-invoice/qaq-p/14273878</id>
    <title>Vendor Automatically Changes to Head Office Vendor During Supplier Invoice Posting in SAP S/4HANA</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:11:36.325000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Praveen06</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1676610</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are working on SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud 3SL in India localization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our supplier has multiple GST registrations across different states, so we created one vendor BP for each GSTIN (branch vendors). We also have one Head Office (HO) Vendor with bank details, which is maintained as the Alternative Payee for payment run purposes. This is aligned with GST design.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expected SAP Standard Behaviour&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Invoices (PO-based &amp;amp; non-PO) must always post to the branch vendor, because GST reporting is state-specific.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Only the APP payment run should redirect payment to the HO Vendor via Alternative Payee.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Issue We Are Facing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During supplier invoice posting (Create Supplier Invoice / MIRO equivalent), even after selecting the branch vendor, SAP automatically replaces the vendor with the HO vendor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system shows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Account has been changed: dependent data will be initialised.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The invoice is finally posted to the HO vendor, which is incorrect for GST and vendor reconciliation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What We Have Already Validated&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No custom logic exists in Custom Logic (BAdI) app&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;PO is created with the correct branch vendor&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Branch vendor has no bank details&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;HO Vendor is maintained only as Alternative Payee&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No extensions are influencing vendor fields&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Questions to the Community&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this automatic replacement of vendor during invoice posting standard behaviour in S/4HANA Public Cloud 3SL?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does Alternative Payee affect invoice posting, or only the payment run?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could this be caused by BP Partner Functions (FLVN01 → Purchasing → Partner Functions)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Should SSCUI 102561 (Partner Determination for Supplier) or 102617 (Supplier Account Groups) be checked for default partner assignments?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is the correct SAP recommended configuration for multi-GST vendor scenarios where invoice must post to branch vendor and payment must go to HO vendor?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need a confirmation from SAP experts because invoice posting to HO vendor breaks GST compliance and vendor-level ageing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance for your guidance.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/vendor-automatically-changes-to-head-office-vendor-during-supplier-invoice/qaq-p/14273878"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:11:36.325000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/decimal-amount-in-wip-acc-rev-post-0l-amp-amp-2l/qaa-p/14273881#M4231857</id>
    <title>Re: Decimal amount in WIP Acc Rev post 0L &amp;amp; 2L.</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:17:39.037000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Petr_Eisinger</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1641300</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Customer,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for reaching out. Based on the information provided, it’s difficult to fully evaluate your case. Please note that the event-based revenue recognition period-end close run will only reduce accrued or deferred revenue to zero when the project stage is set to Completed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If further investigation is required, we recommend creating a customer incident with SAP for detailed analysis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Petr&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/decimal-amount-in-wip-acc-rev-post-0l-amp-amp-2l/qaa-p/14273881#M4231857"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:17:39.037000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/implementing-bapi-contract-change/qaa-p/14273882#M4932099</id>
    <title>Re: Implementing BAPI_CONTRACT_CHANGE</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:18:25.948000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>A_Ramesh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1779414</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1467797"&gt;@FabioMendona&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fabio,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We did this change for BAPI_PO_CHANGE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We did not implement any other BADIs or Exits, but, an existing user exit was posing a problem.&amp;nbsp;EXIT_SAPMM06E_016&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It was not a problem in ECC but in S4 it was. Had to add this as first block in user exit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;IF i_no_screen EQ abap_true "Called by Function ( BAPI )
   OR i_aktyp EQ 'A'.

  " This is being called by a Function module ( BAPI ) or Called in Dialog in Display mode
  " During display, data derivation should not happen

  ekpo_ci = CORRESPONDING ekpo_ci( i_ekpo ).

  RETURN.

ENDIF.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/implementing-bapi-contract-change/qaa-p/14273882#M4932099"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:18:25.948000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/latest-people-profile-configuration/qaa-p/14273884#M49457</id>
    <title>Re: Latest People Profile Configuration</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:20:30.645000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aaron_Corban</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/174396</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;Linda,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope you are well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upon checking this KBA associated with your query -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3601520" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3601520&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- it mentions the below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"Currently, it is not possible to modify or hide this display using configuration or permission settings. The People Profile Preview will display "N/A" for employees who do not have Department data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you believe this is an important subject for your business requirements, please consider submitting an enhancement idea by following the instructions listed in KBA&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2090228" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/2090228&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Aaron&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/latest-people-profile-configuration/qaa-p/14273884#M49457"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:20:30.645000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2511/bc-p/14273885#M186520</id>
    <title>Re: SAP BTP ABAP Environment - Release 2511</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:24:02.523000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FrankJentsch</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4296</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I corrected the blog post regarding the Email Templates (ADT editor was shipped, no Fiori app) and I added the documentation link to the Analytical Table feature und the hint to live demos.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2511/bc-p/14273885#M186520"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:24:02.523000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/pd7a-report-shows-employee-assigned-to-the-incorrect-business-number/qaq-p/14273886</id>
    <title>PD7A report shows employee assigned to the incorrect business number</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:26:04.599000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sarah1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/63744</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have several employees that show up in my PD7A report, assigned to the wrong business number for past pay periods. How can I re-assign them to a different business number and also have the system re-calculate the YTD amounts? I am very new to payroll.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/pd7a-report-shows-employee-assigned-to-the-incorrect-business-number/qaq-p/14273886"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:26:04.599000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-get-exchange-rate-for-customer-invoice/qaa-p/14273887#M4932100</id>
    <title>Re: How to get Exchange Rate for Customer Invoice?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:26:29.114000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mic_L</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121626</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi fceylan_hs,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wondering if you ever got an answer to this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We found that Invoice XML extract shows different structure than Odata service, hence we are not able to match the data. It ends up empty.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Curious how you have resolved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mic&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-get-exchange-rate-for-customer-invoice/qaa-p/14273887#M4932100"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:26:29.114000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/integrating-sap-s-4hana-with-kafka-via-sap-advanced-event-mesh-part1/bc-p/14273888#M176446</id>
    <title>Re: Integrating SAP S/4HANA with Kafka via SAP Advanced Event Mesh: Part1 – Outbound connection</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:26:43.533000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ckp</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1479976</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Great post, Sailee! Really enjoyed reading it. Keep it up!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":clapping_hands:"&gt;👏&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/integrating-sap-s-4hana-with-kafka-via-sap-advanced-event-mesh-part1/bc-p/14273888#M176446"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:26:43.533000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-production-ready-sap-composable-storefront-architecture-best/bc-p/14273895#M186521</id>
    <title>Re: Building a Production-Ready SAP Composable Storefront: Architecture, Best Practices &amp; Bluepr</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:36:23.709000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>gauravkamboj</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1042044</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Very detailed guide. T&lt;SPAN&gt;his will definitely be valuable for Spartacus developers and architects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-production-ready-sap-composable-storefront-architecture-best/bc-p/14273895#M186521"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:36:23.709000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/review-customer-projects-business-requirement-period-wise-project/qaa-p/14273896#M4231859</id>
    <title>Re: Review Customer Projects - Business Requirement: Peri...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:36:53.788000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dawid90</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172309</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/12596"&gt;@bangaru198251&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;below is a proposal of your requirements and available functionalities in the Public Cloud system, while maintaining the clean-core and Cloud-friendly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Story 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plan monthly effort in hours, use Plan Customer Projects&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F0719')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F0719')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/21218854c46ee75ee10000000a44176d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/21218854c46ee75ee10000000a44176d.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For each work package /role you can see availability per month and manually redistribute effort across periods of the work package (months in your case)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;That gives you a true time-phased baseline for effort and thus planned costs (since planned cost = hours × cost rate)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Run the monthly forecast review, use Review Customer Projects + Set Forecast Month:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/1a8fa3529556495592a29cdda3f70824.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/1a8fa3529556495592a29cdda3f70824.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/2c41db55e8187816e10000000a44538d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/2c41db55e8187816e10000000a44538d.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How variance is handled&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP standard logic when you set / change the forecast month is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Variances between planned and actual efforts and expenses before the new forecast month are plugged into the forecast month rather than being spread automatically across future months&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;So the system does calculate variance, but it concentrates it in the forecast month, not distributed into all remaining months&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get the forecast into Finance by period&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use Transfer Project Forecast to Finance:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This job takes the confirmed forecast from Review Customer Projects and creates / updates CO plan data in Finance, time-phased by period&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unlike Review Customer Projects, it looks at all actuals, not only up to the forecast month&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/5d577318fb924200877a167566837e81.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/5d577318fb924200877a167566837e81.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Story 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How cost rates work in Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Cost Rates Services&lt;BR /&gt;Define cost rates for professional services for combinations like: company code, receiving cost center, activity type, service cost level, employee (personnel number), work item and even WBS element&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/c56f622a2edf491b9f1b596b55587009/9fca5b12d8df4591a240100305da6357.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/c56f622a2edf491b9f1b596b55587009/9fca5b12d8df4591a240100305da6357.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Cost Rates Plan&lt;BR /&gt;Maintain planned activity prices by period (fiscal year/month) and ledger; these feed planning and (depending on set-up) can be used as the standard rate during the period&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/c56f622a2edf491b9f1b596b55587009/bd39911453324bf7900cccb4531e206e.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/c56f622a2edf491b9f1b596b55587009/bd39911453324bf7900cccb4531e206e.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage Cost Rates Actual&lt;BR /&gt;Store actual cost rates, manually or via Actual Cost Rate Calculation at period end. These override the other rates if maintained&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/c56f622a2edf491b9f1b596b55587009/10c16133145f4f0ca9be1e9e3e4a6cdd.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/c56f622a2edf491b9f1b596b55587009/10c16133145f4f0ca9be1e9e3e4a6cdd.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All these apps support time-dependency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Story 3&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where standard functionality diverges from your requirement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Employees record time using Manage My Timesheet&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the Professional Services scenario, process steps include:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Record time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Approve timesheet entries&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transfer time recordings to target components&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key points:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once a time entry is transferred to CO/Project, cost is posted immediately based on the cost rate determination&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note with details:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0002951857" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/0002951857&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can back post time into past periods as long as FI/CO periods are open so Timesheet entries can be posted for past periods when rates become available is standard&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You do see provisional cost during the month.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;But the final period cost equals hours × final rate, without needing to buffer hours.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Revenue recognition in customer projects already works with dynamic/confirmed EAC logic and will adjust PoC based on updated costs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Side-by-side BTP extension&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your business requirement is truly absolutely no cost postings before rate approval, you’d need a side-by-side design&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Story 4&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Standard month-end sequence&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Close time and billing for the month&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure timesheets are complete and transferred&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run project billing as needed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set Forecast Month&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use Set Forecast Month to set the current closed month as the forecast reference.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This controls which actuals are shown in Review Customer Projects and how previous variances are rolled into the forecast month&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/1a8fa3529556495592a29cdda3f70824.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/1a8fa3529556495592a29cdda3f70824.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review Customer Projects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transfer Project Forecast to Finance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run the job so that your updated forecast is written into time-phased financial plan data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/5d577318fb924200877a167566837e81.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/5d577318fb924200877a167566837e81.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/financial-planned-data-in-professional-services-by-project-financial/ba-p/14241364" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/financial-planned-data-in-professional-services-by-project-financial/ba-p/14241364&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/89d896ca9cd64318b1667df5ec00e4b2/5e6d33c7a74d4c528d496dde89c8957c.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/89d896ca9cd64318b1667df5ec00e4b2/5e6d33c7a74d4c528d496dde89c8957c.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Repeat next month&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Next month, set the forecast month forward and repeat the cycle so you’re literally working sequentially month by month.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Story 1 and 4 can be covered with standard Public Cloud (Professional Services) using: Plan Customer Projects, Review Customer Projects, Set Forecast Month and Transfer Project Forecast to Finance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Story 2 time-dependent rates are fully standard via Manage Cost Rates Services / Plan / Actual. The system works with validity periods and rate overrides (even down to WBS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Story 3 the hold hours until rates exist, then post once is not how Public Cloud works in standard&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dawid&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/review-customer-projects-business-requirement-period-wise-project/qaa-p/14273896#M4231859"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:36:53.788000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-doha-qa/ev-p/14273897</id>
    <title>🇰🇼 Getting started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core (Doha, QA)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:38:24.336000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vitaliy-R</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CodeJam&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;event is on the topic of&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Getting started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with Python. You don't need any prior background in the topic, but you should have a strong curiosity and basic coding skills.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this SAP CodeJam, you will learn how to use Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core to implement a retrieval augmented generation (RAG) use case to improve the responses of large language models (LLMs) and reduce hallucinations. You will learn how to work with LLMs and the orchestration service on SAP AI Core and query it via SAP AI Launchpad and the Python SDK. Furthermore, you will learn about the most important genAI concepts and create and use embeddings to improve your RAG response and build your own chatbot with memory.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is an&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;in-person event&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;only&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(not virtual, no streaming) and is planned for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wednesday, December 10&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;, 2025,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;from 10:00 to&amp;nbsp;16:00 local time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The event's language and content will be in English.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The event is being &lt;STRONG&gt;hosted by Mark9&lt;/STRONG&gt; at&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;A href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/Jdms6HRVFWbgMoH27" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Regus, D-Ring Road&lt;/A&gt;,&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Al Mataar / Al Qadeem District, Doha&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prerequisites: Bring your own laptop with&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a Chromium-based web browser, such as Google Chrome, Microsoft Edge, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that seating is limited to 20 seats and is available on a first-come, first-served basis.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-doha-qa/ev-p/14273897"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:38:24.336000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sf-compensation-worksheet-one-time-payment/qaq-p/14273898</id>
    <title>SF Compensation worksheet - one time payment</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:39:43.516000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Maria851</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/176150</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi experts,&lt;BR /&gt;I need to display in my salary review worksheet the various dates when the one-time payment was made.&lt;BR /&gt;Currently, the system reads the relevant portlet and shows only the latest value as of today.&lt;BR /&gt;How can I display all the different dates from one year onwards?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sf-compensation-worksheet-one-time-payment/qaq-p/14273898"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:39:43.516000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/splitting-100000-records-to-two-internal-tables-and-post-in-al11/m-p/14273900#M230</id>
    <title>Re: splitting 100000 records to two internal tables and post in al11</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:43:17.791000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>radinator</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/681078</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If I understand you correctly you have one internal table with 100k entries and you want to split them into 2 internal tables with 50k entries each?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If my assumption is correct you can do a very basic approach of looping at the main table and utilizing SY-INDEX variable as a index(er) (or create a index variable yourself - which you have to increase inside the loop. Add a IF statement that checks wether or not the current index is below 50k or above and distribute the data accordingly. Either you just move data from the original iTab to a second iTab or move data from the original one to iTab1 at counter &amp;lt; 50k and into iTab2 when counter &amp;gt; 50k. The LOOP AT structure allows you to either use a field symbol (for performance optimization) or work area. I would suggest you use the field-symbol approach since it is generally faster (due to the lack of the need for memory allocation) since you are working with a field symbol instead of moving data from the tab to a work area.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are also other methods that involve more advanced language features like the VALUE keyword but depending on your needs sometimes the easiest option is jus the best. If you want "the best" option you'd need to supply a bit more information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope it helps and: happy coding!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Edit: I overlooked the mentioning of AL11 in the title, do you wish to split the original table into 2 and export this into a file (with a certain format)? If so it would help&amp;nbsp;tremendously if you could specify a bit more what the output format should be. I imagine you need some sort of CSV format? For that the easiest way would be to use OPEN DATASET, but again: more details needed &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face_with_sweat:"&gt;😅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/splitting-100000-records-to-two-internal-tables-and-post-in-al11/m-p/14273900#M230"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:43:17.791000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/custom-cards-are-not-showing-on-the-home-page/qaa-p/14273901#M49459</id>
    <title>Re: Custom Cards are not showing on the Home Page</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:43:54.067000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CristianScheu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39815</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Soren,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to Help Guide&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-platform/managing-sap-successfactors-user-experience/creating-or-editing-custom-cards-for-home-page?version=2511&amp;amp;q=date+range+Based+on+start+date+custom+card" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-platform/managing-sap-successfactors-user-experience/creating-or-editing-custom-cards-for-home-page?version=2511&amp;amp;q=date+range+Based+on+start+date+custom+card&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;Date Range works to specify a date range when the card is shown and the&amp;nbsp;Based on Start Date to show the card in relation to a person's start date. Then specify the number of days before and after the start date to show the card. (Requires Onboarding or Onboarding 1.0). If you are experiencing a different behaviour from the one documented I would to open a support ticket to investigate any possible bug.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kind Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cristian&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/custom-cards-are-not-showing-on-the-home-page/qaa-p/14273901#M49459"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:43:54.067000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-joule-analytics-center-no-data-to-display/qaq-p/14273904</id>
    <title>SAP Joule Analytics Center, No Data to display</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:46:35.327000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Indrajeet_25</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1733454</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I have done the setup of SAP Joule with SuccessFactor and currently exploring Joule Analytics Center to know insights.&lt;BR /&gt;Followed steps given in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/joule-tools-12ace5a963e147ffa6f5aab8a4cf15f4/enabling-joule-analytics-center" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enabling Joule Analytics Center | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I am able to access center but there is no data to show PFB snip, when checked in inspect it says&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;message: "Rejected due to too few users". As per limitation it says 8 minimum users are required, currently more than 10 users are using it still data is not being showed in analytics platform.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Indrajeet_25_0-1763649263625.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343259iBFFB8CD92EA48F9A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Indrajeet_25_0-1763649263625.png" alt="Indrajeet_25_0-1763649263625.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;are there alternative ways or other options to understand why data is not displayed here?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;any APIs available to get data?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Joule/pd-p/d0136351-8a9c-4881-aebc-bf414b785998" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1207-1"&gt;Joule&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Data+and+Analytics/pd-p/87817424-f4e7-46f2-af14-88bf0f4ba034" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="44-1"&gt;Data and Analytics&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Joule/pd-p/d0136351-8a9c-4881-aebc-bf414b785998" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1207-2"&gt;Joule&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-joule-analytics-center-no-data-to-display/qaq-p/14273904"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:46:35.327000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/po-not-getting-creating-error-express-document-quot-update-was-cancelled/qaa-p/14273907#M4932102</id>
    <title>Re: PO not getting creating error EXPRESS DOCUMENT "UPDATE WAS CANCELLED"</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:50:15.433000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>radinator</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/681078</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello! The screenshot shows a message class ZFI with number 049. You could try to search in the code of the report Z_MM_ENTRY_NEU if you can find the line of code which creates the message. Something like MESSAGE e049(zfi) should be the culprit. Anything more than this is pure speculation.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/po-not-getting-creating-error-express-document-quot-update-was-cancelled/qaa-p/14273907#M4932102"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:50:15.433000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-advanced-formula-searching-for-the-right-record-in-a-linked-model-in-a/qaq-p/14273908</id>
    <title>sac advanced formula - searching for the right record in a linked model in a foreach statement</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:52:39.060000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Maximilian_Layes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1902304</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Hi&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;I&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;have&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;an&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;advanced&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;formula&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;that&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;needs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;find&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;a specific record in a&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;linked&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;model.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Here is example data for both models:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;main&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;model&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;contains&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;hours&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;per&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;month&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;employees&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;and&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;PSP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="52"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Date&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;FCMONTH&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;PERSONAL&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;PARAMETER&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49"&gt;&lt;P&gt;PSPELEMENT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;BMOT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="84"&gt;&lt;P&gt;DESTINATION&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;VTYPE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51"&gt;&lt;P&gt;HOURS&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="62"&gt;&lt;P&gt;REVENUE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="52"&gt;&lt;P&gt;202501&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;100&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;101&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="84"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;020&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51"&gt;&lt;P&gt;83&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="62"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="52"&gt;&lt;P&gt;202503&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;100&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;101&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="84"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;020&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51"&gt;&lt;P&gt;100&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="62"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="52"&gt;&lt;P&gt;2025010&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;100&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;101&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="84"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;020&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51"&gt;&lt;P&gt;60&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="62"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="52"&gt;&lt;P&gt;2025011&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;100&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;101&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="84"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;020&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51"&gt;&lt;P&gt;75&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="62"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="52"&gt;&lt;P&gt;202501&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;101&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;101&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="84"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;020&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51"&gt;&lt;P&gt;110&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="62"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="52"&gt;&lt;P&gt;202504&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;101&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;101&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="84"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;020&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51"&gt;&lt;P&gt;43&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="62"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="52"&gt;&lt;P&gt;202501&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="68"&gt;&lt;P&gt;102&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;101&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="84"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="46"&gt;&lt;P&gt;020&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51"&gt;&lt;P&gt;24&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="62"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;linked&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;model&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;contains&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;hourly&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;rates&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;for&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;employees&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;PSP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;and&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;valid&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;from&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;month&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="60"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Date&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="87"&gt;&lt;P&gt;VALIDFROM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="57"&gt;&lt;P&gt;PSPELEMENT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;PERSONAL&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="89"&gt;&lt;P&gt;PARAMETER&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="64"&gt;&lt;P&gt;BMOT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="96"&gt;&lt;P&gt;DESTINATION&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="73"&gt;&lt;P&gt;AMOUNT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="60"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="87"&gt;&lt;P&gt;202501&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="57"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;100&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="89"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="64"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="96"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="73"&gt;&lt;P&gt;165&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="60"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="87"&gt;&lt;P&gt;202510&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="57"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;100&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="89"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="64"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="96"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="73"&gt;&lt;P&gt;180&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="60"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="87"&gt;&lt;P&gt;202501&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="57"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;101&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="89"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="64"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="96"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="73"&gt;&lt;P&gt;165&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="60"&gt;&lt;P&gt;000000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="87"&gt;&lt;P&gt;202501&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="57"&gt;&lt;P&gt;235.02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="78"&gt;&lt;P&gt;102&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="89"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="64"&gt;&lt;P&gt;I1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="96"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="73"&gt;&lt;P&gt;165&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;My formula looks as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;//-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
//The data region against which the formulas will be executed.
//-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
MEMBERSET [d/PSPELEMENT] = BASEMEMBER([d/PSPELEMENT].[h/PSPHIER], %PSPElemBaseMember%)
MEMBERSET [d/Date] = %STARTDATUM% TO %ENDDATUM%
MEMBERSET [d/Parametertyp] = "100"
MEMBERSET [d/VTYPE] = %VTYPE%
MEMBERSET [d/PERSONAL] = %Mitarbeiter%

//-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
//Calculation and Data Writing
//-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
MODEL [APC_BASIC_DATA]
ENDMODEL

FOREACH [d/PERSONAL], [APC_BASIC_DATA].[d/VALIDFROM] ASC
	IF DATEDIFF([d/Date], [APC_BASIC_DATA].[d/VALIDFROM], "MONTH") &amp;gt;= 0 THEN
		IF LINK([APC_BASIC_DATA], [d/Measures] = "Betrag", [d/PSPELEMENT] = %PSPElemQuelle%, [d/Parametertyp] = "1", [d/Version] = "public.Actual", [d/Date] = "000000") &amp;gt; 0 THEN

			DATA([d/Measures] = "Umsatz") = RESULTLOOKUP([d/Measures] = "STUNDEN") * LINK([APC_BASIC_DATA], [d/Measures] = "Betrag", [d/PSPELEMENT] = %PSPElemQuelle%, [d/Parametertyp] = "1", [d/Version] = "public.Actual", [d/Date] = "000000")

		ENDIF
	ENDIF
ENDFOR&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;purpose&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;of&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;this&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;function&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;is&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;find&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;correct&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;hourly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;rate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;for&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;each&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;record&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;in&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;main&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;and then to calculate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;revenue&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;FOREACH&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;should&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;check&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;for&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;each&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;employee&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;and&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;validfrom&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;whether&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;month&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;of&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;current&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;record&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;in&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;main&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;is&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;greater&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;than&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;or&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;equal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;validfrom&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;month&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;of&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;linked&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;By&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;sorting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;in&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ascending&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;order&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;I&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ensure&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;that&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;hourly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;rate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;with&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;largest&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;validfrom&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;month&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;is&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;calculated&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;last&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;and&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;that&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;each&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;hour&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;is&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;calculated&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;with&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;correct&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;hourly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;rate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;problem&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;is&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;that&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;LINK&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;command&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;within&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;FOREACH&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;does&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;not&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;take&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;validfrom&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;value&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;of&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;current&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;iteration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;It&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;seems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;as&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;if&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;it&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;takes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;aggregation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;of&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;all&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;hourly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;rates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;for&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;an&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;employee&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;How&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;can&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;I&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;specify&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;filter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;for&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;validfrom dimension&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;of&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;current&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;iteration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;in&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;LINK&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;command&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Max&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-advanced-formula-searching-for-the-right-record-in-a-linked-model-in-a/qaq-p/14273908"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:52:39.060000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-reference-child-object-in-another-custom-mdf-object/qaa-p/14273909#M49460</id>
    <title>Re: How to reference child object in another custom MDF o...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:52:52.183000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CristianScheu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39815</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi syeapAB,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003383815" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/0003383815&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;it is not&amp;nbsp;recommended to configure a child object in another MDF Object as a Generic Object reference field and the system will throw the error message you received.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But the data updating from UI (manage data, people profile.etc) may work, however, it may not work for MDF import / Odata API scenarios to update MDF data, the Odata API updating or the MDF import will fail.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cristian&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-reference-child-object-in-another-custom-mdf-object/qaa-p/14273909#M49460"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:52:52.183000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-in-activating-custom-model-in-custom-islm-scenario/qaq-p/14273910</id>
    <title>Error in activating custom Model in custom ISLM scenario</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:53:40.326000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vijayvenkat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46932</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to create a embedded ISLM Scenario in S4 2023 system. I am following the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-embedded-machine-learning-app-in-s-4hana/ba-p/13503223" target="_self"&gt;blog.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However I am unable to activate the model. I have close to 17000 records in the training view. But still I am not able to train the model. An help is appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131707"&gt;@Masaaki&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Can you help ?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Model : Z12343&lt;BR /&gt;MV: ZPQWLLAXFP0IWNSY3VRZH1KMVF&lt;BR /&gt;Status: training&lt;BR /&gt;Creating intelligent model&lt;BR /&gt;Error occurred during Specified Model training&lt;BR /&gt;Exception occurred in CL_ISLM2_ENGINE-&amp;gt;TRAIN_SPECIFIED_MODEL at line 201&lt;BR /&gt;A database error occured. The error message in the database was: "transaction rolled back by an inte&lt;BR /&gt;rnal error: "SAP_HANA_UMML_ENGINE_STATIC"."sap.hana.pai.Engine::TrainModel": line 127 col 3 (at pos&lt;BR /&gt;5378): "SAP_HANA_UMML_ENGINE_DYNAMIC"."sap.hana.pai.Engine.internal::TrainModelHelper": line 44 col&lt;BR /&gt;5 (at pos 1923): "SAP_HANA_UMML_ENGINE_STATIC"."sap.hana.pai.Engine.APL::TrainModel": line 143 col 5&lt;BR /&gt;(at pos 6790): "SAP_PA_APL"."sap.pa.apl.base::TRAIN_MODEL": line 45 col 4 (at pos 2381): AFL error:&lt;BR /&gt;search table error: _SYS_AFL.APL_AREA:TRAIN_MODEL: [423] (range 3) AFL error exception: [APL error]&lt;BR /&gt;Automated Analytics error (-2147024809): phase 'KxCPPInterf::IKxenModel::sendMode()'&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; [The data sou&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;rce doesn't have enough rows to produce a reliable predictive model. Use a dataset with more rows.]"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Exception occurred in CL_SQL_STATEMENT-&amp;gt;PREPARED_UPDATE at line 3&lt;BR /&gt;Model Training was unsuccessful&lt;BR /&gt;Exception occurred in CL_ISLM2_MODELVERSION-&amp;gt;EXECUTE_TRAIN_FROM_SPEC at line 141&lt;BR /&gt;Model Training was unsuccessful&lt;BR /&gt;Status: error&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Intelligent+Scenario+Lifecycle+Management+for+SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/5fd89ff4-ccea-40fd-9272-b22eeeba2873" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="186-1"&gt;Intelligent Scenario Lifecycle Management for SAP S/4HANA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vijay V&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-in-activating-custom-model-in-custom-islm-scenario/qaq-p/14273910"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:53:40.326000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/automating-training-assignments-using-integer-custom-fields/bc-p/14273911#M7354</id>
    <title>Re: Automating Training Assignments Using Integer Custom Fields</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:54:01.893000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DavidLanglotz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/115310</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This is exactly what I need to solve my current problem. Thank you!!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/automating-training-assignments-using-integer-custom-fields/bc-p/14273911#M7354"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:54:01.893000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/teched-recap-creating-ai-enhanced-ux-for-your-own-applications-with-sap/ba-p/14273694</id>
    <title>TechEd Recap: Creating AI-Enhanced UX for Your Own Applications with SAP Design System</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:55:07.560000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ThomasReiss</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149639</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;By Sophia Levens and Thomas Reiss&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We were thrilled to speak at this year’s TechEd conference in Berlin on how the SAP Design System is powering the next generation of AI-led product design. Our Deep Dive talk entitled “Creating AI-enhanced UX for your own applications with SAP Design System” focused on three key areas: an introduction into the SAP Design System, new AI patterns for the design system and SAPUI5, and our AI-powered tools for our UI technologies. We then closed the session with an overview of the resources available to designers and developers today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below we’ll share a recap of the major points and announcements from the session. You can also &lt;STRONG&gt;watch the recorded session &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1753179705783001L1CP" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636461799"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction to the SAP Design System&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The overall mission of the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design System&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; is to unify and advance the SAP user experience. We achieve this in two ways:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unify&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The SAP Design System serves as the central hub of ready-to-use assets, guidance and standards for building delightful experiences that are consistent across the SAP portfolio. This is how we directly contribute to SAP’s Suite-First strategy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advance: &lt;/STRONG&gt;The SAP Design System provides the essential patterns and tools to embed transformative AI experiences across all products and touchpoints. This is how we directly contribute to the AI-First goal.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="01 Our mission.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343227iB5AE153E9EEBDC33/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01 Our mission.jpg" alt="01 Our mission.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What exactly is a design system?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to deliver consistent and inclusive UX, the SAP Design System is made up of the following elements:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Design Language&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The most foundational elements that go into any brand. For example, color, type, iconography, illustrations, etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Components&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The building blocks for creating user interfaces, like buttons, drop down menus, or input fields.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Patterns&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Covers a use case or user flow, things like exporting data to PDF or a search workflow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Floorplans&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A full UI layout. Typically, floorplans are a complete page or even span several pages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F5hybr7zNvjI%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D5hybr7zNvjI&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F5hybr7zNvjI%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="Are you ready to design a new way to work?" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Design System extends across SAP. It helps to unify all touchpoints across the SAP brand including our products, our digital experiences like sap.com, and other marketing and communications including interactive events like TechEd. And because the system is open source, our customers can also use the design system to build upon and customize our products and platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="02 Design System (naming).jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343238i8F1C38F4A1E8B813/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="02 Design System (naming).jpg" alt="02 Design System (naming).jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What UI technologies are supported with the SAP Design System? &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For each element in the SAP Design System, we build reusable components in code that developers can leverage to accelerate their workflow. There are two ways to leverage SAP technologies—via “floorplans and building blocks” or “freestyle”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build “freestyle” with SAPUI5 and SAP Web Components: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Freestyle allows you full control of every element on the screen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use “floorplans and building blocks” with SAP Fiori Elements: &lt;/STRONG&gt;This lets you accelerate development when the desired app or workflow is close to one of the out-of-the box floorplans or building blocks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because both of these choices are based on SAPUI5, you don’t have to choose one or the other, you can mix both ways of developing leveraging each when needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="03 SAP UI technologies.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343229iF4C39AC4719A0B06/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="03 SAP UI technologies.jpg" alt="03 SAP UI technologies.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439948294"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New AI Patterns for the SAP Design System and SAPUI5&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is proud to offer AI components and patterns for web and mobile. We’re investing in making it easy to design and build great AI experiences that are responsible, flexible, and work across ecosystems. Our AI experience principles are built on the following six pillars: design for clarity, earn trust, give control, design fairly, boost flow, fail-safe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find the latest AI patterns and components:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/fiori-design-web/ui-elements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design System portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/community/file/1494295794601744471/sap-fiori-for-web-ui-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Web UI Kit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/community/file/1450853598524410675/sap-fiori-for-ios-ui-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori for iOS UI Kit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/community/file/1497649798412067020/sap-fiori-for-android-ui-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori for Android UI Kit&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://ui5.github.io/webcomponents/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UI5 Web Components&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our AI components and patterns have gone through the process of reviews and testing by our experts in user assistance, accessibility, user research, and are compliant with SAP’s legal and ethical AI standards. These are patterns you and your users can trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372517508"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046921284"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using our AI-powered UI Technologies to Help You Build Faster&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have introduced powerful AI tools to help you build UIs and applications faster.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-for-developers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule for Developers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;is a collection of embedded AI capabilities for SAP Build as well as for ABAP, delivered through Joule, that accelerates development of apps and extensions, reduces costs, and improves developer proficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Fiori tools project accelerator, which can be started from Joule in SAP Build Code, enables developers to create CAP-based (Cloud Application Programming model based) SAP Fiori elements applications directly from an image of the intended outcome. These images can be high fidelity Figma models, lower fidelity screenshots or a sketch on paper. Simply upload the image and use AI to generate the data models, services and the UI. Find out more in this blog post: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-idea-to-app-using-ai-powered-project-accelerator-to-develop-sap-fiori/ba-p/14095300" target="_blank"&gt;From idea to app: using AI-powered Project Accelerator to develop SAP Fiori apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Generate a complete CAP-based application from a sketch with SAP Fiori tools project accelerator: data models, services and UI." style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343232iB9228A4C5F5D8701/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="04 AI generate Fiori elements from sketch.jpg" alt="Generate a complete CAP-based application from a sketch with SAP Fiori tools project accelerator: data models, services and UI." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Generate a complete CAP-based application from a sketch with SAP Fiori tools project accelerator: data models, services and UI.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently, we have gone even further and introduced MCP servers for freestyle SAPUI5 development as well as for developing with SAP Fiori elements and the associated building blocks. These open-source &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Model Context Protocol (MCP)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; servers equip developers with valuable support by providing AI agents with comprehensive UI5 and SAP Fiori elements knowledge, including best practices and project-aware context information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read about the new MCP servers in these blog posts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_blank"&gt;UI5 MCP Server&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-tools-update-first-release-of-the-sap-fiori-mcp-server-for/ba-p/14204694" target="_blank"&gt;MCP Server for SAP Fiori&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-850407779"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This deep dive session gave an overview of how customers and partners can create AI-enhanced UX for their own applications with the SAP Design System and SAP’s UI technologies. Find everything you need to get started designing and developing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get started with the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design System portal.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.figma.com/@sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP's UI kits&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; with the new AI patterns.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapui5.hana.ondemand.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAPUI5.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/teched-recap-creating-ai-enhanced-ux-for-your-own-applications-with-sap/ba-p/14273694"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:55:07.560000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/solman-7-2-rfc-unable-to-set-to-confirmed-in-production-when-linked/qaa-p/14273912#M4932105</id>
    <title>Re: SolMan 7.2 RFC unable to set to confirmed in producti...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:55:22.101000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dave_S30</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/201476</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;To limit this situation from happening again, I suggest configuring the predecessor-successor status attributes (Specify Status Attributes) so the incident status cannot be confirmed until the successor RFC is confirmed, or whatever status values your business case requires. For example, we've configured the incident transaction so that before it can be set to Proposed Solution, the successor RFC must have one of the statuses, Implemented, Confirmed, or Withdrawn.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#800000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proceed with caution:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; But, to update an RFC where the predecessor incident is already closed, you might consider using the report,&amp;nbsp;CRM_SOCM_SERVICE_REPORT. &lt;EM&gt;Please read the fine documentation for the report.&lt;/EM&gt; This report can update the status of a transaction (or set of transactions), but will &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; make the consistency checks&lt;/EM&gt; built into the application. Be sure of what you're about to do, and use the "List Output Only (No Update)" option to check the selected transaction(s), etc., before committing updates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/solman-7-2-rfc-unable-to-set-to-confirmed-in-production-when-linked/qaa-p/14273912#M4932105"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:55:22.101000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-analytics-cloud-assertion-failed-could-not-find-translatable-text/qaq-p/14273913</id>
    <title>SAP Analytics Cloud: Assertion Failed could not find translatable text</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T15:56:25.970000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>charles_braybrook</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/300195</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A client of mine is experiencing a UI issue in their SAC tenants. See below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="charles_braybrook_0-1763650150939.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343261iD2D854876568F941/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="charles_braybrook_0-1763650150939.png" alt="charles_braybrook_0-1763650150939.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When looking, this is the case for multiple users. Although my user is not experiencing it. Potentially because I am using a different network and security setup than the client.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When opening console, I get large number of the following error: Assertion Failed Could not find translatable text.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any suggestions as to what is causing this and how to fix, would be much appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Charles&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-analytics-cloud-assertion-failed-could-not-find-translatable-text/qaq-p/14273913"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T15:56:25.970000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-for-joule-in-sap-fieldglass-november-2025/ba-p/14273914</id>
    <title>What’s New for Joule in SAP Fieldglass – November 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:00:03.345000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sian_Thompson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1479807</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Joule in SAP Fieldglass was first introduced in July, and since then its capabilities have continued to expand. Our latest November 2025 release brings several key enhancements designed to streamline processes, boost efficiency, and improve accessibility and inclusivity for users globally.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New for Joule in the SAP Fieldglass November 2025 Release:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/76e97fe0cccf4d37a5dadc652a375e33/73e7763136d644ec96df37eb045360fe.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multi-Language Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Joule can now automatically detect the user’s input language, interacting and responding in the user’s preferred language&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/76e97fe0cccf4d37a5dadc652a375e33/4d6e0d5026184da28aa6018c8b3c6cab.html?parentHref=https%3A%2F%2Fhelp.sap.com%2Fwhats-new%2F0c2fc99f5fd34e8e8662fbdff4cbbb0d%3FVersion%3D2025.11.0.0&amp;amp;parentName=What%27s+New+in+SAP+Fieldglass&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Translated Templates and Report Retrieval&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For organizations that translate Job Posting Templates, SOW Templates, and Reports, Joule will identify the user’s preferred language and retrieve the corresponding localized version when available.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/76e97fe0cccf4d37a5dadc652a375e33/262647be707c4067a49464f4178a0389.html?parentHref=https%3A%2F%2Fhelp.sap.com%2Fwhats-new%2F0c2fc99f5fd34e8e8662fbdff4cbbb0d%3FVersion%3D2025.11.0.0&amp;amp;parentName=What%27s+New+in+SAP+Fieldglass&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified Job Posting Template Recommendations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Users can now describe their needs in natural language. Joule will interpret the requirement and retrieve relevant templates—removing the previous dependency on specific job titles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/76e97fe0cccf4d37a5dadc652a375e33/9d08b7c3b9f84dd68e148370ffde28ac.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Decision Form Approvals&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Users can now approve or reject Decision Forms directly within Joule when reviewing their pending Work Items, making the approval process faster and more intuitive.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/76e97fe0cccf4d37a5dadc652a375e33/c4175a5568104a0fba37aa84d4b0f695.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Legal Entity Recognition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;When Legal Entity functionality is enabled, users can include the Legal Entity as part of their requirements when creating Job Postings or Statements of Work. Joule will recognize and automatically populate the correct value in the appropriate documents.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Want to Learn More?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watch our short &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/4GrhEki?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1257314&amp;amp;includeRelatedAssets=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Release Highlights video&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;demonstrating these items.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore our &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/76e97fe0cccf4d37a5dadc652a375e33/e3dc12e0215447cfa4507eff66e8224b.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule in SAP Fieldglass&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; Help Portal page for a comprehensive overview of the tool and its current capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Visit the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/spend-management/fieldglass" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; for additional release resources and the latest AI insights.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-for-joule-in-sap-fieldglass-november-2025/ba-p/14273914"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:00:03.345000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/solman-7-2-rfc-unable-to-set-to-confirmed-in-production-when-linked/qaa-p/14273918#M4932107</id>
    <title>Re: SolMan 7.2 RFC unable to set to confirmed in producti...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:05:46.226000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Raghavendranath</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/181293</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Yes at present we are able to confirm RFC using CRMD_Order tcode. But it is getting difficult every time as most of the users are clsoing the incident without confirming RFC.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/solman-7-2-rfc-unable-to-set-to-confirmed-in-production-when-linked/qaa-p/14273918#M4932107"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:05:46.226000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2511/bc-p/14273919#M186522</id>
    <title>Re: SAP BTP ABAP Environment - Release 2511</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:06:20.204000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>michael_speight2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/213474</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4296"&gt;@FrankJentsch&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; - thanks for the update. We discovered the option to create templates in Eclipse and this is fine. It would be nice to have them all together in a single app of course. The Fiori App itself seems to be there, I can see the objects, it is just not available for use.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards, Mike&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2511/bc-p/14273919#M186522"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:06:20.204000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/solman-7-2-rfc-unable-to-set-to-confirmed-in-production-when-linked/qaa-p/14273920#M4932108</id>
    <title>Re: SolMan 7.2 RFC unable to set to confirmed in producti...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:06:58.471000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Raghavendranath</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/181293</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Can you please help on step by step guidance if possible on how to restrict users not closing incident until the linked RFC 's are confirmed or rejected.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/solman-7-2-rfc-unable-to-set-to-confirmed-in-production-when-linked/qaa-p/14273920#M4932108"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:06:58.471000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-cap-blog-posts/complete-guide-setting-up-cap-plugin-for-advanced-event-mesh-with-oauth/bc-p/14273921#M10</id>
    <title>Re: Complete Guide: Setting Up CAP Plugin for Advanced Event Mesh with OAuth Authentication</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:07:22.498000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Fiona_Zhang_FZ</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/54417</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Roberto,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a very nice blog and very informative! I'm wondering if this also handles when CAP application and AEM are in different global accounts? I try to use below line but because my aem-validation-service is in another BTP account so it cannot be found..&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;cds bind aem-validation-service -2 aem-validation-service:yourkeyname --for hybrid --kind aem-validation-service&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Error after this line:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;cds bind aem-validation-service -2 aem-validation-service:AEM-SERVICE_KEY --for hybrid --kind aem-validation-service&lt;BR /&gt;retrieving data from Cloud Foundry...&lt;BR /&gt;service instance aem-validation-service not found.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do you think it's possible to bind them together?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fiona&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-cap-blog-posts/complete-guide-setting-up-cap-plugin-for-advanced-event-mesh-with-oauth/bc-p/14273921#M10"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:07:22.498000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/adoption-isn-t-a-phase-it-s-a-relationship/ba-p/14273120</id>
    <title>Adoption Isn’t a Phase, It’s a Relationship</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:16:07.130000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AliaDouglas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/151389</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you know me, you know I love an analogy. It’s always helpful to make new information make sense by likening it to something we already understand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my role here at SAP, I talk about adoption a lot. It’s a point that I (and my wonderful team, Solution Value Advisory) really push with our customers, who sometimes think of adoption as a step in the overall process, something you &lt;EM&gt;do&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;after go-live.&amp;nbsp; So, my analogy for today is to look at adoption like a relationship, because it’s never just about the software, but about the people and how they interact with the system and each other.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s not much of a stretch, really. At the start, it’s a mix of excitement, a little confusion, and commitment that comes with bringing something new into your life, and hoping it thrives, grows, and has the support of people around you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#3366FF"&gt;The honeymoon stage&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;In my last role several years back, I worked on Ariba solution implementations. Being on a shared services team, I got to stick my hands into a lot of different customers’ Ariba deployments. It felt great, for the customer and for me, to reach what felt like a finish line: &lt;EM&gt;go-live&lt;/EM&gt;. That point of the new solution(s) going live after months of setup and testing. The vibes were always good - everyone was hopeful, users explored the system, performed tests. Teams got trained. There was that spark of possibility, that sense of &lt;EM&gt;this time, things will be different.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But just like any new relationship, the shine fades if the day-to-day connection isn’t nurtured. Old habits creep back in, shortcuts resurface. And, before long, that beautiful new tool starts gathering dust.&amp;nbsp; Remember, &lt;STRONG&gt;adoption doesn’t end at go-live, that’s when it begins.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#3366FF"&gt;Relationships thrive on consistency, and so do systems&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Healthy adoption looks a lot like a healthy partnership: steady, intentional, and full of small moments that build trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s when someone logs in and sees that their preferences were remembered. It’s when data syncs across systems, so people stop fighting with spreadsheets and endless back-and-forth email. It’s when users realize the tool makes their jobs easier, not harder. It keeps the relationship alive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But breakdowns don’t usually happen with a bang, but a fizzle. Users don’t revolt, they quietly disengage. They skip the process “just this once.” Then they stop trusting the data, because the process is getting skipped and they can’t find what they were looking for. And now something that was originally set up to create efficiency is now only causing frustration, and becomes a pain in the…well, you know. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my work with customers, I see this all the time.&amp;nbsp; I work a lot with customers on their supplier management processes especially, and I see a lot of this disengagement when it comes to onboarding. Tools like &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ariba Supplier Lifecycle &amp;amp; Performance (SLP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be super powerful, but they depend on trusted data and consistency. If people don’t understand why something matters, they won’t invest in making it work.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#3366FF"&gt;The love language of AI is good data&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Now we’re entering a new chapter, one where AI tools like &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt; are ready to help make our jobs easier. But even Joule, which might seem like magic when you see it presented, needs a foundation of trust. This has been my main message of the year - reminding people that AI doesn’t make magic out of thin air, rather it builds on what we give it. If data is messy, disconnected, or if established processes are underused, Joule’s insights will be, too.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(Pausing here for a shoutout to anyone who was at the Customer Success Day in NYC earlier this year where I did a whole session to essentially say, “Garbage in, garbage out”. The highlight, at least to me, was my AI-generated Ariba song parody of Naughty by Nature’s O.P.P.&amp;nbsp; &lt;EM&gt;Who’s down with SLP? Yeah you know me!&lt;/EM&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But back to my relationship analogy, think of it this way: if you never talk to your partner, you can’t expect them to finish your sentences. Joule works the same way. The relationship only deepens when we communicate through connected, clean, and well-adopted systems.&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#3366FF"&gt;Adoption is ongoing care.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;As I said before, adoption isn’t a task. We don’t “complete” adoption. We maintain it. We check in with our users, we update them on changes, and we listen when something isn’t working and adjust before resentment sets in.&amp;nbsp; The most successful customers I see are those who treat adoption as a living process. Not just implementing technology, but inviting it into their company culture. When adoption is healthy, everything else (innovation, automation, AI, etc.) starts to flow naturally.&amp;nbsp; But just like any great relationship, it takes attention, empathy, and patience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I encourage you all to stay in tune with our &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=42F2E964F4E71EDAA2D4E26DA01500E3&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;roadmap&lt;/A&gt;, as there’s a lot of exciting stuff to come in 2026 when it comes to AI in SAP. But as you read up on that and start to think how cool it will be and how much time it will save to have all of those new capabilities, remember that &lt;STRONG&gt;now&lt;/STRONG&gt; is the time to build the foundation for that new relationship.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any doubts about how well your company is adopting your solutions and how you’re doing on usage in comparison to other customers, do reach out to your CSM who can either help, or can pull in the right people to have that conversation. Sometimes that person is me, so say hi and maybe I'll share my library of Ariba song parodies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/adoption-isn-t-a-phase-it-s-a-relationship/ba-p/14273120"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:16:07.130000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/review-customer-projects-business-requirement-period-wise-project/qaa-p/14273923#M4231860</id>
    <title>Re: Review Customer Projects - Business Requirement: Peri...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:16:18.651000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bangaru198251</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/12596</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172309"&gt;@dawid90&lt;/a&gt; for quick response, I am sure you have went through the requirement is more while performing the forecasting.. not initial planning.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/review-customer-projects-business-requirement-period-wise-project/qaa-p/14273923#M4231860"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:16:18.651000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-advanced-formula-searching-for-the-right-record-in-a-linked-model-in-a/qaa-p/14273924#M4932109</id>
    <title>Re: sac advanced formula - searching for the right record...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:17:41.381000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Maximilian_Layes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1902304</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Shortly&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;after&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;writing&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;post&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;I&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;found&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;solution&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;1&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt; M&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;y &lt;/SPAN&gt;D&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ATEDIFF &lt;/SPAN&gt;f&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;unction &lt;/SPAN&gt;w&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;as &lt;/SPAN&gt;d&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;efined &lt;/SPAN&gt;i&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ncorrectly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt; T&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;he &lt;/SPAN&gt;a&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ggregation &lt;/SPAN&gt;d&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;id &lt;/SPAN&gt;n&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ot &lt;/SPAN&gt;c&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ome &lt;/SPAN&gt;v&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ia &lt;/SPAN&gt;t&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;he &lt;/SPAN&gt;L&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;INK &lt;/SPAN&gt;c&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ommand &lt;/SPAN&gt;b&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ut &lt;/SPAN&gt;i&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s &lt;/SPAN&gt;c&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ontained &lt;/SPAN&gt;i&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;n &lt;/SPAN&gt;t&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;he &lt;/SPAN&gt;D&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ATA &lt;/SPAN&gt;s&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;tatement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;H&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ere &lt;/SPAN&gt;i&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s &lt;/SPAN&gt;t&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;he &lt;/SPAN&gt;c&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;orrected &lt;/SPAN&gt;c&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ode:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;MODEL [APC_BASIC_DATA]
ENDMODEL

FOREACH [d/PERSONAL], [APC_BASIC_DATA].[d/VALIDFROM] ASC
	IF DATEDIFF([APC_BASIC_DATA].[d/VALIDFROM], [d/Date], "MONTH") &amp;gt;= 0 THEN
		IF LINK([APC_BASIC_DATA], [d/Measures] = "Betrag", [d/PSPELEMENT] = %PSPElemQuelle%, [d/Parametertyp] = "1", [d/Version] = "public.Actual", [d/Date] = "000000") &amp;gt; 0 THEN

			DATA([d/Measures] = "Umsatz") = 0
			DATA([d/Measures] = "Umsatz") = RESULTLOOKUP([d/Measures] = "STUNDEN") * LINK([APC_BASIC_DATA], [d/Measures] = "Betrag", [d/PSPELEMENT] = %PSPElemQuelle%, [d/Parametertyp] = "1", [d/Version] = "public.Actual", [d/Date] = "000000")

		ENDIF
	ENDIF
ENDFOR&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;kind regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Max&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-advanced-formula-searching-for-the-right-record-in-a-linked-model-in-a/qaa-p/14273924#M4932109"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:17:41.381000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/pir-update-based-on-rfq/qaq-p/14273927</id>
    <title>PIR Update Based on RFQ</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:19:34.747000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;When checking the 'info record update' button in Mange RFQs I noticed that upon initial creation of the quotation the PIR is not pulled in. Also, the PIR price is not updated upon awarding the quote until some time later.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;After several minutes if I go back into the quotation I can see that the PIR number is pulled, and if I check Manage Purchasing Info Records the info records do eventually get created.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am opening this ticket to ask the following questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is there is a job running to update the PIRs based on the supplier quotations?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If there is a job running, do I have access to modify it?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How often is the job running?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;PERSON_NAME&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;--- Support Assistant ---&lt;BR /&gt;Manage RFQs&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Q: Which CB user should be used to reproduce the issue?&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;A: CBPHONE_NUMBER&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/pir-update-based-on-rfq/qaq-p/14273927"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:19:34.747000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/pir-update-based-on-rfq/qaa-p/14273928#M208230</id>
    <title>Re: PIR Update Based on RFQ</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:19:43.087000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For Info Record updates from the supplier quotation process using Manage RFQ and Manage Supplier Quotation apps, the scheduled reports FOLLOW_ON_FROM_QUOTATION, which are essential for&amp;nbsp; updating the Info Records,&amp;nbsp; runs in the background for info record update&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Its a backend transaction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer does not have access to it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It runs in every 10 min&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/pir-update-based-on-rfq/qaa-p/14273928#M208230"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:19:43.087000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/workflow-to-pick-task-processor-as-agent-in-quality-notification/qaa-p/14273931#M4231861</id>
    <title>Re: workflow to pick task processor as agent in quality notification</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:21:36.023000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaghavanKathamuthu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17050</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Actually the Workflow 20000314 itself picking the task responsible person as the receiver. But for triggering the sap inbox mail it took time. Later I checked my inbox it was there in SBWP&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="RaghavanKathamuthu_0-1763652157451.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343270i74A29714441F445D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="RaghavanKathamuthu_0-1763652157451.png" alt="RaghavanKathamuthu_0-1763652157451.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_NETWEAVER_701/6d9feefa6c4b101494abec9186d53d58/4f3bed495cc018c8e10000000a42189e.html?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_NETWEAVER_701/6d9feefa6c4b101494abec9186d53d58/4f3bed495cc018c8e10000000a42189e.html?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/workflow-to-pick-task-processor-as-agent-in-quality-notification/qaa-p/14273931#M4231861"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:21:36.023000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2511/bc-p/14273942#M186524</id>
    <title>Re: SAP BTP ABAP Environment - Release 2511</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:31:54.100000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OliverBeck01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1496866</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Mike,&lt;BR /&gt;we apologize for the confusion, but at the moment we are unable to offer the Fiori app &lt;STRONG&gt;“&lt;/STRONG&gt;Maintain Email Templates&lt;STRONG&gt;”&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the BTP ABAP Environment for various reasons. Could you please let us know which objects you can see but are unable to use?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&amp;nbsp;Oliver Beck&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2511/bc-p/14273942#M186524"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:31:54.100000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crystalreportviewer-text-field-is-grow-to-whole-row-unlike-winforms-version/qaa-p/14273943#M4932110</id>
    <title>Re: CrystalReportViewer text field is grow to whole row....</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:32:44.788000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DonWilliams</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121895</uri>
    </author>
    <content>By default a lot of the registry keys are not installed, create them according to the KBA, see if that works. Also, no one else is having this problem so it's not a bug.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crystalreportviewer-text-field-is-grow-to-whole-row-unlike-winforms-version/qaa-p/14273943#M4932110"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:32:44.788000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/successfactors-2h-2025-release-smarter-review-flows-with-new-business-rule/ba-p/14273940</id>
    <title>SuccessFactors 2H 2025 Release: Smarter Review Flows with New Business Rule Scenario</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:32:45.272000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rag_98</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1456205</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP SuccessFactors introduces a powerful enhancement via the new feature &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Rules for Performance Management:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Rule Scenario – “Add Review Steps Upon Form Routing.”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This capability allows organizations to design &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;dynamic, conditional review processes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; by automatically inserting additional review steps during form routing — based on specific business conditions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Highlights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Review Steps:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Add one or multiple review steps during the &lt;STRONG&gt;Modify&lt;/STRONG&gt; stage of a form.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conditional Visibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Keep steps &lt;STRONG&gt;hidden&lt;/STRONG&gt; until triggered by a business rule.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexible Criteria:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Configure rules based on overall ratings, custom fields, or competency rating.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Use Cases&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If a manager’s overall rating is &lt;STRONG&gt;above&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;below a given threshold &lt;/STRONG&gt;(e.g. Either at higher or at lower end of the rating scale), an extra reviewer step can be added automatically.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For &lt;STRONG&gt;PIP &amp;amp; Confirmation forms&lt;/STRONG&gt;, granting an extension can trigger an additional approval step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Configure&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable the &lt;STRONG&gt;latest Performance Management form experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Admin Center. The business rule scenario described here works only if the customer has enabled the latest experience of Performance Management forms.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add relevant steps in the Route Map.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify the steps that need to be triggered only when the business rule condition is met.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mark these steps as &lt;STRONG&gt;Hidden Until Rule Execution&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the Route Map.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a rule using &lt;STRONG&gt;Add Review Steps Upon Form Routing&lt;/STRONG&gt; scenario in Business Rules Admin.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign the rule to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Form Routing to Next Step&lt;/STRONG&gt; trigger.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This important enhancement empowers HR and system administrators to create &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;smarter, conditional review flows&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; - &lt;EM&gt;fostering fairness, helps eliminate bias, balancing consistency with flexibility&lt;/EM&gt; in performance management processes that align seamlessly with overarching organizational goals of transparency and impartiality.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Take Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Performance reviews should adapt to your business needs. With this new rule scenario, you can make your process &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;intelligent and responsive&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Start configuring today and experience the difference!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+SuccessFactors+Performance+%252526+Goals/pd-p/73555000100800000774" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="170-1"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Performance &amp;amp; Goals&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+SuccessFactors+HCM+Core/pd-p/67837800100800006332" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="847-1"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors HCM Core&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+SuccessFactors+HCM+Suite/pd-p/67838200100800004730" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="163-1"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors HCM Suite&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/successfactors-2h-2025-release-smarter-review-flows-with-new-business-rule/ba-p/14273940"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:32:45.272000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/turning-sap-data-into-process-intelligence-the-future-of-seamless/ba-p/14273944</id>
    <title>Turning SAP Data into Process Intelligence: The Future of Seamless Connectivity</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:33:04.846000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jelisaveta_Nikolic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/175903</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Every transformation journey starts with one question: &lt;STRONG&gt;Can I truly trust the data that drives my decisions?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For many SAP customers, the answer depends on how easily and reliably process-relevant data can move from core ERP systems into the analytical layer. Until now, that often meant complex setups, manual extractions, and limited scalability.&lt;BR /&gt;But that’s changing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A New Era of Data Replication&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;With SAP Datasphere replication flows, SAP customers can now connect SAP ECC and SAP S/4HANA systems directly to SAP Signavio Process Intelligence with even more efficiency - turning operational data into actionable insight at enterprise scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Mass extraction of SAP data with SAP Datasphere replication flows" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343276i157912897F658FDD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mass extr.png" alt="Mass extraction of SAP data with SAP Datasphere replication flows" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Mass extraction of SAP data with SAP Datasphere replication flows&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In process transformation, speed and reliability are everything. Organizations need to see how their processes actually run - not last month, but right now. By leveraging SAP Datasphere’s built-in replication and Change Data Capture (CDC) capabilities, businesses can ensure continuous, near real-time synchronization of their SAP data landscape, having their data automatically updated in SAP Signavio Process Intelligence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The result?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Faster insights:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Data from SAP systems flows instantly into SAP Signavio Process Intelligence for mining and monitoring.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proven reliability:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Built on SAP-standard connectivity, it ensures compliance, governance, and peace of mind.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;True scalability:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Whether you run SAP ECC, SAP S/4HANA on-prem, private, or public cloud — it grows with your transformation journey.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplicity Meets Power&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;By reusing the SAP standard connectivity (e.g. SAP Cloud Connector), the integration offers a clean, standardized setup. No additional approval and implementation needed for Signavio dedicated connectivity. No data staging. Just smooth, direct data replication, monitored and managed through SAP Datasphere’s transparent interface and a future-proof way to bring data to life.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Empowering Continuous Transformation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;When your process data is always current, your insights are always relevant. This is what makes SAP Datasphere replication flows more than a connectivity upgrade: it’s a strategic foundation for data-driven transformation.&lt;BR /&gt;Together, SAP Datasphere and SAP Signavio Process Intelligence empower organizations to turn system data into business truth, helping leaders make faster, smarter decisions with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, SAP Datasphere replication flows are redefining how SAP customers move from data to insight — unlocking reliability, scalability, and transparency across the enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;It’s not just integration.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;It’s connection with purpose.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapsignavio.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/releases/index.html?show=slide!SL_5D77A1DD0DC2B188" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to start a step-by-step enable now tutorial for this feature.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Want to know more? &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/source-data-extraction-for-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-using-sap/ba-p/14030384?emcs_t=S2h8ZW1haWx8dG9waWNfc3Vic2NyaXB0aW9ufE1IVTIxQTQ5VVFJOEpIfDE0MDMwMzg0fFNVQlNDUklQVElPTlN8aEs" target="_self"&gt;Check out this end-to-end explanation of the feature!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/turning-sap-data-into-process-intelligence-the-future-of-seamless/ba-p/14273944"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:33:04.846000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/bc-p/14273947#M186526</id>
    <title>Re: Give Your AI Agent Some Tools: Introducing the UI5 MCP Server</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:34:53.335000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FlorianVogt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/216201</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145953"&gt;@MartinSommer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;thanks a lot for your comment. Currently, UI5 MCP server does not support the offline use case but this is definitely a good candidate for a feature request. Feel free to create one via&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server/issues/new?template=2-feature-request.yml" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server/issues/new?template=2-feature-request.yml&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/bc-p/14273947#M186526"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:34:53.335000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/outlook-activities-failing-in-automation-is-there-an-alternative-method-to/qaq-p/14273948</id>
    <title>Outlook activities failing in automation – Is there an alternative method to send emails or a versio</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:35:17.572000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yomayusa92</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1400478</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have an automation in SAP (formerly SAP Intelligent RPA, now SAP Build Process Automation) that sends emails using the Outlook activities. This process has worked for a long time, but recently it has started failing frequently due to an Outlook permission error. The issue seems to be related to Outlook restrictions or blocked access when the automation tries to send the email.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to know:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this behavior related to any version or compatibility requirement of Microsoft Outlook when using the Outlook activities in SAP automations?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does SAP offer an alternative or recommended method for sending emails that does not depend on the Outlook desktop client?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there any official guidance on whether the Outlook version installed on the machine affects the reliability of these activities?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any insights, documentation references, or best practices would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/outlook-activities-failing-in-automation-is-there-an-alternative-method-to/qaq-p/14273948"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:35:17.572000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-forum/joule-skill-behavior-will-custom-skills-override-or-combine-with-sap/td-p/14273952</id>
    <title>Joule Skill Behavior: Will Custom Skills Override or Combine with SAP Default Knowledge Sources?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:40:26.152000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DIpanshuBhangale</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1641847</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If Joule is integrated in a shared environment like s4hana, sfsf and currently retrieves answers from SAP’s default knowledge sources (such as SAP KBAs),&lt;BR /&gt;and if we later develop and publish a custom Joule Skill,&lt;BR /&gt;then will user queries trigger only the custom skill,&lt;BR /&gt;or will Joule still perform multi-source retrieval, combining outputs from both our custom skill and the default SAP KBAs?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-forum/joule-skill-behavior-will-custom-skills-override-or-combine-with-sap/td-p/14273952"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:40:26.152000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-added-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-with-databricks-snowflake-and-ms/ba-p/14273953</id>
    <title>The Added Value of SAP Business Data Cloud with Databricks, Snowflake and MS Fabric</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:41:22.717000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>florian_hamon</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/60103</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;There as been a lot of partnership announcement lately broadening the extend of SAP Business Data Cloud capabilities and integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s multi-platform data landscapes, organizations are increasingly blending SAP and non-SAP data to drive insights, automate decision-making, and accelerate innovation. But combining the trusted semantics of SAP with the scalability and flexibility of modern cloud data platforms is not always straightforward.&lt;BR /&gt;This is where &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;—powered by SAP Datasphere—delivers extraordinary strategic value. And with &lt;STRONG&gt;BDC connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP takes cross-ecosystem integration even further, enabling a harmonized, governed, bidirectional data fabric that works seamlessly with platforms such as &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Fabric, Snowflake, and Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765547276"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why SAP Business Data Cloud Changes the Game&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud is designed to bridge the historical gap between SAP’s rich business context and the broader data landscape. It moves beyond simple data replication or extraction: it &lt;STRONG&gt;preserves SAP’s business semantics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, delivers harmonized models, and enables federated consumption with minimal data movement, to take on-time decisions based on data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s what makes it transformative:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698116490"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Business-ready data out of the box&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP systems contain deeply embedded logic—currency conversions, hierarchies, master data relationships, authorizations, time-dependencies—none of which carry over when raw tables are moved into a data lake or modern warehouse.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Throughts Business Data Cloud, SAP provides out-of-the box Data Products that automatically collects and exposes SAP data &lt;STRONG&gt;with meaning intact&lt;/STRONG&gt;, avoiding:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;custom semantic reconstruction&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;brittle pipelines&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;manual hierarchical transformations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This dramatically reduces time-to-insight for downstream analytics platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501602985"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Governance, lineage, and security at enterprise scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;BDC maintains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;end-to-end lineage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP role-based security&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;metadata enrichment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;business catalogs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This ensures that downstream platforms consume &lt;STRONG&gt;trusted, governed data&lt;/STRONG&gt;, not raw or misinterpreted tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176006761"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How BDC combines with Microsoft Fabric, Snowflake, and Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAP Business Data Cloud is a fully standalone powerful platform for data and analytics, customers may have chosen another technology to handle some aspects of their data storage and governance. Providing a partnership with these platforms enables to propose a deep integration within a broader ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108575975"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":blue_book:"&gt;📘&lt;/span&gt; SAP Business Data Cloud + Microsoft Fabric&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;BDC connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Fabric can tap directly into SAP semantic models with a zero-copy capabilities enabling to successfully combine SAP and non-SAP data and leverging the existing features of Microfot Fabric.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912062470"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":snowflake:"&gt;❄️&lt;/span&gt; SAP Business Data Cloud + Snowflake&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Snowflake excels at multi-cloud elasticity, secure data sharing, and workload isolation. BDC complements Snowflake through:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-optimized data contracts exposed as Snowflake-ready datasets&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replication or federation with preserved semantics&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Accelerated development of Snowflake Data Cloud applications using SAP-trusted data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here too, the BDC Connect capabilities enables to do a zero-copy sharing of the data, avoiding data replication and keeping the context of the data..&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715548965"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":fire:"&gt;🔥&lt;/span&gt; SAP Business Data Cloud + Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Databricks is the leader in lakehouse architecture, ML/AI workloads, and open data formats. With BDC:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data scientists gain business-aware SAP data without reverse-engineering SAP logic&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;ML models can be trained on harmonized SAP+non-SAP datasets&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Semantic consistency is maintained from source to model consumption&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unity Catalog benefits from SAP lineage and metadata&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;BDC connect enables bi-directional zero-copy interoperability, including pushing curated datasets back into analytics or operational systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-389952741"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BDC connect: The Integration Accelerator&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A core enabler in the ecosystem is &lt;STRONG&gt;BDC connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;, providing a streamlined, governed, and high-performance integration zero-copy mechanism between SAP Business Data Cloud and modern data platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With BDC connect, your data platform of choice becomes &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP-aware by design&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarize :&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BDC ensures your modern data platforms stop treating SAP as just another source, and start treating it as a first-class, business-ready data foundation.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-added-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-with-databricks-snowflake-and-ms/ba-p/14273953"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:41:22.717000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/po-not-getting-creating-error-express-document-quot-update-was-cancelled/qaa-p/14273956#M4932111</id>
    <title>Re: PO not getting creating error EXPRESS DOCUMENT "UPDATE WAS CANCELLED"</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:48:55.745000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ANKITAPRAJAPATI1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2052868</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/681078"&gt;@radinator&lt;/a&gt;,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/po-not-getting-creating-error-express-document-quot-update-was-cancelled/qaa-p/14273956#M4932111"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:48:55.745000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-erp-onprem-with-sap-drc-cloud-vs-ksef-number-in-fi-docs/qaq-p/14273958</id>
    <title>SAP ERP onPrem with SAP DRC Cloud vs. Ksef number in FI docs</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:57:19.673000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MSL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1574762</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In our SAP ERP on-prem system integrated with SAP DRC Cloud, the KSeF number is stored in the &lt;CODE&gt;EDOPLINV&lt;/CODE&gt; table. Could you clarify where and how this KSeF number is transferred to the FI document generated for the SD invoice?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-erp-onprem-with-sap-drc-cloud-vs-ksef-number-in-fi-docs/qaq-p/14273958"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:57:19.673000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/help-with-a-webi-variable/qaa-p/14273959#M458229</id>
    <title>Re: help with a webi variable</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:58:27.257000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bekart</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/699280</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;hello,&lt;BR /&gt;I guess there is more than one solution but let's focus on that:&lt;BR /&gt;you can create additional variable:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;if date:&lt;BR /&gt;=If([date]=[last amended date]) Then 1&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Then in your table add column and put formula (or make another variable):&lt;BR /&gt;=Max([old status] Where ([if date]=1)) In ([Account];[Category])&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I am doing it without access to Webi so I hope that will help&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face_with_sweat:"&gt;😅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/help-with-a-webi-variable/qaa-p/14273959#M458229"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:58:27.257000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/increase-business-outcomes-by-unleashing-the-power-of-ai-agents/ba-p/14273934</id>
    <title>Increase business outcomes by unleashing the power of AI agents</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:00:00.036000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoseBastidas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Increase business outcomes by unleashing the power of AI agents.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343268iFB47D9281F8FA21A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Increase business outcomes by unleashing the power of AI agents.png" alt="Increase business outcomes by unleashing the power of AI agents.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re an SAP partner, you’ve probably heard “AI agents” mentioned in every second customer conversation lately. &amp;nbsp;The thing is… most teams still aren’t sure &lt;STRONG&gt;how&lt;/STRONG&gt; to use them in real projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s exactly what we’ll unpack in our upcoming webinar, &lt;STRONG&gt;“Increase business outcomes by unleashing the power of AI agents.”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ll start by demystifying SAP’s &lt;STRONG&gt;agentic landscape&lt;/STRONG&gt;—what agents are, how they think and act, and when they’re the right tool. &amp;nbsp;Then we’ll roll up our sleeves and show how you can use &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Studio’s low-code / no-code agent builder&lt;/STRONG&gt; to design content-based agents that plug into SAP BTP, SAP Build, and your existing processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My favorite part? A &lt;STRONG&gt;real customer-style scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;: an AI-powered technical advisory/support system for professional services that quietly accelerates delivery without sacrificing quality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you know the basics of cloud-native, AI, and SAP BTP, you’re ready.&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt; and let’s turn the hype into outcomes your customers will feel.&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jun/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010558.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jun/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010558.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPBTP #SAPPartnerEcosystem #GenerativeAI #JouleStudio #SAPBuild #ProcessAutomation&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/increase-business-outcomes-by-unleashing-the-power-of-ai-agents/ba-p/14273934"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:00:00.036000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-business-objects-webi-toggle-columns/qaa-p/14273961#M4932112</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Business Objects WebI toggle Columns</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:01:38.889000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bekart</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/699280</uri>
    </author>
    <content>may is worth to consider put multiple tables and just use option Hide when formula is true. So if user will enter any input then the table will be shown as expected. also is feasible to do filtering based on User ID.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-business-objects-webi-toggle-columns/qaa-p/14273961#M4932112"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:01:38.889000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crystalreportviewer-text-field-is-grow-to-whole-row-unlike-winforms-version/qaa-p/14273962#M4932113</id>
    <title>Re: CrystalReportViewer text field is grow to whole row....</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:04:49.212000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SoftwareMemo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1391290</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hey , Thanks for your reply. but actually Registry keys doesn't works. regardless of my previous modified EnableCanGrow code. the text is still overlapping. I use latest SP38 CR Runtime now. all reports are same. any description/database text field overlapping its width and shrinker into next elements.I tried&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Wow6432Node\SAP BusinessObjects\Crystal Reports for .NET Framework 4.0\Crystal Reports\DesignerOptions] &amp;nbsp;"DealWithMinimalMarginsWhenPrinting"=”0”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\SAP BusinessObjects\Crystal Reports for .NET Framework 4.0\Crystal Reports\DesignerOptions] "DealWithMinimalMarginsWhenPrinting"=”0”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\WOW6432Node\SAP BusinessObjects\Suite XI 4.0\Crystal Reports\DesignerOptions] "DealWithMinimalMarginsWhenPrinting"=”0”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I don't know how this not happened to any client before. If you never mind can you try in your side? empty ASP.NET Webforms with empty simple crystal reports *.rpt. and assign database text field into it with large data that is larger than field width inside .rpt?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Edit:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here's new fresh *.rpt file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Web same issue&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In WinForms no problem&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;in rpt designer&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;script.sql file&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1zleObOxQ-U9-sq5aLVsARc-FI-OMtL-t/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1zleObOxQ-U9-sq5aLVsARc-FI-OMtL-t/view?usp=sharing&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;simple *.rpt file&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1tXTzadjg7mksT-4oSWUuH1P_rkyU0dY_/view?usp=drive_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1tXTzadjg7mksT-4oSWUuH1P_rkyU0dY_/view?usp=drive_link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Would you mind if you can test it in your PC? and send me a screenshot please?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Edit: short Video of the issue:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4_z-usjHHYo" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4_z-usjHHYo&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Edit: 06:20 UTC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I found strange link that have same issue I have&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/can-grow-option/qaq-p/9713374" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/can-grow-option/qaq-p/9713374&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;there's answer from DellSC Contributor. looks like registry key for very old CrystalReports?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some old posts have similar issue but its very old &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/truncateclippedfieldstrings-registry-setting-not-fixing-overlap-problem/qaq-p/11575425" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/truncateclippedfieldstrings-registry-setting-not-fixing-overlap-problem/qaq-p/11575425&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Edit: Finally A solution that worked!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CRYSTAL_REPORTS,_DEVELOPER_VERSION_FOR_MICROSOFT_VISUAL_STUDIO/0d6684e153174710b8b2eb114bb7f843/45c0992c6e041014910aba7db0e91070.html#enabletextclipping" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CRYSTAL_REPORTS,_DEVELOPER_VERSION_FOR_MICROSOFT_VISUAL_STUDIO/0d6684e153174710b8b2eb114bb7f843/45c0992c6e041014910aba7db0e91070.html#enabletextclipping&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;in Web.Config just add this line:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-csharp"&gt;&lt;code&gt;      &amp;lt;crystalReportViewer&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;add key="ResourceUri" value="/crystalreportviewers13" /&amp;gt;
		  &amp;lt;add key="EnableTextClipping" value="true"/&amp;gt;
	  &amp;lt;/crystalReportViewer&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crystalreportviewer-text-field-is-grow-to-whole-row-unlike-winforms-version/qaa-p/14273962#M4932113"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:04:49.212000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/scrapping-materials-from-warehouse/qaa-p/14273964#M4231863</id>
    <title>Re: Scrapping Materials from Warehouse</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:05:43.216000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jignesh_mehta3</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/186721</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;To me Sales Order process looks more suitable here.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Sales Order Type for this process can have a Delivery Block and only designated employees can release this block.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also look at Workflows for Sales Order Approval.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/scrapping-materials-from-warehouse/qaa-p/14273964#M4231863"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:05:43.216000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/is-there-any-way-to-send-automatic-reminders-for-overdue-tasks-in-calm/qaq-p/14273979</id>
    <title>Is there any way to send automatic reminders for overdue tasks in CALM implementation?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:07:20.949000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>YK7</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1401149</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear colleagues,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we have to invest great amount of effort for reminding the project team nearly everyday for the overdue tasks in CALM. Is there any way to automize this process? Or any way to make mass emails?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/is-there-any-way-to-send-automatic-reminders-for-overdue-tasks-in-calm/qaq-p/14273979"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:07:20.949000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-set-a-field-to-filter-people-in-directory-search-based-on-their/qaq-p/14273998</id>
    <title>How to set a field to filter people in directory search based on their skills? (SAP SF)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:11:02.287000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dariavalgutskova</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2258055</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I need the following to be set in the system:&amp;nbsp; directory searach should have a custom field (as on a screen), that allows to filter based on skills of employees, that are entered in growth portfolio of employees.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dariavalgutskova_0-1763654212440.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343280i8DF3AEABA057B534/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dariavalgutskova_0-1763654212440.png" alt="dariavalgutskova_0-1763654212440.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, I struggle to understand, what settings I need to set for the custom field, that I choose in "custom filters" to add the field in directory search.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are 2 main issues for me:&lt;BR /&gt;1) Skills do not come from picklists&lt;BR /&gt;2) There are no field, that include skills in HRIS elements.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because of that I am not sure how this customization is supposed to be done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-set-a-field-to-filter-people-in-directory-search-based-on-their/qaq-p/14273998"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:11:02.287000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/inbound-delivery-attachment/qaa-p/14273997#M208231</id>
    <title>Re: Inbound delivery attachment</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:11:05.586000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Instead of checking in VL33N, did you check in Fiori Display Inbound Delivery app for user B? Attachments are fully visible there with display-only roles.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/inbound-delivery-attachment/qaa-p/14273997#M208231"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:11:05.586000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/contract-and-lease-management-pricing-based-on-usable-or-rentable-objects/qaa-p/14274046#M256531</id>
    <title>Re: Contract and Lease management Pricing based on Usable or Rentable Objects</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:14:13.752000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Emma_Boye</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2266882</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have the same problem with CLM.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Did you have an answer ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/contract-and-lease-management-pricing-based-on-usable-or-rentable-objects/qaa-p/14274046#M256531"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:14:13.752000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-professional-services-complex-discount/qaa-p/14274086#M4231864</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Professional Services - Complex Discount Structure</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:18:09.118000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you very much!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you please check whether the following post provides helpful information:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/which-way-to-provide-discount-in-customer-project-in-professional-service/qaq-p/12623008" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/which-way-to-provide-discount-in-customer-project-in-professional-service/qaq-p/12623008&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/89d896ca9cd64318b1667df5ec00e4b2/c7ce61533be7ff4fe10000000a44176d.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Contract-Based Revenue Recognition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Henrike&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-professional-services-complex-discount/qaa-p/14274086#M4231864"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:18:09.118000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/issue-with-loading-creating-story-reports-in-non-production-instances/qaa-p/14274087#M49462</id>
    <title>Re: Issue with Loading/Creating Story Reports in Non-Prod...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:20:23.566000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>boxcarpilot</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1691009</uri>
    </author>
    <content>In our case, this was solution! Thanks. A resync to IAS fixed the issue with Story Reports after a domain change</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/issue-with-loading-creating-story-reports-in-non-production-instances/qaa-p/14274087#M49462"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:20:23.566000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/getting-error-while-importing-tr-for-role-collection-transport-in-ctms/qaq-p/14274090</id>
    <title>Getting error while importing TR for role collection transport in CTMS</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:25:03.851000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Incture</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/94629</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to transport custom role collections from my DEV subaccount to my QA subaccount through CTMS (integration with Content Agent Service UI). I have followed the blogs and SAP documentation regarding the same and have configured all the required steps. The integration is successful and I am able to perform the export and TR creation inside the Content Agent Service. But when trying to import the same into my QA system through CTMS I am encountering the following error -&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"CTS+ deployment for "850413f5-c" failed: "Error with creating a client for content service "xsuaa_service": Error retrieving required property "uaa" for service key "Z_IS-CPI_ADMIN-xsuaa_service-credentials" for service "xsuaa_service" "&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, I am not sure on the below point:&lt;BR /&gt;1.&amp;nbsp; Should the XSUAA service instance and key be created from the BTP tenants manually, or just getting the API credentials from the BTP CLI and using that for creating the destination is enough?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please let me know what I am missing here as everything seems to working till the point of the XSUAA instance and key creation in the target subaccount.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the help. Appreciate it.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/getting-error-while-importing-tr-for-role-collection-transport-in-ctms/qaq-p/14274090"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:25:03.851000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/enterprise-content-management/qaa-p/14274091#M4231865</id>
    <title>Re: Enterprise content Management</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:26:25.319000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ericliam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2266884</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’re right that SAP DMS and SAP ECM are related but not the same. A SAP DMS consultant mainly focuses on Web DMS, Easy DMS, and document handling within SAP. SAP ECM is broader, covering content management, workflows, and enterprise-wide integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s not strictly necessary for a DMS consultant to know all of ECM, but understanding it helps, especially when considering integrations with other platforms. Tools like&amp;nbsp;Dokmee can complement SAP DMS/ECM by offering advanced document management, workflow automation, and secure content storage outside SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warm regards.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/enterprise-content-management/qaa-p/14274091#M4231865"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:26:25.319000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-adt-package-deleted/qaa-p/14274092#M4932116</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud ADT Package deleted</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:27:15.748000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aarnavpant</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1544342</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160542"&gt;@adnanmaqbool&lt;/a&gt;, I do not have much idea about whether it can be recovered from the QAS or production system. but if you have the deleted objects in other systems. you can shift them to your working system using abapgit. Here are the steps you can perform:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- create a new branch and push all deleted objects to the new branch.&lt;BR /&gt;- now in your repository link switch branch to the newly created one (this feature should be there is the newest AbapGit version).&lt;BR /&gt;- trigger a pull but while selecting modified objects do not select any removal of existing objects. (this would allow your objects to be pulled to the system with current set of objects).&lt;BR /&gt;- after your pull is finished you will have all the deleted objects and your existing objects together. As for objects with inconsistencies, I can't say if this approach will help that case as well.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Aarnav&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-adt-package-deleted/qaa-p/14274092#M4932116"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:27:15.748000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/part-7-how-to-search-for-sap-standard-cds-views/bc-p/14274093#M72263</id>
    <title>Re: Part#7. How to search for SAP standard CDS Views</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:28:00.190000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Soami</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1631797</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Please upgrade this Blog for SAP On Premise 2023&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/part-7-how-to-search-for-sap-standard-cds-views/bc-p/14274093#M72263"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:28:00.190000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/we-want-to-use-quot-predecessor-journal-entry-quot-in-custom-logic/qaa-p/14274095#M4231866</id>
    <title>Re: We want to use "Predecessor Journal Entry" in Custom...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:29:27.384000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you very much for your question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you please check whether the following CDS view serves your purpose?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/c0c54048d35849128be8e872df5bea6d/98a0b7ae68b14856acad8228201f77d7.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Journal Entry Item Browser (C_JournalEntryItemBrowser)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Henrike&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/we-want-to-use-quot-predecessor-journal-entry-quot-in-custom-logic/qaa-p/14274095#M4231866"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:29:27.384000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-studio-goes-live-answers-to-your-top-questions/bc-p/14274096#M186528</id>
    <title>Re: Joule Studio Goes Live: Answers to Your Top Questions</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:30:35.829000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Goncalo_Nolasco</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/167993</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we're facing the same error as&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1401043"&gt;@MuhammadSubhan&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131145"&gt;@StefanieSchulke&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Was anyone able to find a solution? It's strange as the skill works as intended in the standalone Joule client but fails with the error when executed in SuccessFactors:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Destination SAP_SBPA_API could not be found (error code: BusinessConnector - 0001, id: 5965709e-14cc-4737-b279-ef81e92d2162) Original Error: Failed to retrieve destination: SAP_SBPA_API for CURRENT_TENANT strategy (error code: JCore - 5802, id: 25c16f9a-30cf-4b85-a35c-c93156484b07&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-studio-goes-live-answers-to-your-top-questions/bc-p/14274096#M186528"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:30:35.829000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-blog-posts/free-sap-certification-and-practice-systems-for-students-amp-lecturers/bc-p/14274098#M4287</id>
    <title>Re: Free SAP Certification and practice systems for students &amp; lecturers</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:34:55.044000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>juan_tarapuez</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2264795</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/113"&gt;@David_Chaviano1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Hola, el proceso de registro de estudiantes ya lo realice e hice todos los pasos recomendados por la Universidad de la CUC Colombia, para ser verificado pero aun no me verifican este proceso ya lo hice hace mas de dos semanas pero aun me sale este mensaje no se cuanto tiempo deba seguir esperando&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="juan_tarapuez_0-1763656466425.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343394iEF0A8424FAB2DC06/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="juan_tarapuez_0-1763656466425.png" alt="juan_tarapuez_0-1763656466425.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-blog-posts/free-sap-certification-and-practice-systems-for-students-amp-lecturers/bc-p/14274098#M4287"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:34:55.044000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/scanning-the-storage-bin-s-barcode-s4h-public-cloud/qaq-p/14274099</id>
    <title>Scanning the storage bin's barcode S4H public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:35:17.650000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CarmenRuiz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/167727</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The client requires that when they change/confirm the storage bin of an HU using the RF device, the barcode in the warehouse is scanned to identify the storage bin. This code being the storage bin verification code, which is different from the storage bin code.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This happen when performing a goods receipt from a vendor and also when transferring a Handling Unit (HU) to a different storage bin.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This functionality is part of the standard process: the system should use the location verification code as the storage bin code because the user is physically in front of the correct bin. The verification code is intentionally different from the actual storage bin code to prevent users from entering the bin code from anywhere in the warehouse.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's like 3435076 - Control de verificación en /SCWM/RFUI&amp;nbsp; Note SAP but for 4Shanna public Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please let us know if there is any customizing we still need to activate for this to work as intended, or how it should be done.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance for your support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/scanning-the-storage-bin-s-barcode-s4h-public-cloud/qaq-p/14274099"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:35:17.650000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/scrapping-materials-from-warehouse/qaa-p/14274100#M4231868</id>
    <title>Re: Scrapping Materials from Warehouse</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:37:45.581000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Two options are there to meet your requirement.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Option-1&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Go with sales order delivery block as suggested already but it has its own limitations which are&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Delivery Block is a binary control (blocked/unblocked). It doesn’t support multi‑level approvals or workflow like PO release strategy.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;You will know who removed the block, but you don’t get structured approval history like in MM release strategy. From audit point of view, this method is weak&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Introducing customer master data and logistics flows that are irrelevant for scrapping.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Option-2&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Create a dedicated vendor master (e.g., “SCRAP VENDOR”) flagged as internal. Configure PO document type specifically for scrapping. Assign account assignment category (e.g., K = Cost Center) to ensure postings hit the correct G/L and cost center. Maintain release strategy for this PO type, so scrapping requests go through approval.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Once PO is approved, scrapping can be executed via MIGO against the PO (movement type 551). This will still generate TR/TO, so RF picking remains intact. The warehouse process does not change — only the initiation step is controlled via PO release.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Finance can monitor scrapping via PO reporting. G/L accounts and cost centers are explicitly controlled in PO account assignment. Audit trail is stronger: PO → Release → MIGO → TR/TO.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/scrapping-materials-from-warehouse/qaa-p/14274100#M4231868"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:37:45.581000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-cpq-tableau/qaq-p/14274102</id>
    <title>SAP CPQ → Tableau?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:37:54.206000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sergey_L</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/666005</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Has anyone figured out a way to get Tableau to connect to CPQ? And on what engine, Quote 2.0?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-cpq-tableau/qaq-p/14274102"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:37:54.206000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-direct-connectivity-with-event-mesh-in-integration-suite/bc-p/14274105#M186529</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S/4HANA direct connectivity with Event Mesh in Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:40:07.596000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Giuseppe432</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1472968</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Satishvch,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;have you solved the issue? I have the same issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Giuseppe&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-direct-connectivity-with-event-mesh-in-integration-suite/bc-p/14274105#M186529"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:40:07.596000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/integration-of-sap-s-4hana-and-sap-analytics-cloud-enterprise-edition/bc-p/14274107#M62512</id>
    <title>Re: Integration of SAP S/4HANA and SAP Analytics Cloud Enterprise Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:41:45.710000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>imtihaz_hussein1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/194257</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Miraoui,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the great blog. As this was written in 2021, is there a more recent blog or help guide to embed SAC stories in S4?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The above help link does not work for me. I get the message I am not authorised. What authorizations do I need?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/integration-of-sap-s-4hana-and-sap-analytics-cloud-enterprise-edition/bc-p/14274107#M62512"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:41:45.710000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/getting-error-while-importing-tr-for-role-collection-transport-in-ctms/qaa-p/14274108#M4932117</id>
    <title>Re: Getting error while importing TR for role collection transport in CTMS</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:42:36.072000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Incture</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/94629</uri>
    </author>
    <content>PS: I tried both the approached (creating XSUAA instance manually in both subaccounts and creating destinations/ creating API credentials using CLI for both subaccounts and then creating destination using those details) but I am getting the same error in both scenarios.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/getting-error-while-importing-tr-for-role-collection-transport-in-ctms/qaa-p/14274108#M4932117"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:42:36.072000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crystal-report-not-supressing-empty-sub-report/qaa-p/14274109#M4932118</id>
    <title>Re: Crystal report not supressing empty sub-report</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:43:01.006000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ido_millet</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/210105</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;1. Make sure the subreport is located in its own main report section.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;2. In the Section Expert for that section, turn on the property of '&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Suppress Blank Section&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;'&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crystal-report-not-supressing-empty-sub-report/qaa-p/14274109#M4932118"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:43:01.006000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/mac-os-java-lang-illegalaccesserror-xmltask-xpathanalyser15-cannot-access/qaq-p/14274112</id>
    <title>Mac OS | java.lang.IllegalAccessError: xmltask XPathAnalyser15 cannot access</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:53:02.583000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vijay2604</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1936688</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to run an Ant build (&amp;nbsp;ant clean all&amp;nbsp;) for my SAP Commerce Cloud (Hybris) project on a local macOS environment. The build fails immediately with a &amp;nbsp;java.lang.IllegalAccessError&amp;nbsp; related to the &amp;nbsp;xmltask&amp;nbsp; library attempting to access internal JDK classes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;OS: macOS 26 (Tahoe)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Java Version: Java 17&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Error: Here is the full stack trace I am receiving:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;BUILD FAILED
/Users/shrikanth/Documents/Vijay/CCv2/hybris/bin/platform/build.xml:100: The following error occurred while executing this line:
.../hybris/bin/platform/resources/ant/modulegen.xml:351: The following error occurred while executing this line:
.../hybris/bin/platform/resources/ant/modulegen.xml:357: The following error occurred while executing this line:
.../hybris/bin/platform/resources/ant/modulegen.xml:271: &lt;STRONG&gt;java.lang.IllegalAccessError: class com.oopsconsultancy.xmltask.jdk15.XPathAnalyser15 (in unnamed module @0x52caa9d8) cannot access class com.sun.org.apache.xpath.internal.objects.XNodeSet (in module java.xml) because module java.xml does not export com.sun.org.apache.xpath.internal.objects to unnamed module @0x52caa9d8&lt;/STRONG&gt;
    at com.oopsconsultancy.xmltask.jdk15.XPathAnalyser15.analyse(XPathAnalyser15.java:29)
    at com.oopsconsultancy.xmltask.XmlReplace.apply(XmlReplace.java:72)
    at com.oopsconsultancy.xmltask.XmlReplacement.apply(XmlReplacement.java:61)
    at com.oopsconsultancy.xmltask.ant.XmlTask.processDoc(XmlTask.java:692)
    at com.oopsconsultancy.xmltask.ant.XmlTask.execute(XmlTask.java:661)
    at org.apache.tools.ant.UnknownElement.execute(UnknownElement.java:299)
    at jdk.internal.reflect.GeneratedMethodAccessor4.invoke(Unknown Source)
    at java.base/jdk.internal.reflect.DelegatingMethodAccessorImpl.invoke(DelegatingMethodAccessorImpl.java:43)
    at java.base/java.lang.reflect.Method.invoke(Method.java:569)
    at org.apache.tools.ant.dispatch.DispatchUtils.execute(DispatchUtils.java:99)
    at org.apache.tools.ant.Task.perform(Task.java:350)
    at java.base/java.util.Vector.forEach(Vector.java:1365)
    at org.apache.tools.ant.taskdefs.Sequential.execute(Sequential.java:67)
    at net.sf.antcontrib.logic.IfTask.execute(IfTask.java:197)
    at jdk.internal.reflect.GeneratedMethodAccessor23.invoke(Unknown Source)
    at java.base/jdk.internal.reflect.DelegatingMethodAccessorImpl.invoke(DelegatingMethodAccessorImpl.java:43)&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have already attempted the fixes mentioned in top search results—specifically the ones linked below—but nothing works:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/53633788/java-lang-illegalaccesserror-cannot-access-class-because-module-does-not-export" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;java.lang.IllegalAccessError: cannot access class because module does not export to unnamed module&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/xpathanalyser15-error-during-build/qaq-p/12688941" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/xpathanalyser15-error-during-build/qaq-p/12688941&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone else faced this blocking issue specifically on macOS 26 (Tahoe)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/mac-os-java-lang-illegalaccesserror-xmltask-xpathanalyser15-cannot-access/qaq-p/14274112"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:53:02.583000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/add-new-column-that-pull-its-value-from-goal-plan/qaq-p/14274113</id>
    <title>add new column that pull its value from goal plan</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T17:53:04.900000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>user116</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1448673</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Our variable pay form pulls the list of users objectives from the goal plan, but we want also to add another column on the form (which is "objective indicator"&amp;nbsp; and its value should also be pulled from the user goal plan). Is it possible to map between these 2 fields so that the indicator field in the variable pay form pulls data from the indicator field in the goal plan?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/add-new-column-that-pull-its-value-from-goal-plan/qaq-p/14274113"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T17:53:04.900000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/i-have-one-requirement-where-download-file-in-al11-and-email-it/qaq-p/14274119</id>
    <title>I have one requirement where download file in al11 and email it</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:00:47.074000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nanditasarkar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2254353</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have one standard program -RAGITT_ALV01.i need to create one z program which will store the data in a internal table and save it in application server as xlsx also email it as xlsx&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/i-have-one-requirement-where-download-file-in-al11-and-email-it/qaq-p/14274119"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:00:47.074000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-license-counting-logic/bc-p/14274120#M186530</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance License Counting Logic</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:01:16.969000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JuliaLu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131826</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Sorry, how can I delete it here, and would you help to provide the link to Q&amp;amp;A? Thank you so much.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-license-counting-logic/bc-p/14274120#M186530"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:01:16.969000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/bods-designer-crashes-with-faulting-module-path-c-windows-system32-ucrtbase/qaa-p/14274121#M4932121</id>
    <title>Re: BODS Designer Crashes with Faulting module path: C:\windows\System32\ucrtbase.dll</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:02:24.763000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alluri006</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2266894</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I have followed the KB Article still same issue. Please help me if i miss something</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/bods-designer-crashes-with-faulting-module-path-c-windows-system32-ucrtbase/qaa-p/14274121#M4932121"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:02:24.763000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/bods-designer-crashes-with-faulting-module-path-c-windows-system32-ucrtbase/qaa-p/14274122#M4932122</id>
    <title>Re: BODS Designer Crashes with Faulting module path: C:\windows\System32\ucrtbase.dll</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:03:08.002000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alluri006</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2266894</uri>
    </author>
    <content>C:\Program Files (x86)\SAP BusinessObjects\Data Services\bin&amp;gt;CreateDemoCerts.bat Could Not Find C:\Program Files (x86)\SAP BusinessObjects\Data Services\ssl\demo_temp\*.pem Could Not Find C:\Program Files (x86)\SAP BusinessObjects\Data Services\ssl\demo_temp\*.crt Could Not Find C:\Program Files (x86)\SAP BusinessObjects\Data Services\ssl\demo_temp\DS_Root_CA_serial Could Not Find C:\Program Files (x86)\SAP BusinessObjects\Data Services\ssl\demo_temp\DS_IntermediateCA_serial Could Not Find C:\Program Files (x86)\SAP BusinessObjects\Data Services\ssl\demo_temp\id.txt WARNING: can't open config file: ../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/ssl/openssl.cnf Generating Root CA private key WARNING: can't open config file: ../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/ssl/openssl.cnf Generating RSA private key, 2048 bit long modulus .........................................................+++ ................................................+++ e is 65537 (0x10001) Generating Root CA certificate WARNING: can't open config file: ../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/ssl/openssl.cnf Generating Intermediate CA private key WARNING: can't open config file: ../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/ssl/openssl.cnf Generating RSA private key, 2048 bit long modulus ....................................................................................................................+++ .......................................................+++ e is 65537 (0x10001) Generating Intermediate CA certificate WARNING: can't open config file: ../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/ssl/openssl.cnf Signing Intermediate CA certificate with Root CA private key WARNING: can't open config file: ../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/ssl/openssl.cnf Signature ok subject=/O=default_company/CN=Intermediate_CA_for_default_user_66969263077483ef Getting CA Private Key WARNING: can't open config file: ../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/ssl/openssl.cnf Generating DS Server private key WARNING: can't open config file: ../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/ssl/openssl.cnf Generating RSA private key, 2048 bit long modulus ..............................+++ .............................................................................................................+++ e is 65537 (0x10001) Generating DS Server certificate WARNING: can't open config file: ../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/ssl/openssl.cnf Signing DS Server certificate with Intermediate CA private key WARNING: can't open config file: ../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/../../../bin/tp.openssl/static/ssl/openssl.cnf Signature ok subject=/O=default_company/CN=DataServices_default_user_66969263077483ef Getting CA Private Key Copying trusted certificates to "C:\Program Files (x86)\SAP BusinessObjects\Data Services"\ssl\trusted_certs 1 file(s) copied. 1 file(s) copied. Copying CA certificates to "C:\Program Files (x86)\SAP BusinessObjects\Data Services"\ssl\CA 1 file(s) moved. 1 file(s) moved. 1 file(s) moved. 1 file(s) moved. 1 file(s) moved. 1 file(s) moved. 1 file(s) moved. 1 file(s) moved. 1 file(s) moved.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/bods-designer-crashes-with-faulting-module-path-c-windows-system32-ucrtbase/qaa-p/14274122#M4932122"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:03:08.002000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/automatic-reversal-functionality-after-payment-rejection/qaq-p/14274123</id>
    <title>Automatic reversal functionality after payment rejection</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:05:36.966000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;How to activate Auto-reject and reversal of payment batch in SAP S/4HANA public cloud edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/automatic-reversal-functionality-after-payment-rejection/qaq-p/14274123"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:05:36.966000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/automatic-reversal-functionality-after-payment-rejection/qaa-p/14274124#M4231870</id>
    <title>Re: Automatic reversal functionality after payment rejection</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:05:45.212000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;To set Payment Batch to the status "Automatically Rejected" in Public Cloud. For taking this activity all Clearing Payment Documents has to be manually Reset and Reversed (FBRA).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use the configuration SSC-UI 106107 Fix Errors for Payment Batches.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Read the configuration help on the SSC-UI details page.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable the functionality for "StatusFix" "AutoReject" "Mass Rest and Reversal" "AgentFix"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/automatic-reversal-functionality-after-payment-rejection/qaa-p/14274124#M4231870"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:05:45.212000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-license-counting-logic/qaq-p/14274125</id>
    <title>SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance License Counting Logic</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:11:03.269000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JuliaLu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131826</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expired Users&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP ERP and SAP S/4HANA, they will not be counted for SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance License, right?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When a SAP S/4HANA User is deemed to be expired, will IAG automatically stop monitoring that user and will the license consumption be reduced by 1? Thanks.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-license-counting-logic/qaq-p/14274125"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:11:03.269000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/creating-variable-from-2-different-queries/qaq-p/14274126</id>
    <title>Creating variable from 2 different queries.</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:11:42.940000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adrianp89</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2266892</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to create a variable that relies on data from two queries. Query A is database (limited data set) and Query B (master data) is excel. both have related IDs. I have merged the IDs into a merged field.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I attempt to use the below formula (modified to hide PI) I get incompatibility issues starting the QueryB data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;=If([Field1fromQueryA]="XYZ"; "P4";&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; If(&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; [Field2fromQueryA] InList("1"; "2"; "3"; "4"; "5")&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Or [Field1fromQueryB]="John Smith"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Or [Field2fromQueryB]="Jane Doe";&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "P1";&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; If(&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Pos([Field3fromQueryB]; "Sample") &amp;gt; 0&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Or Pos([Field4fromQueryB]; "Demo") &amp;gt; 0;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "P3";&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "P2"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; )&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; )&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/creating-variable-from-2-different-queries/qaq-p/14274126"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:11:42.940000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/i-9-reverification-in-onboarding-2-0/qaq-p/14274129</id>
    <title>I-9 Reverification in Onboarding 2.0</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:18:11.750000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aratishrestha</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/73542</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We have a scenario where an employee was hired on an EAD. As those document has Employment Authorization Expiration date, the I-9 reverification is triggered. Now the employee has a Green Card. While completing the I-9 reverification in Onboarding 2.0, our corporate representative does not get an option to select Green Card as an option. I found a KBA that says the I-9 Reverification can be cancelled and create a new Form I-9 needs with the new supporting document. Has anyone tried this before and can confirm if it is compliant? In Onboarding 1.0, this used to be an option.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/i-9-reverification-in-onboarding-2-0/qaq-p/14274129"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:18:11.750000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-support-components-powering-successfactors-integration-suite/ba-p/14274131</id>
    <title>SAP Support Components Powering SuccessFactors–Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:22:00.997000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ali_Chalhoub1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/194448</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Support Components Powering SuccessFactors–Integration Suite:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let's &lt;STRONG&gt;Fast-track your support!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check KBA - &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003663880" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3663880 - Support Component for issues between SAP SuccessFactors and Cloud Integration [Video KBA]&lt;/A&gt;. This essential video KBA guides you to the right Support Component for &lt;STRONG&gt;speedy case resolution&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Overview:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cloud Integration (CPI) is a middleware solution used for integrations between various systems, where source and target errors are seen, but&amp;nbsp;LOD-HCI-PI*&amp;nbsp;is not necessarily the correct component to address the issue. It is very important to know what the correct component for your Issues for an error in CPI for Integration scenarios with SuccessFactors.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Details:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Below picture shows that different component is responsible for error at different point in the end-to-end flow.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ali_Chalhoub1_0-1763658859710.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343405i091E19FC581C06B3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Ali_Chalhoub1_0-1763658859710.png" alt="Ali_Chalhoub1_0-1763658859710.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Here’s your &lt;STRONG&gt;One-Stop Quick Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the &lt;STRONG&gt;Right Support Components for SuccessFactors- SAP Cloud Platform Integration (CPI) scenarios:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SuccessFactors SFTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;KBA &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3649052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3649052 – Support Component for SFTP Issues in SAP SuccessFactors &amp;amp; Cloud Integration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SuccessFactors OData&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;KBA &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3650939" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3650939 – Support Components for OData Integration Issues between SAP SuccessFactors and Other Systems&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SuccessFactors Employee Central (EC)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;KBA &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3643421" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3643421 – Support Component for EC–SAP ERP Integration Issues&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SuccessFactors Recruiting Management (RCM)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;KBA &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3649444" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3649444 – Support Component for RCM Issues in SAP SuccessFactors &amp;amp; Cloud Integration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bookmark this now – Save time, solve errors faster, and always pick the &lt;STRONG&gt;right KBA at first go!&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-support-components-powering-successfactors-integration-suite/ba-p/14274131"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:22:00.997000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/help-needed-error-running-zdmo-cl-fe-travel-generator-in-learning-journey/qaa-p/14274134#M20110</id>
    <title>Re: Help Needed – Error Running ZDMO_CL_FE_TRAVEL_GENERAT...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:30:48.712000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FranCanul</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1526462</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1783930"&gt;@tisdenhakim&lt;/a&gt;, try using ZDMO_CL_FE_TRAVEL_GENERATOR, in my case /DMO/CL_FE_TRAVEL_GENERATOR only generated 11 objects, and the other class generated all 41 objects.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/help-needed-error-running-zdmo-cl-fe-travel-generator-in-learning-journey/qaa-p/14274134#M20110"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:30:48.712000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-in-equipment-replication-from-s4hana-to-sap-sales-cloud/qaq-p/14274140</id>
    <title>Error in Equipment Replication from S4HANA to SAP Sales Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T18:43:04.596000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mohamed982</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1757991</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We currently have a requirement to replicate Equipment from SAP S4Hana to SAP Sales Cloud version2. We have setup event mesh default plan in btp , and create channel via service key in Tcode &lt;STRONG&gt;/o/IWXBE/CONFIG&lt;/STRONG&gt;. But during activation the channel there is error displayed “ AMQP connection setup error for channel 'S4HANANEVENTMESH'”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Kindly advise on the required configuration to enable activation channel in S4Hana&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;note : we are using cloud connector&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Mohamed982_0-1763660487213.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343412i056BAE5A9000D8D5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Mohamed982_0-1763660487213.png" alt="Mohamed982_0-1763660487213.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-in-equipment-replication-from-s4hana-to-sap-sales-cloud/qaq-p/14274140"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T18:43:04.596000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/wildcard-search-within-successfactors-rule/ba-p/14273025</id>
    <title>Wildcard search within SuccessFactors rule</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T19:03:04.039000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nmanghnani</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/34497</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In SAP SuccessFactors, you cannot use wildcard characters like&amp;nbsp;*&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;?&amp;nbsp;directly within the standard business rule expression language. However, there is powerful duo of Match function and regular expression in SuccessFactors, which achieves pattern-matching functionality and is a powerful alternative to traditional wildcard searches.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765538536"&gt;Use cases for Regex in business rules:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validation of fields: Ensure that the value of a field, such as a phone number, employee ID, or cost center, matches a specific format.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Checking string pattern: Verify that a string field begins, ends, or contains a certain pattern of characters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data integrity: Compare data in one field to see if it matches a pattern in another field or object.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569025031"&gt;Regex patterns for common wildcard needs:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To match a value that starts with a string: Use ^ to anchor the start of the string, followed by the desired text and .* to match any remaining characters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; o Wildcard: HR02*&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; o Regex: "^HR02.*"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To match a value that ends with a string: Use .* to match any preceding characters, followed by the desired text and $ to anchor the end of the string.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; o Wildcard: *Delhi&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; o Regex: ".*Delhi$"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To match a value that contains a string: Use .* on both sides of the text you want to find.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; o Wildcard: *India*&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; o Regex: ".*India.*"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To match a specific number of characters: Use . for a single character and {n} to specify the exact number of occurrences.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; o Wildcard: N?30&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; o Regex: "N.30" (Matches N followed by any single character, then 30)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372511526"&gt;Sample Rules:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Requirement was to have a string field to allow only year to be entered. Caveat was that the data type could not be changed as migrated data already existed on the field for a large set of population&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nmanghnani_0-1763576016402.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342790iF1D2595EA6A25B18/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nmanghnani_0-1763576016402.png" alt="nmanghnani_0-1763576016402.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Requirement was to trigger a workflow only for capabilities which have HR02 or DO in their name. To make the rule future scalable, match and regex were used&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nmanghnani_1-1763576016405.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342792iD244148F66AE1DE4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nmanghnani_1-1763576016405.png" alt="nmanghnani_1-1763576016405.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The requirement was to trigger rule for all the picklist values which have matrix manager as the non-unique external code. Though other string functions could also be used, but here is a sample with match and regex&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nmanghnani_2-1763576016406.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342791i9D16B099FE25E57F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nmanghnani_2-1763576016406.png" alt="nmanghnani_2-1763576016406.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175998021"&gt;Please Note:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;While Regex offers great flexibility, complex patterns can impact system performance, particularly in onSave or onChange rules. Use simple and targeted patterns whenever possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regex should be validated for the right pattern, I personally use regex101.com to validate it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979484516"&gt;Cheatsheet for Regex tokens:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Literal Characters:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Any character that is not a special metacharacter (listed below) matches itself literally.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For example,&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;a&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;matches the character 'a', and&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;ab&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;matches the string 'ab'.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Metacharacters:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Anchors:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;^&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches the beginning of a string or line (when multiline flag&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;m&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;is used).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;$&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches the end of a string or line (when multiline flag&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;m&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;is used).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;\b&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches a word boundary.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;\B&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches a non-word boundary.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quantifiers:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;*&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches zero or more occurrences of the preceding element.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;+&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches one or more occurrences of the preceding element.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;?&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches zero or one occurrence of the preceding element.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;{n}&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches exactly&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;n&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;occurrences.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;{n,}&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;n&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;or more occurrences.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;{n,m}&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches between&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;n&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;m&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;occurrences (inclusive).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Character Classes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;.&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches any character except newline (unless&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;dotAll&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;flag&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;s&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;is used).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;[abc]&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches any one of the characters 'a', 'b', or 'c'.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;[^abc]&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches any character not 'a', 'b', or 'c'.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;[a-z]&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches any lowercase letter from 'a' to 'z'.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;\d&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches any digit (equivalent to&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;[0-9]&lt;/CODE&gt;).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;\D&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches any non-digit.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;\w&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches any word character (alphanumeric and underscore, equivalent to&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;[a-zA-Z0-9_]&lt;/CODE&gt;).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;\W&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches any non-word character.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;\s&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches any whitespace character (space, tab, newline, etc.).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;\S&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches any non-whitespace character.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Alternation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;|&lt;/CODE&gt;: Matches either the expression before or after the&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;|&lt;/CODE&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Escaping:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;`\`: Escapes a special metacharacter, treating it as a literal character.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For example,&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;\.&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;matches a literal dot, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;\*&lt;/CODE&gt;&amp;nbsp;matches a literal asterisk.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;\n&lt;/CODE&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;\t&lt;/CODE&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;\r&lt;/CODE&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;\f&lt;/CODE&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;\v&lt;/CODE&gt;: Special character escapes for newline, tab, carriage return, form feed, and vertical tab, respectively.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/wildcard-search-within-successfactors-rule/ba-p/14273025"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T19:03:04.039000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-calm-and-backup-monitor-in-operations-health-monitoring/qaq-p/14274143</id>
    <title>SAP CALM and Backup monitor in Operations - Health Monitoring</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T19:04:36.338000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kritikos</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1475580</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have not found so far something similar to configure an event to monitor backups status in SAP CALM Health Monitoring - Operations Section. Do you have any advises on this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;George&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-calm-and-backup-monitor-in-operations-health-monitoring/qaq-p/14274143"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T19:04:36.338000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/export-control-email-not-received/qaq-p/14274145</id>
    <title>Export Control email not received</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T19:11:24.924000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>facu3030</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2266905</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When trying to create the Trial Appliance for&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA 2023 FPS01, Fully-Activated Appliance, I get the following error:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your request is under clarification by export control. We will send you an email as soon as the clarification has been provided.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;But I never receive any e-mail at all. I would like some help with this, thank you.&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/export-control-email-not-received/qaq-p/14274145"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T19:11:24.924000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/why-wouldn-t-a-minority-indicator-populate-for-every-line-on-a-po/qaq-p/14274156</id>
    <title>Why wouldn't a minority indicator populate for every line on a PO?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T19:58:37.598000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>taylor_nero</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2266910</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a question surrounding minority indicators.&amp;nbsp;Why wouldn't a minority indicator populate for every line on a PO? At the vendor master level, the minority indicator is populated for a supplier but when a purchase order is released, not every line populates the minority indicator.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any insight into this? Appreciate any guidance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/why-wouldn-t-a-minority-indicator-populate-for-every-line-on-a-po/qaq-p/14274156"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T19:58:37.598000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/copenhagen-events/christmas-socializing-and-networking/ev-p/14274161</id>
    <title>Christmas socializing and networking</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T20:02:11.155000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChristianStarbaekDK</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2259202</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Copenhagen SAP Community!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We had a successful relaunch kick-off with the SAP TechEd keynote and networking earlier in November.&lt;BR /&gt;Now with Christmas and holidays coming up, we will arrange new event. This time it will be a socializing event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please join us.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agenda:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;17:00 We meet at Taphouse&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;When:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;10th of December&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Taphouse, Lavendelstræde 15, 1462 København - This event is physical only.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;S-Train and Metro within walking distance. Parking possible in the area&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please sign up so we can reserve space in the bar&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/copenhagen-events/christmas-socializing-and-networking/ev-p/14274161"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T20:02:11.155000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/splitting-100000-records-to-two-internal-tables-and-post-in-al11/m-p/14274162#M231</id>
    <title>Re: splitting 100000 records to two internal tables and post in al11</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T20:02:20.948000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I don't know if your question is about splitting or uploading.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's assume it's about splitting. It's very simple ABAP code:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;DATA(itab_1) = VALUE tt_itab( ( LINES OF itab FROM 1 TO 50000 ) ).
DATA(itab_2) = VALUE tt_itab( ( LINES OF itab FROM 50001 TO 100000 ) ).&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/splitting-100000-records-to-two-internal-tables-and-post-in-al11/m-p/14274162#M231"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T20:02:20.948000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-ai-agents-revolutionizing-how-governments-deliver-value/bc-p/14274164#M186532</id>
    <title>Re: SAP AI Agents – Revolutionizing How Governments Deliver Value</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T20:12:09.943000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RyanVanLeent</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476792</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great work illustrating the value of AI agents for government, Nicolas. Nice also to see the examples from City of Antibes and the German Federal Foreign Office of AI delivering real value to citizens.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-ai-agents-revolutionizing-how-governments-deliver-value/bc-p/14274164#M186532"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T20:12:09.943000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/behavior-of-advanced-foreign-currency-valuation-after-clearing/bc-p/14274166#M62513</id>
    <title>Re: Behavior of Advanced Foreign Currency Valuation after Clearing</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T20:13:35.527000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KevinSigl</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/156176</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148614"&gt;@ParkJongKyu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your feedback and the question WRT to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Valuation Line Types&lt;/EM&gt;. Since this seems to be a topic more customers and user might be interested in, I will share a blogpost in the next couple of days. I'll reply in this section and provide the link to the respective blogpost.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks again and sorry for the late response.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kevin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/behavior-of-advanced-foreign-currency-valuation-after-clearing/bc-p/14274166#M62513"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T20:13:35.527000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
