<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-12-15T20:14:01.361672+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-discussions/configure-based-on-customer-types/m-p/14290583#M29713</id>
    <title>Re: Configure based on Customer types</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T14:42:28.216000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ricky_shaw</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/202195</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Can we configure in MR control?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-discussions/configure-based-on-customer-types/m-p/14290583#M29713"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T14:42:28.216000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/retrieve-sp-user-id-using-ias-rest-api/qaa-p/14290586#M4933563</id>
    <title>Re: Retrieve SP User ID using IAS Rest API</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T14:50:23.424000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ahmedragabraptors</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/874903</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Did you find a solution? I'm also facing this issue. I suspect that it has something to do with authorization</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/retrieve-sp-user-id-using-ias-rest-api/qaa-p/14290586#M4933563"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T14:50:23.424000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-maintain-documentation-for-data-elements-on-cloud-erp-public-cloud/qaa-p/14290588#M4933564</id>
    <title>Re: How to maintain documentation for data elements on Cl...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T14:53:47.941000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>francesco_scibilia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/464592</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello Daniel, thank you for providing more context. This Help Portal page provides extensive information about the environment you need to set up in the context of extensibility: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_DEVELOPMENT_TOOLS_FOR_ECLIPSE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_DEVELOPMENT_TOOLS_FOR_ECLIPSE&lt;/A&gt;. These blogs may help you, too: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-key-user-extensibility-easier-than-you-may-think/ba-p/13565771" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-key-user-extensibility-easier-than-you-may-think/ba-p/13565771&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q1a4TfVQaZg" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q1a4TfVQaZg&lt;/A&gt; Best regards, Francesco</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-maintain-documentation-for-data-elements-on-cloud-erp-public-cloud/qaa-p/14290588#M4933564"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T14:53:47.941000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/miro-assign-bkpf-awkey-to-bseg-zuonr/m-p/14290598#M296</id>
    <title>Re: MIRO- Assign BKPF-AWKEY to BSEG-ZUONR</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:01:26.433000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ekekakos</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/38961</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;It has only the year. I have check this BADI, substitutions and FIBF. I think that the only way is updated ZUONR at the end but which end.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/miro-assign-bkpf-awkey-to-bseg-zuonr/m-p/14290598#M296"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:01:26.433000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/parallel-processing-error-with-call-transaction/m-p/14290608#M297</id>
    <title>Re: Parallel processing Error with call transaction</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:05:12.248000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ronaldo_aparecido</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/202053</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks i&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;don't catch the errors&amp;nbsp;correctly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/parallel-processing-error-with-call-transaction/m-p/14290608#M297"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:05:12.248000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-maintain-documentation-for-data-elements-on-cloud-erp-public-cloud/qaa-p/14290620#M4933565</id>
    <title>Re: How to maintain documentation for data elements on Cl...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:13:30.021000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DanielSchneider</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6135</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Francesco,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thanks for the provided urls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've already setup Eclipse for the public cloud system.&lt;BR /&gt;Unfortunately the links you provided don't explain how you could maintain documentations for data elements. The youtube video shows how to open a data element with SAP GUI in SE11. But this is the problem I have: I am not able to do that on a public cloud system.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;So the issue is still the same as stated in the initial question: Am I right, that currently there is no option to maintain the documentation of a data element on S4HC?&lt;BR /&gt;If there is not, it would be great if you could think about this for a the future roadmap. With this it would be possible to integrate custom build applications seamlessly in a sense of provided help documentation.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you&lt;BR /&gt;Daniel&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-maintain-documentation-for-data-elements-on-cloud-erp-public-cloud/qaa-p/14290620#M4933565"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:13:30.021000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-creating-document-when-it-is-subject-to-an-approval-process-sap-b1/qaa-p/14290627#M4233275</id>
    <title>Re: Error creating document when it is subject to an approval process sap b1 service layer</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:16:44.834000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>asadmateenkhan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/672537</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I have SAP Business One 10.0 version for SAP HANA (10.00.290) SP 2505 (64-bit)</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-creating-document-when-it-is-subject-to-an-approval-process-sap-b1/qaa-p/14290627#M4233275"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:16:44.834000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-edici%C3%B3n-de-cierre-2025/ba-p/14290629</id>
    <title>🤖 SAP BTP Weekly | Edición de cierre 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:18:30.762000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FedericoTokman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150724</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Cierro el último newsletter del año con una mirada clara: CIOs acelerando con foco, CFOs pidiendo impacto medible, arquitectos cuidando el core y consultores redefiniendo su rol. En estas líneas repaso cómo SAP BTP, Joule y Business Data Cloud dejaron de ser promesa en 2025 y empiezan a sentar las bases de cómo vamos a trabajar, decidir e innovar en 2026.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember201" id="toc-hId-1896384694"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_1:"&gt;1️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Joule for Developers: IA para acelerar la adopción sin perder control del código&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP potencia a los desarrolladores con Joule for Developers, integrado en el ciclo de desarrollo para acelerar tareas repetitivas. La IA ayuda a generar y adaptar código dentro del contexto de SAP BTP sin perder estándares de calidad. Esto no reemplaza la lógica de diseño, pero reduce el tiempo en tareas técnicas básicas. Impulsa la adopción de IA en entornos empresariales con prácticas seguras. El foco es mantener clean core mientras se amplía la productividad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Según SAP, esta capacidad está pensada para que los developers no solo codifiquen más rápido, sino con mayor confianza y alineados al estándar de la empresa. La ventaja principal es eliminar fricción en actividades tediosas y permitir que el equipo se concentre en lógica de negocio. El desafío es integrar estas asistencias en pipelines existentes sin perder gobernanza.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://news.sap.com/latinamerica/2025/11/sap-empodera-a-los-desarrolladores-para-acelerar-la-adopcion-de-la-ia-en-el-mundo-empresarial/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://news.sap.com/latinamerica/2025/11/sap-empodera-a-los-desarrolladores-para-acelerar-la-adopcion-de-la-ia-en-el-mundo-empresarial/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember205" id="toc-hId-1699871189"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_2:"&gt;2️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Joule for Consultants: acelerando entregas y calidad de proyectos SAP&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Joule for Consultants ya está disponible y diseñado para asistir a consultores en transformaciones SAP a gran escala con guía inteligente y contexto experto.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;Reduce tiempo de búsqueda de documentación, interpretación de código y adopción de mejores prácticas, apoyado en una base de conocimiento profundamente curada por SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;Puede acelerar la ejecución de proyectos hasta ~14 % y disminuir iteraciones de diseño y retrabajo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;La integración con herramientas como Microsoft 365 Copilot ofrece un flujo fluido entre contextos.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Esto permite que los consultores se concentren más en decisiones de negocio que en tareas repetitivas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Un caso concreto viene de grandes firmas de consultoría que están adoptando Joule for Consultants para mejorar tiempos de entrega y calidad del servicio a clientes: por ejemplo, Deloitte anunció que la solución les permite acceder rápidamente a prácticas líderes y contenido SAP exclusivo, liberando tiempo para actividades de mayor impacto estratégico en SAP Engage y proyectos de transformación integral.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Más allá de métricas de tiempo ahorrado, el impacto real se ve en mejor alineación entre diseño técnico y necesidades del cliente, reduciendo rework y elevando la confianza en decisiones durante el ciclo del proyecto. El reto para muchas organizaciones será definir métricas claras de impacto (KPIs) que puedan medir estos beneficios en cada entrega.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/latinamerica/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-assistant/sap-consulting-capability.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/latinamerica/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-assistant/sap-consulting-capability.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_3:"&gt;3️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Joule Studio: agentes de IA que ejecutan procesos, no solo tareas&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Joule Studio permite crear agentes de IA en SAP Build. Los agentes ejecutan workflows con contexto de negocio. No es solo RPA, es automatización inteligente. Se reduce código y tiempo de diseño. La gobernanza se vuelve crítica.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Imaginar un agente que gestione excepciones de facturación o approvals complejos ya no es ciencia ficción. El desafío real es definir límites, auditoría y “human-in-the-loop”. La ventaja es eficiencia; el riesgo, cajas negras operativas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-studio.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-studio.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_4:"&gt;4️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Nuevos skills SAP: del funcional técnico al “AI-enabled consultant”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;La llegada de Joule cambia los perfiles SAP. Menos foco en ejecución manual. Más foco en diseño, validación y gobierno. Los skills técnicos se combinan con negocio. La capacitación se vuelve estratégica.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Saber configurar ya no alcanza. Entender procesos, datos e IA será diferencial. SAP impulsa nuevas certificaciones, pero el reto está en reconvertir talento existente. Ventaja: perfiles más completos. Riesgo: brecha de skills si no se actúa a tiempo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://training.sap.com/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://training.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_5:"&gt;5️⃣&lt;/span&gt; SAP BDC Connect + Microsoft Fabric: datos SAP donde el negocio ya trabaja&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP anunció Business Data Cloud Connect para Microsoft Fabric, extendiendo la integración de BDC con la plataforma de datos de Microsoft. Esto habilita acceso bi-direccional sin copia de datos entre BDC y Microsoft Fabric OneLake, preservando contexto semántico. Los equipos pueden usar SAP data products directamente en Fabric para analytics, AI y BI. Potencia herramientas como Power BI, Copilot Studio y agentes de IA dentro del ecosistema Microsoft. El enfoque acelera insights y reduce la fricción de replicar datos.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;En la práctica, esto significa que los datos SAP ya gobernados en BDC pueden ser usados en vivo en herramientas cotidianas del negocio (Power BI, Excel, Teams) sin mover o duplicar la información. La ventaja es una sola fuente de verdad que impulsa tanto AI generativa como analítica avanzada. El reto principal está en coordinar roles y seguridad entre plataformas diferentes, especialmente en organizaciones grandes donde existen múltiples silos y políticas de acceso.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://news.sap.com/2025/11/sap-bdc-connect-for-microsoft-fabric-business-insights-ai-innovation/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://news.sap.com/2025/11/sap-bdc-connect-for-microsoft-fabric-business-insights-ai-innovation/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember226" id="toc-hId-1503357684"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_6:"&gt;6️⃣&lt;/span&gt; IA + Datos nativos: SAP HANA Cloud, agentic memory y cero-copias con Snowflake&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP HANA Cloud se consolida como la base de datos &lt;EM&gt;AI-native&lt;/EM&gt; con Model Context Protocol (MCP) disponible en GA, permitiendo a agentes IA navegar relaciones complejas de datos. Los knowledge graphs automáticos agilizan la generación de modelos semánticos del negocio sin semanas de esfuerzo manual (Q1 2026). La incorporación de agentic memory permite a agentes de IA aprender de interacciones pasadas para decisiones más inteligentes. SAP BDC se integra con Snowflake como extensión para habilitar datos semánticamente ricos con zero-copy, preservando contexto y gobernanza. Esto impulsa una visión donde datos empresariales e IA coexisten con escalabilidad y menor duplicación.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Hacia fines de 2025 SAP reporta cientos de casos de uso de Business AI con impacto medible en valor de negocio. MCP en HANA Cloud permite que agentes IA entiendan estructuras más allá de filas y columnas, abarcando relaciones complejas y búsquedas semánticas. La generación automática de knowledge graphs y la memoria &lt;EM&gt;agentic&lt;/EM&gt; reducen tiempo de preparación y elevan la inteligencia contextual de los agentes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Por otro lado, la integración de SAP BDC con Snowflake habilita &lt;EM&gt;zero-copy data sharing&lt;/EM&gt;, reduciendo silos y costos de replicación sin perder gobernanza. Esto abre modelos híbridos donde SAP conserva el contexto semántico y Snowflake aporta escala e innovación para analítica y AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://news.sap.com/2025/11/business-ai-innovation-unveiled-at-sap-teched/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://news.sap.com/2025/11/business-ai-innovation-unveiled-at-sap-teched/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember231" id="toc-hId-1306844179"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_7:"&gt;7️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Reflexión de fin de año: de experimentar con IA a rediseñar la empresa para 2026&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;2025 fue el año donde SAP dejó claro que la IA empresarial ya es real. Joule pasó de asistente a agente, y los datos dejaron de ser solo reporting. BTP, BDC y HANA Cloud se alinearon en una visión coherente. La conversación cambió de “qué probar” a “qué escalar”. El foco ahora está en impacto, no en hype.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Mirando todo lo anunciado este año, Joule en sus distintas formas, Business Data Cloud conectando ecosistemas como Microsoft Fabric y Snowflake, HANA Cloud volviéndose &lt;EM&gt;AI-native&lt;/EM&gt;, creo que 2026 no va a tratar de sumar más tecnología, sino de tomar decisiones más valientes. Las organizaciones que lleguen a 2026 con datos gobernados, skills preparados y una visión clara de dónde usar IA tendrán una ventaja enorme. Las que sigan en pilotos aislados van a sentir que “llegaron tarde”, aunque la tecnología esté ahí. SAP puso las piezas sobre la mesa; ahora el desafío es cultural, organizacional y estratégico.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-edici%C3%B3n-de-cierre-2025/ba-p/14290629"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:18:30.762000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/comparing-md07-md04-vs-monitor-material-coverage-app-1-2/bc-p/14290630#M72340</id>
    <title>Re: Comparing MD07 - MD04 Vs Monitor material coverage app - 1/2</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:19:32.412000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Patrcia_Teixeira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1743574</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Is this Fiori app also used in MRP Types not MRP relevant like X0?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/comparing-md07-md04-vs-monitor-material-coverage-app-1-2/bc-p/14290630#M72340"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:19:32.412000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/add-more-types-of-retention-in-po-sap-s-4hana/qaq-p/14290632</id>
    <title>Add more types of retention in PO SAP S/4HANA</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:20:55.099000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kabouki</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/781728</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Expert,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a way to use several types of retention in a purchase order?&lt;BR /&gt;In the standard system, there is only one retention field expressed as a percentage. My requirement is to have three retention fields with amounts (RE01, RE02, RE03) in the purchase order.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/add-more-types-of-retention-in-po-sap-s-4hana/qaq-p/14290632"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:20:55.099000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-creating-document-when-it-is-subject-to-an-approval-process-sap-b1/qaa-p/14290634#M4233276</id>
    <title>Re: Error creating document when it is subject to an approval process sap b1 service layer</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:22:00.804000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>asadmateenkhan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/672537</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I have SAP Business One 10.0 version for SAP HANA (10.00.290) SP 2505 (64-bit). Why this feature is no longer working. Status is 201 Created and Location doesnt contain draft</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-creating-document-when-it-is-subject-to-an-approval-process-sap-b1/qaa-p/14290634#M4233276"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:22:00.804000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-fields-of-type-codelist-based-on-cds-views-in-analytical-apps-how-to/ba-p/14284985</id>
    <title>Custom Fields of type CodeList based on CDS Views in Analytical Apps: How to get text display option</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:28:21.988000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>georg_wilhelm</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/457497</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1637417964"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Custom Fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;of Type Code List based on CDS Views in Analytical Apps&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;: How&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;to&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;get&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;text display options&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do you&amp;nbsp;use a key user custom field of type “Code List based on CDS Views” in an analytical app like&amp;nbsp;“Journal Entry Analyzer”?&amp;nbsp;Did you ever wonder&amp;nbsp;why only&amp;nbsp;the code&amp;nbsp;component&amp;nbsp;of this custom field&amp;nbsp;is shown?&amp;nbsp;Do&amp;nbsp;you also want to&amp;nbsp;see the respective description field,&amp;nbsp;as&amp;nbsp;you (or&amp;nbsp;other&amp;nbsp;people)&amp;nbsp;are not familiar with the code values?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If your answer is yes, then this blog post is just for you.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog post&amp;nbsp;tells you what to do&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;make the description field available in analytical apps like the&amp;nbsp;“Journal Entry Analyzer”&amp;nbsp;app&amp;nbsp;based on a concrete example.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please&amp;nbsp;note that while we took an example from SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition, it's&amp;nbsp;basically the&amp;nbsp;same for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569987178"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create a field of type&amp;nbsp;“Code List based on CDS Views”&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;enable it for&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;analytical app&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s assume you created a custom field&amp;nbsp;“ZZ1_EmployeeReference”&amp;nbsp;of type “Code List based on CDS Views”&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;business context&amp;nbsp;“FINS_JOURNAL_ENTRY_ITEM”&amp;nbsp;(Accounting: Journal Entry Item).&amp;nbsp;For your field you&amp;nbsp;chose&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;standard SAP CDS view&amp;nbsp;“I_WorkforcePerson”&amp;nbsp;as&amp;nbsp;value&amp;nbsp;help view. To make your custom field available for&amp;nbsp;the analytical app&amp;nbsp;“Journal Entry Analyzer”&amp;nbsp;you already&amp;nbsp;enabled CDS&amp;nbsp;query&amp;nbsp;view&amp;nbsp;“C_GLLINEITEMSQ0001”.&amp;nbsp;With this, the underlying cube view&amp;nbsp;“I_GLACCOUNTLINEITEMCUBE”&amp;nbsp;was enabled&amp;nbsp;for this field as well.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1502556392"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finding the relevant CDS view&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You may wonder how to figure out that you need to enable CDS view&amp;nbsp;“C_GLLINEITEMSQ0001” to make the field available for the&amp;nbsp;Journal Entry Analyzer&amp;nbsp;app.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are several ways to find that out:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1435125606"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Using the Custom Fields app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Within the Custom Fields app, navigate to the detail screen of your custom field. Go to the “User Interfaces” tab, select “All” and&amp;nbsp;enter “Journal Entry Analyzer” in the search field on the top right of the&amp;nbsp;table showing the search results. One of the results is CDS view&amp;nbsp;“C_GLLINEITEMSQ0001”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note: this only works in case the descriptions&amp;nbsp;for the respective objects involved provided by&amp;nbsp;SAP&amp;nbsp;are&amp;nbsp;100% consistent&amp;nbsp;– which is not always the case.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1238612101"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Using the&amp;nbsp;Fiori Apps Reference Library&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can use the Fiori Apps Reference Library as a more reliable and generic way to find out the name of the CDS view that you must&amp;nbsp;enable&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;make the field available for the&amp;nbsp;Journal Entry Analyzer&amp;nbsp;app&amp;nbsp;(and for any other analytical app).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open the Fiori Apps Library and search for the app “Journal Entry Analyzer”.&amp;nbsp; You'll find this&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F0956')/S31PCE" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;entry&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Make sure to select the correct release on top of the page, which is&amp;nbsp;“2025 (Private Cloud)”&amp;nbsp;in our case.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;On this page, select the “IMPLEMENTATION INFORMATION” tab and then navigate to the “Configuration” section. Search for the “Bex Query” entry.&amp;nbsp;The “Bex Query” entry states “2CCFIGLLITMQ0001”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Note:&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;“Bex Query” entry is only shown for analytical apps.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When you remove the first two leading characters (“2C”), you get the name of the DDIC view (“CFIGLLITMQ0001”) belonging to the respective CDS view that is exposed in this analytical application.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note:&amp;nbsp;In this&amp;nbsp;case, the Bex Query&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2C&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CFIGLLITMQ0001 refers to CFIGLLITMQ0001, which is a classic&amp;nbsp;DDIC&amp;nbsp;view. Therefore, the CDS view name differs from the view name. For view&amp;nbsp;entities, the names would be the same.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_0-1764962285075.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349086iF1DC38C944432076/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_0-1764962285075.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_0-1764962285075.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiori Apps Reference Library&amp;nbsp;entry of&amp;nbsp;the app “Journal Entry Analyzer”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To&amp;nbsp;derive&amp;nbsp;the CDS view name from the view name, you can open&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;view in ADT and find the name of the&amp;nbsp;CDS view&amp;nbsp;in the&amp;nbsp;Data Definition&amp;nbsp;property&amp;nbsp;of this&amp;nbsp;view.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_1-1764960838796.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349078iCA22F460A269AB4F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_1-1764960838796.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_1-1764960838796.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;View&amp;nbsp;CFIGLLITMQ0001&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now that you know the name of the CDS view, you can:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;navigate to the&amp;nbsp;detail screen of your custom field&amp;nbsp;within the Custom Fields app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;then, navigate to the “CDS view” tab&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;in the search field, enter the name of this CDS view. The entry for the view will be&amp;nbsp;shown&amp;nbsp;and you can enable it&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-783933158"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Make&amp;nbsp;the custom field&amp;nbsp;visible in&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;analytical app&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When you have published the custom field&amp;nbsp;“ZZ1_EmployeeReference”, the next step is to make it visible in the&amp;nbsp;“Journal Entry Analyzer” app.&amp;nbsp;To&amp;nbsp;do this, open the app&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;populate the selection properties so that a list of entries is shown as soon as you press the “Go” button.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the&amp;nbsp;“Available&amp;nbsp;Fields”&amp;nbsp;section, you'll now see the custom field&amp;nbsp;“Employee Reference”. You&amp;nbsp;can move it to the rows section by selecting the “Add Field to column axis” option.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As soon as you've done&amp;nbsp;that, the field becomes visible as an&amp;nbsp;additional&amp;nbsp;row on the right side of the screen.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Right-click on the column header of the additional&amp;nbsp;row of the “Employee Reference”&amp;nbsp;field and select "Display". The pop-up shows options such as&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“ID only”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Description only”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“ID and description”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Description and ID”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These display&amp;nbsp;options allow you to show the description belonging to the code value of the “Employee Reference” field. In our&amp;nbsp;case,&amp;nbsp;none of these options&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;available (see screenshot below).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_2-1764960838796.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349079i1A727E45BE23DEBF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_2-1764960838796.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_2-1764960838796.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Employee Reference” custom field as column in analytical app: no&amp;nbsp;text display options available&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-587419653"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to get the text display options&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To&amp;nbsp;make the&amp;nbsp;missing&amp;nbsp;text display&amp;nbsp;options&amp;nbsp;available, go to the Custom Fields app and navigate to the detail screen of your custom field. In the General tab, you'll find a slider button called “Analytical Support”. Choosing this button, an&amp;nbsp;addition&amp;nbsp;field is displayed called “Master Data View”.&amp;nbsp;Here, you can enter the&amp;nbsp;master data view which is used for this field in analytical apps (like&amp;nbsp;the “Journal Entry Analyzer” app). In our case, it's prefilled with&amp;nbsp;“I_WorkforcePerson”, which is the same CDS view we had already chosen as&amp;nbsp;value&amp;nbsp;help view&amp;nbsp;(see screenshot below).&amp;nbsp;Note that there is also a dedicated value help view called “I_WorkforcePersonVH”,&amp;nbsp;which&amp;nbsp;would be&amp;nbsp;even more suitable for use as “Value Help View”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_3-1764960838797.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349081iD579B67C8A3DE984/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_3-1764960838797.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_3-1764960838797.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Employee Reference” custom field:&amp;nbsp;activating Analytical Support and choosing Master Data View&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prefilling the “Master Data View”&amp;nbsp;is the default&amp;nbsp;behavior&amp;nbsp;of the Custom Fields app&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;cases where&amp;nbsp;the value&amp;nbsp;help&amp;nbsp;view fulfills all the requirements of an analytical master data view. The view must&amp;nbsp;have&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;header&amp;nbsp;annotation&amp;nbsp;“@Analytics.dataCategory: #DIMENSION”. Please note that&amp;nbsp;within the value help&amp;nbsp;for the “Master Data View”, only CDS views that fulfill&amp;nbsp;this criterion are shown.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Go ahead and save and publish the custom field again.&amp;nbsp;Next, reload the “Journal Entry Analyzer” app. Click on the column header of the “Employee Reference” custom&amp;nbsp;field to see that all of the four&amp;nbsp;text display&amp;nbsp;options are displayed.&amp;nbsp;These&amp;nbsp;allow you to configure whether and how the description should be displayed (see screenshot below).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_4-1764960838798.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349080iF016431B80F6985B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_4-1764960838798.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_4-1764960838798.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Employee Reference” custom field as column in analytical app: text display options available&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With&amp;nbsp;this, you are done.&amp;nbsp;Congratulations!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-390906148"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Technical details&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In case you are interested in the technical&amp;nbsp;details, let me shortly explain&amp;nbsp;what you have changed by selecting a “Master Data View” for your custom field&amp;nbsp;“Employee Reference”:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before selecting a master data view, the CDS extension&amp;nbsp;that had been generated for the custom field "Employee Reference" for&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;cube view "I_GLACCOUNTLINEITEMCUBE" underneath&amp;nbsp;the query&amp;nbsp;view&amp;nbsp; "C_GLLINEITEMSQ0001" looked like&amp;nbsp;this:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_5-1764961899062.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349083i1B1057BFC85A128C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_5-1764961899062.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_5-1764961899062.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CDS Extend on cube view&amp;nbsp;I_GLACCOUNTLINEITEMCUBE&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;before&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;setting the “Master Data View” on the custom field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After specifying the master data view and publishing the field again, the CDS extension looks like this:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="georg_wilhelm_6-1764961978378.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349084iAFBCF13428F825F8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="georg_wilhelm_6-1764961978378.png" alt="georg_wilhelm_6-1764961978378.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CDS Extend on cube view&amp;nbsp;I_GLACCOUNTLINEITEMCUBE&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;after&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;setting the “Master Data View” on the custom field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The difference lies within the foreign key association and the respective foreign key association annotation marked in red.&amp;nbsp;The analytics infrastructure needs this metadata to&amp;nbsp;provide the&amp;nbsp;text field.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You may wonder how the analytics infrastructure knew which&amp;nbsp;field in the “Meta Data View”&amp;nbsp;I_WORKFORCEPERSON&amp;nbsp;is the text&amp;nbsp;field.&amp;nbsp;This is derived from the&amp;nbsp;annotation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ObjectModel.text.element: 'PersonFullName'&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;of the key field in&amp;nbsp;“Meta Data View”&amp;nbsp;I_WORKFORCEPERSON.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-194392643"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feedback, Comments, or Questions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You’re&amp;nbsp;cordially invited to provide them in the comments section below.&amp;nbsp;Please follow our&amp;nbsp;profiles&amp;nbsp;to get updates when&amp;nbsp;we&amp;nbsp;publish more posts on these topics.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feel invited to post and answer questions here (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://answers.sap.com/tags/270c4f37-c335-46e1-bfad-a256637d5e26" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://answers.sap.com/tags/270c4f37-c335-46e1-bfad-a256637d5e26&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) and read other posts on the topic (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/tags/270c4f37-c335-46e1-bfad-a256637d5e26/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://blogs.sap.com/tags/270c4f37-c335-46e1-bfad-a256637d5e26/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I want to thank Yasmina van Rooij (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1393455" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;YasminavanRooij&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) and Karsten Schaser (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/164194" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Karsten_Schaser&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) for their extremely helpful contributions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--2120862"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Other related blog posts:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/key-user-custom-fields-when-to-use-what-type-of-code-list/ba-p/13557853" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key User Custom Fields: When to use what type of code list&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-key-user-extensibility-powered-by-embedded-steampunk-custom/ba-p/13533713" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Key User Extensibility powered by Embedded Steampunk: Custom Field with ABAP implemented Value Help&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-key-user-extensibility-custom-field-with-context-dependent/ba-p/13530963" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Key User Extensibility: Custom field with context-dependent value help&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/enrich-sap-s-4hana-key-user-custom-fields-with-intent-based-navigation/ba-p/13554319" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enrich SAP S/4HANA Key User Custom fields with Intent-Based Navigation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-fields-of-type-codelist-based-on-cds-views-in-analytical-apps-how-to/ba-p/14284985"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:28:21.988000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-public-cloud-2508-mass-maintenance-of-tax-classification/qaa-p/14290638#M4233277</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud 2508 / Mass Maintenance of Tax class...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:28:31.330000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;cannot &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;directly &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;mass‑update &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;country &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;code&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;tax &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;classification &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;entries &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(KNVI) &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;using &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;standard &lt;/SPAN&gt;Mass Maintenance or Mass Import &lt;SPAN&gt;apps. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;migration &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;cockpit &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;also &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;does &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;not &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;support &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;overwriting &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;existing &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;entries &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;way. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;recommended &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;approaches &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;are &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;either &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(a) &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;re‑migrating &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;correct &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;data &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;using &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Replace &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Existing &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Records”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;option &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;migration &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;cockpit, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;or &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(b) &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;using &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Correction &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;via &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Partner &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;APIs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;(OData &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;services) &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;or &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MDG &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Partner&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;if &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;available.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-public-cloud-2508-mass-maintenance-of-tax-classification/qaa-p/14290638#M4233277"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:28:31.330000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/lumpsum-issue-guidelines-show-0-and-lumpsum-field-cannot-be-filled-in-the/qaa-p/14290641#M49927</id>
    <title>Re: Lumpsum issue - guidelines show 0 and Lumpsum field cannot be filled in the form</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:31:02.175000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DavidSomelofske</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I am not sure what this could be based on the screenshots. I would go back to the xml and see if you have a tag that indicates what the basis of the lump sum would be. Like this: &amp;lt;lumpsum-calc basedOn="CurrentSalary"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/lumpsum-calc&amp;gt; This will indicate the denominator of the lump sum. In addition, the percentage will always be zero until an amount is entered. If you want a default value in the sheet when you open it, it will have to be defined in the guidelines.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/lumpsum-issue-guidelines-show-0-and-lumpsum-field-cannot-be-filled-in-the/qaa-p/14290641#M49927"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:31:02.175000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/service-layer-no-longer-creates-draft-approval-for-documents-returns-201/qaq-p/14290642</id>
    <title>Service Layer no longer creates Draft / Approval for Documents (returns 201 instead of Draft)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:33:18.253000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>asadmateenkhan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/672537</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business One 10.0 version for SAP HANA (10.00.290) SP 2505 (64-bit) / Service Layer, we noticed a change in behavior when creating &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Quotations&lt;/STRONG&gt; via Service Layer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business One 10.0 (HANA)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Approval procedure active for Sales Quotations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Approval works correctly in SAP B1 client&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Previous behavior&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;POST /b1s/v2/Quotations&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Returned &lt;STRONG&gt;404&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Location&lt;/CODE&gt; header pointed to &lt;CODE&gt;/Drafts(&amp;lt;DocEntry&amp;gt;)&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Draft (ODRF) created and approval triggered&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current behavior&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Returns &lt;STRONG&gt;201 Created&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Location&lt;/CODE&gt; points to &lt;CODE&gt;/Quotations(&amp;lt;DocEntry&amp;gt;)&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Final document is created&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;No draft / no approval triggered&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Question&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this a known change or limitation in newer Service Layer versions?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is approval-based draft creation no longer supported via Service Layer?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is creating drafts explicitly via &lt;CODE&gt;/b1s/v2/Drafts&lt;/CODE&gt; now the only supported approach?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any official confirmation or SAP Note reference would be appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="asadmateenkhan_0-1765808685832.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352165i452E8A7B75D8E219/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="asadmateenkhan_0-1765808685832.png" alt="asadmateenkhan_0-1765808685832.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/service-layer-no-longer-creates-draft-approval-for-documents-returns-201/qaq-p/14290642"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:33:18.253000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/custom-field-with-lookup-formula-returns-n-a-after-filling-merit-etc/qaa-p/14290643#M49928</id>
    <title>Re: Custom field with lookup formula, returns N/A after filling merit etc.</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:35:13.934000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DavidSomelofske</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I agree with Xavier. in addition, there is no way for us to help you if you say you have a question regarding a formula and then do not include the formula or any screenshots. You need to help us help you.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/custom-field-with-lookup-formula-returns-n-a-after-filling-merit-etc/qaa-p/14290643#M49928"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:35:13.934000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-net-the-invoice-amount-by-business-partner/qaa-p/14290645#M256981</id>
    <title>Re: How to Net the invoice amount by Business Partner?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:36:52.012000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JonathanEemans</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/173593</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi May,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Please ensure the following prerequisites are met:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Customer is linked to Supplier and vice/versa in BP under general data for both Supplier and Customer.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. The option “Clearing with customer/vendor” is flagged in BP under payment transactions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Jonathan&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-net-the-invoice-amount-by-business-partner/qaa-p/14290645#M256981"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:36:52.012000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule%E7%9A%84%E6%A0%B8%E5%BF%83%E6%9E%B6%E6%9E%84%E6%A6%82%E8%BF%B0/ba-p/14290646</id>
    <title>Joule的核心架构概述</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:38:07.135000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ArthurYang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/138892</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1767302034"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;如果您对BTP感兴趣，&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/07/26/btp%e4%b8%aa%e4%ba%ba%e7%b2%be%e9%80%89%e5%86%85%e5%ae%b9%e7%9b%ae%e5%bd%95/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;BTP个人精选内容目录 | SAP Blogs&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;可能有更多你需要的内容&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule作为SAP的官方对话助手，天然具有对接SAP应用的能力，但其背后的架构是怎么设计的呢？今天我们一起来一探究竟&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1570788529"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;用户界面与背后的架构&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;首先明确一个观点，用户感受到的Joule目前主要是嵌入在各个SAP应用中的界面&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;点击应用界面右上角的钻石图标即可唤出Joule&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ArthurYang_0-1765807416900.png" style="width: 380px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352143iE41620847BB63149/image-dimensions/380x452/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="380" height="452" role="button" title="ArthurYang_0-1765807416900.png" alt="ArthurYang_0-1765807416900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;但真实接收到用户指令的Joule大脑，却是部署在BTP上的，同时结合BTP提供的各项能力比如知识图谱，RAG向量数据库，身份中心来真正执行工作，核心架构如下图&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ArthurYang_2-1765807597400.png" style="width: 663px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352152i732C74CB6971719F/image-dimensions/663x378/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="663" height="378" role="button" title="ArthurYang_2-1765807597400.png" alt="ArthurYang_2-1765807597400.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1374275024"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;调用一次Joule时背后发生的事情&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;以Success Factors（SF）内嵌的Joule为例，&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1.用户的指令会进入SF中的Joule用户端，进而发送到BTP上独属于该用户的Joule后台&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.Joule会自行判断是否需要额外能力&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.如果需要额外能力，Joule会查询BTP中的服务，以确定可用的额外能力，然后具体执行动作&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.结合额外能力的结果后，回答用户指令&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;这里提到的额外能力就包括了额外的历史对话记忆库，知识库，文档库，工具库，Agent库，业务语义库等，这些能力都是构建在BTP上的，具体情况会在其他文章详述&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1177761519"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule调用额外能力的方式详解&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;从架构图中可以看出，Joule的额外能力就是一个个BTP上的服务，但Joule在调用能力之前，&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.首先需要知道自己有哪些服务可以调用&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;所以SAP将已经对接上Joule的应用，例如SF的可用能力包装成了CDM，可以理解为一本带有说明书的菜单，Joule会根据菜单来确定能力，并根据说明书确定如何调用能力&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.然后需要知道当前用户有权限调用哪些能力&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;然后Joule同时也对接了BTP上的身份中心(可用于SSO等)，可以获取到当前用户在不同系统的角色，例如SF系统中的管理员角色，进而根据角色对应的能力权限列表，综合Joule的可用能力列表，取重叠的部分供Joule调用&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.需要安全的完成能力调用&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;由于整套系统都打通了身份体系，Joule会基于用户的身份来调用API，这样即使遇到最坏情况，Joule尝试调用超过权限的数据，应用也会拒绝访问&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-981248014"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;总结&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;从用户点击钻石图标的那一刻起，到最终得到回答，整个过程涉及了前后端分离、服务调用、权限验证等多个环节。SAP在设计这套架构时考虑得很周全——既要保证功能的强大，又要确保安全可控。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;对于企业级应用来说，这种稳妥的设计思路是必要的。当然，随着技术的发展，这套架构肯定还会继续演进。但至少目前看来，它已经为Joule提供了一个相当坚实的技术基础。&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule%E7%9A%84%E6%A0%B8%E5%BF%83%E6%9E%B6%E6%9E%84%E6%A6%82%E8%BF%B0/ba-p/14290646"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:38:07.135000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-intercompany-asset-transfer-across-different-countries-supported-in-sap/qaa-p/14290648#M4233279</id>
    <title>Re: Is Intercompany Asset Transfer Across Different Countries Supported in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:40:05.024000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Enda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/130750</uri>
    </author>
    <content>adding tag SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Finance</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-intercompany-asset-transfer-across-different-countries-supported-in-sap/qaa-p/14290648#M4233279"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:40:05.024000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/joining-two-sac-planning-models-on-common-key/qaa-p/14290660#M4933566</id>
    <title>Re: Joining two SAC Planning Models on common key</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:45:13.136000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TApen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1813713</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I was mistaken to discard the LINK formula too quickly. It was the way to go, but I wasn't aware that I also have to link the dimensions that I don't want to perform the join on, which is very different to SQL.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/joining-two-sac-planning-models-on-common-key/qaa-p/14290660#M4933566"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:45:13.136000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/custom-field-with-lookup-formula-returns-n-a-after-filling-merit-etc/qaa-p/14290661#M49929</id>
    <title>Re: Custom field with lookup formula, returns N/A after f...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:45:21.094000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tal_Sedov</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1941829</uri>
    </author>
    <content>thanks. i checked one of the threads and the solution was to add "else" condition that was missing. in my case there is no "if", just simple lookup formula that takes values from custom calculated field from the form (the calculated field is based on concatenation of Managerial Level and pmRating) and then I have a lookup table with all the variations of Level+Rating and what I want to show in the custom lookup field.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/custom-field-with-lookup-formula-returns-n-a-after-filling-merit-etc/qaa-p/14290661#M49929"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:45:21.094000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/andriod-studio-setup-for-btp-sdk-for-andriod/qaq-p/14290662</id>
    <title>Andriod Studio Setup for BTP SDK for Andriod</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:46:35.218000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rmz01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/725901</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have installed&amp;nbsp;Android Studio Otter 2 Feature Drop | 2025.2.2&lt;BR /&gt;And BTP SDK Andriod 25.11.0&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;When i'm trying to setup a new BTP App its stuck here on the Server Connection Screen.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Initial Screen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rmz01_0-1765809565549.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352168iC47BFCBA09F10E4B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rmz01_0-1765809565549.png" alt="rmz01_0-1765809565549.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;After Clicking next it screen content stays same and "Next" button is disabled.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rmz01_1-1765809698666.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352170iE97480D0004D90B2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rmz01_1-1765809698666.png" alt="rmz01_1-1765809698666.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;I also tried in Andriod Version&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Android Studio Meerkat | 2024.3.1 -&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;same issue&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;With Andriod Versoin&amp;nbsp;Android Studio Koala Feature Drop 2024.1.2 Patch 1 - &lt;STRONG&gt;New BTP Andriod App Option Not Coming&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/andriod-studio-setup-for-btp-sdk-for-andriod/qaq-p/14290662"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:46:35.218000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/the-re-emergence-of-community-in-the-sap-ecosystem/m-p/14290665#M3351</id>
    <title>Re: The Re-emergence of Community in the SAP Ecosystem</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:50:45.191000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MarceloPinheiro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1042</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I agree with you and I believe that, unless we exchange knowledge in some way, AI cannot help to make it quickly available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is much knowledge in people's minds that cannot be discovered until we grab a coffee, take a break, or be together in a Community conference. Sometimes, whether close to us or not, we have someone with questions, concerns, or challenges, and we have experienced that challenge before. Together, a better solution can arise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is always a bit more difficult when the relations are 100% virtual....&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/the-re-emergence-of-community-in-the-sap-ecosystem/m-p/14290665#M3351"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:50:45.191000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/backofficesearchservices-incompatible-with-adaptivesearchsolr/qaq-p/14290668</id>
    <title>Backofficesearchservices incompatible with adaptivesearchsolr?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:54:20.707000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rbespalovnc</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/610475</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am super confused by the impexes in backofficesearch extension.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;There is an impex `hybris/bin/modules/search-services/backofficesearchservices/resources/impex/productSearchServicesFacet/productSearchservices-facet.impex` which at the end imports several facets of type MULTISELECT:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;INSERT_UPDATE AsFacet; searchConfiguration(uid); uid[unique = true]                   ; indexProperty        ; facetType(code); priority; ranged[default = false]; searchConfigurationPOS;
                     ; $backofficeSearchCfgId  ; ba01fe6d-c2ca-4cff-a699-438e4a6aaebb ; approvalStatus       ; MULTISELECT    ; 100     ; false                  ; 0                     ;
                     ; $backofficeSearchCfgId  ; 5fcbd84d-5ad3-4b8c-8bcb-2982eb58f87a ; facet_catalogVersion ; MULTISELECT    ; 100     ; false                  ; 1                     ;
                     ; $backofficeSearchCfgId  ; 86a8220b-3fc0-400e-8798-3afe09dcc973 ; facet_catalog        ; MULTISELECT    ; 100     ; false                  ; 2                     ;
                     ; $backofficeSearchCfgId  ; 3bf25fa8-d97a-42f7-8a4d-75b11dbb869d ; categoryLabel        ; MULTISELECT    ; 100     ; false                  ; 3                     ;
                     ; $backofficeSearchCfgId  ; 138c9eb7-d359-46a8-87a7-a4d2ac1c5839 ; facet_itemtype       ; MULTISELECT    ; 100     ; false                  ; 4                     ;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;When they are imported they pass through `AsFacetConfigurationInterceptor::onValidate()` from `adaptivesearch` which checks their type:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-java"&gt;&lt;code&gt;                    AsFacetType facetType = facetConfiguration.getFacetType();// 83
                    if (!searchProvider.isValidFacetType(indexType, facetType)) {// 84
                        throw new InterceptorException("Facet type cannot be used for facets: " + String.valueOf(facetType));// 86
                    } else {&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here `searchProvider` is configurable but&amp;nbsp; by default it's Solr.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;But now the most interesting part: check the code of `&lt;SPAN&gt;SolrAsSearchProvider::isValidFacetType()` from the `adaptivesearchsolr` extension:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-java"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    public List&amp;lt;AsFacetType&amp;gt; getSupportedFacetTypes(final String indexType) {
        return SUPPORTED_FACET_TYPES;// 314
    }

    public boolean isValidFacetType(final String indexType, final AsFacetType facetType) {
        return this.getSupportedFacetTypes(indexType).contains(facetType);// 320
    }
 &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So solr just checks the facet type against a static list, which is initialized&amp;nbsp; as:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-java"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    static {
        SUPPORTED_FACET_TYPES = List.of(AsFacetType.REFINE, AsFacetType.MULTISELECT_OR, AsFacetType.MULTISELECT_AND);// 101
    }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So...&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Solr supports MULTISELECT_OR and MULTISELECT_AND but doesn't support MULTISELECT which we're trying to import in backofficesearch.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;And because of that the impex from the backofficesearch fails when I do platform update.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Am I misconfiguring something here or are these extensions incompatible?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/backofficesearchservices-incompatible-with-adaptivesearchsolr/qaq-p/14290668"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:54:20.707000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/step-by-step-guide-to-data-migration-cockpit-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud/bc-p/14290669#M72341</id>
    <title>Re: Step-by-Step Guide to Data Migration Cockpit in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:54:47.655000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FrankFinkbohner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/41006</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-container"&gt;&lt;a class="lia-spoiler-link" href="#" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Spoiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;noscript&gt; (Highlight to read)&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-border"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-content"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-container"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-content"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;P&gt;@pavankumart1127: can you please create a "question" and then ask your "Question" again,. Adding a specific question under a Blog as comment to get this answered is never a good idea as someone else cannot directly answer to your question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Create a Post with location "Enterprise resource planning Q&amp;amp;A"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Frank&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;P.S. both messages have a long text, that explains what the error is.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/step-by-step-guide-to-data-migration-cockpit-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud/bc-p/14290669#M72341"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:54:47.655000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-subtotal-challenges/qaa-p/14290677#M4933568</id>
    <title>Re: SAC subtotal challenges</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T15:59:58.219000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RajuRao</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Yes, this behavior is expected in SAP Analytics Cloud.The SUBTOTAL function has a hard limit of 10 dimensions, and there is no alternative function that removes this limit. SUBTOTAL also works only on base measures, not on aggregated or calculated measures created in the model. When used on aggregated measures, it fails by design due to calculation order restrictions. The recommended workaround is to reduce dimensions, or calculate percent of total in the source query or model instead of using SUBTOTAL.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-subtotal-challenges/qaa-p/14290677#M4933568"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T15:59:58.219000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-public-cloud-2508-mass-maintenance-of-tax-classification/qaa-p/14290678#M4233280</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud 2508 / Mass Maintenance of Tax class...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:00:02.563000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dawid90</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172309</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1448638"&gt;@LukasKuhn&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Public Cloud you basically have two hard constraints in your scenario:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can’t fix this by direct table work KNVI is just the persistence there’s no supported way to mass-update it directly in Public Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Migration Cockpit is not the right tool to correct existing production master data. SAP explicitly positions migration objects as initial load only&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/7c9e0bbbd1664c2581b2038a1c7ae4b3/2508.500/en-US/FSD_CE2508.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/doc/7c9e0bbbd1664c2581b2038a1c7ae4b3/2508.500/en-US/FSD_CE2508.pdf&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So re-running the same Migration Cockpit object won’t mass-correct those wrong Departure Country entries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For a true mass correction of the country code you need an interface that can remove the wrong key-records and create the correct ones.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The released way is the Business Partner (A2X) OData API, API_BUSINESS_PARTNER specifically the entity for Sales Area Tax:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expose the API&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Set up Communication Arrangement for scenario SAP_COM_0008 (scope item 1RO) to use API_BUSINESS_PARTNER. If you don’t see SAP_COM_0008, it’s typically because scope item &lt;STRONG&gt;1RO&lt;/STRONG&gt; isn’t activated&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3357532" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3357532&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Identify the wrong records&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use GET on entity set A_CustomerSalesAreaTax with filters like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CustomerTaxCategory: TTX1&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;DepartureCountry&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/API_BUSINESS_PARTNER/resource/Sales_Area_Tax" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/API_BUSINESS_PARTNER/resource/Sales_Area_Tax&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/API_BUSINESS_PARTNER/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/API_BUSINESS_PARTNER/overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Delete the wrong-key entries (mass-safe cleanup)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create the correct entry or update if it already exists:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the correct-key entry does not exist POST the correct combination&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If it does exist and only the classification value is wrong use PATCH&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP even has a Note showing the correct PATCH pattern and the key structure for A_CustomerSalesAreaTax and warns not to use POST for updates&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3293109" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3293109&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach is the closest equivalent to what you’re doing manually in the UI but automated and supported.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you can’t use APIs, open an SAP Incident if you suspect the data state is blocking standard maintenance tools and you need SAP guidance for a supported correction path in your tenant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My recommendation (cloud-friendly):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Do a small pilot (5 or 10 BPs) in using API_BUSINESS_PARTNER/A_CustomerSalesAreaTax:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET-&amp;gt;DELETE wrong DepartureCountry rows-&amp;gt;POST correct row or PATCH if already there&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run it in mass for all affected BPs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dawid&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-public-cloud-2508-mass-maintenance-of-tax-classification/qaa-p/14290678#M4233280"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:00:02.563000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/updated-sap-service-level-agreement-credit-claim-made-easy-in-sap-for-me/bc-p/14290679#M595</id>
    <title>Re: Updated! SAP Service Level Agreement Credit Claim made easy in SAP for Me</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:01:29.596000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pboulicaut</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/27536</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;what is happening when SAP is communicating 100% availability while the Cloud service were having down time ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;these happened to SuccessFactors learning being down (learning item unable to be launch for more than half a day)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;how can we claim credit for these ?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/updated-sap-service-level-agreement-credit-claim-made-easy-in-sap-for-me/bc-p/14290679#M595"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:01:29.596000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/incorrect-quantity-weight-conversion-during-outbound-delivery-creation/qaa-p/14290680#M4233281</id>
    <title>Re: Incorrect Quantity / Weight Conversion during Outboun...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:01:37.417000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; a bug but a master data/customizing issue. SAP standard logic uses:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Material master UoM conversion factors&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Gross/net weight maintained in material master&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Copy control settings between SO and delivery&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If any of these are inconsistent, delivery weight will be wrong even though the delivery posts successfully.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/incorrect-quantity-weight-conversion-during-outbound-delivery-creation/qaa-p/14290680#M4233281"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:01:37.417000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-heatmap-css/qaa-p/14290681#M4933569</id>
    <title>Re: SAC - Heatmap CSS</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:07:27.540000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RajuRao</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;No, it is not possible to apply custom colors to Heatmap rows using CSS or any other styling method in SAP Analytics Cloud.SAC does not support CSS access or custom styling at the widget or row level. The Totals row color in a Heatmap cannot be changed independently from the default theme. Conditional formatting also does not apply to Totals rows in Heatmaps.&lt;BR /&gt;A practical workaround is to place totals in a separate table or numeric point and style that widget instead.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-heatmap-css/qaa-p/14290681#M4933569"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:07:27.540000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/fiori-elements-valuelist-combobox/qaa-p/14290682#M4933570</id>
    <title>Re: Fiori Elements ValueList ComboBox</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:10:23.314000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NaveenVarma571</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Were you able to achieve this. And also what is connected_entity in this above code. I am also trying to achieve the same.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are from the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility team&lt;/STRONG&gt;, working on implementing a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ValueList field&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;using the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CDS extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;feature.&lt;BR /&gt;Currently, the field is displayed as a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;single-selection dropdown&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;in the application, but we want to make it&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;multi-select with checkboxes&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1896384873"&gt;Current Implementation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1828954087"&gt;1. Create field&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;pickListMulti&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;under table&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Students&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CSN used:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;"extensions": [
  {
    "extend": "Students",
    "elements": {
      "pickListMulti": {
        "default": { "val": "Multi" },
        "enum": {
          "Multi": { "val": "Multi" },
          "Multi1": { "val": "Multi1" },
          "Multi2": { "val": "Multi2" }
        },
        "length": 50,
        "@Extensibility.isEditable": true,
        "type": "cds.String"
      }
    }
  }
]&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1632440582"&gt;2. Create table&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Students.pickListMulti&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to store the ValueList data&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CSN used:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;"definitions": {
  "Students.pickListMulti": {
    "kind": "entity",
    "elements": {
      "name": {
        "type": "cds.String",
        "key": true
      }
    }
  }
}&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1435927077"&gt;3. Create a projection/view for collection path&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CSN used:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;"definitions": {
  "StudentService.Students.pickListMulti": {
    "kind": "entity",
    "projection": {
      "from": { "ref": ["Students.pickListMulti"] }
    }
  }
}&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1239413572"&gt;4. Populate data into&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Students.pickListMulti&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;entity&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data inserted using SQL&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;INSERT&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;commands.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1042900067"&gt;5. Add ValueList annotation to expose the field&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CSN used:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;"extensions": [
  {
    "annotate": "StudentService.Students",
    "elements": {
      "pickListMulti": {
        "@Common.ValueList.CollectionPath": "StudentService.Students.pickListMulti",
        "@Common.ValueList.Parameters": [
          {
            "$Type": "Common.ValueListParameterInOut",
            "LocalDataProperty": "pickListMulti",
            "ValueListProperty": "name"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  }
]&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The above setup successfully renders&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;pickListMulti&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;as a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ValueList dropdown&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but it only supports&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;single selection&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-717303843"&gt;Tried Approaches&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We tried adding the following annotations both individually and together on&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;StudentService.Students.pickListMulti&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;StudentService.Students&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;— but the behavior remains single-select.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;"@Capabilities.FilterRestrictions": {
  "FilterExpressionRestrictions": [
    {
      "Property": "pickListMulti",
      "AllowedExpressions": "MultiValue"
    }
  ]
}&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-520790338"&gt;Question&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a way to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;enable multiple selection (checkboxes)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for ValueList fields created through&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CDS extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;?&lt;BR /&gt;Are we missing any additional annotation or configuration at the API/service level to make it multi-select?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/fiori-elements-valuelist-combobox/qaa-p/14290682#M4933570"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:10:23.314000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/check-out-the-expert-guided-implementation-egi-sessions-for-january-2026/ba-p/14290683</id>
    <title>Check out the Expert Guided Implementation (EGI) sessions for January 2026</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:12:02.189000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LeeanDeLoria</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/57061</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="January 2026.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352181iDC7BBC382717B9C7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="January 2026.png" alt="January 2026.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check out the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expert Guided Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(EGI) sessions for&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;November 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp; EGI’s are instructor led sessions.&amp;nbsp; The sessions below are designed to facilitate effective adoption and utilization of the SAP Signavio solutions.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The links in this blog connect to the SAP Learning Hub, edition for SAP Enterprise Support, which requires a one-time registration.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Follow the "sign up" link below to register.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://esasupportportal.hana.ondemand.com/esa2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Sign up&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/html5/html5lib/v2.91/mwEmbedFrame.php/p/1921661/uiconf_id/35919811/entry_id/1_59z2n8fc?wid=_1921661&amp;amp;iframeembed=true&amp;amp;playerId=kaltura_player_1195878186&amp;amp;entry_id=1_59z2n8fc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Walkthrough video&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;January 2026 sessions are outlined here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;SAP Signavio Adoption Starter:&amp;nbsp; Process Insights for IT&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &lt;A href="https://saplearninghub.plateau.com/learning/user/deeplink.do?linkId=ITEM_DETAILS&amp;amp;componentID=SUP_EDE_0060_0822&amp;amp;targetStudentSysGUID=&amp;amp;componentTypeID=EXPERT_LED&amp;amp;fromSF=Y&amp;amp;revisionDate=1660148460000&amp;amp;actingAs=#/FEB28420B5DD48271800F7020C381E64" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Here&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp; In this course you learn how to connect your SAP System to SAP Signavio Process Insights and collect relevant data to get ready for quick process insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goals:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get a clear understanding of how to setup your Process Insights solution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explore the administration functionalities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Leverage the analytics and improvement capabilities to optimize your business.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;SAP Signavio Adoption Starter:&amp;nbsp; Plug and Gain approach - process discovery and analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &lt;A href="https://saplearninghub.plateau.com/learning/user/deeplink.do?linkId=ITEM_DETAILS&amp;amp;componentID=SUP_EDE_00010281&amp;amp;targetStudentSysGUID=&amp;amp;componentTypeID=EXPERT_LED&amp;amp;fromSF=Y&amp;amp;revisionDate=1747316545000&amp;amp;actingAs=#/40C736F218AFCD5C19005C425A217473" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register Here&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp; This course introduces participants to a streamlined methodology for exploring and analyzing their SAP ERP processes.&amp;nbsp;Utilizing SAP Signavio Process Insights, Process Intelligence, and Collaboration Hub.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goals:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discover and understand current as-is processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Make informed transformation decisions by leveraging key insights from your existing process landscape.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;SAP Signavio Adoption Starter:&amp;nbsp; Value Accelerators, Process Explorer and Process Navigator:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://saplearninghub.plateau.com/learning/user/deeplink.do?linkId=ITEM_DETAILS&amp;amp;componentID=SUP_EDE_110_1023&amp;amp;targetStudentSysGUID=&amp;amp;componentTypeID=EXPERT_LED&amp;amp;fromSF=Y&amp;amp;revisionDate=1698069180000&amp;amp;actingAs=#/5FBE4442E74092B118005D42E52C4616" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Here.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;This course helps you to adopt and consume the capability and usability of the SAP Signavio Process Explorer to enable business users to run in-depth process analysis. Also get insight on country- and deployment-specific SAP solution value accelerators using Process Navigator, different deployment options, countries and localization requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goals:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Signavio Process Explorer is set up and ready to use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Have a basic understanding of Value Accelerators.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Understand SAP Signavio Process Navigator.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Understand how to Navigate through different value accelerators​​.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned each month to learn what courses will be offered next.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Leean De Loria - Topic Expert for SAP Enterprise Support value maps.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/check-out-the-expert-guided-implementation-egi-sessions-for-january-2026/ba-p/14290683"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:12:02.189000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/question-on-mdk-extension-project-amp-version-control-behavior/qaa-p/14290684#M4933571</id>
    <title>Re: Question on MDK Extension Project &amp; Version Control B...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:18:38.111000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>piyushpotey</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/227900</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you, Bill, for the quick response. If I understand correctly, for each new feature we need to create a new Z extension project and include it in the base project’s .cim list. With this approach, the number of extension projects will continue to grow as new features are released. This also means we must ensure that: Extension project names are maintained in alphabetical order in the .cim file. The Overview.page is copied from the previous extension project into the new extension project so that it always contains the latest modified version of the code. Additionally, all SAP BAS projects and extension projects would be maintained within a single Git repository, initialized at the projects/ folder level. Could you please confirm if this is the recommended best practice, or point me to the appropriate documentation or SAP Learning course that describes the correct and supported approach?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/question-on-mdk-extension-project-amp-version-control-behavior/qaa-p/14290684#M4933571"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:18:38.111000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-university-alliances-global-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-app-development-and-coding-teaching-portfolio-of-sap/ba-p/14290688</id>
    <title>What's new in App Development and Coding Teaching Portfolio of SAP University Alliances</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:25:48.051000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yury</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16444</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why SAP BTP matters for teaching&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP BTP remains the cornerstone of SAP’s strategy: it enables the clean‑core principle while demonstrating side‑by‑side extension patterns that safely extend SAP core systems. For academic programs preparing students for industry practice, BTP offers an integrated, modern platform for application extension, integration, data management, analytics and AI — all in a cloud environment that maps directly to real‑world patterns.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s in the App Development and Coding portfolio&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Below are the principal curricula and academic experiences available now for classrooms teaching and labs. Each entry includes a placeholder for the curriculum one‑pager so you can link to full instructor materials and logistics when ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Build Process Automation &lt;/U&gt;— Teaches how to identify, design and implement workflow automation using Build Process Automation to reduce repetitive tasks and streamline processes.&lt;BR /&gt;(One‑pager: &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/QcqHqJG?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1235761" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;link)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Low/No‑Code Development with SAP Build Apps &lt;/U&gt;— Teaches the concepts and practice of low/no‑code app composition, connecting apps to SAP S/4HANA, and designing user experiences.&lt;BR /&gt;(One‑pager: &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/1JuYD5P?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1247573" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;link)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Pro‑Code Development with SAP Build Code&lt;/U&gt; — Equips learners with modern pro‑code practices, including SAP Joule‑assisted code generation and development workflows for scalable applications.&lt;BR /&gt;(One‑pager: &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/GbCLev8?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1260720" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;link)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Pro‑Code Application Development with SAP BTP (ABAP Environment &amp;amp; BAS)&lt;/U&gt; — Covers RAP and CAP models, RESTful application programming, and Cloud Foundry deployment to support clean‑core and side‑by‑side extension patterns.&lt;BR /&gt;(One‑pager: &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/WwxB4UV?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1235759" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;link)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/U&gt; &amp;nbsp;— Hands‑on curriculum for application and data integration across cloud and on‑premise systems, using standard integration patterns and monitoring practices.&lt;BR /&gt;(One‑pager: &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/w86z7XL?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1235760" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;link)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Document AI Tutorials &amp;amp; Global Bike extension (coming soon)&lt;/U&gt; &lt;EM&gt;— Practical tutorials on Document AI, including an extension scenario for the Global Bike sample system to demonstrate document processing in real use cases.&lt;BR /&gt;(Tutorials: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-university-alliances-global-blog-posts/leveraging-sap-document-ai-to-bring-intelligent-document-processing-into-a/ba-p/14231967" target="_self"&gt;link)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;No-barrier assets for faculty: Academic Lessons&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;A central asset across the portfolio is the set of Academic Lessons designed to be well aligned with a typical course syllabus structure. We encourage faculty to build course syllabus around Learning Journeys and to leverage SAP cloud practice system access available through &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/lecturers" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning Hub, student edition (LHSE)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This approach gives students step&lt;/SPAN&gt;‑&lt;SPAN&gt;by&lt;/SPAN&gt;‑&lt;SPAN&gt;step learning alongside hands&lt;/SPAN&gt;‑&lt;SPAN&gt;on practice in real SAP cloud systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Relevant Academic Lessons already prepared to include in a teaching pathway:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI and GenAI Fundamentals (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-university-alliances-global-academic-content/coming-soon-artificial-intelligence-and-generative-ai-fundamentals/ta-p/14248664" target="_self"&gt;Academic Lesson)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Introduction to AI and SAP Business AI (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-university-alliances-global-academic-content/new-introduction-to-artificial-intelligence-and-sap-business-ai/ta-p/14091393" target="_self"&gt;Academic Lesson)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Low/No‑Code Composition and Automation with SAP Build Apps (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-university-alliances-global-academic-content/low-code-no-code-composition-and-automation-with-sap-build/ta-p/14068845" target="_self"&gt;Academic Lesson)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These lessons map naturally into a Learning Journey that progresses from foundational concepts (AI fundamentals, low‑code design) to applied practice (Build Apps, Integration Suite, Document AI), with optional pro‑code extensions (Build Code, ABAP/BAS). Using LHSE cloud practice access, students can complete Discovery Center missions, follow guided tutorials, and earn records of achievement and have 2 attempts of professional certifications per year.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hands‑on, flexible academic editions and support&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The portfolio supports a range of academic needs: free sandboxes and trials for many BTP services, low‑cost exclusive teaching environments (typical UCC offers such as 600€ / 1.100€ per half/full year), Discovery Center missions, and Train‑the‑Trainer sessions upon request. University Competence Centers (UCCs) and Academic Competence Centers (ACCs) deliver regional classroom packages and guided exercises. Faculty at SAP University Alliances member institutions can contact their local UCC/ACC or &lt;A href="mailto:universityalliances@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;universityalliances@sap.com to get started&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:universityalliances@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Looking ahead and community engagement&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;In this series we will report updates, announce new Discovery Center missions available for academic use, sandboxes and pilots (including further content developments in GenAI, Agentic and Business AI), and showcase classroom case studies. We welcome your feedback and classroom experiences to help refine these materials, broaden and scale our academic portfolio.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-university-alliances-global-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-app-development-and-coding-teaching-portfolio-of-sap/ba-p/14290688"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:25:48.051000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/story-report-in-onobarding-query-design/qaq-p/14290693</id>
    <title>Story Report in Onobarding Query Design</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:29:39.684000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>piotr_retecki</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/49706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am facing the issue with the story report which I am building for my client.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;They want to include a lot of data, i.e. personal information, biographical information, job information and data gathered during the additional data collection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I managed to build the query which includes all of the data tables which are needed to meet the business requirement. But I am facing the following issue: not all data which is there in the onboarding dashboard, is in the report. I was modyfying the query multiple times but there is always something missing. I managed to determine that there are following issues:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- the query which contains the biographical information and linked tables (country-specific Information, dependents, email information, phone information).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- the report has the filter for legal entity used for the country which data should be visible in the report.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Removing the above from makes all the data which is missing appeared in the report. However it appears with empty rows, only the process ID is visivble, but all the rest (i.e. user ID) is empty. User ID should be there as the data collection steps are in most of the cases completed. Moreover, keeping them is needed to meet the business requirement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I raised the support ticket with SAP, but they replied that this is due to the query design and does not fall under the scope of the product support team. There seems to be no clear documentation on how to design the query to make it working correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any feedback will be much appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I attached the screen shot of the query for your reference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Piotr Retecki&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/story-report-in-onobarding-query-design/qaq-p/14290693"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:29:39.684000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/incorrect-quantity-weight-conversion-during-outbound-delivery-creation/qaa-p/14290694#M4233282</id>
    <title>Re: Incorrect Quantity / Weight Conversion during Outboun...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:31:15.965000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaymondGiuseppi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/185148</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Did you first check the values generated from Sales Order&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are quantity and uom already correct when delivery&amp;nbsp; is created (values and format) before calculations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check for&amp;nbsp;confirm quantities/uom in schedule lines of Sales Order&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Look for Customizing of &lt;SPAN&gt;VTLA&lt;/SPAN&gt;, delivery creation BAdI such as&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;LE_SHP_DELIVERY_PROC or routine such as 102&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Only then, check the created delivery&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Also provide some samples of 'delivery quantity / weight after unit conversion is incorrect'&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/incorrect-quantity-weight-conversion-during-outbound-delivery-creation/qaa-p/14290694#M4233282"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:31:15.965000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/onboarding-your-hr-manager-has-requested-a-correction-to-your-personal-data/qaa-p/14290698#M49931</id>
    <title>Re: Onboarding - Your HR manager has requested a correcti...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:35:57.564000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dren</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/52447</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;we also encountered this for the first time today &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":disappointed_face:"&gt;😞&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/onboarding-your-hr-manager-has-requested-a-correction-to-your-personal-data/qaa-p/14290698#M49931"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:35:57.564000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-public-cloud-2508-mass-maintenance-of-tax-classification/qaa-p/14290699#M4233283</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud 2508 / Mass Maintenance of Tax class...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:36:41.609000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LukasKuhn</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1448638</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you for the response &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348"&gt;@Lakshmipathi&lt;/a&gt; . Could you explain the first option "Replace Existing Records" in the migration cockpit more ?&lt;BR /&gt;To my knowledge it is not possible, once you have migrated a data set, to update this imported data with a new import, but only with MDG tools.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best regards&lt;BR /&gt;Lukas&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-public-cloud-2508-mass-maintenance-of-tax-classification/qaa-p/14290699#M4233283"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:36:41.609000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/text-overlap-on-overflow/qaa-p/14290702#M4933572</id>
    <title>Re: Text Overlap on overflow</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:38:36.592000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thkolz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/156280</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Great!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/text-overlap-on-overflow/qaa-p/14290702#M4933572"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:38:36.592000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/remove-unnecessary-transaction-type-from-insert-scope/qaq-p/14290703</id>
    <title>Remove Unnecessary Transaction Type from Insert Scope</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:39:30.906000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S0027212682</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2214469</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are trying to remove unnecessary transaction type(SMMJ) in Insert Scope of RFC as we have our own custom transaction type ZMMJ. We are following the below Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2598158 What controls the transaction type offered in RfC Scope assignment block? - Solution Manager&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What we noticed that there is no option for below. We don't have option for allowed or disallowed. Only Entry removal option is there&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Copy Control Rules&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Target Transaction Type&lt;/EM&gt; values that are offered are listed here.&amp;nbsp; Modify the values that should be allowed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/remove-unnecessary-transaction-type-from-insert-scope/qaq-p/14290703"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:39:30.906000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/possibility-to-register-different-branches-within-one-business-partner-s/qaa-p/14290704#M4233284</id>
    <title>Re: Possibility to register different branches within one business partner - S/4HANA public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:40:06.116000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KR05</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1743799</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello Kerisha, I have the same requirement for a UK public sector SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud customer. The customer has suppliers with multiple postal and email addresses, and for the same reasons you outlined below, we do not want to use partner functions. It has been almost six months since you raised the improvement request with SAP — could you please share SAP’s response or current status?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/possibility-to-register-different-branches-within-one-business-partner-s/qaa-p/14290704#M4233284"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:40:06.116000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/possibility-to-register-different-branches-within-one-business-partner-s/qaa-p/14290716#M4233285</id>
    <title>Re: Possibility to register different branches within one business partner - S/4HANA public cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:43:07.135000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KR05</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1743799</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Here is a concise and polished rewording: &amp;gt; Hello Kerisha, I have the same requirement for a UK public sector SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud customer. The customer has suppliers with multiple postal and email addresses, and for the same reasons you outlined below, we do not want to use partner functions. It has been almost six months since you raised the improvement request with SAP — could you please share SAP’s response or current status? If you want it more formal or more conversational, I can adjust it.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/possibility-to-register-different-branches-within-one-business-partner-s/qaa-p/14290716#M4233285"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:43:07.135000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/miro-assign-bkpf-awkey-to-bseg-zuonr/m-p/14290717#M298</id>
    <title>Re: MIRO- Assign BKPF-AWKEY to BSEG-ZUONR</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:44:00.982000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaymondGiuseppi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/185148</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As a substitution at call up point 3 for complete document wont be executed in MIRO, you could look at following&amp;nbsp; BTE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;process interface 00001130 - only If you are an SAP employee&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;process interface 00001120 -&amp;nbsp;DOCUMENT POSTING: Field substitution header/items&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/miro-assign-bkpf-awkey-to-bseg-zuonr/m-p/14290717#M298"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:44:00.982000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-tax-reporter-year-end-2025/bc-p/14290722#M62792</id>
    <title>Re: U.S Tax Reporter Year End 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:51:07.843000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Zachary_Carrier96</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1956530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are trying to apply NOTE 3665751 into 604-M2. We are in the post implementation steps it has worked up until Georgia and on Georgia it is giving an error that HR_F_MWR_GA - ALLFIELDS-DCORR does not exist.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone else ran into this issue?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-tax-reporter-year-end-2025/bc-p/14290722#M62792"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:51:07.843000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/s-4hana-group-reporting-group-view-on-accounting-gva/bc-p/14290724#M62794</id>
    <title>Re: S/4HANA Group Reporting - Group View on Accounting (GVA)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:53:18.372000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HengyeZhu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1383754</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Nice feature. Couple of comments&lt;BR /&gt;1. It seems that the underlying queries are still leveraging the nameclass ABAP implementation with the gap of hierarchies for custom fields. This gap of nameclass is not exposed to many customer as it was only used in GR in prior release. With this booklet, the gap is exposed to more customers in Accounting.&lt;BR /&gt;2. We do see nowdays ANI are abled to be posted to CU, PC and SEG. But it is not flexible to extend to all fields, especially custom fields.&lt;BR /&gt;3. With GRPL, it is easier to map from standard fields in ACDOCA to custom fields in ACDOCU, but why ACDOCU could not have those standard fields? and make the fields structure exactly same between ACDOCA and ACDOCU? We do see the business function for public sector has been enhanced to fill this gap, but why not for all fields?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/s-4hana-group-reporting-group-view-on-accounting-gva/bc-p/14290724#M62794"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:53:18.372000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/do-i-need-to-reversed-the-direct-activity-allocation-after-actual-cost/qaa-p/14290725#M4233286</id>
    <title>Re: Do I need to reversed the direct activity allocation,...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:53:55.016000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>garyding</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/27803</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Henrike,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot for your reply, but it's not what I am looking for.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me change my question, in which scenario, direct activity type allocation is needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;since I will post actual cost into WBS(for example labor cost by posting salary in month end), why I need direct activity allocation to post a cost with plan labor cost rate,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;B,R&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/do-i-need-to-reversed-the-direct-activity-allocation-after-actual-cost/qaa-p/14290725#M4233286"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:53:55.016000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/unlocking-the-power-of-model-context-protocol-mcp-for-sap-business/bc-p/14290726#M176794</id>
    <title>Re: Unlocking the Power of Model Context Protocol (MCP) for SAP Business Applications</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:54:05.002000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kristiyan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1453093</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Pretty interesting topic. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/unlocking-the-power-of-model-context-protocol-mcp-for-sap-business/bc-p/14290726#M176794"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:54:05.002000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-learning-group-knowledge-base/meet-the-team/tac-p/14290727#M2</id>
    <title>Re: Meet the team</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:56:07.774000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vitaliy-R</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for introducing the team. It would be great to have an image, a profile page (like &lt;A href="https://profile.sap.com/u/markgreen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://profile.sap.com/u/markgreen,&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to follow), and a LinkedIn page (if willing to share) for each of you, too!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-learning-group-knowledge-base/meet-the-team/tac-p/14290727#M2"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:56:07.774000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-tax-reporter-year-end-2025/bc-p/14290730#M62795</id>
    <title>Re: U.S Tax Reporter Year End 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:58:46.703000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Zachary_Carrier96</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1956530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are seeing the issue with NOTE 3665751 on other states as well.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-tax-reporter-year-end-2025/bc-p/14290730#M62795"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:58:46.703000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-public-cloud-2508-mass-maintenance-of-tax-classification/qaa-p/14290732#M4233287</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud 2508 / Mass Maintenance of Tax class...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T16:59:46.468000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaymondGiuseppi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/185148</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Read KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="To update and change an existing record, a mass maintenance and/or processing app available for the Migration Object must be used. This is the standard behavior." href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2650201/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2650201 - Migration Cockpit: How to create/update data records&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Accelerator Hub -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/API_BUSINESS_PARTNER/resource/Sales_Area_Tax" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Partner A2X&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-public-cloud-2508-mass-maintenance-of-tax-classification/qaa-p/14290732#M4233287"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T16:59:46.468000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/qm-mic-classed-recording/qaa-p/14290733#M208557</id>
    <title>Re: QM- MIC - Classed Recording</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:01:02.414000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ZGIUS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2142292</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks for sharing. Where could this type of setup be useful? Is it possible to give an example of applicability? Thanks Giuseppe</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/qm-mic-classed-recording/qaa-p/14290733#M208557"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:01:02.414000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/question-on-mdk-extension-project-amp-version-control-behavior/qaa-p/14290736#M4933574</id>
    <title>Re: Question on MDK Extension Project &amp; Version Control B...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:02:52.885000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bill_froelich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14699</uri>
    </author>
    <content>No, typically only one Z project is created to contain all the changes for the particular base version.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/question-on-mdk-extension-project-amp-version-control-behavior/qaa-p/14290736#M4933574"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:02:52.885000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/step-by-step-guide-to-data-migration-cockpit-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud/bc-p/14290737#M72342</id>
    <title>Re: Step-by-Step Guide to Data Migration Cockpit in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:03:54.604000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S0027070337</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2166680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, does it make sense to create a profit center and cost center with the migration cockpit or would it be better directly through the application? It is just 1 of each. Our system is already live.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/step-by-step-guide-to-data-migration-cockpit-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud/bc-p/14290737#M72342"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:03:54.604000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/ui-theme-designer-custom-theme-parameters-how-to/qaq-p/14290738</id>
    <title>UI Theme Designer - custom theme parameters - How to</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:05:08.791000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S0027140105</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2213661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;i started working with UI Theme Designer cause we need to setup different color setting for each system in S/4 landscape. However, after setting some basic stuff i run into issue, that when i want to e.g. setup colors in Calendar, i have no idea which parameters should be set. There is no indication in Designer itself and i ended up with trial &amp;amp; error, but this is time consuming, e.g. for Calendar:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="S0027140105_0-1765814311069.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352211i8F643219F2FFFBFF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="S0027140105_0-1765814311069.png" alt="S0027140105_0-1765814311069.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I want to have more saturated text and in my custom color scheme, but i am at loss where to look for. Is there any interactive help in Designer or somewhere else when i need to change something particular? Also Search bar is visible only when i Save &amp;amp; Preview in another page, which is really time consuming so trial &amp;amp; error is really not possible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;FYI: Theme Designer is updated and no issues indicated in report&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;WDG_MAINTAIN_UR_MIMES&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Many thanks.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/ui-theme-designer-custom-theme-parameters-how-to/qaq-p/14290738"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:05:08.791000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-advanced-financial-closing-definition-of-parameters/qaa-p/14290739#M256982</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Advanced Financial Closing - definition of Parame...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:13:01.365000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chholzermsg</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9522</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Thomas,&lt;BR /&gt;thank you for clarification.&lt;BR /&gt;So I have only the derived parameters listed &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/advanced-financial-closing/user/parameter-maintenance" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; available in Fiori Apps, correct?&lt;BR /&gt;Because in theory I would expect that I could define new task list models and this way define additional parameters.&lt;BR /&gt;But the desciption I find &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/advanced-financial-closing/local-settings/how-to-define-parameter-types" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; only refers to ABAP programs (=jobs).&lt;BR /&gt;Or is there another way to add parameters to a task list?&lt;BR /&gt;Regards&lt;BR /&gt;Christian&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-advanced-financial-closing-definition-of-parameters/qaa-p/14290739#M256982"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:13:01.365000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/flexible-real-estate-accrual-engine-legacy-migration-technique/bc-p/14290740#M72343</id>
    <title>Re: Flexible Real Estate - Accrual Engine Legacy Migration Technique</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:15:27.325000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MMarinhoMendes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1469469</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you&amp;nbsp;Mohamed!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In a Merge scenario where transfer the contracts between companies, is there a way to keep the accrued amount in the&amp;nbsp; both companies and not double booking it?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Condition Start : 01.08.2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cutoff date : 01.12.2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;3 months Accrued in Original Company code – OK&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;9 months Accrue the remaining value without post the initial 4 moths initial periodic posting (it happens using your Way).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Miguel Mendes&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/flexible-real-estate-accrual-engine-legacy-migration-technique/bc-p/14290740#M72343"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:15:27.325000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/exchange-rate-difference-postings-at-payment-time-additional-6680-7680/qaq-p/14290745</id>
    <title>Exchange Rate Difference Postings at Payment Time – Additional 6680 / 7680 Entry in  Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:37:34.356000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AlvaroFernandezMorales</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2087949</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;Dear community,&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;I am working in an SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud environment and analyzing the exchange rate difference postings generated during the procurement and payment process. I have encountered a posting logic that I do not fully understand from a functional and accounting perspective.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;I will describe the scenario in a simplified way:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Purchase order for 1,000,000 in foreign currency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Goods Receipt posted with an exchange rate of 1.1566.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Subsequently, the Supplier Invoice is posted for the same amount (1,000,000), but with an exchange rate of 1.1727.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Due to the exchange rate difference between the Goods Receipt and the Invoice, the system posts an adjustment to price/variance accounts, impacting purchase or consumption accounts (for example 6011 / 6111). This behavior is clear to me.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Later on, the payment to the vendor is executed using an exchange rate of 1.1634.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;At payment time, the accounting document contains the following postings:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Bank posting (as expected).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Clearing of the vendor account 4000 (as expected).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• A negative exchange rate difference, posted to account 668 (exchange rate losses).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; My question arises here:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;In addition to the above, the system generates an additional accounting entry with the same amount, where:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• A debit is posted to account 6680 (negative exchange rate difference), and&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• A corresponding credit is posted to account 7680 (positive exchange rate difference).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;In other words, an additional posting between 6680 and 7680 is created with no net impact on P&amp;amp;L. While the balances offset each other, I do not fully understand the functional purpose of this posting in the context of standard exchange rate difference handling.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Could someone please explain why SAP generates this additional “mirror” entry between negative and positive exchange rate difference accounts at payment time?&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Is this related to the clearing or reversal of previously posted exchange rate differences, or is it part of the standard exchange rate difference logic in S/4HANA Public Cloud?&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Many thanks in advance for your support&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/exchange-rate-difference-postings-at-payment-time-additional-6680-7680/qaq-p/14290745"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:37:34.356000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/3-must-know-configuration-setups-in-variable-pay/bc-p/14290747#M9574</id>
    <title>Re: 3 Must-Know configuration setups in Variable Pay</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:43:57.054000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/18635"&gt;@ErikaT&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;most likely you have a mismatch between the format of fields: you can only aggregate amount with amount and money with money (and I would think percent with percent). Also make sure the lower level field is marked as reportable and calculate total (it cannot be editable either it needs to be read-only = yes I believe).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/3-must-know-configuration-setups-in-variable-pay/bc-p/14290747#M9574"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:43:57.054000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ewm-layout-oriented-storage-control-losc-behind-the-scenes/bc-p/14290769#M6292</id>
    <title>Re: SAP  EWM Layout oriented storage control (LOSC) behind the scenes</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:50:01.404000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dilli</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/154312</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;It is really great to understand the frontend config and the backend logics with debugging screen. Much appreciated. Thanks Rudra&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ewm-layout-oriented-storage-control-losc-behind-the-scenes/bc-p/14290769#M6292"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:50:01.404000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-central-business-configuration-best-practices-during-sap-s-4hana-cloud/ba-p/14290770</id>
    <title>SAP Central Business Configuration Best Practices During SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Upgrades</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:53:22.925000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FabianAckermann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131646</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;, customers benefit from regular upgrades and updates that bring the latest innovations, enhanced security, and improved performance. With SAP Central Business Configuration serving as the single entry point for scoping, organizational structures, and configuration activities, it is natural that upgrade cycles involve certain considerations within SAP Central Business Configuration.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Protective Measures Matter During Upgrades&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Think of these measures as the safety rails on your system. By locking down critical operations (transports, data migrations, extensibility) during upgrade windows, SAP ensures the upgrade process can run smoothly without unintended side effects − protecting the system from half-done changes or version mismatches.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With SAP rolling out major &lt;STRONG&gt;upgrades&lt;/STRONG&gt; twice a year (typically in February and August) and regular &lt;STRONG&gt;updates&lt;/STRONG&gt; (hotfix collections) every two weeks between major upgrades, having a clear restriction schedule allows customers to adopt innovations in a controlled, manageable way. For more information on the schedule, please refer to: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Upgrade &amp;amp; Maintenance Schedule for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, 3-System Landscape" href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2021/09/58ffa59e-f97d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Upgrade &amp;amp; Maintenance Schedule for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, 3-System Landscape&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Upgrade &amp;amp; Maintenance Schedule for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, 2-System Landscape" href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2017/01/867629d8-a27c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Upgrade &amp;amp; Maintenance Schedule for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, 2-System Landscape&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Protective Measures and Best Practices&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keep your team well informed about upcoming upgrade cycles.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Avoid &lt;STRONG&gt;initial activation&lt;/STRONG&gt; around upgrade time, as it’s typically time consuming. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Avoid &lt;STRONG&gt;large deployments&lt;/STRONG&gt;to prevent stuck deployments or partial content activation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Perform business &lt;STRONG&gt;configuration activities&lt;/STRONG&gt; until &lt;STRONG&gt;8 hours&lt;/STRONG&gt; before system downtime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Make changes to your &lt;STRONG&gt;scope&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;organizational structure&lt;/STRONG&gt; up until the content upgrade begins. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For the parallel line, avoid initiating &lt;STRONG&gt;rebase&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;merge&lt;/STRONG&gt; before the upgrade starts, as these actions lock the workspace.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Avoid scheduling &lt;STRONG&gt;critical go-lives&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;User Acceptance Testing&lt;/STRONG&gt; (UAT) around upgrades.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For the 2-system landscape, in addition to the above, avoid releasing &lt;STRONG&gt;transport requests&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the quality system to the production system.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Central Business Configuration Impacts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s look at how the SAP Central Business Configuration system behaves during these system upgrades.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. &lt;STRONG&gt;During Update&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;SPAN&gt;Here’s the update maintenance schedule for the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, 3-system landscape:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Update windows and time of workspace locking per region" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352218iF7A9B756A9B1AE48/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="FabianAckermann_0-1765817241166.png" alt="Update windows and time of workspace locking per region" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Update windows and time of workspace locking per region&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please note that &lt;STRONG&gt;deployments&lt;/STRONG&gt; are automatically locked &lt;STRONG&gt;12 hours before&lt;/STRONG&gt; the software update starts, aligning with the timing of the Major Upgrade Window (MUW).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business &lt;STRONG&gt;configuration activities&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be performed until the system enters downtime.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Organizational structure&lt;/STRONG&gt; updates, &lt;STRONG&gt;scope&lt;/STRONG&gt; extensions, and new country activations are allowed until the content update begins and the SAP Central Business Configuration workspace becomes locked.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. &lt;STRONG&gt;During Upgrade&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Here’s the&amp;nbsp;upgrade&amp;nbsp;maintenance schedule for the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, 3-system landscape:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Upgrade windows and time of workspace locking per region" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352217iEEB3BEE730FF5308/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="FabianAckermann_1-1765817241167.png" alt="Upgrade windows and time of workspace locking per region" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Upgrade windows and time of workspace locking per region&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please note that &lt;STRONG&gt;deployments&lt;/STRONG&gt; are automatically locked &lt;STRONG&gt;30 hours before&lt;/STRONG&gt; the software upgrade starts, aligning with the timing of the Major Upgrade Window (MUW).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business configuration activities can be performed &lt;STRONG&gt;until 12 hours before&lt;/STRONG&gt; the system enters downtime.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organizational structure updates, scope extensions, and new country activations are allowed &lt;STRONG&gt;until the content update begins&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the SAP Central Business Configuration workspace becomes locked.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To learn more, check out the following resources: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Note 3215993 (SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, 3-System Landscape)" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3215993" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 3215993 (SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, 3-System Landscape)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Note 3464889 (SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, 2-System Landscape)" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3464889" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 3464889 (SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, 2-System Landscape)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;That wraps up the new features this time. Did you like this blog? If so, please leave us a thumbs up at the top. Also, make sure to follow the &lt;EM&gt;SAP Central Business Configuration&lt;/EM&gt; tag or follow this dedicated&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="blog collection" href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/11/14/sap-central-business-configuration-blog-collection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;blog collection&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to stay up to date with the latest blog posts.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-central-business-configuration-best-practices-during-sap-s-4hana-cloud/ba-p/14290770"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:53:22.925000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ebs-interpretation-algorithm-015-febep-chect-has-only-13-characters/qaa-p/14290771#M4233288</id>
    <title>Re: EBS Interpretation Algorithm 015 - FEBEP-CHECT has on...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:54:18.393000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marcduf001</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/572118</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;See note 396776 &amp;nbsp;&lt;I&gt;Bank statement/MT940: Customer reference too long&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ebs-interpretation-algorithm-015-febep-chect-has-only-13-characters/qaa-p/14290771#M4233288"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:54:18.393000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/datasphere-association-to-a-dimension-with-input-parameter/qaa-p/14290774#M4933576</id>
    <title>Re: Datasphere - Association to a dimension with input pa...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:58:14.865000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mitko1994</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/548155</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Not possible I'm afraid! The workaround would be a view with a join.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/datasphere-association-to-a-dimension-with-input-parameter/qaa-p/14290774#M4933576"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:58:14.865000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enhancing-business-processes-with-sap-btp-ai-in-sap-integration-suite/ba-p/14290773</id>
    <title>Enhancing Business Processes with SAP BTP AI in SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:59:01.038000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arunmaarirajha_kv</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2033343</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Preface&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modern enterprises increasingly expect their integration platforms to do more than reliably move data between systems. SAP Integration Suite, combined with SAP BTP AI services, provides a foundation to embed intelligence directly into integration flows. This post highlights how combining integration with AI can unlock new capabilities and drive smarter, more adaptive processes across the enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enterprise integrations traditionally rely on deterministic, structured data—a design paradigm that has supported SAP business processes for decades. This determinism is what allows ERP systems to automatically and reliably create documents, update statuses, or trigger follow-on actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When a payload arrives in a predefined, standard format—via interfaces such as APIs, IDocs, or RFCs—the ERP system can create a business document and drive it forward to the furthest possible system-determined state, guided entirely by the incoming structured fields and the process logic configured within SAP ERP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, an incoming ORDERS05 IDoc carries fields such as BSART (document type), VKORG (sales organization), KUNNR (sold-to), MATNR, MENGE, and PSTYV (item category). Each of these fields is restricted to predefined, allowed values and mapped to controlled domains in SAP—document types, organizational structures, master data, and item categories. Because of this, the system can deterministically derive pricing, partner functions, credit checks, availability checks, and subsequent status movements without any human involvement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, many real-world processes reach a designed stopping point—not due to technical limitations, but because a critical decision input exists only as free-text narrative that requires interpretation. At this point, the system can no longer progress deterministically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One scenario where this consistently occurs is when free-text inputs determine the next business action. High-value examples include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;customer return comments in RMAs (Return Merchandise Authorization), capturing defect descriptions, expectations, or reason narratives;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;exception remarks on delivery notes, such as damage details, refusal reasons, or access issues; and&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;justification text in travel expense claims, explaining non-compliant or unusual charges.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These narrative fields often dictate the downstream outcome—whether a return is approved, a delivery is blocked, or an expense is reimbursed—but only after a human reads and interprets them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GenAI as the Semantic Bridge&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recent advances in Generative AI — powered by large language models (LLMs) — make it possible to automate this traditionally human-only interpretation step. These models can read the free-form comments contained in incoming messages, infer intent and context, and return structured, process-ready attributes in a fast and consistent manner, which the integration layer can pass directly into ERP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To realize this, the integration flow could simply call the LLM and instruct it to convert narrative comments into ERP-compatible attributes, codes, or flags. The model applies reasoning to questions such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is the customer asking for a refund or a replacement?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is the delivery refusal due to damage or customer unavailability?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is the expense violation justified or not justified?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on this, the model produces clean ERP-friendly outputs, for example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ReturnActionCode = "REFUND" or "REPLACEMENT"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;DeliveryBlockReason = "DAMAGED_GOODS" or "CUSTOMER_NOT_AVAILABLE"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ExpenseExceptionStatus = "APPROVED_JUSTIFIED" or "REJECTED_UNJUSTIFIED"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of receiving verbose, unstructured text that a human must interpret, the backend now receives clear, deterministic signals it can immediately act on — allowing the business process to progress further downstream rather than stopping at the point where human intervention was previously required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deep Dive Example: Customer Returns (As-Is vs. AI-Enhanced Flow)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let us consider a model company named Smart Sense Technologies (SST), a global manufacturer of smart security devices. Like many enterprises today, SST’s IT organization faces both challenges and opportunities driven by internal and external factors such as a rapidly evolving technology landscape, shifting customer expectations, and increasing business demand for speed and agility. To respond effectively and deliver optimal outcomes for its stakeholders, SST embarked on a digital transformation journey supported by SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP). The organization leverages BTP to innovate and extend business capabilities, enabling greater process efficiency, faster time-to-market, and increased operational agility. To stay ahead of the competition, SST continuously evaluates and optimizes its end-to-end business processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the As-Is process, SST’s customer returns initiated in SAP Commerce Cloud are integrated with SAP S/4HANA using the standard &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/SAPHybrisCommerceIntegrationwithS4HANA/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Commerce Cloud Integration with SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. This package provides a ready-made integration flow that transmits return requests from Commerce Cloud to S/4HANA as ORDERS05 IDocs, establishing a reliable and widely adopted baseline for returns processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_0-1765817257218.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352220i665BA72B8EEB7B22/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_0-1765817257218.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_0-1765817257218.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_1-1765817257244.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352219i58838ED2F4C90638/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_1-1765817257244.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_1-1765817257244.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;This iflow sends the transactional data required to create the returns order in S/4HANA. Along with structured order attributes, it also forwards free-text return comments entered by the customer. These narrative descriptions are embedded in the IDoc and successfully persisted in the returns document, but they are not interpreted or acted upon automatically by the system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/7b24a64d9d0941bda1afa753263d9e39/6222a7ef62294a45b437e4d2e99525b7.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;For more background on the Sales &amp;amp; Return process integration using IDOC&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the IDoc level, two fields are particularly relevant in this context. E1EDP01-ABGRT carries the free-text return or cancellation description provided upstream, while E1EDP01-ABGRU represents the structured rejection or decision reason that drives subsequent processing in Sales and Returns Management. In real-world configurations, ABGRT is commonly populated by the inbound integration, whereas ABGRU is often left empty until a human has reviewed the return and made a decision.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_2-1765817257278.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352221iB079CF7EFD30764C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_2-1765817257278.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_2-1765817257278.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is also important to note that approval responsibilities may vary by landscape. In some scenarios, return approval may already occur in an upstream portal such as SAP Commerce Cloud in our example, while in others it is intentionally deferred to SAP S/4HANA. For the purpose of this example, we assume that the approval step is handled in S/4HANA. As a result, when the ORDERS05 IDoc arrives from Commerce Cloud, the return order is created with descriptive context (ABGRT) but without a decision code (ABGRU), causing the process to pause for human review.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of SST’s continuous improvement efforts, the IT organization is tasked with the responsibility to help the business improve its processes – with specific metrics such as cutting sales / return processing lead-time, improving accuracy, offering consistent customer experience. Considering this, SST’s integration architecture team proposes a solution leveraging BTP AI within Integration Suite iflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_3-1765817257286.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352222iD548B52AC01FF010/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_3-1765817257286.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_3-1765817257286.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this scenario, SST extends the standard integration flow with a focused AI-based classification step executed in a post-exit iflow in SAP Integration Suite. The free-text return description (ABGRT) received from SAP Commerce Cloud is passed to an LLM using a tightly constrained prompt that maps narrative customer input to a single, predefined SAP rejection reason code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_4-1765817257307.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352224i0DA251A7E2BF758C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_4-1765817257307.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_4-1765817257307.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following figure shows the Post-exit iflow that is called from the main flow. This iflow uses AI adapter to call an LLM to convert the free-text customer rejection comments into a deterministic return code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_5-1765817257327.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352223i40771C9255099E7F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_5-1765817257327.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_5-1765817257327.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_6-1765817257344.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352226iD6F3A6CC24E611C6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_6-1765817257344.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_6-1765817257344.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_7-1765817257349.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352225i07354000D58A6BA4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_7-1765817257349.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_7-1765817257349.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, we pass the prompt directly from the processing tab of the AI Adapter, with the rejection text as parameter, that is fetched from the incoming message from Commerce cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_8-1765817257365.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352227i2A832DC7ABAD94C9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_8-1765817257365.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_8-1765817257365.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After deploying the post-exit iflow, next we proceed to test using a HTTP client (to mimic a message from SAP Commerce cloud). Here, rejection text is parameterized and fed from a variable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_9-1765817257393.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352230i7B989673ADA97E51/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_9-1765817257393.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_9-1765817257393.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The rejection text is passed as “Item arrived much later than agreed”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_0-1765818457859.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352250i6990E9A19504880C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_0-1765818457859.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_0-1765818457859.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the actual prompt that is sent to the LLM – after substitution of the rejection text, passed from the HTTP call.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_11-1765817257439.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352229i7697FAC3697CC67E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_11-1765817257439.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_11-1765817257439.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following is the LLM response, with S4_RejectionReasonCode being populated, strictly adhering to the prompting made to the LLM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_12-1765817257456.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352232iB0B02BC49AA6A2E4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_12-1765817257456.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_12-1765817257456.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, we use this LLM derived RejectionReasonCode to enrich the IDOC mapping, to populate E1EDP01-ABGRU.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_13-1765817257495.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352231iD54B57BC61872A32/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_13-1765817257495.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_13-1765817257495.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_14-1765817257518.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352233i47387932A2CD5DEF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="arunmaarirajha_kv_14-1765817257518.png" alt="arunmaarirajha_kv_14-1765817257518.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As demonstrated in the preceding steps, the extended integration flow now enriches the inbound ORDERS05 IDoc with a populated rejection reason code (ABGRU), derived from the customer’s free-text input (ABGRT) using AI-based reasoning and interpretation. With the decision code present at creation time, the returns document no longer stalls in an indeterminate state and can proceed through the standard S/4HANA returns process without waiting for manual interpretation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depending on landscape design and process ownership, this semantic enrichment can also be taken a step further. Instead of—or in addition to—populating the IDoc, the same inferred outcome can be used to directly invoke standard SAP S/4HANA APIs such as the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/19d48293097f4a2589433856b034dfa5/4f5736c166ce4a2da425335751b52907.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Advanced Returns Management approval&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; service (API_CUSTOMER_RETURN_SRV) to explicitly release or reject the return order. This represents the post–human-action document state that would traditionally be reached only after a manual approval step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, these patterns illustrate how introducing AI-driven interpretation at the integration layer allows unstructured customer intent to be converted into structured, actionable business signals at the point of entry.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI in Integration: Why It Fits and How to Govern It&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1) Reasserted: The Integration platform’s timeless role as the enabler of Process Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In many enterprises, the integration layer, such as Integration Suite, serves as the natural ingestion point and middleware platform that facilitates transactions and orchestrates message flows between applications across the ERP landscape. Embedding GenAI-driven interpretation here fits naturally into CPI’s existing responsibilities: it allows the business meaning hidden inside narrative text to be converted into actionable signals before the request reaches the core ERP process. For integration architects and developers, this aligns perfectly with the integration layer’s role as the control point for routing, orchestration, and decisioning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When free-text descriptions are converted into deterministic attributes—such as &lt;EM&gt;return_reason_code&lt;/EM&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;refund_flag&lt;/EM&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;inspection_required&lt;/EM&gt;, or &lt;EM&gt;damage_classification&lt;/EM&gt;—CPI can now call the exact API operation that corresponds to the post-review document state. In other words, CPI can directly invoke the relevant API to post the document in the status it would have reached only after a human had read, approved, or actioned the text. This removes the need to always invoke a “pre-review” API and wait for downstream human review.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This shift eliminates traditional bottlenecks: manual interpretation steps, workflow inbox approvals, delays from human availability, and intermediate document states that halt progression. Because decisioning happens at the moment the request enters the landscape, CPI sends a clean, enriched, decision-ready payload to S/4HANA (or any backend), enabling the system to execute the correct business logic immediately.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rather than replacing human judgment, this pattern formalizes and codifies human insight into a governed, automated, and fully auditable integration layer. This is why, in this scenario, AI belongs in the integration layer: This architectural capability empowers CPI to transform narrative inputs into deterministic, actionable signals, enabling downstream process automation while keeping the ERP core clean.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2) Clean Core by Design&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Placing the intelligence in SAP BTP ensures that ERP systems remain standard, maintainable, and free from any text-interpretation logic. This approach avoids enhancing S/4HANA to parse unstructured text or extending it to process AI-derived attributes—both of which introduce long-term complexity and technical debt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead, ERP systems receive clean, structured, enriched payloads through the REST/OData APIs designed for standard CRUD operations. This keeps backend applications stable and upgrade-friendly, while positioning the intelligence in a layer that is flexible, governed, and purpose-built to support innovation. By keeping the semantics outside the ERP and feeding it deterministic attributes through established integration patterns, the core remains clean by design.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3) A Perfect Problem–Solution Fit for AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Interpretation of natural-language free text is inherently a language-understanding problem — a task that humans have traditionally handled because it requires context, nuance, and inference. GenAI models excel exactly in this domain: extracting meaning, identifying intent, and classifying the actions implied by narrative input.&lt;BR /&gt;Once the integration layer converts this text into deterministic attributes, every subsequent step becomes standard ERP automation — pricing behaviour, blocking, approvals, follow-on documents, status progression, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4) High Business Value When Applied to High-Impact Scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A clear business value emerges when Generative AI is applied to the right type of problem—specifically, scenarios where narrative text shapes important decisions. While many processes contain free-text fields, the highest value appears when unstructured descriptions create friction, ambiguity, or costly delays that materially affect customer satisfaction, compliance, or financial outcomes. The architectural decision to integrate an LLM must be strictly justified by a measurable Return on Investment (ROI), as these models operate on a metered consumption model. Consequently, the value delivered must always outweigh the cost of the service call, meaning GenAI should be applied only to high-impact, high-volume scenarios where the operational expense of manual intervention significantly exceeds the cost of an LLM call.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Typical examples of processes (as previously mentioned) that run at scale, carry high consequence, and often suffer from a high cost of delay include: Customer Returns (RMAs), delivery exceptions, and expense justifications. In these situations, shifting the interpretation logic to the point of ingestion (within the Integration Suite) fundamentally reshapes the flow. Processing accelerates because items no longer wait for manual review; accuracy and consistency improve through uniform, model-driven interpretation; and downstream data quality is strengthened. This leads to tangible improvements in efficiency and decision reliability, with human attention reserved for genuine edge cases. Scenarios that combine high repetition, high consequence, and high ambiguity are the strongest candidates for this GenAI-driven interpretation, whereas traditional deterministic approaches remain the appropriate and cost-effective choice when these characteristics are absent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5) Auditability and Control Built In&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While in our deep-dive example, we directly applied the prompt at the AI Adapter, it is also possible to build the request body, incorporating orchestration configurations provided out of the box with BTP AI Core (GenAI Hub), in the form of LLM guard-railing steps such as prompt templating, data masking, model configuration, and so on. Also, it is a best practice to make use of prompt templates, to make use of reusability. With such controls in place, the LLM response can stay relevant, reliable, and responsible (3 “R”s &lt;SPAN&gt;that constitute the key pillars of&amp;nbsp;SAP's AI&amp;nbsp;strategy&lt;/SPAN&gt;) ensuring that business process outcomes are explainable and auditable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These details about Orchestration workflow can be found in this &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-ai-core/sap-ai-core-service-guide/orchestration-workflow-v2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP help portal page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’d also recommend that you read &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/invoking-llm-from-cloud-integration-responsibly-made-easy-with-generative/ba-p/14176222" target="_blank"&gt;this blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; by my colleague Daniil, where Orchestration workflow in Generative AI Hub is used to invoke an LLM in a secure, GDPR-compliant way, from within an integration flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By leveraging SAP BTP AI services within SAP Integration Suite, organizations can elevate integration from a transport layer to a semantic processing layer—converting human intent into deterministic business signals at the point of entry. This approach enables Straight-Through Processing, automating decision-making while preserving governance, auditability, and maintainability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Combining Integration and AI opens up new possibilities for business process efficiency. Are you examining how this could apply within your own landscape?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/intelligent-orchestration-in-iflows-business-aware-routing-with-sap-btp-s/ba-p/14162148" target="_blank"&gt;Read our earlier article on how BTP’s AI Services can help in your Integration flow’s routing, decision-making steps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enhancing-business-processes-with-sap-btp-ai-in-sap-integration-suite/ba-p/14290773"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:59:01.038000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-central-business-configuration-blog-collection/bc-p/14290776#M62797</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Central Business Configuration – Blog Collection</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:59:23.834000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FabianAckermann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131646</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New blog alert − Check out our latest blog post:&amp;nbsp;"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Central Business Configuration Best Practices During SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Upgrades" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-central-business-configuration-best-practices-during-sap-s-4hana-cloud/ba-p/14290770" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Central Business Configuration Best Practices During SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Upgrades&lt;/A&gt;"&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-central-business-configuration-blog-collection/bc-p/14290776#M62797"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T17:59:23.834000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-rising-beef-prices-reveal-in-sap-business-network-spend-trends/ba-p/14276385</id>
    <title>What Rising Beef Prices Reveal in SAP Business Network Spend Trends</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:00:47.260000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christopher_Chase</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1657480</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The New York Times reported the average price of a pound of ground beef was around&amp;nbsp;$&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6.32 in September. This is an increase of about 11−14% from the previous year, driven primarily by a smaller U.S. cattle herd.&amp;nbsp; As global temperatures rise, shrinking cattle herds are straining the nation's beef supply even as demand remains strong.&amp;nbsp; As of July, USDA&amp;nbsp;data&amp;nbsp;shows there were 28.7 million beef cows across the US, the lowest number in decades.&amp;nbsp; Other factors lifting beef prices include higher grain costs and labor supply shortages at slaughterhouses.&amp;nbsp; Furthermore, tariffs on beef from Brazil, America's largest import source, may be curbing supplies.&amp;nbsp; The total tariff on Brazilian beef imports sat at 76.4% in September,&amp;nbsp;according&amp;nbsp;to the American Farm Bureau Federation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You may be asking if spending on SAP Business Network reflects these economic factors. Here is what network data shows.&amp;nbsp; Two meat classes are traded on SBN:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Processed Meat &amp;amp; Poultry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Processed meat has undergone additional treatment beyond basic cutting or packaging. Examples include deli meats (ham, turkey breast slices, roast beef), sausages, hot dogs, bratwurst, bacon, chicken nuggets or patties.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Minimally Processed Meat &amp;amp; Poultry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These products undergo only basic processing needed to make them safe or convenient.&amp;nbsp; Examples include raw chicken breasts, thighs, or wings, raw turkey or whole chickens, and ground beef or ground turkey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beef cannot be analyzed in isolation until we extend demand trends to level 4 of UNSPSC.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="processed.png" style="width: 794px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344549i4D0F34A06701BC8D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="processed.png" alt="processed.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There’s $364M in spend of processed meat on the network.&amp;nbsp; There was a large spike spread over Q3 with spend increase 76.4% compared to the prior quarter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="min processed.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344550iEE57C8A462079285/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="min processed.png" alt="min processed.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The plot thickens however when viewing minimally processed meats.&amp;nbsp; Minimally processed meat spend was $578M and relatively flat with an extreme spike in September.&amp;nbsp; Q3 spend increased 43% compared to Q2.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Growth.png" style="width: 762px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344552iDBF1EA7D8C276DFA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Growth.png" alt="Growth.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analyst&lt;STRONG&gt;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;have&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;obse&lt;/STRONG&gt;rved differences in behavior of both classes.&amp;nbsp; Analysts say:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;minimally processed meat has steadier baseline demand but more volatility due to supply constraints, inflation, and contract timing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;processed meat shows steady, healthy growth driven by convenience and value-added products.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SBN data appears to support both of these observations as exhibited by the following:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Steady growth of processed meat from February – September with few dips&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Processed meat less volatile. No extreme spikes or crashes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Minimally processed meat is more volatile. Large swings early year from December – February.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Minimally processed meat shows occasional extreme spikes. The 147M spike in September.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Minimally processed demand tied more to supply chain fluctuations. &amp;nbsp;Jumps and reversals in monthly data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-rising-beef-prices-reveal-in-sap-business-network-spend-trends/ba-p/14276385"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:00:47.260000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/integration-advisor-use-custom-xslt-as-mag/ba-p/14280963</id>
    <title>Integration Advisor – Use Custom XSLT as MAG</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:06:27.350000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joerg_Ackermann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/671194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I am excited to announce our latest feature: Within the Integration Advisor capability of SAP Integration Suite, you can now define a Mapping Guideline (MAG) using a custom XSLT file. In this blog post, I will provide a brief overview of this new feature and explain how to use it.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1072960254" id="toc-hId-1766381455"&gt;Motivation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integration Advisor, through its MAG Editor, provides a tool that enables Business Experts or Integration Developers to implement mappings between different message structures. The MAG Editor is specifically designed for B2B interactions and includes numerous value-added features, particularly useful for handling EDI messages (such as qualification concept, code value mapping, date-time conversion, and proposal service). One of the key advantages of the MAG Editor is its graphical mapping approach, which empowers Business Experts without developer skills to define mappings with minimal assistance from Integration Developers (following a no-code/low-code approach).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But there are scenarios where customers prefer to use a custom XSLT file instead of a graphical mapping. Such use cases include:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Significant structural differences between the source and target message that cannot be easily resolved by a graphical mapping editor like the MAG Editor.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The need for additional pre- or post-processing steps (in addition to a graphical mapping) that can be handled more efficiently using XSLT.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A desire to reuse an existing XSLT mapping file, for instance, from another mapping platform such as SAP Process Integration.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the past, this functionality could already be achieved through a separate mapping step (of type XSLT) in Cloud Integration or via a Process Direct configuration in Trading Partner Management (TPM).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Through the SAP Customer Influence program, we received the requirement to enable custom XSLT mappings directly within Integration Advisor (see &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/298620" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;). The advantage of this approach is the ability to maintain all graphical and XSLT mapping artifacts in one place, leverage Integration Advisor's versioning capabilities, and reach a unified configuration in&amp;nbsp;Trading Partner Management.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-876446749" id="toc-hId-1569867950"&gt;Feature Description&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When creating a new Mapping Guideline (MAG), you now have the option to choose between a Graphical MAG (either Standard or Overlay) and an XSLT MAG. When selecting the XSLT option, the MAG is defined in the traditional way by selecting Source and Target&amp;nbsp;Message Implementation Guidelines (MIGs).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After the MAG is created, you can upload your custom XSLT file. (Please note that the MAG must be saved before the XSLT file is applied.) The screenshot below illustrates the appearance of an XSLT MAG.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="screenshot-1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347204iBB74EF9E4AF554C1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="screenshot-1.jpg" alt="screenshot-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can view the content of the uploaded XSLT file, download it, and re-upload an updated XSLT file if needed. Additionally, you can use the Simulate MAG feature in the same way as for a Graphical MAG. We also plan to introduce an option to validate the XSLT syntax of your file soon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that it is not possible to edit the content of the XSLT file directly within Integration Advisor. If updates are required, you can make the necessary changes in your preferred XSLT editor and re-upload the XSLT file. Furthermore, certain configurations available for Graphical MAGs, such as Global Parameters, Shared Code, Duplicate Target Nodes, or Pretransformation, are not applicable to XSLT MAGs and are therefore not offered in the UI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And one final comment regarding the specific XSLT in the screenshot above: The Ship Notice message (856) from ASC X12 frequently requires a very specific structure for the HL Segment Groups in terms of order and identifiers. It is a well-known issue that graphical mapping editors, such as the MAG Editor, often face&amp;nbsp;challenges in producing all the required details. In such cases, we recommend utilizing an additional XSLT as post-processing - see this blog post (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/taming-the-x12-856-message-in-sap-integration-advisor-a-step-by-step-guide/ba-p/14115410" target="_self"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;) for a detailed explanation. The example above illustrates how this XSLT would appear as an XSLT MAG.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-876446749" id="toc-hId-1373354445"&gt;Two Architectural Assumptions&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The purpose of this new feature is to achieve closer integration of custom XSLT mappings within the Integration Advisor framework. In this section, I would like to highlight two key design decisions made to support this purpose. If you plan to use this feature, please keep these two aspects in mind:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. An XSLT MAG maps between a Source and a Target MIG&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explanation: Similar to current Graphical MAGs, you need to define a Source MIG and a Target MIG for your custom XSLT mapping.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reasoning:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Aligns with the current principal design of Integration Advisor.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensures seamless integration into Trading Partner Management (if TPM is utilized).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Allows MAG Simulation to function similarly to Graphical MAGs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. An XSLT MAG works with Integration Advisor Payload Format (ICA format)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explanation:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Background: We call the payload format after applying MIG preproc.xslt the ICA payload format. This format differs from the original XML payload format (called CPI payload format) in several aspects, most notably added qualifier suffixes but also other processing simplifications (e.g., the inclusion of an extra node CONTENT for nodes based on XSD Simple Content).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Similar to Graphical MAGs, the custom XSLT shall map between the ICA payload format of the Source MIG and the ICA payload format of the Target MIG.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reasoning:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Aligns with the current principal design of Integration Advisor.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensures seamless integration into Trading Partner Management (if TPM is used).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintains consistent processing steps in Integration Flows within Cloud Integration (if TPM is not used), allowing the same Integration Flow logic as for Graphical MAGs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Advantage:&amp;nbsp;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leverages Integration Advisor's value-added features, such as the powerful MIG qualification concept, which could also simplify a custom XSLT mapping.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enables the use of Extended Semantic Payload Validation based on your MIG.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;(Potential) Disadvantage:&amp;nbsp;If you already have an XSLT file that maps between standard XML formats (CPI format or PO format), you may need to make some adjustments to work with the ICA payload format.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Additional info: The Integration Advisor Payload Format is depicted by the MIG structure you see in MIG Editor or MAG Editor. By clicking on a node, you can navigate to the Technical Information section to find the exact XML Node Name and the exact Node XPath, which need to be used to address a node. See screenshot below for an example.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="screenshot-2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347205i37C8533D837F0F8C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="screenshot-2.jpg" alt="screenshot-2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If these two architectural assumptions do not align with your use case, you can still utilize the XSLT mapping feature of Cloud Integration or the Process Direct option in TPM. In such cases, you have greater flexibility in your design decisions but will not benefit from the closer integration with Integration Advisor.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176840940"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consumption in Trading Partner Management and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Integration &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When you export the runtime artifacts of an XSLT MAG, there is no difference compared to a Graphical MAG. The runtime artifacts include a mapping XSLT file, which is named according to your MAG Name. This exported MAG XSLT file contains the XSLT definitions you uploaded in your XSLT MAG. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using this approach, you can consume an XSLT MAG in &lt;/SPAN&gt;Trading Partner Management as well as in Cloud Integration in the same way as you would consume a Graphical MAG.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-483419739" id="toc-hId-980327435"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With this new feature, you can create a&amp;nbsp;Mapping Guideline in Integration Advisor based on your own custom XSLT file. This provides greater flexibility where needed while still leveraging Integration Advisor features such as versioning and integration with TPM. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking ahead, we plan to introduce an additional standard feature in TPM/IA that will allow you to combine multiple MAGs in a mapping sequence. This would enable scenarios where you can combine a Graphical MAG with additional XSLT pre- and/or post-processing.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-286906234" id="toc-hId-783813930"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further reading&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/integration-advisor-overview-of-components-for-building-b2b-integration/ba-p/13512772" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/integration-advisor-overview-of-components-for-...&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/integration-content-advisor-create-a-customized-interface-using-mig-editor/ba-p/13354699" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/integration-content-advisor-create-a-customized...&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/integration-content-advisor-create-a-mapping-using-mag-editor/ba-p/13424264" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/integration-content-advisor-create-a-mapping-using-mag-editor/ba-p/13424264&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/taming-the-x12-856-message-in-sap-integration-advisor-a-step-by-step-guide/ba-p/14115410" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/taming-the-x12-856-message-in-sap-integration-advisor-a-step-by-step-guide/ba-p/14115410&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/integration-advisor-use-custom-xslt-as-mag/ba-p/14280963"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:06:27.350000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/add-more-types-of-retention-in-po-sap-s-4hana/qaa-p/14290791#M208558</id>
    <title>Re: Add more types of retention in PO SAP S/4HANA</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:09:12.172000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ankurch</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11196</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/781728"&gt;@kabouki&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; - In Standard SAP only provided one retention field, which can only carry the value in percentage, however you can create custom field to carry these values.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/add-more-types-of-retention-in-po-sap-s-4hana/qaa-p/14290791#M208558"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:09:12.172000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/activate-joule-in-sap-concur-a-step-by-step-guide/bc-p/14290793#M187157</id>
    <title>Re: Activate Joule in SAP Concur - a Step-by-Step Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:14:36.758000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nageshcaparthy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2099</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi GAKJ,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the link and the details shared above. The above option is recommended only when you have cloud.sap migration. As you see the help page, it runs into multiple problems if not take care of it. I would not recommend if customers are using ondemand.com as it clearly states not to use it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nageshcaparthy_0-1765818793649.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352251iE796FA3015289475/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nageshcaparthy_0-1765818793649.png" alt="nageshcaparthy_0-1765818793649.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, Global ID is a pre-req for Joule and hence this a mandatory activity at this point of time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nagesh&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/activate-joule-in-sap-concur-a-step-by-step-guide/bc-p/14290793#M187157"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:14:36.758000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/best-practices-for-onboarding-and-miniec-with-a-focus-on-offboarding-and/bc-p/14290794#M9575</id>
    <title>Re: Best Practices for Onboarding and MiniEC – With a Focus on Offboarding and Crossboarding</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:15:38.554000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adacalugarean</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/33859</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For a client we have to configure ONB 2.0 with Mini EC for 2 countries USA and CAN. How is the Address portlet being configured, considering that MiniEC doesn't support Country Specific Fields? To enable the Address portlet for USA and CAN I need to import the CSF Succession Data Model. What is the best approach in this matter?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/best-practices-for-onboarding-and-miniec-with-a-focus-on-offboarding-and/bc-p/14290794#M9575"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:15:38.554000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-can-we-get-the-packing-data-of-a-material-in-a-ppd/qaa-p/14290796#M4233289</id>
    <title>Re: How can we get the packing data of a material in a PPD</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:19:49.350000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManoelCosta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/175657</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, I´m afraid that material packing data details are currently not exposed by any PAPI at the moment, so I suggest you use Customer Influence portal at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3537" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3537&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to share your requirements and request it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope it helps! Br, Manoel&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-can-we-get-the-packing-data-of-a-material-in-a-ppd/qaa-p/14290796#M4233289"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:19:49.350000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/deep-dive-into-sap-hana-database-encryption-concepts-setup-amp-best/bc-p/14290804#M176796</id>
    <title>Re: Deep Dive into SAP HANA Database Encryption: Concepts, Setup &amp; Best Practices</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:20:26.528000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Subhashree_Bhuyan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2158199</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Very helpful&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/deep-dive-into-sap-hana-database-encryption-concepts-setup-amp-best/bc-p/14290804#M176796"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:20:26.528000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/your-start-with-abap-there-are-many-good-reasons/bc-p/14290812#M176797</id>
    <title>Re: Your start with ABAP - there are many good reasons</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:23:14.529000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanieMarley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1895422"&gt;@jferreirabr&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;wishing you a lot of success. We hope that you share and engage your experience in the community!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/your-start-with-abap-there-are-many-good-reasons/bc-p/14290812#M176797"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:23:14.529000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/warehouse-physical-inventory-document-creation-unable-to-change-data-in/qaq-p/14290815</id>
    <title>Warehouse Physical Inventory document creation, unable to change data in field.</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:24:16.491000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Muhammedali</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1404165</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi SAP team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are trying to create physical inventory document in warehouse management using the app &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Inventory Documents - Physical Inventory &lt;/STRONG&gt;(SCWM/PI_DOC_CREATE). Here by default the blocking indicator is marked as X i.e. has been enabled and is unable to edit it. likewise the freeze inventory indicator is also not changeable. is it a standard system behavior or is there any settings or configurations missing from our side? please guide.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/warehouse-physical-inventory-document-creation-unable-to-change-data-in/qaq-p/14290815"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:24:16.491000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/designing-an-effective-grievance-process-in-sap-successfactors-performance/ba-p/14290817</id>
    <title>Designing an Effective Grievance Process in SAP SuccessFactors Performance &amp; Goals Management</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:25:42.344000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SachinPachauri</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/24035</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Employee trust in the performance management process depends heavily on transparency, fairness, and the ability to raise concerns. A well-designed Grievance Process in SAP SuccessFactors Performance and Goals Management (PMGM) ensures that employees can formally challenge or seek clarification on performance outcomes, while HR and management can handle these cases in a structured, auditable way.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog explains how to design and configure a grievance process in SuccessFactors PMGM using:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Performance Management (PM) Templates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Route Maps&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Rules&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add Review Steps upon form routing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dynamically control field visibility, editability, and required status&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Build a Grievance Process in PMGM?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A grievance process in PMGM enables organizations to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide a formal appeal mechanism for performance ratings&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure consistency and compliance across regions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve employee confidence in performance outcomes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintain auditability of all actions and comments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce off-system emails and manual escalations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of managing grievances outside SuccessFactors, organizations can embed the process directly into the performance form lifecycle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High-Level Grievance Process Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A typical grievance flow in PMGM looks like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Employee Submits Grievance Request&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Additional Review Steps Triggered&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HR / Grievance Committee Review&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Final Decision Communicated&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Form Completed &amp;amp; Locked&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This flow is achieved using a combination of PM template fields, route maps, and intelligent business rules.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Configuring the PM Template for Grievance Handling&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Fields to Add in the PM Template&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Add custom fields in the relevant sections (Summary / Overall Rating / Custom Section)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt; Best Practice: Place employee-facing grievance fields in a separate custom section for clarity.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SachinPachauri_0-1765819232589.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352260i69DDBEE0A0217951/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SachinPachauri_0-1765819232589.png" alt="SachinPachauri_0-1765819232589.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Designing the Route Map with Conditional Grievance Steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Route Maps control who sees the form and when.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SachinPachauri_9-1765819466129.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352269i0C9C537521EA3EF8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SachinPachauri_9-1765819466129.png" alt="SachinPachauri_9-1765819466129.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enable &lt;STRONG&gt;“Hidden Until Rule Execution”&lt;/STRONG&gt; option in all the route steps which you want to use in the business rule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SachinPachauri_2-1765819284161.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352262iC535AFB0DBF64566/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SachinPachauri_2-1765819284161.png" alt="SachinPachauri_2-1765819284161.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Add Review Steps Upon Form Routing (Business Rule)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the most powerful capabilities in PMGM is dynamically adding route map steps when specific conditions are met.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SachinPachauri_5-1765819335289.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352265iF775429472C5F2F4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SachinPachauri_5-1765819335289.png" alt="SachinPachauri_5-1765819335289.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SachinPachauri_4-1765819329366.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352264i63CD4253E45B29A2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SachinPachauri_4-1765819329366.png" alt="SachinPachauri_4-1765819329366.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Controlling Field Visibility, Editability, and Mandatory Status Using Business Rules&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A grievance process requires different users to see different fields at different times.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This is achieved using Business Rules for Field Properties.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SachinPachauri_6-1765819383707.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352266i2CBF8B4F05D01D9B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SachinPachauri_6-1765819383707.png" alt="SachinPachauri_6-1765819383707.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5: In the&amp;nbsp;Assign Rules in Talent&amp;nbsp;admin tool, you've assigned the rule to the&amp;nbsp;Field Change&amp;nbsp;trigger.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SachinPachauri_8-1765819409852.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352268iA175EC92CD53DCEE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SachinPachauri_8-1765819409852.png" alt="SachinPachauri_8-1765819409852.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the business rule is assigned to a template, Admin can launch a form and meet the conditions to trigger the additional steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reporting &amp;amp; Audit Considerations&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;To strengthen governance:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use Story or Table Reports to track:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Number of grievances raised&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Approval vs rejection trends&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Average grievance resolution time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable field audit history for grievance-related fields&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintain role-based permissions strictly&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;By combining PM Templates, Route Maps, and Business Rules, SAP SuccessFactors PMGM provides a robust and flexible framework to manage employee grievances within the performance cycle.&lt;BR /&gt;A well-implemented grievance process not only improves compliance and transparency but also reinforces employee trust in performance management outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/designing-an-effective-grievance-process-in-sap-successfactors-performance/ba-p/14290817"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:25:42.344000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-maintenance-notifications-with-sap-situation-handling/bc-p/14290818#M7964</id>
    <title>Re: Handling Maintenance Notifications with SAP Situation Handling</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:28:51.310000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>amdev</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/606453</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Beautifully written and extremely insightful. You’ve captured both the technical depth and practical relevance of the topic so well!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-maintenance-notifications-with-sap-situation-handling/bc-p/14290818#M7964"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:28:51.310000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/this-is-new-tile-way-to-use-joule-carousel-control/bc-p/14290822#M187158</id>
    <title>Re: This is new tile way to use joule, carousel control</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:29:05.068000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sachin_kaura2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/240994</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="284502_shutterstock_1049407283_low_nwm (1).jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352270iA02321FE5193FFAF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="284502_shutterstock_1049407283_low_nwm (1).jpg" alt="284502_shutterstock_1049407283_low_nwm (1).jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="305394_AdobeStock-200481352_large_jpg (1).jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352272iD0D003B60CFF401F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="305394_AdobeStock-200481352_large_jpg (1).jpeg" alt="305394_AdobeStock-200481352_large_jpg (1).jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="305453_AdobeStock-507422337_large_jpg (1).jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352271i24F788B94EC2DDB4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="305453_AdobeStock-507422337_large_jpg (1).jpeg" alt="305453_AdobeStock-507422337_large_jpg (1).jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;   &lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/this-is-new-tile-way-to-use-joule-carousel-control/bc-p/14290822#M187158"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:29:05.068000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/the-re-emergence-of-community-in-the-sap-ecosystem/m-p/14290823#M3352</id>
    <title>Re: The Re-emergence of Community in the SAP Ecosystem</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:39:19.191000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanieMarley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14127"&gt;@ChrisRae&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1042"&gt;@MarceloPinheiro&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53"&gt;@qmacro&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and all community members, what struck me as incredible in 2025 was so many community members attending events in person all around the globe. Additionally, so many community members wrote&amp;nbsp;blog posts afterward -- to consolidate their thoughts and share their insights gained during the event with a wider audience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I truly appreciate your blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14127"&gt;@ChrisRae&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;since I personally observed that in&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2025 tech conferences seem to focus on human connections and community. This is fantastic, and the best is yet to come for community in 2026 and beyond.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Season's Greetings!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/the-re-emergence-of-community-in-the-sap-ecosystem/m-p/14290823#M3352"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:39:19.191000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/this-is-new-tile-way-to-use-joule-carousel-control/bc-p/14290825#M187159</id>
    <title>Re: This is new tile way to use joule, carousel control</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:42:07.908000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sachin_kaura2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/240994</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="305453_AdobeStock-507422337_large_jpg (1)_cropped_processed_by_imagy.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352273iC528437B5EE93828/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="305453_AdobeStock-507422337_large_jpg (1)_cropped_processed_by_imagy.jpg" alt="305453_AdobeStock-507422337_large_jpg (1)_cropped_processed_by_imagy.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/this-is-new-tile-way-to-use-joule-carousel-control/bc-p/14290825#M187159"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:42:07.908000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/create-deal-in-current-accounting-period/qaq-p/14290826</id>
    <title>Create Deal in current accounting period</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:42:10.127000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jithendrashiva</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/846337</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have missed to post a deal in transaction FTR_CREATE with 10 million dollars in March 2025 and it is wrongly calculating the interest, can we post a deal in current accounting period so that interest will calculated in correctly?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;it is a sale posting deal&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please share your thoughts on this&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Jithendra Shivashankar&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/create-deal-in-current-accounting-period/qaq-p/14290826"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:42:10.127000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/this-is-new-tile-way-to-use-joule-carousel-control/bc-p/14290828#M187160</id>
    <title>Re: This is new tile way to use joule, carousel control</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T18:42:55.963000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sachin_kaura2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/240994</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="305453_Changed_large.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352274i3AE80AEA1FFF564F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="305453_Changed_large.png" alt="305453_Changed_large.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/this-is-new-tile-way-to-use-joule-carousel-control/bc-p/14290828#M187160"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T18:42:55.963000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/we-are-facing-an-issue-with-barcode-scanning-on-a-honeywell-ck65-hardware/qaa-p/14290836#M4933577</id>
    <title>Re: We are facing an issue with barcode scanning on a Hon...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T19:04:36.602000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bill_froelich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14699</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The barcode scanner icon in the search bar and in the simple property field both will open the camera by default to try and scan a barcode and place the value into the respective field.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;MDK also provides a way to override this and execute a custom rule to use a hardware scanner for example.&amp;nbsp; Integration of any other scanner is not provided out of the box from MDK.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How are you using the scanner in this case?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are using the default camera scanning as defined out of the box?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are you defining an OnScanPress rule for your SimpleProperty field?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are you using the "keyboard wedge" mode of the hardware scanner?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/we-are-facing-an-issue-with-barcode-scanning-on-a-honeywell-ck65-hardware/qaa-p/14290836#M4933577"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T19:04:36.602000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-cap-blog-posts/building-custom-authentication-in-sap-cap/bc-p/14290847#M15</id>
    <title>Re: Building Custom Authentication in SAP CAP</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T19:21:09.918000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Italo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476479</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Is it possible to use XSUAA for most services and implement a custom authentication mechanism for some specific services?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m working on an architecture where XSUAA would handle authentication and authorization for the majority of the services, but a few specific services would require a custom authentication approach.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-cap-blog-posts/building-custom-authentication-in-sap-cap/bc-p/14290847#M15"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T19:21:09.918000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-set-up-label-printing-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-using-output/qaq-p/14290849</id>
    <title>how to set up label printing  SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud using output parameter determination.</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T19:22:07.420000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MWaehlen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2258793</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Print queue is via Maintain Print Queues available. I found no way to assign a store printers. Selection list for choice of a printers in the app&amp;nbsp;F1563 ( store operations print labels in fashion modul public cloud )&amp;nbsp; is empty. SAP Cloud Print manager PI works fine and shows the mentioned queue.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-set-up-label-printing-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-using-output/qaq-p/14290849"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T19:22:07.420000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/scheduling-bi-4-3-reports-to-microsoft-drives-sharepoint-onedrive-teams/bc-p/14290853#M187161</id>
    <title>Re: Scheduling BI 4.3 reports to Microsoft drives (SharePoint / OneDrive / Teams)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T19:30:08.947000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cgpark</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/839567</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Does this work when Business objects in on-prem and SharePoint online? Per SAP Tech in Expert session, it was stated a report in BOs cannot be directly scheduled to SharePoint.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/scheduling-bi-4-3-reports-to-microsoft-drives-sharepoint-onedrive-teams/bc-p/14290853#M187161"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T19:30:08.947000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-1/ba-p/14288990</id>
    <title>How to transport variants and bookmarks in SAP Fiori Launchpad | Part 1 - Introduction</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T19:33:48.477000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VictoriaEnzmann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1416159</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1637537154"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How variants are transported via GUI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you have created a new variant in ERP development system and want to maintain them to the test and production system you can simply add them to a transport request using program RSTRANSP (via transaction SE38). Once the transport request is released all variants will be imported into all subsequent systems (DEV - QAS - PROD) according to your transport and system settings.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Programm RSTRANSP" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351304iE12477416AF9B116/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_0-1765471457978.png" alt="Programm RSTRANSP" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Programm RSTRANSP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1441023649"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Fiori Launchpad and Fiori Apps&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the SAP Fiori Launchpad, you’ll find different types of Fiori Apps, including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GUI-to-HTML Fiori Apps,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;UI5 Fiori Apps and&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Web Dynpro Fiori Apps.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to identify the type of a Fiori App:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;To determine which type of SAP Fiori App you’re using, follow these simple steps:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Fiori App.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on the initials in the upper-right corner.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select&amp;nbsp;"About"&amp;nbsp;from the menu.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the dialog box that appears, check the&amp;nbsp;"Framework ID"&amp;nbsp;section - this will indicate the app type.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The&amp;nbsp;"Trial Balance" (F0996)&amp;nbsp;app is a&amp;nbsp;Web Dynpro Fiori App.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The&amp;nbsp;"Audit Journal" (F0997)&amp;nbsp;app is a&amp;nbsp;UI5 Fiori App.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The&amp;nbsp;"Display Asset" (AS03)&amp;nbsp;app is a&amp;nbsp;GUI-to-HTML Fiori App.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Fiori App &amp;quot;Trial Balance&amp;quot; (F0996)" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351306i9FD2CC81E67A74DA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_0-1765472608989.png" alt="Fiori App &amp;quot;Trial Balance&amp;quot; (F0996)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fiori App "Trial Balance" (F0996)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Fiori App &amp;quot;Audit Journal&amp;quot; (F0997)" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351308iD29DA852C4C756CE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_2-1765473194584.png" alt="Fiori App &amp;quot;Audit Journal&amp;quot; (F0997)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fiori App "Audit Journal" (F0997)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Fiori App &amp;quot;Display Asset&amp;quot; (AS03)" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351309i4CCC9DAC71FC02CC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_3-1765473329114.png" alt="Fiori App &amp;quot;Display Asset&amp;quot; (AS03)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fiori App "Display Asset" (AS03)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that we’ve explored how to locate different Fiori Apps, our next two blog posts will take a closer look at UI5 Apps and Web Dynpro Apps. GUI-to-HTML Apps won’t be covered in a separate post since the process remains unchanged from what was explained at the beginning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s a sneak peek at the next two blog posts in this series. For a deeper dive, stay tuned!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351311iB3B80B8A99518CE8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_0-1765475535114.png" alt="How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blog Series "How to transport variants and bookmarks in SAP Fiori Launchpad"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Part 1 - Introduction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Part 2 - UI5 Fiori Apps" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-2-ui5/ba-p/14289008" target="_blank"&gt;Part 2 - UI5 Fiori Apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Part 3 - Web Dynpro Fiori Apps" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-3-web/ba-p/14290212" target="_blank"&gt;Part 3 - Web Dynpro Fiori Apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy learning! Read you in the next part.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-1/ba-p/14288990"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T19:33:48.477000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-2-ui5/ba-p/14289008</id>
    <title>How to transport variants and bookmarks in SAP Fiori Launchpad | Part 2 - UI5 Fiori Apps</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T19:36:15.608000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VictoriaEnzmann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1416159</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766640744"&gt;How to transport in UI5 Fiori Apps&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now that we’ve explored the different types of Fiori Apps, let’s dive deeper into the first category. Referring to the chart from the initial blog post in this series, we’ll focus on the left section of the diagram and start with UI5 Fiori Apps.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351311iB3B80B8A99518CE8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_0-1765475535114.png" alt="How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not all SAP Fiori Apps support the AdaptUI function, even though they are built on SAPUI5 technology. The key distinction is that while an app may be a UI5 application, AdaptUI can be explicitly disabled. Examples:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fiori App "&lt;SPAN&gt;Display G/L Account Balances" (ID:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;F0707A) - AdaptUI &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; active&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fiori App "&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage Supplier Line Items" (ID: F0712&lt;/SPAN&gt;) - AdaptUI active&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Activate AdaptUI" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352290iE4A4E21B436B6E0A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="2025-12-15_19-24-30.png" alt="Activate AdaptUI" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Activate AdaptUI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Fiori App &amp;quot;Display G/L Account Balances&amp;quot; (ID:&amp;nbsp;F0707A)" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351962iD91A8ED4757E7E98/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_0-1765789684483.png" alt="Fiori App &amp;quot;Display G/L Account Balances&amp;quot; (ID:&amp;nbsp;F0707A)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fiori App "Display G/L Account Balances" (ID:&amp;nbsp;F0707A)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ID:&amp;nbsp;F0707A - AdaptUI not active" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352289iA0842B7A3895D16C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_0-1765822996809.png" alt="ID:&amp;nbsp;F0707A - AdaptUI not active" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;ID:&amp;nbsp;F0707A - AdaptUI not active&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Fiori App &amp;quot;Manage Supplier Line Items&amp;quot; (ID: F0712)" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351975i230A6220E18B09E6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="image0021.png" alt="Fiori App &amp;quot;Manage Supplier Line Items&amp;quot; (ID: F0712)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Fiori App "Manage Supplier Line Items" (ID: F0712)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ID: F0712 - AdaptUI active" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352291iDC2B96EB203EE797/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="2025-12-15_19-28-15.png" alt="ID: F0712 - AdaptUI active" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;ID: F0712 - AdaptUI active&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depending on whether AdaptUI is active or not, please follow the corresponding instructions explained in this blog post.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before proceeding, ensure you have a workbench request created.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1699209958"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AdaptUI active - step-by-step instruction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 1: &lt;STRONG&gt;Login&lt;/STRONG&gt; to Fiori Launchpad development system.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 2: &lt;STRONG&gt;Open Fiori App&lt;/STRONG&gt;, then click&amp;nbsp;on your user icon in the top-left corner and select &lt;STRONG&gt;"Adapt UI"&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AdaptUI active - Step 2" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352277i477FD986AF045CA4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-15 185848.png" alt="AdaptUI active - Step 2" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AdaptUI active - Step 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 3:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;In the newly visible toolbar, navigate to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Navigation"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;tab.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 4:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define selection criteria&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for each field you wish to include in the variant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AdaptUI activ - Step 3 and 4" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352278i3C8E122F1B21457D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-15 190139.png" alt="AdaptUI activ - Step 3 and 4" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AdaptUI activ - Step 3 and 4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 5:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Return to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"UI Adaptation"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;tab.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 6:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Click the arrow next to&amp;nbsp;"Standard"&amp;nbsp;and select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Save View As"&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 7:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activate &lt;/STRONG&gt;the &lt;STRONG&gt;new version&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;by clicking the &lt;STRONG&gt;wand icon&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 8:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add &lt;/STRONG&gt;the variant&lt;STRONG&gt; to the workbench request&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;by selecting the &lt;STRONG&gt;truck icon&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 9: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exit &lt;/STRONG&gt;Adapt UI&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;release the workbench request&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AdaptUI active - Step 5 to 9" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352279i9F7CF35CE061BCA9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-15 190509.png" alt="AdaptUI active - Step 5 to 9" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AdaptUI active - Step 5 to 9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can use the same instruction for layouts in UI5 Apps where AdaptUI is active.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1502696453"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AdaptUI not active - step-by-step instruction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Instruction reference : &lt;STRONG&gt;Note &lt;A title="Note 3196205" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3196205/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3196205&lt;/A&gt; - How to migrate the variants/views of UI5 apps from one system to the other system&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Before you start make sure you have a workbench request created.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351311iB3B80B8A99518CE8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_0-1765475535114.png" alt="How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 1:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Login&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the Fiori Launchpad development system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 2:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt; the &lt;STRONG&gt;variant &lt;/STRONG&gt;and &lt;STRONG&gt;save &lt;/STRONG&gt;it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 3:&amp;nbsp;Execute program&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;/UIF/MIGRATE_FES_PERSO&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;via transaction&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SE38&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Enter the user that was used to create the variant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AdaptUI not active - Step 3" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352288i4F73961BEB1FADC8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="AdaptUI not active - Step 3" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AdaptUI not active - Step 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 4:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deselect&lt;/STRONG&gt; the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Test mode"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;option and assign a workbench request. Run the program (&lt;STRONG&gt;F8&lt;/STRONG&gt;) and &lt;STRONG&gt;release&lt;/STRONG&gt; the &lt;STRONG&gt;workbench&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;request&lt;/STRONG&gt; afterward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AdaptUI not active - Step 4" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351929i2C31B85545B8CE86/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_6-1765784642037.png" alt="AdaptUI not active - Step 4" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AdaptUI not active - Step 4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next and last part we will focus on&amp;nbsp;Web Dynpro Apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blog Series "How to transport variants and bookmarks in SAP Fiori Launchpad"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Part 1 - Introduction" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-1/ba-p/14288990" target="_blank"&gt;Part 1 - Introduction&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Part 2 - UI5 Fiori Apps&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Part 3 - Web Dynpro Fiori Apps" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-3-web/ba-p/14290212" target="_blank"&gt;Part 3 - Web Dynpro Fiori Apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy learning! Read you in the next part.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-2-ui5/ba-p/14289008"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T19:36:15.608000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-3-web/ba-p/14290212</id>
    <title>How to transport variants and bookmarks in SAP Fiori Launchpad | Part 3 - Web Dynpro Fiori Apps</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T19:41:01.962000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VictoriaEnzmann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1416159</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766640744" id="toc-hId-1767298093"&gt;How to transport in Web Dynpro Fiori Apps&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the final blog post in the series "How to transport variants and bookmarks in SAP Fiori Launchpad."&amp;nbsp;In this concluding part, we'll focus on the last segment of the process - Web Dynpro Apps. Here, it is essential to distinguish between the transportation of&amp;nbsp;variants&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;bookmarks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This procedure for variants is based on&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note &lt;A title="Note 3386445" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3386445" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3386445&lt;/A&gt; - FPM_SEARCH_UIBB&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and outlines the steps for transporting saved variants in WebDynpro applications.&lt;BR /&gt;The instruction for bookmarks is based on &lt;STRONG&gt;Note &lt;A title="Note 3336542" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3336542" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3336542&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- BICS Data Grid: Transport of Bookmarks&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352252i166AF8D1F8C155C1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_0-1765819064511.png" alt="How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;How to transport variants and bookmarks - Overview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before proceeding, ensure that a transport request has been created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1699209958" id="toc-hId-1699867307"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transport of variants - s&lt;/STRONG&gt;tep-by-step instruction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 1:&lt;STRONG&gt; Login &lt;/STRONG&gt;to the Fiori Launchpad development system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 2:&lt;STRONG&gt; Create a variant&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;(in this scenario&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;"&lt;/SPAN&gt;Asset History Sheet" Fiori App is used).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Transport of variants - Step 2" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352281i7BDB6C8B384AEEF0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-15 190915.png" alt="Transport of variants - Step 2" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transport of variants - Step 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 3: &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;the variant as public.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Transport of variants - Step 3" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352282iBBC5E35BE87AFD37/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-15 191013.png" alt="Transport of variants - Step 3" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transport of variants - Step 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 4: &lt;STRONG&gt;Run&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;program&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;FPM_SEARCH_TRANSPORT_VIEWS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in transaction&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SE38&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Select the &lt;STRONG&gt;configuration ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;of the variant and execute (&lt;STRONG&gt;F8&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Transport of variants - Step 4" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351945i7388FB20F7298B78/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="image001.png" alt="Transport of variants - Step 4" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transport of variants - Step 4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 5: Each line represents a variant. Select the relevant entries and add them to the transport request by clicking the truck icon. Once all variants are added,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;release the transport&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Transport of variants - Step 5" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351946iB2454DFC1D08A399/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="image002.png" alt="Transport of variants - Step 5" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transport of variants - Step 5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 6: &lt;STRONG&gt;Login &lt;/STRONG&gt;to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;test system&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(or the target system where the variants should be imported).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 7: &lt;STRONG&gt;Execute&lt;/STRONG&gt; program&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;FPM_SEARCH_IMPORT_SSEARCH&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SE38&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Note:&amp;nbsp;This import must be performed in&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;each client&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Transport of variants - Step 7" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351950i595C331BB896FA15/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="image003.png" alt="Transport of variants - Step 7" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transport of variants - Step 7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 8: Execute &lt;STRONG&gt;test run&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;to verify the number of variants to be imported.&amp;nbsp;Execute&lt;STRONG&gt; in production mode&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to complete the import.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1699209958" id="toc-hId-1503353802"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transport of bookmarks - s&lt;/STRONG&gt;tep-by-step instruction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 1: &lt;STRONG&gt;Login&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the Fiori Launchpad development system&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(&lt;SPAN&gt;in this scenario the user is called VARIANT&lt;/SPAN&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 2: &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;bookmark&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and save it as&amp;nbsp;public. Note: &lt;SPAN&gt;To create a bookmark, the system must contain data - at least one posting. Without data, you are not able to add or rearrange columns and rows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 3: &lt;STRONG&gt;Run&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;program&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FPM_BICS_TRANSPORT_BOOKMARKS &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;in&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; SE38&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Transport of bookmarks - Step 3" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352285i8A1EA58AD8939B23/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="2025-12-15_19-15-48.png" alt="Transport of bookmarks - Step 3" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transport of bookmarks - Step 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 4: Enter or &lt;STRONG&gt;select&lt;/STRONG&gt; your &lt;STRONG&gt;query&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Note: How to find the related query? Open the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Fiori App Library" href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/index.html#" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fiori App Library&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and search for your corresponding Fiori App. Then click on tab "Implementation Information" and open the "Configuration" section.&amp;nbsp; Scroll down to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Bsa Query.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Transport of bookmarks - Step 4" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351938iFBA1C70A6EA6B784/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictoriaEnzmann_0-1765786678347.png" alt="Transport of bookmarks - Step 4" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transport of bookmarks - Step 4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 5:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Execute&lt;/STRONG&gt; the program (&lt;STRONG&gt;F8&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Select &lt;/STRONG&gt;the &lt;STRONG&gt;bookmark&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;from the list and &lt;STRONG&gt;add &lt;/STRONG&gt;it &lt;STRONG&gt;to&lt;/STRONG&gt; a&lt;STRONG&gt; transport request&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;by clicking the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;truck icon&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Transport of bookmarks- Step 5" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352284iD33D636719D6A23F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="2025-12-15_19-13-55.png" alt="Transport of bookmarks- Step 5" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transport of bookmarks- Step 5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 6: &lt;STRONG&gt;Login to the target system&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;where the bookmark should be imported.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 7: Execute import report: run &lt;STRONG&gt;SE38&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and execute&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FPM_BICS_IMPORT_BOOKMARKS&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Deselect test run&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and execute the program.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Transport of bookmarks - Step 7" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352286i8259B1CFD51CC17A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="2025-12-15_19-16-47.png" alt="Transport of bookmarks - Step 7" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transport of bookmarks - Step 7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blog Series "How to transport variants and bookmarks in SAP Fiori Launchpad"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Part 1 - Introduction" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-1/ba-p/14288990" target="_blank"&gt;Part 1 - Introduction&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Part 2 - UI5 Fiori Apps" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-2-ui5/ba-p/14289008" target="_blank"&gt;Part 2 - UI5 Fiori Apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Part 3 - Web Dynpro Fiori Apps&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy learning!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-transport-variants-and-bookmarks-in-sap-fiori-launchpad-part-3-web/ba-p/14290212"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T19:41:01.962000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/step-by-step-with-the-sap-cloud-platform-sdk-for-android-part-1/bc-p/14290858#M187162</id>
    <title>Re: Step by Step with the SAP Cloud Platform SDK for Android -- Part 1</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T19:46:30.929000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rmz01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/725901</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Hi I'm following this tutorial&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/sdk-android-wizard-app.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/sdk-android-wizard-app.html&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;but the version mentioned is not working for me, after installling&amp;nbsp;Android Studio Koala Feature Drop 2024.1.2 Patch 1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;and BTP SDK for Andriod 25.11.0 i'm not able to see option New Btp Andriod App in Andriod Studio.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;But After installing the latest Andriod Studio Version i was able to see the option but once I enter the details of my trial account and clicking next i get the same screen and "Next" button is disabled. Please help&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Andriod Studio Version:&amp;nbsp;Android Studio Otter 2 Feature Drop | 2025.2.2&lt;BR /&gt;BTP SDK for Andrion Version: 25.11.0&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rmz01_0-1765824259538.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352293iB1FB2EB26DF655F2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="rmz01_0-1765824259538.png" alt="rmz01_0-1765824259538.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/step-by-step-with-the-sap-cloud-platform-sdk-for-android-part-1/bc-p/14290858#M187162"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T19:46:30.929000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-integrate-and-monitor-sap-rise-with-cloud-alm/qaa-p/14290860#M4933579</id>
    <title>Re: How to integrate and monitor SAP RISE with Cloud ALM</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T19:57:56.824000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Damcho</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1660581</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Dear Paul,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-integrate-and-monitor-sap-rise-with-cloud-alm/qaa-p/14290860#M4933579"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T19:57:56.824000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-rename-a-sap-bi-4-3-universe-without-losing-its-version-continue/qaq-p/14290861</id>
    <title>How to rename a SAP BI 4.3 universe without losing its version (continue incrementing the version)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T20:00:07.854000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Boubafia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2270802</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bonjour,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Je sollicite votre aide sur le sujet de renommage d'un univers dans SAP BO 4.3.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;En fait, j'ai renommé l'univers sous plusieurs manière (IDT, CMC) mais au niveau WEBI rien ne change, j'ai toujours l'ancien nom de l'univers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Comment renommé un univers et faire apparaitre le nouveau nom dans webi sans perdre le versionning c'est à dire que la&amp;nbsp; version ne repart pas 1. je suis actuellement à v25.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Merci pour votre aide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;**********************************************************English**************************************&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;BR /&gt;I'm requesting your help with renaming a universe in SAP BO 4.3.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've renamed the universe in several ways (IDT, CMC), but nothing changes in Web Intelligence; I still see the old universe name.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How can I rename a universe and have the new name appear in Web Intelligence without losing versioning? I don't want the version to revert to version 1. I'm currently on version 25.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thx for your help&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-rename-a-sap-bi-4-3-universe-without-losing-its-version-continue/qaq-p/14290861"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T20:00:07.854000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-integrate-and-monitor-sap-rise-with-cloud-alm/qaa-p/14290862#M4933581</id>
    <title>Re: How to integrate and monitor SAP RISE with Cloud ALM</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T20:04:57.856000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Damcho</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1660581</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Paul,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for the support, your post really help me in troubleshooting the issue that I have encounter. In addition, after the changes as per you suggestion, I did get followup issues with regards to the SSL certificate. By following the&amp;nbsp; SAP notes -&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;3338197 - Error SSL handshake SSSLERR_PEER_CERT_UNTRUSTED (-102) during setup on /SDF/ALM_SETUP for ALM setup I was able to add SSL certificate in the SAP RISE system and was able to successfully connect RISE system to SAP Cloud ALM for monitoring.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-integrate-and-monitor-sap-rise-with-cloud-alm/qaa-p/14290862#M4933581"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T20:04:57.856000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14290863#M14626</id>
    <title>Re: Reimagining Certification for the Way We Work Today</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T20:06:54.432000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>iliano</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/158737</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10529" target="_blank"&gt;@DianaRoesner&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I've just finished the P_BTPA exam and received a congratulations message with a score of 80%. However, when I check the My Certification site, the exam is shown as failed. Here's the case ID&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;5000266797. I'd appreciate any help, thank you!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14290863#M14626"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T20:06:54.432000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14290865#M14627</id>
    <title>Re: Reimagining Certification for the Way We Work Today</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T20:09:08.508000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>iliano</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/158737</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10529"&gt;@DianaRoesner&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I've just finished the P_BTPA exam and received a congratulations message with a score of 80%. However, when I check the My Certification site, the exam is shown as failed. Here's the case ID&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5000266797. I'd appreciate any help, thank you!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;PS: oops the message has duplicated. Can't find any button to delete it.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14290865#M14627"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T20:09:08.508000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-sales-cloud-v2-opportunity-update-extension-fields-via-sap-build-app/qaa-p/14290867#M62400</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Sales Cloud V2 Opportunity Update Extension Field...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T20:16:18.627000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1982542"&gt;@MeetSAP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;you must use PATCH method with IfMatch tag to get any updates into extension fields&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;use this blog for reference...&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-sales-amp-service-cloud-v2-esm-apis-etag-header-for-client-side-http/ba-p/14095058" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-sales-amp-service-cloud-v2-esm-apis-etag-header-for-client-side-http/ba-p/14095058&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-sales-cloud-v2-opportunity-update-extension-fields-via-sap-build-app/qaa-p/14290867#M62400"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T20:16:18.627000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-blog-posts/abap-rap-download-any-kind-of-file-from-rap-application-object-page/ba-p/14290667</id>
    <title>ABAP RAP - Download any kind of file from RAP application object page</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T20:33:03.556000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis-Arnaud</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15467</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;To the best of my knowledge, there is no built-in solution in RAP applications to add a 'Download' action on the object page without resorting to custom UI5 JavaScript coding.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This can be very useful when you need to download a file that is generated dynamically (such as an Adobe form, SmartForm, or any type of flat file). The ABAP RAP framework only provides upload/download functionality for objects stored in database tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, I aim to present a simple workaround that enables adding a download button which triggers custom code to generate the file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The concept is straightforward: create a virtual element (in fact, three virtual elements) in the consumption view and apply the appropriate file management annotations. In my example, I wanted to enable downloading a JSON file (hence the naming), but as mentioned earlier, this approach works for any type of file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ObjectModel.virtualElementCalculatedBy: 'ABAP:ZCL_VIRTUAL_CALC'
@Semantics.largeObject: { fileName: 'jsonFileName', mimeType: 'jsonMimeType', contentDispositionPreference: #ATTACHMENT }
virtual jsonOutputFile: abap.rawstring(0),

@Semantics.mimeType: true
@ObjectModel.virtualElementCalculatedBy: 'ABAP:ZCL_VIRTUAL_CALC'
virtual jsonMimeType: abap.char(128),

@ObjectModel.virtualElementCalculatedBy: 'ABAP:ZCL_VIRTUAL_CALC'
virtual jsonFileName: abap.char(128),&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the ABAP class responsible for virtual element calculation, you simply retrieve the &lt;CODE&gt;xstring&lt;/CODE&gt; of your file and set its name and type. In my example, we chose to call a function from our behavior definition, but other approaches are possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that I removed the &amp;lt;&amp;gt; of field symbols (conflict with the sap community blog post html, don't know why).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;CLASS zcl_virtual_calc DEFINITION
  PUBLIC
  FINAL
  CREATE PUBLIC .

  PUBLIC SECTION.
    INTERFACES if_sadl_exit .
    INTERFACES if_sadl_exit_calc_element_read .
  PROTECTED SECTION.
  PRIVATE SECTION.
ENDCLASS.

CLASS zcl_virtual_calc IMPLEMENTATION.

  METHOD if_sadl_exit_calc_element_read~calculate.

    IF it_requested_calc_elements IS INITIAL.
      "Method was called but no virtual elements have been requested -&amp;gt; skip calculation
      RETURN.
    ENDIF.

    LOOP AT it_requested_calc_elements REFERENCE INTO DATA(requested_element).

      LOOP AT it_original_data ASSIGNING FIELD-SYMBOL(original_entity).

        "Get changing line for calculation result
        READ TABLE ct_calculated_data ASSIGNING FIELD-SYMBOL(calculated_data) INDEX sy-tabix.
        IF sy-subrc &amp;lt;&amp;gt; 0.
          CONTINUE.
        ENDIF.

        DATA(original) = CORRESPONDING zc_myobjectconsumptionview( original_entity ).

        CASE requested_element-&amp;gt;*.

          WHEN 'JSONMIMETYPE'.
            ASSIGN COMPONENT requested_element-&amp;gt;* OF STRUCTURE calculated_data TO FIELD-SYMBOL(field_value).
            IF field_value IS ASSIGNED.
              field_value = |application/json|.
            ENDIF.

          WHEN 'JSONFILENAME'.
            ASSIGN COMPONENT requested_element-&amp;gt;* OF STRUCTURE calculated_data TO field_value.
            IF field_value IS ASSIGNED.
              field_value = |file name_{ original-period }.json|.
            ENDIF.

          WHEN 'JSONOUTPUTFILE'.
            ASSIGN COMPONENT requested_element-&amp;gt;* OF STRUCTURE calculated_data TO field_value.
            IF field_value IS ASSIGNED.

              READ ENTITIES OF zr_myobjectbehviour
                ENTITY Header
                  EXECUTE exportjsonfilefunction
                  FROM VALUE #( ( %key-uuidkey = original-uuidkey ) )
                RESULT FINAL(result)
                FAILED FINAL(failed)
                REPORTED FINAL(reported).

              READ TABLE result ASSIGNING FIELD-SYMBOL(field_value) INDEX 1.
              IF sy-subrc = 0.
                field_value = -%param-file_content. "Should be xstring !
              ENDIF.
            ENDIF.

          WHEN OTHERS.
            CONTINUE.

        ENDCASE.

      ENDLOOP.

      UNASSIGN .

    ENDLOOP.

  ENDMETHOD.

  METHOD if_sadl_exit_calc_element_read~get_calculation_info.

    LOOP AT it_requested_calc_elements REFERENCE INTO DATA(requested_element).

      CASE requested_element-&amp;gt;*.

        WHEN 'JSONOUTPUTFILE' OR 'JSONMIMETYPE' OR 'JSONFILENAME'.
          INSERT |PERIOD| INTO TABLE et_requested_orig_elements.

        WHEN OTHERS.
          CONTINUE.

      ENDCASE.

    ENDLOOP.

  ENDMETHOD.

ENDCLASS.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, you need to add the file field to your object page using the appropriate annotations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;.identification: [ { position: 50 } ]
@UI.fieldGroup: [ { qualifier: 'GeneralInformations', position: 50 } ]
@EndUserText.label: 'JSON file'
jsonOutputFile;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result is a download link available directly on the object page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="LouisArnaud_0-1765813827798.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352209i3EF8B4EAB293665D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="LouisArnaud_0-1765813827798.png" alt="LouisArnaud_0-1765813827798.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-blog-posts/abap-rap-download-any-kind-of-file-from-rap-application-object-page/ba-p/14290667"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T20:33:03.556000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/returning-a-boolean-from-an-u212-ufl-does-not-work-for-me/qaq-p/14290875</id>
    <title>Returning a boolean from an u212-ufl does not work for me</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T20:38:23.727000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndersG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/334722</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am using the u212samp.* sample project and I am wondering how to return a boolean?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If I name it like this:&amp;nbsp;{L"Number MyFn (String, Date)", MyFn, NULL, NULL, FALSE}, and return the value as&amp;nbsp;ParamBlock-&amp;gt;ReturnValue.ReturnNumber = var * CRNumberScalingFactor, then it works, but not&amp;nbsp;{L"Boolean MyFn (String, Date)", MyFn, NULL, NULL, FALSE} and return in&amp;nbsp;ParamBlock-&amp;gt;ReturnValue.ReturnBoolean = var then it always say false no matte what I put in var. An UFBoolean appears to be an unsigned, 2-byte int, so what am I doing wrong?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/returning-a-boolean-from-an-u212-ufl-does-not-work-for-me/qaq-p/14290875"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T20:38:23.727000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-2025-fully-activated-appliance-known-issues/bc-p/14290879#M187163</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S/4HANA 2025 Fully-Activated Appliance: Known Issues</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T20:45:18.311000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tsvetinka_gaydazhieva</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/610260</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Sergio,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Actually &lt;EM&gt;SAP S/4HANA 2025 Fully-Activated Appliance&lt;/EM&gt; is available under&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://cal.sap.com/catalog#/applianceTemplates/1a264e32-a314-4578-bad7-83acc155d28b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://cal.sap.com/catalog#/applianceTemplates/1a264e32-a314-4578-bad7-83acc155d28b&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;with &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Release Date&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Dec 15, 2025.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tsvetinka&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-2025-fully-activated-appliance-known-issues/bc-p/14290879#M187163"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T20:45:18.311000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-advanced-financial-closing-definition-of-parameters/qaa-p/14290883#M256984</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Advanced Financial Closing - definition of Parame...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T20:48:53.798000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_kunze</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/193409</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Christian, your understanding is correct. Additional parameters is only for ABAP programs. Regards Thomas</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-advanced-financial-closing-definition-of-parameters/qaa-p/14290883#M256984"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T20:48:53.798000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/s-alr-87012284-plan-version-hard-currency-comparison-period-issue/qaq-p/14290895</id>
    <title>S_ALR_87012284 Plan version Hard currency comparison period issue</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T21:02:18.705000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vijay_Adwani93</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2155329</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Post stack upgrade of S/4 Hana 2023, we noticed that there is a new field of plan version to be selected to execute the report. If we do not enter the plan version (0), hard currency (40) values do not display for reporting as well as comparison period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If we enter Plan version as 0, hard currency values display for reporting period but not for the comparison period. Can anyone share valuable insights&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAPS/4HANA #FIN (Finance)&amp;nbsp;#Accounting and Financial Close&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1569761"&gt;@sapcommunity1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/s-alr-87012284-plan-version-hard-currency-comparison-period-issue/qaq-p/14290895"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T21:02:18.705000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-blog-posts/building-a-real-rap-application-step-by-step-vlog-series-introduction/ba-p/14290896</id>
    <title>Building a Real RAP Application Step by Step — Vlog Series Introduction</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T21:13:47.721000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kinsbrunner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124164</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1638221392"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This vlog series aims to demonstrate how to build a real-life ABAP RAP application, following a practical, incremental, and production-oriented approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This series focuses on showcasing how a RAP application can be built incrementally from real functional requirements. The app is intentionally kept practical and educational, rather than exhaustive or fully hardened for production. Some edge cases or potential enhancements are intentionally not covered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The purpose of the vlog is to share knowledge, demonstrate real development workflows, and contribute to the SAP community, not to deliver a fully polished commercial-grade application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To allow anyone to follow the vlog series, I will be using an SAP BTP Trial. This environment carries several limitations compared to a customer system, but it is perfectly sufficient for demonstrating the concepts and end-to-end implementation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of showing a pre-built demo or isolated RAP examples, the series walks through the development process from scratch, implementing the application one requirement at a time, exactly as it would be done in an actual ABAP Cloud project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each episode focuses on a small, well-defined set of user stories, keeping the learning process smooth and allowing you to see how the application grows after every step. The structure ensures the app is testable from the very beginning, and every enhancement is immediately visible in the UI preview.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to understand RAP not just in theory but in practice, including determinations, validations, feature control, actions, side effects, completeness checks, semantic keys, and UI configuration, this series is for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1441707887"&gt;What are we going to build?&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ll be developing an internal equipment request application for a consulting firm.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Employees can request items kept in internal stock (laptops, monitors, headsets, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each request follows a simple lifecycle:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Not Prepared / In Preparation / Delivered / &lt;EM&gt;(later also Cancelled)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each request includes header data (requester, deadline, priority, status) and one or more items referencing products from a customizing table of available materials.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The scenario is intentionally simple but rich enough to cover the most important RAP concepts: CDS data modeling, RAP behavior definitions in managed scenarios, Semantic keys, Determinations &amp;amp; validations, UI annotations, Feature control, Prechecks, Popup actions, Value helps, Inline editing, Integration with customizing tables, ABAP Cloud–compliant development practices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1245194382"&gt;How the Vlog is structured&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The application is built based on a list of functional requirements expressed as user stories. These stories are implemented in the same order they would typically be addressed in a real project. The format of each episode is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Short and focused&lt;/STRONG&gt; (usually covering 1-3 user stories)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Incremental&lt;/STRONG&gt; (the app evolves visibly every episode)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical&lt;/STRONG&gt; (every change is immediately testable)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aligned with ABAP Cloud guidelines&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Designed for long-term learning and reference&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're starting with RAP or expanding your expertise, this series aims to provide a clear, realistic, and reusable learning path.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1048680877"&gt;Full requirement backlog (User Stories)&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is the collection of user stories implemented throughout the series, listed in almost the exact order used for development:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-01: Basic request object:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As an employee, I want to create internal equipment requests so that I can receive the products I need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-02: Search and Filter capabilities:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want to search requests using structured filters so that I can quickly locate relevant orders. I need to be able to search through the following criteria:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;free search field,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;by Requester (with search help),&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;by Priority (drop-down )&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;by Status (drop-down with multiple selections).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-03: Sequential External ID and semantic key:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As the system, I want to assign each request a sequential external number so that users can reference meaningful IDs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-04: Mandatory fields:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want the system to require Requester Name and Deadline Date so that requests are always complete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-05: Deadline validation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As the system, I want to validate that the deadline date is at least one day in the future so that operations can prepare on time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-06: Automatic priority determination:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As the system, I want priority to be set based on deadline so that urgent requests receive proper attention (High: &amp;lt; 3 days, Medium: &amp;lt;7 days, otherwise, Low).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-07: Status icons:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want statuses displayed with colored icons so that I can understand them at a glance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-08: Cancel status restrictions:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want to search for cancelled requests but not manually set status as “Cancelled” so that lifecycle rules are respected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-09: Default status:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As the system, I want new requests to default to “In Preparation” so that the lifecycle begins correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-10: Status editability rules:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want status to be editable only after creation so that inconsistencies are avoided.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-11: Cancel action:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want to cancel one or more requests from the list so that I can invalidate unnecessary requests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-12: Cancellation popup:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want to cancel and justify cancellations through a popup so that the system enforces to have reasons registered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-13: Cancel reason rules:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want “Cancellation Reason” to be editable only when status is “Cancelled” so that it appears available only when relevant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-13b:&lt;/STRONG&gt; changing dynamic field hiding approach from CDS into virtual element.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-14: No editing after cancellation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As the system, I want cancelled requests to become read-only so that historical data is kept intact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-15: Product catalog restriction:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want to select products only from internal stock so that I request only available items. Internal stock is customized through a customizing table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-16: Product value help:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want a value help showing only available products so that selection is efficient.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-17: Unique product per request:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a system, I want to prevent duplicate products within a request so that items remain consistent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-18: Item creation via popup:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a user, I want to create items in a popup and edit them inline so that maintenance is fast and intuitive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-19: Make popup fields mandatory:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a system, I want to ensure that the data entered through the Product popup is complete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;US-20: Make item fields mandatory:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a system, I want to ensure that the data entered through the Product object page is complete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-852167372"&gt;Episode Roadmap&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each episode implements a specific subset of user stories.&amp;nbsp;Episodes are planned to be released on a &lt;STRONG&gt;weekly basis (approx.)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Episode 1 will be released shortly, before end of year!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="723px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Project introduction + Data model basics&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;02&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Service exposure + First UI (read-only) preview&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-01&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;03&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Basic behavior + Search fields (Part 1): Free text + Requester&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-02 (Requester + Free text)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;04&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Search fields (Part 2): Status &amp;amp; Priority&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-02 (Status + Priority)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;05&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Semantic key &amp;amp; Sequential numbering&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-03&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;06&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Mandatory fields + Deadline validation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-04 + US-05&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;07&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Automatic Priority determination + Status icons &amp;amp; visual enhancements&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-06 + US-07&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;08&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Status behavior rules&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-08 + US-09 + US-10&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;09&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Cancel feature (Part 1)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-11 + US-12&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;10&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Cancel feature (Part 2)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-13 + US-13b + US-14&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;11&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Item popup creation &amp;amp; inline editing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-18 + US-19&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;12&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Product customizing + availability&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-15 + US-16&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="40px"&gt;13&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="473.25px"&gt;Item consistency: prevent duplicates&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="208.75px"&gt;US-17&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;!--     notionvc: 901e9484-b00c-44be-842e-77412ea38c89     --&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If this introduction was helpful, a like or follow would be appreciated as it helps others in the community find the series.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-blog-posts/building-a-real-rap-application-step-by-step-vlog-series-introduction/ba-p/14290896"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T21:13:47.721000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
