<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-11-13T15:59:02.537144+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/curitiba-blog-posts/sitcwb2025-como-criar-apps-nativos-para-android-usando-sapui5/ba-p/14268056</id>
    <title>#SITCWB2025 🎤 Como criar apps nativos para Android usando SAPUI5</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T13:52:02.229000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LuizSouza_cwb</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1442973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="5.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340096i0853AA391FF132F2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.jpg" alt="5.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737003536" id="toc-hId-1764764064"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Palestrante&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nome:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Cristiano Santos&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cargo:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Educador e Produtor de Conteúdos Digitais On Line&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Link da Palestra:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/rO-8qPx-BMI?si=JtDU-Fws989DaAqx" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/live/rO-8qPx-BMI?si=JtDU-Fws989DaAqx&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resumo da Palestra&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nesta sessão, você vai explorar como utilizar o framework SAPUI5 para desenvolver &lt;STRONG&gt;aplicativos Android nativos&lt;/STRONG&gt; eficientes e integrados no ambiente corporativo. A proposta é mostrar como a tecnologia facilita:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Desenvolvimento com base em UI/UX bem estruturado, utilizando componentes SAPUI5 adaptados para mobile.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integração com recursos nativos do dispositivo Android, como câmera, armazenamento, notificações — ampliando o alcance dos aplicativos empresariais.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Publicação e distribuição na Google Play Store para usuários finais, mantendo governança, segurança e compatibilidade.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exemplos práticos ou boas práticas com SAPUI5 que ajudam a acelerar o desenvolvimento, reduzir retrabalho e tornar o app corporativo escalável.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Por que você deve assistir?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Se você trabalha com desenvolvimento mobile, TI corporativa, automação ou plataformas SAP, essa palestra traz insights valiosos para:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Elevar o nível técnico da equipe de desenvolvimento mobile.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduzir o tempo de entrega de apps, reutilizando conhecimento UI5 no contexto Android.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrar suas soluções SAP com mobilidade de forma mais estratégica.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Seja você dev SAPUI5, arquiteto mobile ou gestor de apps corporativos — não perca!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Patrocinadores:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sports_medal:"&gt;🏅&lt;/span&gt;OURO: CHpro Solutions | CVA&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":3rd_place_medal:"&gt;🥉&lt;/span&gt;BRONZE: Lupus Consulting | FioriNET - Programação SAP ABAP Cloud S/4HANA Fiori UI5 | Aline ExplicaSAP&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":handshake:"&gt;🤝&lt;/span&gt;Apoio: Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Paraná&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":mobile_phone_with_arrow:"&gt;📲&lt;/span&gt;Quer receber as novidades em primeira mão. Entre no nosso grupo do WhatsApp: &lt;A href="https://lnkd.in/eYyGuvkc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://lnkd.in/eYyGuvkc&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":busts_in_silhouette:"&gt;👥&lt;/span&gt;Organização: Simone Azevedo | Tiago Felipe | Luiz Carlos de Souza | Adriano Marques de Oliveira | Marssel Vilaça&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SITCWB2025&lt;BR /&gt;#SAPCommunity&lt;BR /&gt;#SAPCommunityCWB&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/curitiba-blog-posts/sitcwb2025-como-criar-apps-nativos-para-android-usando-sapui5/ba-p/14268056"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T13:52:02.229000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/tricentis-test-automation-for-sap-integrated-with-sap-cloud-alm/bc-p/14268057#M176334</id>
    <title>Re: Tricentis Test Automation for SAP integrated with SAP Cloud ALM</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T13:52:53.751000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HemantVaswani6</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/147458</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149312"&gt;@Delia_Barabasy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Good Day to you,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;is there a way to integrate TTA on-prem with Cloud ALM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pl share if any blog on this this subject.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;will this be different in steps, from the one mentioned in the above blog of your's.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the information in this post.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/tricentis-test-automation-for-sap-integrated-with-sap-cloud-alm/bc-p/14268057#M176334"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T13:52:53.751000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/managers-approval-required-for-reserving-a-seat/qaa-p/14268058#M49325</id>
    <title>Re: Managers approval required for Reserving a seat</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T13:53:57.624000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Deepali</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/51987</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Daniel</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/managers-approval-required-for-reserving-a-seat/qaa-p/14268058#M49325"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T13:53:57.624000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-events/kickoff-da-comunidade-sap-bh-1%C2%BA-lote/ec-p/14268059#M6</id>
    <title>Re: Kickoff da Comunidade SAP BH (1º LOTE)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T13:55:16.128000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AMNeto</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1713891</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Poderemos participar remotamente?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/belo-horizonte-events/kickoff-da-comunidade-sap-bh-1%C2%BA-lote/ec-p/14268059#M6"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T13:55:16.128000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/need-to-add-a-custom-field-into-import-supplier-invoices/qaa-p/14268060#M4231400</id>
    <title>Re: Need To Add a Custom Field into Import Supplier Invoices</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T13:55:33.446000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BrittoL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2172835</uri>
    </author>
    <content>what is this? explain briefly.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/need-to-add-a-custom-field-into-import-supplier-invoices/qaa-p/14268060#M4231400"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T13:55:33.446000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/the-field-quot-xxxx-quot-does-not-have-a-corresponding-field-in-the-work/m-p/14268062#M199</id>
    <title>Re: The field "XXXX" does not have a corresponding field in the work area.</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T13:55:42.380000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>oliver_am</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/423937</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Well, its actually in the workarea:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="oliver_am_1-1763038609751.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340106iB0635DF1004764B5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="oliver_am_1-1763038609751.png" alt="oliver_am_1-1763038609751.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;EDIT: Ok, the problem was duplicates in the field list...&amp;nbsp; dont know who created this program but put a lot of fields and duplicates... sorry.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="oliver_am_2-1763039059556.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340109i3126AD2692A2BED8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="oliver_am_2-1763039059556.png" alt="oliver_am_2-1763039059556.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/the-field-quot-xxxx-quot-does-not-have-a-corresponding-field-in-the-work/m-p/14268062#M199"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T13:55:42.380000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-connect-sap-cloud-alm-and-a-test-automation-tool/bc-p/14268063#M186312</id>
    <title>Re: How to connect SAP Cloud ALM and a Test Automation Tool</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T13:56:26.847000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HemantVaswani6</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/147458</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/164863"&gt;@XavierPicquart&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Good Day to you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does this solution work for on-prem TTA being integrated with SAP Cloud ALM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pl share informantion in this regard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the information in above post.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-connect-sap-cloud-alm-and-a-test-automation-tool/bc-p/14268063#M186312"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T13:56:26.847000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/leveraging-the-s-4hana-test-automation-tool-with-sap-cloud-alm/bc-p/14268065#M186313</id>
    <title>Re: Leveraging the S/4HANA Test Automation Tool with SAP Cloud ALM</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T13:58:34.931000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HemantVaswani6</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/147458</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1782536"&gt;@NandhiniRavisankar&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Good Day to you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How do you integrate Cloud ALM with on-prem TTA setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly share the blog or some documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the information in above post.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/leveraging-the-s-4hana-test-automation-tool-with-sap-cloud-alm/bc-p/14268065#M186313"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T13:58:34.931000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-prepare-for-sap-s-new-certification/ba-p/14268066</id>
    <title>How to Prepare for SAP’s New Certification</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:00:18.140000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SuyashVerma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1593598</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For years, SAP certification relied on multiple-choice questions and memorized answers. That approach no longer fits the realities of modern SAP work, where professionals configure systems, solve business problems, and increasingly collaborate with AI-driven tools. Simply recalling information isn’t enough.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new SAP certification model shifts the focus from “knowing SAP” to “doing SAP,” i.e., applying skills in real-world scenarios, navigating tools, and demonstrating practical competence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re planning to get certified soon, your preparation needs to evolve with it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764764095"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Changing and What It Means for Your Preparation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s new practical certification exams introduce a more authentic and performance-oriented approach to skill validation. Instead of testing whether you can recall a configuration detail, the new exams examine whether you can complete tasks, solve problems, and make decisions in situations that resemble real project environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;They use two primary formats: System-based assessment and Scenario-based assessment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;System-based assessment &lt;/STRONG&gt;is&amp;nbsp;where learners work inside a time-limited SAP system simulation. You are required to perform actual tasks, such as configuring components, building processes, developing artifacts, or resolving issues, just as you would in a project environment. The assessment measures your fluency in SAP tools, your ability to execute steps accurately, and your ability to apply best practices in a live system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario-based assessment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;places you in time-limited role-play situations with an AI avatar. In these scenarios, you must pitch SAP solutions, advise on architecture, justify design choices, respond to stakeholder concerns, and guide the conversation toward appropriate outcomes. Rather than executing system tasks, this format evaluates how you think, communicate, analyse requirements, and represent SAP’s capabilities in a business context.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each certification will use &lt;STRONG&gt;only one format&lt;/STRONG&gt;, either system-based or scenario-based, depending on the nature of the role being assessed. Technical roles emphasise hands-on execution, while consulting and architecture roles prioritise analytical and advisory depth. This creates a more precise and meaningful measurement of job readiness.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The exams are also now &lt;STRONG&gt;open-book&lt;/STRONG&gt;, allowing access to documentation, help portals, and AI-assisted guidance during the assessment. This change reflects how professionals actually work. They consult resources, verify information, test assumptions, and use intelligent tools like SAP Joule to support decision-making. The exam rewards the ability to locate, interpret, and apply information under realistic constraints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is rolling out this new model in phases. The first six certifications are already live and have received a strong response from the ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/get-certified/reimagining-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click this link to access the SAP Certifications featuring practical exams.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568250590"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Prepare for SAP's New Certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Train on SAP Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hands-on experience is now the most important part of certification readiness. Since the new exams rely heavily on real system usage or scenario execution, you must become comfortable navigating SAP environments directly. Spend time configuring components, building workflows, testing integrations, and troubleshooting issues in SAP BTP, &amp;nbsp;SAP Build, and other relevant tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Memorizing theory will not substitute for actual system familiarity, so create consistent practice sessions that mirror the tasks you expect to face in real projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adopt an Open-Book Learning Mindset&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because SAP’s new exams allow access to documentation and official resources, your success depends on how efficiently you can locate and apply information. Instead of trying to memorize every detail, shift your focus toward learning how SAP documentation is structured, where key topics are located, and how to interpret guidance quickly under time constraints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During preparation, challenge yourself to answer questions by navigating documentation rather than recalling facts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practise Scenario-Based Problem Solving&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new certification format rewards professionals who can think in end-to-end scenarios rather than isolated tasks. To build this skill, spend time working through full business situations that could appear in an exam.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine a client wants to automate approval workflows, integrate an external application, or modernize their analytics landscape. Break down how you would approach the requirement, which SAP tools you would use, what architecture makes sense, and what risks or trade-offs you would consider.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The more you practise this style of thinking, the more natural it becomes to articulate decisions and explain your reasoning during a scenario-based assessment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strengthen Your Architecture and Data Foundations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modern SAP work revolves around cloud services, data modeling, integration patterns, event-driven design, and automation. To prepare for the new certifications, make time to revisit these fundamentals. Understanding how components fit together will help you make informed decisions, whether you are configuring a system or advising a simulated stakeholder. This broader technical foundation also enables you to respond effectively during role-plays that require architectural justification or strategic recommendations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build a Continuous Learning Habit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The redesigned certification model encourages professionals to keep their skills active rather than rely on one-time exam success. As SAP continues to evolve its tools and expand its AI-driven capabilities, staying connected to the ecosystem, whether through hands-on practice, learning content, or experimentation with new features, will help you remain prepared for renewals and future certifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371737085"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What These Changes Mean for Your Career&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new certification format narrows the gap between being certified and being project-ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the assessments test actual capability, credentials earned under this model will carry greater weight with employers seeking professionals who can contribute immediately. It also shifts the ecosystem toward continuous learning, where staying certified means staying active, hands-on, and connected to SAP’s evolving technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The certifications also mark an important milestone in SAP’s broader commitment to equip 12 million people worldwide with AI-ready skills by 2030.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you approach your learning with the mindset of becoming truly project-ready rather than simply exam-ready, you will not only succeed in the new certification format but also build a stronger, more sustainable foundation for your SAP career.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The exam has evolved, and your preparation needs to evolve with it, too.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-prepare-for-sap-s-new-certification/ba-p/14268066"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:00:18.140000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/tricentis-test-automation-for-sap-cloud-alm-tta-for-cloud-alm/bc-p/14268071#M176335</id>
    <title>Re: Tricentis Test Automation for SAP Cloud ALM (TTA for Cloud ALM)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:05:59.319000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HemantVaswani6</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/147458</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149312"&gt;@Delia_Barabasy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Coming again to you for query on on-prem TTA integ with Cloud ALM as of today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;the above blog does mentions something about on-prem SAP systems, but not about on-prem TTA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the information in this blog too.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/tricentis-test-automation-for-sap-cloud-alm-tta-for-cloud-alm/bc-p/14268071#M176335"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:05:59.319000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/curitiba-blog-posts/sitcwb2025-sap-signavio-btp-automa%C3%A7%C3%A3o-inteligente-de-processos-do-insight-%C3%A0/ba-p/14268072</id>
    <title>#SITCWB2025 🎤 [SAP Signavio +BTP] Automação Inteligente de Processos: do insight à execução</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:06:23.422000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LuizSouza_cwb</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1442973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="10.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340108i83E7A2E78B0B7FD7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="10.jpg" alt="10.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nome:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;João Emilio&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cargo:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Especialista em Transformação de Negócios&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Link da Palestra:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/fh_-c7HHjRU?si=RslI8sWgkuK8vyqH" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/live/fh_-c7HHjRU?si=RslI8sWgkuK8vyqH&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resumo da palestra:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Nesta sessão, você vai explorar como combinar as poderosas soluções SAP Signavio e SAP BTP para levar a automação de processos de negócios para um novo nível — passando da &lt;STRONG&gt;descoberta de insights&lt;/STRONG&gt; à &lt;STRONG&gt;execução automatizada&lt;/STRONG&gt;. A palestra abordará:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Como usar o SAP Signavio para mapear, minerar e analisar processos empresariais, identificando gargalos, ineficiências e oportunidades de melhoria.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A integração com o SAP BTP para orquestrar automações de ponta a ponta, conectando dados, IA, workflows e sistemas SAP ou de terceiros.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Como transformar insights em ações concretas: definir prioridades, acionar automações, monitorar desempenho e ajustar continuamente — elevando a maturidade da automação dentro das operações.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exemplos práticos ou frameworks de como estruturar essa jornada de “insight → automação → valor”, com governança, visibilidade e resultados mensuráveis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Por que assistir?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Se você atua em processos de negócio, TI, automação, transformação digital ou em áreas funcionais que desejam otimizar eficiência e agilidade — essa palestra é para você.&lt;BR /&gt;Ela oferece:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Uma visão integrada de como identificar &lt;STRONG&gt;o que melhorar&lt;/STRONG&gt; (com Signavio) e &lt;STRONG&gt;como executar&lt;/STRONG&gt; (com BTP) de modo alinhado.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Insights úteis para estruturar iniciativas de automação que vão além de tarefas pontuais, rumo à automação de processo completo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Uma oportunidade de entender como tecnologias de ponta como IA, mineração de processos e automação de workflow se unem para gerar valor real.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Não perca! Assista à palestra e leve seu entendimento de automação para o próximo nível.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Compartilhe com sua equipe, colegas de TI, processos ou transformação digital — convide todos que querem fazer a automação funcionar de verdade!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Patrocinadores:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sports_medal:"&gt;🏅&lt;/span&gt;OURO: CHpro Solutions | CVA&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":3rd_place_medal:"&gt;🥉&lt;/span&gt;BRONZE: Lupus Consulting | FioriNET - Programação SAP ABAP Cloud S/4HANA Fiori UI5 | Aline ExplicaSAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":handshake:"&gt;🤝&lt;/span&gt;Apoio: Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Paraná&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":mobile_phone_with_arrow:"&gt;📲&lt;/span&gt;Quer receber as novidades em primeira mão. Entre no nosso grupo do WhatsApp: &lt;A href="https://lnkd.in/eYyGuvkc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://lnkd.in/eYyGuvkc&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":busts_in_silhouette:"&gt;👥&lt;/span&gt;Organização: Simone Azevedo | Tiago Felipe | Luiz Carlos de Souza | Adriano Marques de Oliveira | Marssel Vilaça&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SITCWB2025&lt;BR /&gt;#SAPCommunity&lt;BR /&gt;#SAPCommunityCWB&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/curitiba-blog-posts/sitcwb2025-sap-signavio-btp-automa%C3%A7%C3%A3o-inteligente-de-processos-do-insight-%C3%A0/ba-p/14268072"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:06:23.422000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-group-per-cost-center-the-depreciation-posting/qaa-p/14268074#M4231401</id>
    <title>Re: how to group per cost center the depreciation posting</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:08:58.240000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMMED_BASER</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253375</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;BR /&gt;In SAP S/4HANA, standard depreciation posting via AFAB does not support grouping line items by cost center instead of by individual asset. Each asset's depreciation is posted separately, even if multiple assets belong to the same cost center&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Abdul Baser&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-group-per-cost-center-the-depreciation-posting/qaa-p/14268074#M4231401"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:08:58.240000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/tables-in-constraints/qaq-p/14268076</id>
    <title>Tables in Constraints</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:11:11.555000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MSchlosser</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2059988</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope someone here can help me with this problem.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are currently using SAP version ECC 6.0 EHP4.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We would like to enter the name of the operating instructions using existing characteristics from the classification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Class: DSV_VT_OT_GH&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Class type: 001&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the following characteristics are entered in the classification, the name of the operating instructions should be filled in under the characteristic “&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;WC_NUMBER_BA&lt;/FONT&gt;”:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;BAUREIHE_LB&lt;/FONT&gt;” and “&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;LABEL_TYP&lt;/FONT&gt;” and&amp;nbsp;“&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;BETRIEBSDRUCK_LB&lt;/FONT&gt;” and&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;NENNWEITE_O_LB&lt;/FONT&gt;” or “&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;NENNWEITE_U_LB&lt;/FONT&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MSchlosser_3-1763038886270.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340107i075A6D93E1850846/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MSchlosser_3-1763038886270.png" alt="MSchlosser_3-1763038886270.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To do this, I used transaction CU61 to create an SAP table with the following evaluation alternatives:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MSchlosser_0-1763030803141.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340011iC4ECF0F3695A9228/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MSchlosser_0-1763030803141.png" alt="MSchlosser_0-1763030803141.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The table is structured as follows using transaction CU60. I would also like to allow multiple characteristic values for a characteristic (see “Size upper”).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MSchlosser_1-1763030847706.png" style="width: 908px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340012i3770ADCBF1874BEB/image-dimensions/908x289/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="908" height="289" role="button" title="MSchlosser_1-1763030847706.png" alt="MSchlosser_1-1763030847706.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, I created a relationship network and a constraint using transaction CU21.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MSchlosser_2-1763030901397.png" style="width: 564px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340013i21D25EAB648103A2/image-dimensions/564x573/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="564" height="573" role="button" title="MSchlosser_2-1763030901397.png" alt="MSchlosser_2-1763030901397.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm stuck at this point. I'm getting the error message “E28132.”&amp;nbsp;In addition, I don't yet know how to incorporate an OR query (“NENNWEITE_O_LB” or “NENNWEITE_U_LB”) into the formula.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would appreciate it if someone could help me.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance for your help.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/tables-in-constraints/qaq-p/14268076"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:11:11.555000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/wrong-partners-in-bill-type-ig-internal-credit-memo/qaa-p/14268075#M4231402</id>
    <title>Re: Wrong partners in bill type IG Internal Credit Memo</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:11:17.716000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jens_feldkamp1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/852275</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you for your replies. The reason was a programm error: &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3502523" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3502523&lt;/A&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/wrong-partners-in-bill-type-ig-internal-credit-memo/qaa-p/14268075#M4231402"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:11:17.716000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/precise-control-of-fiori-app-access-with-the-app-authorization-variants/bc-p/14268077#M62438</id>
    <title>Re: Precise Control of Fiori App Access with the App Authorization Variants</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:14:41.071000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>George_Yu1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131765</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;You are welcome,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/108863"&gt;@Yang09&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/precise-control-of-fiori-app-access-with-the-app-authorization-variants/bc-p/14268077#M62438"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:14:41.071000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-with-action-buttons-for-purchase-requisition-tasks-in-sap-task-center/qaa-p/14268078#M4931626</id>
    <title>Re: Issue with Action Buttons for Purchase Requisition Tasks in SAP Task Center Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:15:37.493000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>john_co</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-with-action-buttons-for-purchase-requisition-tasks-in-sap-task-center/qaa-p/14268078#M4931626"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:15:37.493000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-with-action-buttons-for-purchase-requisition-tasks-in-sap-task-center/qaa-p/14268080#M4931627</id>
    <title>Re: Issue with Action Buttons for Purchase Requisition Tasks in SAP Task Center Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:17:43.764000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>john_co</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi, we're experiencing the same issue here. Have you been able to solve this?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-with-action-buttons-for-purchase-requisition-tasks-in-sap-task-center/qaa-p/14268080#M4931627"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:17:43.764000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s-4hana%E3%81%AE%E6%96%B0%E3%83%AA%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B9%E4%BC%9A%E8%A8%88%E5%9F%BA%E6%BA%96%E5%AF%BE%E5%BF%9C%E3%81%AB%E3%81%A4%E3%81%84%E3%81%A6/qaa-p/14268081#M4231404</id>
    <title>Re: S/4HANAの新リース会計基準対応について</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:18:28.888000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMMED_BASER</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253375</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;こんにちは、&lt;BR /&gt;現時点では、SAPは2027年4月1日から施行される日本のリース会計基準の改訂に関する具体的な注記やローカライズされた導入事例をまだ公開していません。しかしながら、準備は進められており、SAPの既存のリース管理ツールが移行をサポートすることが期待されています。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hello Friend,&lt;BR /&gt;As of now, SAP has not yet published specific Notes or localized implementation cases for the revised Japanese lease accounting standards effective from April 1, 2027. However, preparations are underway, and SAP’s existing lease management tools are expected to support the transition.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s-4hana%E3%81%AE%E6%96%B0%E3%83%AA%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B9%E4%BC%9A%E8%A8%88%E5%9F%BA%E6%BA%96%E5%AF%BE%E5%BF%9C%E3%81%AB%E3%81%A4%E3%81%84%E3%81%A6/qaa-p/14268081#M4231404"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:18:28.888000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-commerce-cloud-live-series-ai-data-retention-integration-and/ba-p/14268082</id>
    <title>SAP Commerce Cloud Live Series: AI, Data Retention, Integration, and Interceptors</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:19:50.943000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JudyMaa</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2103284</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ready to level up your SAP Commerce Cloud skills before the new year? Join our fast-paced, expert-led live series covering AI-powered commerce, data retention best practices, integration mastery, and interceptor implementation. Pick your track or attend them all—each session is packed with practical insights, real-world scenarios, and tools you can apply immediately.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Title: [End of November] Unlock the Future of Commerce with the SAP CX AI Toolkit&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Description: &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt; Coming Soon! Join us this November for an exclusive live session — Introducing the SAP CX AI Toolkit for SAP Commerce Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how the SAP CX AI Toolkit can revolutionize your digital commerce strategies. This session provides a concise, technical overview of its key features, focusing on how it enhances customer experiences, streamlines operations, and keeps you ahead with the latest updates. Designed for professionals seeking practical insight into SAP Commerce Cloud, you’ll learn how these evolving tools drive success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/introducing-the-sap-cx-ai-toolkit-for-sap-commerce-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/introducing-the-sap-cx-ai-toolkit-for-sap-commerce-cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;________________________________________________________________________________________________________&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Title: Early December - Exploring the Data Retention Framework in SAP Commerce Cloud (Live Session)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Description: Attention Technical Consultants, Architects, Developers, and DevOps! Join our live session to learn about the Data Retention Framework's data structures and how to configure and customize them to meet your business needs. Gain practical, step-by-step insights for effective data management in SAP Commerce Cloud.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Register here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/exploring-the-data-retention-framework-in-sap-commerce-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/exploring-the-data-retention-framework-in-sap-commerce-cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;________________________________________________________________________________________________________&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Title: Early December — Configuring the Integration API Module in SAP Commerce Cloud (Live Session)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Description: Looking to improve your SAP Commerce Cloud integrations? Join our live session now scheduled for early December dedicated to the Integration API Module! We'll explore the architecture of the Integration API, with a focus on inbound integrations, demonstrate best practices for configuration and monitoring, and show you how to use the Backoffice Integration Cockpit to optimize your workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reserve your spot here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/configuring-the-integration-api-module-in-sap-commerce-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/configuring-the-integration-api-module-in-sap-commerce-cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Want a sneak peek beforehand? Read our blog on creating a webhook with a POJO Integration Object:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blogs-by-sap/creating-a-webhook-with-a-pojo-integration-object-in-sap-commerce-cloud-a/ba-p/13706523" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blogs-by-sap/creating-a-webhook-with-a-pojo-integration-object-in-sap-commerce-cloud-a/ba-p/13706523&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;________________________________________________________________________________________________________&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Title: [Early December] Join our live session: Introducing Interceptors in SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Description: In this session, you’ll cover the core concepts, explore the different interceptor types, and learn practical strategies to implement interceptors to streamline and optimize your processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Don’t miss out—reserve your spot now:&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/introducing-interceptors-in-sap-commerce-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/introducing-interceptors-in-sap-commerce-cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note: These sessions are part of our Commerce Live Series, designed to deepen your understanding of SAP Commerce Cloud. Explore other upcoming sessions and expand your knowledge here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/where-you-go-next-after-learning-the-technical-basics-of-sap-commerce-cloud/ba-p/13572461" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/where-you-go-next-after-learning-the-technical-basics-of-sap-commerce-cloud/ba-p/13572461&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-commerce-cloud-live-series-ai-data-retention-integration-and/ba-p/14268082"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:19:50.943000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/navigating-the-bp-transaction-authorizations-in-s-4hana-sap-security/bc-p/14268085#M72244</id>
    <title>Re: Navigating the BP transaction Authorizations in S/4HANA : SAP Security Experts Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:25:07.849000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stephane_lecuyer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/365896</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179914"&gt;@Amit_Parmar1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- This is the best overview of BP authorizations I have come across.&amp;nbsp; Thanks for sharing.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/navigating-the-bp-transaction-authorizations-in-s-4hana-sap-security/bc-p/14268085#M72244"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:25:07.849000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/use-function-rankby-on-charts-with-measures-from-a-measure-input-control/qaq-p/14268086</id>
    <title>Use function .rankBy on charts with measures from a measure input control</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:25:54.329000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>harald_zarakowitis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/309114</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We have a chart where the measure is controlled over a measure input control. With this setup it is not possible to use the rankBy function as far as I can see?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I can get a measure code with getMembers(FeedAxis) but I cannot use it. It looks like this:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;25123745-7560-4113-3967-727090252387&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This seems to be the artificial measure code for the measure input control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When use the measure that is currently selected in the measure input control, which is also the measure if you retrieve the resultSet of a chart, it doesn't work either:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ranking isn’t applied because the structure member 00O2THUHN03AJWRF2G2DRG5G7 isn’t on the chart.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even though this is the measure that is returned by the resultSet (but in the builder the measure is the measure input control).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I can workaround with doing the measure input control essentially myself, but this is more effort.&lt;BR /&gt;It seems quite an obvious requirement from a developer perspective, so I somehow can' t believe that it is not possible.&lt;BR /&gt;Am I missing something here?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Harald&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/use-function-rankby-on-charts-with-measures-from-a-measure-input-control/qaq-p/14268086"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:25:54.329000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-with-action-buttons-for-purchase-requisition-tasks-in-sap-task-center/qaa-p/14268089#M4931629</id>
    <title>Re: Issue with Action Buttons for Purchase Requisition Tasks in SAP Task Center Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:30:03.129000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joaquin_Roldan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2265508</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I'm experiencing the same issue</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-with-action-buttons-for-purchase-requisition-tasks-in-sap-task-center/qaa-p/14268089#M4931629"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:30:03.129000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/automatic-renewal-of-service-contract-cannot-renew/qaa-p/14268090#M4231405</id>
    <title>Re: Automatic Renewal of Service Contract cannot renew</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:32:44.022000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lily16</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2216187</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/162289"&gt;@Wei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I checked the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;configuration activity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The date Duration&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CONTDURA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Contract Validity Period have already set in the date profile like below.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;But the issue still exits.&lt;BR /&gt;The service contract cannot renew automatically.&lt;BR /&gt;Date Profile: ZCONT002&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Lily16_0-1763040798761.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340115i62B8A3E0DC6D6EED/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Lily16_0-1763040798761.png" alt="Lily16_0-1763040798761.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Lily16_3-1763041105776.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340120iB332C0779BE199EC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Lily16_3-1763041105776.png" alt="Lily16_3-1763041105776.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/automatic-renewal-of-service-contract-cannot-renew/qaa-p/14268090#M4231405"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:32:44.022000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-3-final-what-s-new-amp-product/ba-p/14264058</id>
    <title>SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.3: Final What's New &amp; Product Assistance available</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:33:16.186000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>diana_vega</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/755777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With immediate effect, the final What's New information for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&amp;nbsp;2508.3 is now available.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To access the final What’s New information, please use the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/7d3d11840a6543329e72391cf4d48e2d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition, the final Product Assistance (aka Application Help) for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&amp;nbsp;2508.3 is available. Please use the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;page to access it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For you as a customer, we recommend to also use the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/rasd" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Release Assessment and Scope Dependency (RASD) tool&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Release Assessment and Scope Dependency (RASD) tool provides you with a personalized and tailored view on What’s New information based on the activated and used scope within your system. The information for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.3 will be available in RASD within the next few days. A valid Customer S-user ID is required for login. We recommend to use RASD to prepare for upgrades and updates of your system and to focus on the new and changed features that are relevant for you as a customer.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You can use the commenting feature for What’s New. With this feature, authors can evaluate your feedback and incorporate it into the documentation, if needed. We hope that by opening this channel of communication, we can learn how to further improve our What’s New content for you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To use this feature, you need to be logged into the Help Portal. The feature will only be available in the English version of the documents. To learn more about how the feedback process works in SAP Help Portal, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/help_portal/8dae62f6f947468c94b685aba6ead3bd/9614459c61904390a8908c52b5cc4a3d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Giving Documentation Feedback&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-3-final-what-s-new-amp-product/ba-p/14264058"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:33:16.186000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-existing-stock-items-from-non-batch-to-batch-management/qaa-p/14268096#M4231406</id>
    <title>Re: Change existing stock items from Non-Batch to Batch M...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:36:19.728000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaymondGiuseppi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/185148</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Yes (that was my suggestion &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face:"&gt;😀&lt;/span&gt;)</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-existing-stock-items-from-non-batch-to-batch-management/qaa-p/14268096#M4231406"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:36:19.728000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/erfassung-wertkorrektur-vom-erp-bestand-ohne-den-ewm-bestand-zu-bewegen/qaa-p/14268097#M256383</id>
    <title>Re: Erfassung Wertkorrektur vom ERP Bestand - ohne den EW...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:37:44.236000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMMED_BASER</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253375</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hallo David,&lt;BR /&gt;Wie du bereits erwähnt hast, müssen Sie zum Ändern der Bewertungsklasse in SAP zunächst den Bestand auf null reduzieren, den Materialstamm aktualisieren und anschließend den Bestand neu buchen. Der genaue Ablauf hängt von Ihrer Systemkonfiguration ab. Hier finden Sie eine vereinfachte Anleitung.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bitte folgen Sie den Schritten zur Änderung der Bewertungsklasse in SAP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Die Änderung der Bewertungsklasse für Materialien in SAP erfordert sorgfältige Vorgehensweise, um buchhalterische Inkonsistenzen zu vermeiden. Die einzelnen Schritte sind unten aufgeführt:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Bestand ausbuchen (Bestand auf null setzen)&lt;BR /&gt;Bevor Sie die Bewertungsklasse ändern, müssen Sie sicherstellen, dass das Material keinen Bestand mehr hat. Dies erreichen Sie wie folgt:&lt;BR /&gt;Verwenden Sie die Bewegungsart 551 (Verschrottung).&lt;BR /&gt;Transaktionscode: MB1A oder MIGO&lt;BR /&gt;Wählen Sie die Bewegungsart 551 (Verschrottung).&lt;BR /&gt;Geben Sie die Materialnummer, die Menge und das Werk ein.&lt;BR /&gt;Buchen Sie den Beleg, um den Bestand aus dem Lager zu entfernen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alternative: Bestandsanpassung&lt;BR /&gt;Transaktionscode: MI01 (Inventurbeleg anlegen)&lt;BR /&gt;Transaktionscode: MI04 (Bestand erfassen)&lt;BR /&gt;Transaktionscode: MI07 (Differenzen buchen)&lt;BR /&gt;Setzen Sie den Bestand auf null, um den Bestand auszubuchen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Bewertungsklasse ändern&lt;BR /&gt;Sobald der Bestand null ist:&lt;BR /&gt;Transaktionscode: MM02 (Materialstammsatz ändern)&lt;BR /&gt;Wechseln Sie zur Sicht „Buchhaltung 1“.&lt;BR /&gt;Aktualisieren Sie das Feld „Bewertungsklasse“.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Speichern Sie die Änderungen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wenn eine Fehlermeldung wie „Buchung in den Bilanzgruppen nicht ausgeglichen“ erscheint, kann dies an offenen Bestellungen oder Buchhaltungsbelegen liegen, die mit der alten Bewertungsklasse verknüpft sind.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Bestand wieder einbuchen&lt;BR /&gt;Nach Aktualisierung der Bewertungsklasse:&lt;BR /&gt;Verwenden Sie die Bewegungsart 561 (Anfangsbuchung):&lt;BR /&gt;Transaktionscode: MB1C oder MIGO&lt;BR /&gt;Wählen Sie die Bewegungsart 561.&lt;BR /&gt;Geben Sie die Materialnummer, die Menge und das Werk ein.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Buchen Sie den Beleg, um den Bestand wieder einzuführen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ich hoffe, das hilft Ihnen bei der Änderung der Bewertungsklasse.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/erfassung-wertkorrektur-vom-erp-bestand-ohne-den-ewm-bestand-zu-bewegen/qaa-p/14268097#M256383"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:37:44.236000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/questions-about-sap-ecc-on-premise-to-s-4hana-private-cloud-conversion/qaq-p/14268098</id>
    <title>Questions about SAP ECC on-premise to S/4HANA Private Cloud Conversion</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:38:10.940000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohammedBENKHATI1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1645662</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hello SAP Experts,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;I am preparing for a SAP ECC on-premise to S/4HANA Private Cloud conversion and have several questions regarding the process and access requirements:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Does the SAP provider install and prepare the S/4HANA system with the correct version and HANA database?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Can the customer run the Readiness Check on the ECC source system? Is it the same as for an on-premise conversion?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- What type of access is provided for the private cloud system (e.g., root, GUI, HANA DB)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- How is the SUM (Software Update Manager) executed on the source ECC system, and how should I select the migration option (DMO with System Move / DMOVE2S4)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Is it necessary to download and upload files to the target system for DMO with System Move?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Will I have root system access to directories like /usr/sap/&amp;lt;SID&amp;gt;/SUM?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Are the standard HANA directories on the cloud target the same as on-premise (e.g., /hana/shared, /hana/data, /hana/log)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- How do I launch SUM on the cloud OS target for content migration?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Should I prepare a sandbox system, or is it handled directly on the production system in the private cloud?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- If there is any migration failure, is it possible to reset and retry safely?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- I would appreciate any guidance, best practices, or tips for planning this migration to S/4HANA Private Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- I've seen in serval SAP blogs that it's recommended to install an AAS on the private cloud, connect it to the source system, and then run SUM directly on that AAS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Private+Edition+Service/pd-p/3845c5fc-49f8-4da0-90f5-d7a73706a16a" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1267-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Service&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+migration+cockpit/pd-p/791935194581077217831679640306539" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1069-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA migration cockpit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud%25252C+extended+edition/pd-p/73b37c4d-a4aa-4de9-aeb9-a5dc59710b26" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="244-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud, extended edition&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+migration+cockpit/pd-p/791935194581077217831679640306539" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1069-2"&gt;SAP S/4HANA migration cockpit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/questions-about-sap-ecc-on-premise-to-s-4hana-private-cloud-conversion/qaq-p/14268098"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:38:10.940000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-joule-connects-to-sap-business-one-actions/ba-p/14268116</id>
    <title>How Joule Connects to SAP Business One - Actions</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:43:45.762000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>erickgomez-tech</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9329</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Joule Studio's capabilities allow it to connect to a data source, in our case SAP Business One, thanks to Actions, and this is a central and fundamental concept.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Actions in SAP Build are components that allow you to Create, Read, Update or Delete (CRUD) data through Destinations, which in turn connect to the Service Layer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to delve deeper into Actions, I recommend the following link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Conocer más sobre Actions en Odata" href="https://www.odata.org/blog/actions-in-odata/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ODATA - Actions&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently, Actions can be created using the OpenAPI Specification 3.0, but this doesn't yet exist for the SAP Business One Service Layer. It has been documented in a requirement that you can find at this link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="OpenAPI requeriment to SAP" href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/311258" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/311258&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, we can create Actions from scratch. This requires a solid understanding of how to use the SAP Service Layer, as well as access to it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'll explain how they are created, tested, and consumed using Joule Studio's skills; if you master this, you'll be ready to move forward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step 1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-left video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F3vmdXuFYenM%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D3vmdXuFYenM&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F3vmdXuFYenM%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="600" height="337" scrolling="no" title="How Joule Connects to SAP Business One - Actions" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Direct link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Direct link" href="https://youtu.be/3vmdXuFYenM?si=wfnTwnZMpxm5R1g3" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://youtu.be/3vmdXuFYenM?si=wfnTwnZMpxm5R1g3&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Step 2 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Now that we have the Action published, we go to the Joule Studio skill, add it, and configure the input we added, this will make Joule ask the user for the Service call number.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;If the response is successful, Joule will be able to answer the user's queries,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;I'll explain this in another post. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Best regards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Erick Gómez&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-joule-connects-to-sap-business-one-actions/ba-p/14268116"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:43:45.762000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-maintain-texts-in-table-t156ht-for-different-languages-movement-type/qaa-p/14268117#M4931630</id>
    <title>Re: How to maintain texts in table T156HT for different languages (Movement Type Help Texts)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:45:03.600000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMMED_BASER</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253375</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi, T156HT must be maintained manually; it is not automatically updated via OMJJ. You can use transaction SE61 to maintain help texts per language.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-maintain-texts-in-table-t156ht-for-different-languages-movement-type/qaa-p/14268117#M4931630"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:45:03.600000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/handling-long-field-names-in-odata-rap-api-s/ba-p/14268121</id>
    <title>Handling Long Field Names in OData / RAP API's</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:48:12.956000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dinesh_kumar45</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/211788</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Requuirement:-&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While working with OData services in SAP, you might encounter an issue when sending long field&lt;BR /&gt;names like: PuchaseOrdernosendtosalesforcesystem&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In such cases, your CDS view might throw an error due to the length or naming restriction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="1.jpg" style="width: 823px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340131iCD34717D4FFFBB1B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1.jpg" alt="1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Error Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340130iE8924C79E7D65F72/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.jpg" alt="2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use the annotation below to define the desired long field name explicitly:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1599241"&gt;@odata&lt;/a&gt;.property.name: 'PuchaseOrdernosendtosalesforcesystem'&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="3.jpg" style="width: 931px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340132iBCA97EE776CD5526/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.jpg" alt="3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After adding this annotation, activate your CDS view, and then create:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Service Definition&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Service Binding (V4)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Output on POSTMAN / SAP Gateway&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="4.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340133iCC50D9F9677DDC95/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4.jpg" alt="4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="5.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340134iE4971596B9E30580/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.jpg" alt="5.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This simple technique helps you maintain meaningful field names without breaking technical limits in Odata API’s.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dinesh Kumar&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/handling-long-field-names-in-odata-rap-api-s/ba-p/14268121"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:48:12.956000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-what-s-new-leave-us-your-feedback/bc-p/14268127#M62439</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition What’s New: Leave us your Feedback!</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:52:03.149000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>diana_vega</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/755777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Unfortunately, this is is not possible at the moment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-what-s-new-leave-us-your-feedback/bc-p/14268127#M62439"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:52:03.149000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/curitiba-blog-posts/sitcwb2025-desvendando-o-move-to-rise-na-pr%C3%A1tica/ba-p/14268129</id>
    <title>#SITCWB2025 🎤 Desvendando o Move to RISE na prática</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:54:33.250000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LuizSouza_cwb</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1442973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="7.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340136i4077F07E970101D4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="7.jpg" alt="7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nome:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;João Norberto Santos Junior&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cargo:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Architect Rise / BTP Specialist&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Link da Palestra:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/AyCjx--lxOk?si=Ln9s2k61KXMULy42" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/live/AyCjx--lxOk?si=Ln9s2k61KXMULy42&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resumo da palestra:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Nesta sessão, você vai entender de maneira prática como embarcar na jornada RISE with SAP — desde os &lt;STRONG&gt;motivos estratégicos&lt;/STRONG&gt; até os &lt;STRONG&gt;passos concretos&lt;/STRONG&gt; de execução.&lt;BR /&gt;Você verá como:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Avaliar se o momento para migrar para RISE é o certo (custos, suporte, inovação).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Usar metodologias, ferramentas e frameworks da SAP para planejar e executar a transição com menor risco.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Entender os benefícios reais — agilidade, inovação, simplificação da TI — e os desafios que surgem no caminho.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exemplos de “na prática” de como empresas estão fazendo o move, o que dar certo, o que evitar. (Será abordado durante a palestra.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Por que você deve assistir?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Se você atua em TI, transformação digital, operações, ERP ou está envolvido em decisões de migração e inovação — esta palestra é para você.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ela oferece:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Uma visão clara do que significa “mover para RISE” de forma realista — não só o conceito, mas a execução.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ferramentas para ajudar a estruturar seu roadmap, reduzir incertezas e alinhar stakeholders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Não perca!&lt;/STRONG&gt; Assista à palestra e esteja preparado para levar sua organização para o próximo nível de ERP na nuvem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Patrocinadores:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sports_medal:"&gt;🏅&lt;/span&gt; OURO: CHpro Solutions | CVA&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":3rd_place_medal:"&gt;🥉&lt;/span&gt; BRONZE: Lupus Consulting | FioriNET - Programação SAP ABAP Cloud S/4HANA Fiori UI5 | Aline ExplicaSAP&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":handshake:"&gt;🤝&lt;/span&gt; Apoio: Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Paraná&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":mobile_phone_with_arrow:"&gt;📲&lt;/span&gt; Quer receber as novidades em primeira mão. Entre no nosso grupo do WhatsApp: &lt;A href="https://lnkd.in/eYyGuvkc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://lnkd.in/eYyGuvkc&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":busts_in_silhouette:"&gt;👥&lt;/span&gt; Organização: Simone Azevedo | Tiago Felipe | Luiz Carlos de Souza | Adriano Marques de Oliveira | Marssel Vilaça&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SITCWB2025&lt;BR /&gt;#SAPCommunity&lt;BR /&gt;#SAPCommunityCWB&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/curitiba-blog-posts/sitcwb2025-desvendando-o-move-to-rise-na-pr%C3%A1tica/ba-p/14268129"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:54:33.250000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/how-to-ask-a-question-in-sap-community-gt-2024/qaa-p/14268130#M62328</id>
    <title>Re: How to ask a question in SAP Community &gt;= 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:56:30.143000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>omar_nabhan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/753984</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I need a parameter or other method that would allow me to change the user's password, and the user would still be able to use the same password without being prompted to change it upon login.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/how-to-ask-a-question-in-sap-community-gt-2024/qaa-p/14268130#M62328"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:56:30.143000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/how-to-post-a-questions-to-forum/qaa-p/14268131#M62329</id>
    <title>Re: how to post a questions to forum</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:57:06.844000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>omar_nabhan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/753984</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I need a parameter or other method that would allow me to change the user's password, and the user would still be able to use the same password without being prompted to change it upon login.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/how-to-post-a-questions-to-forum/qaa-p/14268131#M62329"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:57:06.844000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enabling-external-workflow-for-features-in-sap-cloud-alm/bc-p/14268132#M186315</id>
    <title>Re: Enabling external workflow for Features in SAP Cloud ALM</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:59:11.195000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ValeriaL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1434895</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Riccardo,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot for your feedback! At the moment, the Feature remains in status "In Testing" which is the default behavior. With the upcoming Feature Status Update API and the following workflow integration iterations we plan to enable the possibility to reset the status back to a specific value.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Valeria&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enabling-external-workflow-for-features-in-sap-cloud-alm/bc-p/14268132#M186315"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:59:11.195000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/integrating-platform-events-using-salesforce-pubsub-adapter-in-sap-cloud/bc-p/14268134#M176338</id>
    <title>Re: Integrating Platform Events using Salesforce PubSub Adapter in SAP Cloud Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:02:16.443000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vishal_Ingale</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1646874</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Nicely explained Manish !!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/integrating-platform-events-using-salesforce-pubsub-adapter-in-sap-cloud/bc-p/14268134#M176338"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:02:16.443000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-in-archiving-for-hrcustax-object/qaa-p/14268135#M4231408</id>
    <title>Re: Error in archiving for HRCUSTAX object</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:03:45.800000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>giorgio-bottegoni</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/29782</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;it seems you have some&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;inconsistencies in your data for that employee.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please check the 2 entries using transaction SE16n ensuring all key components (PERNR, INFTY, SUBTY, BEGDA, ENDDA) match exactly the key in the error message.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, you could execute report&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;RPUFIXDS to know if there are any&amp;nbsp;Data Inconsistencies for that employee and eventually fix them.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finally, please review configuration&amp;nbsp; on table&amp;nbsp;V_T7XSSPERSUBTY: check if there are entries for IT0161 subtype FED and IT0210 subtype FED.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best Regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Giorgio&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-in-archiving-for-hrcustax-object/qaa-p/14268135#M4231408"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:03:45.800000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-maintain-texts-in-table-t156ht-for-different-languages-movement-type/qaa-p/14268136#M4931631</id>
    <title>Re: How to maintain texts in table T156HT for different languages (Movement Type Help Texts)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:05:25.588000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Which text you were referring? I could see the text in T156HT both in ECC &amp;amp; S/4. Please share screen shot with technical name for better clarity</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-maintain-texts-in-table-t156ht-for-different-languages-movement-type/qaa-p/14268136#M4931631"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:05:25.588000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/error-on-candidate-application-when-background-info-are-not-visible/qaa-p/14268137#M49326</id>
    <title>Re: Error on candidate application when background Info a...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:06:20.481000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>matteodavide</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/25523</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/120210"&gt;@karthick_0905&lt;/a&gt;, thank you for your support! For sure option 1 is the best for our requirements (option 3 cannot be considered because we need it on candidate side to be used even when a candidate hasn't applied.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For solution 1, can you help me understanding how to declare the view permission in the xml-template and how to hide all the fields for the candidate? This is our background element now:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;background-element id="skiils" type-id="9" sensitive="false"&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;label&amp;gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[Tech &amp;amp; Soft Skills (only Internal)]]&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;label xml:lang="en_US"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[Tech &amp;amp; Soft Skills (only Internal)]]&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;instruction&amp;gt;&amp;lt;label&amp;gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span style="font-family:Georgia,serif"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span style="font-size:12px"&amp;gt;Data accessible to the Internal Team to enter the Candidate&amp;amp;rsquo;s Tech and Soft Skills.&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;These skills are those declared by the candidate during the interview.&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;]]&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/instruction&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;data-field id="skilltype" field-name="vfld11" hidden="true" max-length="4000" anonymize="false"&amp;gt; &amp;lt;label&amp;gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[Skill Type]]&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; &amp;lt;picklist id="skilltypeREC"/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/data-field&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;data-field id="softskills" field-name="vfld15" hidden="true" max-length="4000" anonymize="false"&amp;gt; &amp;lt;label&amp;gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[Skill]]&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; &amp;lt;label xml:lang="en_US"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[Skill]]&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; &amp;lt;picklist id="softskill" parent-field-id="skilltype"/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/data-field&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;/background-element&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/error-on-candidate-application-when-background-info-are-not-visible/qaa-p/14268137#M49326"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:06:20.481000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/copenhagen-discussions/sap-cap-development-day-copenhagen/td-p/14268149</id>
    <title>SAP CAP Development Day, Copenhagen</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:09:42.091000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JCL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/31293</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join us for an inspiring day dedicated to the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP), featuring practical insights, expert sessions, and interactive discussion.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agenda for the day:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;10:00 – 10:15 - Welcome &amp;amp; Introduction&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;10:15 – 11:30 - SAP CAP Overview &amp;amp; SAP AI for Developers with&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Venu&amp;nbsp;Chembrakalathil, SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Develop cloud native applications in SAP Business Technology Platform using SAP Cloud Application Programming model with best practices served out of the box.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Rapid application development with minimal setup and cost, build applications in shorter development cycles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Focus on domain modeling , service definitions using core data services(CDS) , generating data base schema out of the box and expose services as OData APIs without writing custom code.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Increase productivity using AI coding assistant and accelerate development.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;11:30 – 12:30 - Interactive Group Sessions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;12:30 – 13:15 - Networking Lunch&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;13:15 – 14:30 - Deep Dive into SAP Fiori and Key Elements - Presented by Melwyn Monis, Gavdi Technology&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;14:30 – 15:00 - Q&amp;amp;A and Closing Remarks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join us for an inspiring day dedicated to the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP), featuring practical insights, expert sessions, and interactive discussions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt; Date &amp;amp; Time: 27 November, 10:00 – 15:00 CET&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":round_pushpin:"&gt;📍&lt;/span&gt; Location: Fuglebakken, Borups Allé 177 København NV&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://forms.office.com/pages/responsepage.aspx?id=RnaB3GuzOU-C5BqL6t7IN3nO6EuxqxBOiM4VLi-P6jJUREdPT1FVR1VYWFVEREYzODVLMDNGRkVWNi4u&amp;amp;route=shorturl" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Register Now&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/copenhagen-discussions/sap-cap-development-day-copenhagen/td-p/14268149"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:09:42.091000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/cloud-nf-e-melhorias-nas-configura%C3%A7%C3%B5es-de-e-mail-para-outbound/bc-p/14268156#M9414</id>
    <title>Re: Cloud NF-e: melhorias nas configurações de e-mail para outbound</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:11:35.149000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kaymon</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1527048</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT&gt;&lt;FONT&gt;Bom dia, poderiam compartilhar a configuração padrão de e-mail para o processo de saída, considerando que o parâmetro MAILNFE deve ser mantido no BP? &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT&gt;&lt;FONT&gt;Fiquei com uma dúvida: onde devemos registrar o e-mail que efetivamente enviará os arquivos?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/cloud-nf-e-melhorias-nas-configura%C3%A7%C3%B5es-de-e-mail-para-outbound/bc-p/14268156#M9414"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:11:35.149000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-with-download-template-functionality-in-rap-based-mass-upload-table/qaa-p/14268159#M4931632</id>
    <title>Re: Issue with Download Template Functionality in RAP-Based Mass Upload Table (ADT)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:12:11.971000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ankit_Sinha1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1522668</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Refer App: Mass Changes of Purchase Contract. It provide Template based Upload/Download functionality. Template can be defined under SPRO node-Material Management-Purchasing-Contracts-Excel based Data Exchange. App is based on odata V2 &amp;amp; SEGW project. May be helpful</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-with-download-template-functionality-in-rap-based-mass-upload-table/qaa-p/14268159#M4931632"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:12:11.971000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/asset-depreciation-continues-even-after-enabling-shutdown-flag-in-the-asset/qaq-p/14268175</id>
    <title>Asset depreciation continues even after enabling shutdown flag in the asset master data</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:21:11.576000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When we use the asset shut down for an area of a fixed asset and stop the depreciation for a period, it’s not working as we expected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/asset-depreciation-continues-even-after-enabling-shutdown-flag-in-the-asset/qaq-p/14268175"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:21:11.576000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/asset-depreciation-continues-even-after-enabling-shutdown-flag-in-the-asset/qaa-p/14268176#M256385</id>
    <title>Re: Asset depreciation continues even after enabling shut...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:21:19.025000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The shutdown only works if the depreciation key has shutdown indicator enabled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See KBA 3492938&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/asset-depreciation-continues-even-after-enabling-shutdown-flag-in-the-asset/qaa-p/14268176#M256385"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:21:19.025000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mmam-tcode-in-test-mode/qaq-p/14268177</id>
    <title>MMAM tcode in test mode</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:22:03.127000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Beatriccess</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2125026</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I had to create a report, which allows mass change of material types. I created it with batch input, and call transaction, but here comes the problem. The transaction has own COMMIT WORK during the call, therefore I can't implement a rollback after that, so the database will be updated at the end of the call. Someone advised to use somehow to encapsule the MMAM into a function and use it in CALL FUNCTION - IN UPDATE TASK, but as I know I can't use COMMIT WORK in it. Could someone please give a hint, how is it possible/ or not at all implement this feature? Also tried with local update, didn't help.&amp;nbsp; Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mmam-tcode-in-test-mode/qaq-p/14268177"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:22:03.127000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/why-can-other-users-not-see-the-install-button-for-my-published-data/qaa-p/14268180#M4931633</id>
    <title>Re: Why can other users not see the “Install” button for...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:24:16.910000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>benhaddou</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/891003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hey &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/248387"&gt;@cardoso&lt;/a&gt;, I created a Data Product based on a view in Space A. Then I installed this Data Product from the Marketplace into Space B. In Space B, the Data Product appears as a view, and I built an Analytic Model on top of it, which I use in SAC. Recently, I added a new column to the original view in Space A. However, this column does not appear in the view in Space B or in my SAC story. My question: Does a Data Product not automatically update when the underlying view changes? Is there a specific step I need to perform to apply these changes? Thank you for your support!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/why-can-other-users-not-see-the-install-button-for-my-published-data/qaa-p/14268180#M4931633"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:24:16.910000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-video-series-for-sap-datasphere-data-marketplace/bc-p/14268186#M186317</id>
    <title>Re: New video series for SAP Datasphere data marketplace</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:27:04.707000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>benhaddou</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/891003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2128390"&gt;@RAviraj3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;BR /&gt;I created a Data Product based on a view in &lt;EM&gt;Space A&lt;/EM&gt;. Then I installed this Data Product from the Marketplace into &lt;EM&gt;Space B&lt;/EM&gt;. In &lt;EM&gt;Space B&lt;/EM&gt;, the Data Product appears as a view, and I built an Analytic Model on top of it, which I use in SAC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently, I added a new column to the original view in &lt;EM&gt;Space A&lt;/EM&gt;. However, this column does not appear in the view in &lt;EM&gt;Space B&lt;/EM&gt; or in my SAC story.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My question:&lt;BR /&gt;Does a Data Product not automatically update when the underlying view changes? Is there a specific step I need to perform to apply these changes?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your support!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-video-series-for-sap-datasphere-data-marketplace/bc-p/14268186#M186317"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:27:04.707000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ui-element-dropdown-attribute-modification-in-fiori/qaa-p/14268188#M4231410</id>
    <title>Re: UI element - dropdown attribute modification in Fiori</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:28:23.795000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sagarbasa_22355</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2263922</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks! &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11644"&gt;@sandeep_suggu&lt;/a&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ui-element-dropdown-attribute-modification-in-fiori/qaa-p/14268188#M4231410"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:28:23.795000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/data-product-in-datasphere-does-not-update-after-changes-to-the-underlying/qaq-p/14268189</id>
    <title>Data Product in Datasphere does not update after changes to the underlying view</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:29:40.313000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>benhaddou</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/891003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hey everyone,&lt;BR /&gt;I created a Data Product based on a view in &lt;EM&gt;Space A&lt;/EM&gt;. Then I installed this Data Product from the Marketplace into &lt;EM&gt;Space B&lt;/EM&gt;. In &lt;EM&gt;Space B&lt;/EM&gt;, the Data Product appears as a view, and I built an Analytic Model on top of it, which I use in SAC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently, I added a new column to the original view in &lt;EM&gt;Space A&lt;/EM&gt;. However, this column does not appear in the view in &lt;EM&gt;Space B&lt;/EM&gt; or in my SAC story.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My question:&lt;BR /&gt;Does a Data Product not automatically update when the underlying view changes? Is there a specific step I need to perform to apply these changes?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your support!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/data-product-in-datasphere-does-not-update-after-changes-to-the-underlying/qaq-p/14268189"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:29:40.313000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ui-element-dropdown-attribute-modification-in-fiori/qaa-p/14268190#M4231411</id>
    <title>Re: UI element - dropdown attribute modification in Fiori</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:29:50.560000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sagarbasa_22355</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2263922</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks! &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11644"&gt;@sandeep_suggu&lt;/a&gt;. the solution provided is working. I got the attribute list under 'create search view'.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ui-element-dropdown-attribute-modification-in-fiori/qaa-p/14268190#M4231411"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:29:50.560000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ui-element-dropdown-attribute-modification-in-fiori/qaa-p/14268192#M4231412</id>
    <title>Re: UI element - dropdown attribute modification in Fiori</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:31:22.785000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sagarbasa_22355</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2263922</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks! &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11644"&gt;@sandeep_suggu&lt;/a&gt;. the solution provided is working. I got the attribute list under 'create search view'. Best regards, Sagar</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ui-element-dropdown-attribute-modification-in-fiori/qaa-p/14268192#M4231412"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:31:22.785000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ui-element-dropdown-attribute-modification-in-fiori/qaa-p/14268193#M4231413</id>
    <title>Re: UI element - dropdown attribute modification in Fiori</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:33:02.104000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sagarbasa_22355</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2263922</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks! &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11644"&gt;@sandeep_suggu&lt;/a&gt;. Best regards, Sagar</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/ui-element-dropdown-attribute-modification-in-fiori/qaa-p/14268193#M4231413"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:33:02.104000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/production-resource-tool-integration-with-pm-pp/bc-p/14268198#M72245</id>
    <title>Re: Production Resource Tool Integration with PM &amp; PP</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:35:27.314000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dgolec1964</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/888960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I had the same results as THibault82 measuring point did not create.&amp;nbsp; Is there any configuration that needs changed?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/production-resource-tool-integration-with-pm-pp/bc-p/14268198#M72245"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:35:27.314000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/0mb-memory-and-0-routes-on-cloud-foundry-trial-account/qaa-p/14268200#M4931635</id>
    <title>Re: 0MB memory and 0 routes on Cloud Foundry trial account</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:36:30.448000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ajin_andrews451</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2260933</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Unable to deploy application to Cloud Foundry. It is showing org limit is 0MB.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/0mb-memory-and-0-routes-on-cloud-foundry-trial-account/qaa-p/14268200#M4931635"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:36:30.448000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/new-learning-journey-implementing-sap-customer-data-platform/ba-p/14268068</id>
    <title>New Learning Journey : Implementing SAP Customer Data Platform</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:36:45.903000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KatJankovic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160268</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Announcing: Implementing SAP Customer Data Platform Learning Journey&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are thrilled to announce the launch of our extensive learning journey, &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/implementing-sap-customer-data-platform" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Implementing SAP Customer Data Platform&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;. This carefully designed program is crafted to equip you with the advanced skills and in-depth knowledge necessary to harness the full potential of SAP's powerful Customer Data Platform (CDP).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who this is for:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Target audience: Business users, Admin users, Consultants and Developers &amp;nbsp;who want to expand their functional knowledge and technical skills with SAP Customer Data Platform.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What You Will Learn:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mastering Foundations and Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The journey begins with &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-customer-data-platform-essentials" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Exploring SAP Customer Data Platform Essentials&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;. This course will guide you through the foundations of SAP Customer Data Platform and help you evaluate the functionalities for your implementation scenarios. This foundational understanding is crucial for effectively leveraging the capabilities of the CDP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proficient Administration and Monitoring&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;In the second course, &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/administering-sap-customer-data-platform" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Administering SAP Customer Data Platform&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;, you will become proficient in performing various administrative tasks within the SAP Customer Data Platform Console. This includes managing console users, dividing business units, defining data retention rules, and utilizing export/import package functionalities. Additionally, you will learn to effectively use monitoring capabilities to ensure seamless ingestion and activation of customer data, thus maintaining optimal performance and compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;API Utilization and Data Enrichment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The third course, &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/developing-with-sap-customer-data-platform" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Developing with SAP Customer Data Platform&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;, focuses on API utilization. You will learn to create and manage administrative credentials for accessing the SAP Customer Data Platform API, construct code to utilize the Query and Ingestion APIs, perform Event Metadata configuration, set up an Event Listener, and program and configure Events to enrich Customer Data. This hands-on experience will empower you to integrate and enhance your customer data ecosystem seamlessly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Powered Customer Insights and Predictive Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The fourth course, &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/sap-customer-data-platform-ai-workbench" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Exploring the SAP Customer Data Platform's AI Workbench&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;, delves into the power of AI-driven insights. You will learn to create activity indicators powered by AI to predict future customer loss or determine the value of your customer base. Moreover, you will gain the ability to gather additional insights using analytical graphics to understand future trends in individual customer churn or lifetime value, all through the SAP Customer Data Platform AI Workbench models and insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hands-On Practice System&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;To cement your learning, we provide a preconfigured practice system with all the data you need to carry out exercises from the courses or to experiment on your own. The &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/practice-systems/sap-customer-data-platform-implementation-training-3" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hands-on Practice for SAP Customer Data Platform Implementation Training&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; system is invaluable for reinforcing and applying the skills you acquire throughout the learning journey in practical scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/implementing-sap-customer-data-platform" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Implementing SAP Customer Data Platform&lt;/A&gt; learning journey is your gateway to mastering one of the most powerful customer data tools available today. Whether you are a beginner or an experienced professional looking to upgrade your skills, this journey will equip you with the advanced expertise needed to drive customer data strategies successfully.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Certification Opportunity:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; Upon completion of this learning journey, you will be well-prepared to earn a valuable certification, validating your skills and knowledge in SAP Customer Data Platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join us and unlock the full potential of SAP Customer Data Platform. Enrol now and take the first step toward advanced customer data management and analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to access:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/implementing-sap-customer-data-platform" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;learning journey&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is available now on&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://learning.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;learning.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. The courses are FREE. The practice system requires an SAP Learning Hub &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;license.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/new-learning-journey-implementing-sap-customer-data-platform/ba-p/14268068"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:36:45.903000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/is-it-possible-to-publish-an-sac-dashboard-as-a-data-product-in-the-sap/qaq-p/14268201</id>
    <title>Is it possible to publish an SAC dashboard as a Data Product in the SAP Datasphere Marketplace?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:37:49.206000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>benhaddou</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/891003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hey everyone,&lt;BR /&gt;Is it possible to publish an SAC dashboard as a Data Product in the SAP Datasphere &lt;STRONG&gt;Marketplace&lt;/STRONG&gt; and then open it via a URL?&lt;BR /&gt;Additionally, if this is possible, can specific permissions (e.g., access rights to the dashboard) be requested or managed through the Data Product?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your support!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/is-it-possible-to-publish-an-sac-dashboard-as-a-data-product-in-the-sap/qaq-p/14268201"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:37:49.206000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/how-to-manual-restriction-of-transport-import/qaa-p/14268202#M84541</id>
    <title>Re: How to Manual restriction of Transport import</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:43:07.769000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dave_S30</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/201476</uri>
    </author>
    <content>For the CTS switches to be effective, doesn't TMS need to also be configured to require all transport requests be created as part of a CTS Project?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/how-to-manual-restriction-of-transport-import/qaa-p/14268202#M84541"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:43:07.769000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/can-we-directly-access-the-data-stored-in-sac-when-using-import-connection/qaq-p/14268206</id>
    <title>Can we directly access the data stored in SAC when using Import Connection?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:47:38.804000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sivaramakrishnan_Manickam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/874631</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts, &amp;nbsp;When we use an &amp;nbsp;Import Data in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC), the imported data gets stored in SAC’s internal database ? , which I understand is based on SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My question is — since the imported data resides in this internal HANA environment,&lt;BR /&gt;is it possible to directly access or query that data (for example, using SAP HANA tools, SQL clients, or external connections)?&lt;BR /&gt;Or is this internal storage completely managed and isolated within SAC?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Appreciate any insights or official references on how SAC manages this internal HANA layer and whether external access is technically or administratively possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Siva&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/can-we-directly-access-the-data-stored-in-sac-when-using-import-connection/qaq-p/14268206"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:47:38.804000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-get-best-practice-content-for-sap-transportation-management/bc-p/14268208#M7888</id>
    <title>Re: How to get Best Practice Content for SAP Transportation Management</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:48:05.745000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AmauryFroment</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2151625</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for the blog. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-get-best-practice-content-for-sap-transportation-management/bc-p/14268208#M7888"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:48:05.745000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/mdg-consolidation-process-to-trigger-from-mulesoft/qaa-p/14268211#M4931638</id>
    <title>Re: MDG Consolidation process to trigger from Mulesoft</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:50:57.605000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>titu4mdg</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/745798</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;guys, I need some urgent help on this, please see if I get any lead.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/mdg-consolidation-process-to-trigger-from-mulesoft/qaa-p/14268211#M4931638"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:50:57.605000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/shaping-the-future-of-sap-cloud-alm-join-my-sessions-at-sap-teched-in/bc-p/14268214#M186318</id>
    <title>Re: Shaping the Future of SAP Cloud ALM: Join My Sessions at SAP TechEd in Berlin</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:55:08.414000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>qwertie</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7496</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;thank you for the update&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_up:"&gt;👍&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/shaping-the-future-of-sap-cloud-alm-join-my-sessions-at-sap-teched-in/bc-p/14268214#M186318"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:55:08.414000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/overview-of-background-job-in-the-system/qaa-p/14268219#M4931639</id>
    <title>Re: Overview of background job in the system</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:57:00.377000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>qwertie</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7496</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;i&amp;nbsp; think therefor you can use sm37 search&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="qwertie_0-1763045833199.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340199i80CBFE33DC6D7877/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="qwertie_0-1763045833199.png" alt="qwertie_0-1763045833199.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/overview-of-background-job-in-the-system/qaa-p/14268219#M4931639"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:57:00.377000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/grc-eam-fire-fighter-logs-not-collected-for-hana-db-connector/qaa-p/14268222#M4931640</id>
    <title>Re: GRC EAM: Fire Fighter Logs not collected for HANA DB...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:57:34.463000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S0026475335</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1813681</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have the same issue, I only recover the event "CONNECTION" on GRC, but on HANA i see that i have other events saved on the AUDIT_LOG table&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/grc-eam-fire-fighter-logs-not-collected-for-hana-db-connector/qaa-p/14268222#M4931640"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:57:34.463000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445</id>
    <title>Joule in SAP Build Code can now create freestyle UI5 apps</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:58:38.496000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndreasKunz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Last year, we&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-for-freestyle-sapui5-development-in-sap-build-code/ba-p/13650005" target="_blank"&gt;introduced the SAPUI5 extension for the Joule coding assistant in SAP Build Code&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/now-ai-helps-you-developing-sapui5-applications/ba-p/13649767" target="_blank"&gt;wrote about how to use it&lt;/A&gt;. Over time, it has received more features, like the AI-supported &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sapui5-meets-typescript-a-smooth-migration-journey-with-joule/ba-p/13958872" target="_blank"&gt;conversion of UI5 apps to TypeScript&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and setting up new pages and the respective navigation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The latest improvement, available from November 2025, lets you&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;create new freestyle UI5 apps&lt;/STRONG&gt; according to your requirements. The feature is not absolutely groundbreaking, as there are other tools doing a similar job like the &lt;A href="https://github.com/ui5-community/generator-easy-ui5" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Easy-UI5 templates&lt;/A&gt; and the recently published &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;UI5 MCP Server&lt;/A&gt;. But:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It brings the functionality right to the fingertips of developers using SAP Build Code—no other tools needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It extends the template capabilities beyond what the Easy-UI5 templates provide.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementing it within the Build Code Joule environment yielded interesting insights and further improvements. More on this in my &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_self"&gt;other article&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565993"&gt;The feature&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule makes specific features available using "slash commands". The new one is &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt;. When you open the Joule panel in SAP Build Code and start typing &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5&lt;/FONT&gt;, you might see it suggested, as well as other UI5 features. But which commands appear depends on the context. While some are only available &lt;EM&gt;within&lt;/EM&gt; UI5 apps, this new feature is only available when you are &lt;EM&gt;not&lt;/EM&gt; in a UI5 app. It won't be available e.g. in a workspace which has a ui5.yaml at top-level, or when you have a UI5 controller open in the code editor!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" style="width: 368px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338077i84DC1A2BF1286B93/image-dimensions/368x637/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="368" height="637" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Try it in a workspace with a &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/about/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;CAP&lt;/A&gt; project at root level, so you see some of its magic immediately: as soon as you finish typing the slash command or select it from the suggestion list, another suggestion list with sample prompts comes up. These are based on the actual data structures of the CAP project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" style="width: 470px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336598i81FF249A52996728/image-dimensions/470x310?v=v2" width="470" height="310" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means you can simply select the desired entity and service, then the actual full prompt will automatically be entered into the field(but of course you can also write your own prompt!). This full prompt includes even more details than the short prompt in the suggestion list did.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" style="width: 426px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336599iE4DE35FC0A4A5C5B/image-dimensions/426x146?v=v2" width="426" height="146" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that the prompt includes a concrete list of properties and the service URL. This information has been extracted from CAP using good old deterministic code—no Large Language Model (LLM) used. In fact, this is an area where AI would likely make up ("hallucinate") property names which do not actually exist. Acquiring all this information in advance in a deterministic way not only gives you the chance to review and adjust the prompt with little effort, but also leads to a more reliable functionality overall.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The paradigm: use LLMs (Large Language Models) where they excel—processing and "understanding" language—and use deterministic code for hard facts and well-defined operations, where possible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI part starts soon enough, when you submit this prompt. It proposes a specific app setup, highlighting the key choices for you to review. For example, it will suggest a sensible name (if you didn't provide one) or suggest the best location inside the project structure (which it knows from its context).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" style="width: 419px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336631iE19FE81A151525DB/image-dimensions/419x840?v=v2" width="419" height="840" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" alt="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But you can do more than just review those &lt;EM&gt;parameters&lt;/EM&gt;.&amp;nbsp;A suggested version of the app has already been created behind the scenes, so you can scroll through the 30+ files listed in the box at the bottom and click those you want to preview. If the result already looks fine to you—perfect. Just press the "Accept Application" button and the app will be set up in your workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439052488"&gt;Refining the app&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;But of course you are free to continue the conversation and tweak the result. The LLM in Joule will put its true strength at work, mapping its understanding of your request to what the underlying template can do. No need to type "change parameter x to value y": LLMs also understand you when you are less formal and direct. Look at the below screenshot for an example: it responds almost too compassionately to the developer who is "hesitant about new technologies" and recreates the app with changed parameters—using JavaScript instead of TypeScript. The user did not even mention the programming language specifically, but still the LLM decided that changing it would be the best way to accommodate the app code to the user's preferences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" style="width: 453px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336633i0D1C4439BEED17A1/image-dimensions/453x307?v=v2" width="453" height="307" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" alt="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this stage, you can refine the setup of the initial app—within the limits imposed by the application template used behind the scenes, which only has limited degrees of freedom. We want this &lt;EM&gt;initial&lt;/EM&gt; app to be robust and follow best-practice code. We also want those 30+ files to be created in &lt;EM&gt;one&lt;/EM&gt; fast step. Hence the code is not written by AI, but by using predefined template files we are back in the world of traditional deterministic coding here. You have plenty of opportunity for using AI later on to extend the app from this solid starting point.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule is aware of its limits in this step, so it will not say "yes" to every request you throw at it. Asking for "a trillion tables" or other features beyond the template scope will be politely rejected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" style="width: 444px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336641i7605E4A29BE73A9E/image-dimensions/444x350?v=v2" width="444" height="350" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" alt="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538983"&gt;Accepting the app&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the preview looks good and you have pressed the &lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" style="width: 120px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336642i611B7F59F8108180/image-dimensions/120x28?v=v2" width="120" height="28" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;button, the job of this &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; assistant is done. After app setup has finished (which may take a while because the dependencies need to be installed), it concludes with hints how to continue, including instructions on how to start the app in your respective workspace setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" style="width: 433px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336644i28549BEB965E64F1/image-dimensions/433x492?v=v2" width="433" height="492" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The created application looks roughly like this, with a table and a detail form below. Note: only OData V4 services are supported at this time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" style="width: 852px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336941iA1EC68BDFAA86432/image-dimensions/852x529/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="852" height="529" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You get this kind of UI when you specify an OData V4 service and entity. If you don't, then there is just a generic "Hello World" success page instead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course this UI structure might not be exactly what is desired in the app or even requested in the prompt, but this is what the template can do. When an OData service and entity but no properties are requested, then the tool tries to detect existing properties. If this fails, the table will be empty (no columns at all)—but Joule's success message should then mention this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046025478"&gt;After creation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the assistant suggests, please move to the other Joule assistants&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5&lt;/FONT&gt; and &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-page&lt;/FONT&gt; for developing the app further. In order to create more apps, reset the conversation with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" style="width: 23px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336645iB9B5AF8D09E44E81/image-dimensions/23x23?v=v2" width="23" height="23" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;button at the top of the Joule pane.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;EM&gt;knows&lt;/EM&gt; that it cannot modify the app or re-create it, it will politely guide you to the options you have, no matter what your request is. It may even give instructions on how to achieve the given goal within a UI5 app, but it will not be able to modify the code and it will make this clear when needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849511973"&gt;AI Learnings&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;While there is not much more to say about this feature—simply try it!—there are some facts and learnings about its implementation! If you are curious, head over to the second part of this blog post:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_self"&gt;Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:58:38.496000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/udf-exclude-promotion-type-from-model-forecast/qaa-p/14268223#M208136</id>
    <title>Re: UDF exclude promotion type from model / forecast</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:59:52.762000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jkopkow</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/488067</uri>
    </author>
    <content>unfortunately there is no standard way of excluding promotion types from beeing used by UDF for modelling and forecasting.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/udf-exclude-promotion-type-from-model-forecast/qaa-p/14268223#M208136"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:59:52.762000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447</id>
    <title>Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:00:38.750000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndreasKunz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565995"&gt;Flashback: the feature&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a &lt;EM&gt;"making of"&lt;/EM&gt; article about the implementation of the new&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; slash command available within Joule in SAP Build Code. In short, this new feature enables a conversation between AI assistant and application developer about a new freestyle UI5 application to build, with a full-fledged best-practice application starting point as result.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To see screenshots of this feature in action and understand it better, feel invited to read &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445" target="_self"&gt;my previous blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are just here for the background and AI-related learnings—go ahead!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439052490"&gt;General considerations&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;With open‑ended prompting, users aren’t restricted to predefined interactions. The user could ask for &lt;EM&gt;anything&lt;/EM&gt;. In contrast to traditional programming, a prompt input field can’t be handled with a sprawling web of if/else logic trying to cover all possible use-cases. Attempting this will lead to a frustrating user experience where the user often gets an "I do not understand your request".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some developers try to mimic this traditional programming pattern when crafting prompts and contexts for LLMs, telling an LLM "&lt;EM&gt;if the user asks for x, then answer y&lt;/EM&gt;". Instead, as demonstrated below, tell the LLM what it &lt;EM&gt;can&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;cannot&lt;/EM&gt; do and give it a goal to achieve. It's "smart" enough to figure out a suitable response to whatever the user will throw at it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538985"&gt;A fundamental choice&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking at this specific feature in the specific environment, the implementation options on the table were (for a variety of reasons) these two:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Either just provide a system prompt (a prompt that is added behind the scenes in addition to what the user typed) without interfering with the specific prompts and replies entered during the conversation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Or adopt a new way of creating an "agentic" multi-step execution plan. Similar to a guided activity, this would allow phases of data collection, possibly in different steps for different data, then an app creation step and so forth.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Surely "agentic" and "well-defined steps" sound good for app creation from a template, no? In fact, the initial implementation started like this, but it was soon apparent that this would neither provide the expected flexibility nor allow for a truly intelligent app creation experience. Defining phases in which to acquire specific information and having the application code created at a specific stage in this process did not feel right. The user would still feel like clicking through a traditional template creation process, as something specific was expected from the user at every stage, instead of giving the user the freedom to tweak every aspect at every stage. The true power of AI, on the other hand, would be totally underused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But then again... just a system prompt and that's it? No file read access to explore the environment, no dynamically updated instructions? Is this enough for an intelligent coding assistant?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046025480"&gt;Creating an "AI agent" out of nothing&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consider the now common definition of an "AI agent" which has settled over the course of this year: it's nothing more than "&lt;A href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/395657404_An_LLM_Agent_Runs_Tools_in_a_Loop_to_Achieve_a_Goal_A_Comprehensive_Semantic_Framework_for_Defining_AI_Agents_and_Agentic_Systems_by_Simon_Willison_and_Leading_Research_Laboratories" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;an LLM with tools, called in a loop to achieve a goal&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;". The chat conversation provided by Joule can be our loop, an application template with its parameters is the tool and the goal of assisting the developer to create an app can be stated in the system prompt. Of course a real &lt;EM&gt;autonomous&lt;/EM&gt; agent would require the loop to run without user interaction, but for this feature a loop involving the user is just right.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system prompt used for this feature literally includes: "&lt;EM&gt;Y&lt;SPAN&gt;ou help users create new UI5 applications by analyzing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;their requirements and filling the project template parameters. [...]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your goal is to gather all necessary information to create a new UI5 application.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The application will be generated from a template which&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;has only one page and a hardcoded UI, but can optionally display data from an OData V4 service. [...]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You cannot create the application yourself, but the user will see a preview...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;". There you have it: the goal and the tool!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It then goes on with some behavioral hints and of course a detailed description of what exactly the template parameters do. Finally, it requests &lt;EM&gt;each reply&lt;/EM&gt; to contain a JSON object with the best choice of template parameters according to the current understanding of the user request. The JSON object could look like this example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;{&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "appNamespace": "com.myorg.myapp",&lt;/SPAN&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "basePath": "/path/to/workspace",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
   "createAppDirectory": true,&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "framework": "SAPUI5",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "frameworkVersion": "1.136.0",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "author": "John Doe",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "oDataV4Url": "https://services.odata.org/TripPinRESTierService/(S(s5xrj1t51r41s3ooztsynysq))/",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "oDataEntitySet": "Airports",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "entityProperties": ["Name", "Address"],&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "runNpmInstall": true,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "initializeGitRepository": true,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "typescript": true&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;}&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This JSON object is removed from the LLM response before displaying it, then the application is generated with these parameters, so the user can accept it or request changes. In an environment where tools with a well-defined interface like MCP servers are not enabled, this JSON object as part of the conversation is how the integration with the templating tool is achieved. A note to make this very clear: this environment is &lt;EM&gt;not&lt;/EM&gt; the official SAP Joule assistant running inside end-user applications, as it is now also being enabled for development by customers. Instead, it is a sort of predecessor implementation specifically available in SAP Build Code since spring 2024.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some of these parameters in the JSON object are more important than others with regards to the user explicitly influencing them or having to accept them. Whether the app code is generated as TypeScript or JavaScript is something the user should not be surprised with &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; accepting the app! On the other hand, the author name, which is only written into package.json, can be reliably defaulted to the logged-in user name and also very easily changed later on if needed. Hence, the parameter descriptions explain not only &lt;EM&gt;what&lt;/EM&gt; they do, but also how much the user should be bothered with them. As result, Joule usually does not even mention half of the parameters, thus keeping the conversation focused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" style="width: 455px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339533i8B53DC0B3A50E913/image-dimensions/455x912/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="455" height="912" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849511975"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to stop the agent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regarding the state &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; the app was accepted, the prompt explains "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AFTER the user has generated the application, you **MUST NOT** continue discussing parameters for generation, but rather [...] i&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;n particular by referring the user to the '/ui5' command for most requests or '/ui5-create-page'&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for adding pages to the app, because they are much better than you in developing features, as they have the capability to automatically select a suitable context of files.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This means the transition in the overall process between refining parameters and "no more changes possible" is not a hardcoded step or denoted by changing the system prompt, but rather explained up-front. That's enough. Can you talk Joule into proposing another set of parameters after the app was accepted? Maybe. But its &lt;EM&gt;normal&lt;/EM&gt; behavior is just right: it will explain that the app can not be created again without restarting the conversation. Nevertheless, there are also non-AI guardrails in place to prevent the app from being generated again, thus causing trouble.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All in all, we shape Joule’s behavior by explaining the templating tool and its limits, by stating the goal and desired behavior towards this goal, and by explaining the general flow, in particular the state after app acceptance. This is enough to guide it to a suitable reaction for whatever the user requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Even if the user insists like this:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" style="width: 457px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339649i5AAFEF728BB75C51/image-dimensions/457x620/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="457" height="620" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-652998470"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Context, context, context!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To make the entire feature really user-friendly, however, it is not sufficient to write a good prompt, but the context must also provide enough information to the LLM to allow for informed decisions. Hence, information like the list of project root files and folders, whether a Git repository is present, plus CAP service/entity/property info, and more, are gathered (e.g. using the &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap-ux/project-access" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@sap-ux/project-access&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;package). This knowledge is provided as prompt context behind the scenes or used in another way (like as content of the suggested prompts). This makes Joule aware of the environment it acts in, leading to better responses, like automatically avoiding app names that would conflict with existing folder names.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agentic coding assistants like Cline, GitHub Copilot, Cursor etc. usually have the ability to read files and execute shell commands as needed to understand their environment. In this pure user request + LLM response environment this might have been a bit harder to build. Basically, more tools could have been defined, e.g. by describing other JSON object structures for invoking them. But control would not so easily return to the LLM until after the user has entered another prompt.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But for a narrow scenario like app creation this wasn't necessary. Collecting the most relevant information up front not only provides sufficient context, but also improves performance and reliability by avoiding repeated tool calls and unpredictable LLM loops.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-456484965"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In-response prompting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The real-world context, however, changes over time. Specifically, once the app is created and accepted, there are new additional files present.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When developing the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt;, we observed that the agentic AI tool (e.g. Cline) using the MCP server often decided to inspect the new app directory tree after creation, causing several LLM roundtrips which cost time and tokens. Or it would run "npm install" again, even though it had already been executed. Or it would make specific coding errors very often in subsequent modifications. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To avoid this, we extended the response of the MCP server after creating the app. Normally, it contains just the success message. &lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server/blob/a5a06382e0b3b8b39beaf1f40e95f2d887b3b50b/src/tools/create_ui5_app/createSuccessMessage.ts#L30-L66" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;But now it includes&lt;/A&gt; a full list of generated files, it states that "npm install" was already executed and it instructs how to prevent those coding errors. Basically, the MCP server response added further updated instructions to the conversation context. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Exactly the same principle was applied in this new Joule feature. While there is no autonomous agent loop in this case which would inspect the new files, the knowledge &lt;EM&gt;which&lt;/EM&gt; files were created can be valuable for the conversation with the user. And while the&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; command doesn't modify any code after app creation (thus avoiding the coding issues), facts like whether "npm install" was already executed, or whether the created UI5 Table in the MainView is lacking any columns, are useful for giving the user hints how to continue. Therefore, the context is extended by adding a hidden message to the conversation history.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-259971460"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Traditional coding has its place(s)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition to the process of context collection, deterministic coding is also used &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; the app has been accepted by the user for making the app consumption as smooth as possible. When inside a CAP project, it for example ensures that the &lt;EM&gt;cds-plugin-ui5&lt;/EM&gt; is added as dependency. This allows the UI5 tooling, including TypeScript transpilation of the UI5 app when needed, to run as part of the "cds watch" or "npm start" script of the CAP project itself.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Also, this dependency and all the UI5 app dependencies need to be installed. Unfortunately, there is a wide range of options and specific setups which might be used for dependency management in the already existing app. Probably&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;npm&lt;/EM&gt;? With or without workspaces? &lt;EM&gt;yarn&lt;/EM&gt;? &lt;EM&gt;pnpm&lt;/EM&gt;? Others? The code detects what is used and tries to cover the 95% case. The initial setup might not be complete in &lt;EM&gt;every&lt;/EM&gt; scenario, but for most users it will “just work,” providing a good developer experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is fine and all, but sometimes one has to go the extra mile and do some coding.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-63457955"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use deterministic code where reasonable (because the space of possibilities is bounded and a deterministic and quick result is beneficial) .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use LLMs for language understanding or dealing with an unpredictable range of possible requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don't try to "program" the LLM with an if/else prompt, but treat it like an intelligent human: state the goal, options and boundaries—and let it decide on its own.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Provide solid pre-collected context so the LLM can make good decisions reliably.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:00:38.750000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-note-implementation-steps/qaa-p/14268236#M4231414</id>
    <title>Re: SAP note implementation steps</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:04:53.862000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>qwertie</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7496</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;this is correction instruction, so when you implent the sapnote via snote, it downloads the other sap notes in background on its own. just be aware of the mentioned Manual Pre-Implementation steps at the end of the sap note&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;br&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-note-implementation-steps/qaa-p/14268236#M4231414"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:04:53.862000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/french-sap-user-group-meeting-on-hcm/ev-p/14268238</id>
    <title>‌🇫🇷‌ French SAP User Group Meeting on HCM</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:05:11.387000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OxanaSidorkina</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170162</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are you a member of the USF French SAP User Group?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Network with SAP experts, partners, and customers, and gain insights into HCM topics in France.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Join the online event&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;USF - Commission Ressources Humaines&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;on the November 18, 2025!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agenda&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;“Fait générateur (FG)” : DSN Consequences of developments related to the Triggering Event (FG) published in BOSS on July 1, 2025 (Chapter 5).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;DSN transition P25V01 to P26V01&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Transfer of Blocks 53/Unit 40 from Parent Block 51/Type 002 to Block 51/Type 001&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- New Legal Code '10' for Field 58.003&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Handling regularization of Contributions for Employees after a change of &amp;nbsp;Complementary Retirement Organization&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Handling cancelation of Contributions for Employees after an error of &amp;nbsp;Complementary Retirement Organization (blocs 838495)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- New codes 146 in Block 81&lt;/SPAN&gt;Unique General Degressive Reduction (RGDU)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unique General Degressive Reduction (RGDU)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Removal of Sickness and Family Banners for Employees Entitled to the RGDU&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Implementation of the new RGDU&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Update of Work Zone HCM France&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q/A&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://usf.mynelis.com/extranet/public/events/426" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;REGISTRATION LINK&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;For expert insights into HCM topics in France, consider joining the &lt;A href="https://workzone.one.int.sap/site#workzone-notification?sap-app-origin-hint=&amp;amp;/groups/rX5gv1Afx8ioVUwWIFvsxC/workpage_tabs/wTtE8xs8ST2ADPBHzUDDST" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;France – Human Capital Management Localization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;Work Zone&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; group.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/localization/french-sap-user-group-meeting-on-hcm/ev-p/14268238"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:05:11.387000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/common-troubleshooting-steps-to-identify-and-resolve-issues-related-to/bc-p/14268239#M9450</id>
    <title>Re: Common troubleshooting steps to identify and resolve issues related to Document Flow in Onboardi</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:05:31.235000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mandiarney</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/107139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Is there any update on the custom for enablement from Engineering?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is impacting testing and acceptance of customized compliance forms and flags for our new hires in several integrated systems dependencies and also has a compliance window for completion aligned. This timeline window will relegate response inevitably inaccessible, and prevent integrated updates to critical dependent external systems such as Payroll, credential creation (AD/Auth apps), etc. This will cripple our feature use and inhibit hiring for certain new hires.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any insight would be greatly appreciated as the Support launchpad outage is impacting ability to get to ongoing Support ticket replies that have been ongoing for 3+ weeks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/common-troubleshooting-steps-to-identify-and-resolve-issues-related-to/bc-p/14268239#M9450"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:05:31.235000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-existing-stock-items-from-non-batch-to-batch-management/qaa-p/14268242#M4231415</id>
    <title>Re: Change existing stock items from Non-Batch to Batch M...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:06:39.955000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dominik_Tylczynski</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/141029</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2264864"&gt;@hasancangunal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'd suggest purchasing SAP tool as described in the note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/533276" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;533276 - Setting the batch management requirement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have used it in a project and have very positive impressions. It simply does work. You need to purchase it separately, but it saves tons of otherwise manual work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dominik Tylczynski&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/change-existing-stock-items-from-non-batch-to-batch-management/qaa-p/14268242#M4231415"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:06:39.955000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-tax-reporter-year-end-2025/bc-p/14268244#M62440</id>
    <title>Re: U.S Tax Reporter Year End 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:10:00.485000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavier_joseph</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/226221</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;any update on&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;One Big Beautiful Bill&amp;nbsp;?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-tax-reporter-year-end-2025/bc-p/14268244#M62440"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:10:00.485000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/gpath-for-json-in-cloud-integration/bc-p/14268248#M176339</id>
    <title>Re: Gpath for JSON in Cloud Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:13:23.239000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simon_bredel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/845730</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/767771"&gt;@lalit2054_46&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; thanks for this blog, it inspired us to follow the same approach.&lt;BR /&gt;However, as we currently face some performance issue with our Cloud Integration, SAP has analyzed our iFlows and suspects the&amp;nbsp;groovy.util.Eval.x() usage as well as the&amp;nbsp;jsonSlurper.parseText() to be the reason. Although we are not sure yet if this is really the case, the&amp;nbsp;code will make the &lt;A title="SAP Design Guideline checks" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/design-guidelines?locale=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Design Guideline checks&lt;/A&gt; for your iFlow fail and the effected iFlows suspicious, so maybe you can adjust it to follow the latest Design Guidleines:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1.) Replace parseText(String) with parse(Reader)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;def request = jsonSlurper.parse(message.getBody(java.io.Reader));&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.) Replace groovy.util.Eval.x with these two lines of code*&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;String str_gpath_expr = properties.get('gpath_expr');&lt;BR /&gt;def gpath_result = request."$str_gpath_expr";&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;*this will only work for simple json structures, not for arrays&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;More details about JsonSlurper can be found here:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A title="Parse JSON - help.sap.com" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/parse-json?locale=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Parse JSON - help.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A title="Stream the XMLSlurper input in Groovy Scripts - community.sap.com" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/stream-the-xmlslurper-input-in-groovy-scripts/ba-p/13348915" target="_blank"&gt;Stream the XMLSlurper input in Groovy Scripts - community.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;More details groovy.util.Eval.x() can be found here:&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Eval usage check - help.sap.com" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/general-scripting-guidelines?locale=en#loiofcbf0f20059a4ffba7dfda7d28830ccd__EVAL_USAGE_CHECK" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Eval usage check - help.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A title="SAP Note 3246624 - Avoid using Eval or Groovy Shell to evaluate script or expressions" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3246624/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 3246624 - Avoid using Eval or Groovy Shell to evaluate script or expressions&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/gpath-for-json-in-cloud-integration/bc-p/14268248#M176339"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:13:23.239000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-success-handling-in-odata-v4-by-submitbatch-patchcompleted-restful/qaa-p/14268249#M4931641</id>
    <title>Re: Error- Success- Handling in OData V4 by SubmitBatch - patchCompleted - RESTful ABAP On Premise</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:13:27.445000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vlad</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8242</uri>
    </author>
    <content>have you handled a situation, when a non-201 error is thrown? E.g., 400 or 500?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-success-handling-in-odata-v4-by-submitbatch-patchcompleted-restful/qaa-p/14268249#M4931641"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:13:27.445000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cost-center-not-retrieved-when-executing-depreciation-posting-run/qaa-p/14268250#M4231416</id>
    <title>Re: Cost center not retrieved when executing depreciation...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:13:45.136000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>uzair_ahmed_acca</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/882659</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;It worked&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cost-center-not-retrieved-when-executing-depreciation-posting-run/qaa-p/14268250#M4231416"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:13:45.136000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cost-center-not-retrieved-when-executing-depreciation-posting-run/qaa-p/14268254#M4231417</id>
    <title>Re: Cost center not retrieved when executing depreciation posting run</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:14:53.337000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>uzair_ahmed_acca</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/882659</uri>
    </author>
    <content>KOSTL was missing in Depreciation run. Thank you.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cost-center-not-retrieved-when-executing-depreciation-posting-run/qaa-p/14268254#M4231417"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:14:53.337000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/getting-started-with-joule-studio-in-sap-build-part-2-developing-and/bc-p/14268256#M186319</id>
    <title>Re: Getting Started with Joule Studio in SAP Build - Part 2: Developing and Deploying a Joule Skill</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:17:07.360000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Necronomicon</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157731</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, I followed the tutorial step by step, still having the error in the end :&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Necronomicon_0-1763047018876.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340222i1F902A060C708EE2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Necronomicon_0-1763047018876.png" alt="Necronomicon_0-1763047018876.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;{&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "type": "CUSTOM",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "level": "warning",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "code": "ACTION_FAILED",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "message": "Message action skipped due to invalid scripting expression in message",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "context": {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "capability": {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "name": "displaybusinesspartner",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "namespace": "joule.ext"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; },&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "dialog_function_name": "displayBP"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; },&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "data": {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "warnings": [&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "scripting_error": "Cannot read properties of undefined (reading 'result')",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "invalid_expression": "{\"type\":\"list\", \"content\": { \"title\":\"Business PArtners\",\"subtitle\":\"Top 20 Business Partners\",\"enableDetailView\":true, \"elements\": [ {{#eachJoin _064fcf3f_327e_34ca_8e62_47dc38ce64a4.body.output.result.d.results}} { \"title\":\"{{BusinessPartner}}\",\"subtitle\":\"{{BusinessPartnerName}}\",\"sections\":[{\"attributes\":[]}] } {{/eachJoin}} ]} }"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; }&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; },&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "timestamp": 1763045101587&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;{&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "type": "CUSTOM",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "level": "info",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "code": "DIALOG_FUNCTION_FINISHED",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "message": "Dialog function displayBP finished",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "context": {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "capability": {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "name": "displaybusinesspartner",&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "namespace": "joule.ext"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; },&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "dialog_function_name": "displayBP"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; },&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "data": {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "results": {}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; },&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; "timestamp": 1763045101591&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/getting-started-with-joule-studio-in-sap-build-part-2-developing-and/bc-p/14268256#M186319"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:17:07.360000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/enable-now-table-of-contents-and-audio-integration-in-scrollable-templates/qaq-p/14268257</id>
    <title>Enable Now – Table of contents and audio integration in scrollable templates</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:17:46.583000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Wibke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2032055</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m currently creating &lt;STRONG&gt;training materials in SAP Enable Now&lt;/STRONG&gt; using a &lt;STRONG&gt;scrollable template&lt;/STRONG&gt; and have two questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Table of contents / anchor links:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Is there a way to include a &lt;STRONG&gt;clickable table of contents&lt;/STRONG&gt; within a scrollable template, so that users can jump directly to specific sections of the content? If yes – how can this be implemented (e.g. via anchors or internal links)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Audio integration:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Has anyone integrated &lt;STRONG&gt;audio files&lt;/STRONG&gt; into a scrollable template – for example, short voice recordings or explanations linked to specific learning sections?&lt;BR /&gt;I’m curious what options are available and what works best in terms of usability and performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any advice, examples, or best practices from your experience would be very helpful!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/enable-now-table-of-contents-and-audio-integration-in-scrollable-templates/qaq-p/14268257"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:17:46.583000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/is-it-possible-to-hide-job-requisition-details-from-the-incumbent-at/qaa-p/14268262#M49328</id>
    <title>Re: Is it possible to hide job requisition details from t...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:19:49.955000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Natalie-K</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/92970</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Daniella,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we had the problem of keeping sensitive replacements away from the org chart. it was no possible to hire the requisition. instead we used the new requisition approach avoiding filling our the position ID. &amp;gt; Go to Recruiting &amp;gt; create new requisition in the top right corner. leave the position ID blank. Create custom field for the position ID for information&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;this way we were able to conduct the search and the full recruiting process. However, if order to complete the hiring of the candidate, at some point we had to update the requisition with the position ID. As we use the full recruiting life cycle this was an important last step for HR to be able to hire the candidate from the pending hires from recruiting module.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;hope this help&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Natalie&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/is-it-possible-to-hide-job-requisition-details-from-the-incumbent-at/qaa-p/14268262#M49328"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:19:49.955000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sd-invoice-output-type-external-email-to-multiple-customer-recipient/bc-p/14268263#M72246</id>
    <title>Re: SD Invoice Output Type - External Email to Multiple Customer Recipient</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:22:23.357000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anannya</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1809615</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, very nice blog !&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My question is How are you debugging this email output type? My guess is&amp;nbsp; we need maintain email output type in header -&amp;gt;output , and then we , select Further processing, and select the first option , send as&amp;nbsp; job or option 2 ( we are not selecting send immediately). Then do we use the&amp;nbsp;rsnast00 program to run this output type.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Will this work.?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My debugger in RLB_INVOICE is not triggering when i try to test it. i used both type of debugging.&amp;nbsp; Do let me know ASAP.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sd-invoice-output-type-external-email-to-multiple-customer-recipient/bc-p/14268263#M72246"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:22:23.357000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/supercharge-sap-automate-new-hire-events-with-sap-build-process-automation/ba-p/14268165</id>
    <title>Supercharge SAP: Automate New Hire Events with SAP Build Process Automation and SuccessFactors</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:24:14.773000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>acharyaw</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/151637</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764765055"&gt;Overview&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/technology-platform/process-automation/features.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;a low-code/no-code platform that enables users to automate business processes and tasks using visual drag-and-drop tools.&amp;nbsp;It combines workflow automation, robotic process automation (RPA), and embedded AI capabilities to streamline processes and improve efficiency.&amp;nbsp; To know about the product roadmap, you can follow the link &lt;A href="http://roadmaps.sap.com/board?range=all&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73554900100800006111#Q4%202025" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-cloud-application-event-hub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Event Hub&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;offers a flexible solution to distribute business events across the SAP cloud landscape. This service supports SAP's strategic event-driven architecture initiative to create a well-defined, easily consumable and extensible ecosystem for exchanging SAP business events.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog explains how to use the event-driven automation for the New Hire Onboarding scenario spanning across&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/hcm.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/india/products/technology-platform/process-automation/features.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/A&gt;(SBPA) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-cloud-application-event-hub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Event Hub&lt;/A&gt;. For more information on Success Factors events in Business Accelerator Hub read&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/search?searchterm=success%20factor&amp;amp;tab=Event%20Objects&amp;amp;$refinedBy=true&amp;amp;$type=(%22Event%20Object%22,%22SAP%20Event%20Package%22)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;. Read&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-onboarding/implementing-onboarding/initiating-onboarding-process-manually?q=new+hire+onboarding" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for more details on the scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The integration support of SAP Build Process Automation with SAP Success Factors via SAP Cloud Application Event Hub was released from SAP Build in Q2 2025. For more details refer to the YouTube video&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gaToaQGpPE8" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Whats New in SAP Build – Q2 2025 Highlights&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and Blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-sap-build-q2-2025-release-highlights/ba-p/14142487" target="_blank"&gt;What’s New in SAP Build Q2 2025 - Release Highlights&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;Note : Integration of SAP Build Process Automation with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public&amp;nbsp; Edition and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition is also available with Event Mesh and Advanced Event Mesh.&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are the reference blogs&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/event-mesh-and-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-setup-for-sap-build-process/ba-p/13791480" target="_blank"&gt;Event Mesh and SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud Setup for SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/configure-sap-enterprise-messaging-for-sap-s-4hana-on-premise-2020-via/ba-p/13468533" target="_blank"&gt;Configure SAP Enterprise Messaging for SAP S/4HANA On-Premise 2020 via Service Key&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568251550"&gt;New Hire Scenario Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Onboarding process is a crucial and very common activity of Human Resource department of any organization, influencing the experience and success of new hires. Organisations often face challenges in onboarding process especially with equipment and trainings that are required by the new-hire. If these not done right, the onboarding process can involve manual and repetitive tasks, leading to inefficiencies and delays. An event-driven solution using process automation and customization to provide a personalized onboarding experience for new hires is much needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The current scenario is based on real-time event-driven business process integrations. It involves starting an approval workflow process using the SAP Build Process Automation solution, ensuring you involve the relevant stakeholders in certain scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SFSFArchitecture.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340215iE40CFC4AEC9854F8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SFSFArchitecture.png" alt="SFSFArchitecture.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371738045"&gt;Pre-requisite:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The BTP and the SFSF systems needs to be connected already. This can be done by using Event Mesh, Advanced Event Mesh or SAP Cloud Application Event Hub.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The details of the setup to be done using Cloud Application Event Hub is mentioned in the blog &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://Integrating SAP SuccessFactors with SAP Build Process Automation via SAP Cloud Application Event Hub" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integrating SAP SuccessFactors with SAP Build Process Automation via SAP Cloud Application Event Hub&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;and the Devtoberfest video&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CMVEobhPSIw&amp;amp;list=PL6RpkC85SLQA4Lb9qdevEkcqoCJH2bXek&amp;amp;index=50" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using Intermediate Message Events and Success Factors Events in SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175224540"&gt;Creating the process step by step&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's now create an end to end process. In this section we will create event triggers, add actions, add decisions, approval forms and email notifications.&amp;nbsp; Below are the sample steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107793754"&gt;1. Add an Event Trigger to start the process&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The event here is "New Hire Data Review Initiated".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NewHireDataEventAdded.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340203iE1BB4ED37CC633CD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NewHireDataEventAdded.png" alt="NewHireDataEventAdded.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;Note: The event project should be created , released and published in Lobby already. &lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can refer to this blog link on how to create an Event project in the Lobby or this YouTube video. &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/event/sap-sf-processStep-v1/resource" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Here&lt;/A&gt; is the link for reference in Business Accelerator Hub for details on the &lt;SPAN&gt;New Hire Data Review Initiated event&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911280249"&gt;2. Add the Actions to get further details of the new hire&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need to use additional APIs to get further details for employee and job details. The APIs used in this example are the&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a.&amp;nbsp; GET for /PerPerson('{personIdExternal}') from the&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/ECPersonalInformation/resource/PerPerson" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Personal Information API &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;b.&amp;nbsp; GET for&amp;nbsp;/EmpEmployment(personIdExternal='{personIdExternal}',userId='{userId}') from the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/ECEmploymentInformation/resource/EmpEmployment" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Employment Information API&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GetEmployementDetailsByKeyGeneral.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340205iE11030ACCBD8F5CE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="GetEmployementDetailsByKeyGeneral.png" alt="GetEmployementDetailsByKeyGeneral.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GetEmployementDetailsByKeyMapping.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340207i9AFB542D3C67313E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="GetEmployementDetailsByKeyMapping.png" alt="GetEmployementDetailsByKeyMapping.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GetPerPersonByKeyMapping.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340204i1ED44E93B2E02687/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="GetPerPersonByKeyMapping.png" alt="GetPerPersonByKeyMapping.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Map the inputs of Actions to the required inputs from the events.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;Note: The action projects should be created , released and published in Lobby already.&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714766744"&gt;3. Add decisions to determine the Equipment and Trainings for new hire&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp; EquipmentDetermination Decision takes JobTitle as an Input and Output can be a list of Equipment for which we need to create a Purchase Order later in the S/4HANA Public Cloud System via Actions(APIs).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp; TrainingDetermination Decision can take JobTitle as an Input and Output of&amp;nbsp; can be a list of Trainings that are required for the employee, which can be notified to the&amp;nbsp; employee via email after successful approval.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mapJobTitleForEquipmentDetermination.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340211i6BB3185BB633033E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mapJobTitleForEquipmentDetermination.png" alt="mapJobTitleForEquipmentDetermination.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MapJobTitleForTrainingDetermination.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340210i25436FBB2E0DAC14/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MapJobTitleForTrainingDetermination.png" alt="MapJobTitleForTrainingDetermination.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518253239"&gt;4. Create an Approval form&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Approval form shows the new hire data to be reviewed. Both the outputs from Equipment and Training can be used in the approval form. There are two options for user - Approve and Reject.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Add the Training and Equipment Approval Form.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340213iC47F880A5B164B7A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Add the Training and Equipment Approval Form.png" alt="Add the Training and Equipment Approval Form.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-321739734"&gt;5. Create a Purchase Order via Actions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upon successful Approval, add an Action call to create a Purchase Order in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public System with the equipment determined for the new hire.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The required SAP S/4HANA API call is&amp;nbsp; : POST for&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/CE_PURCHASEORDER_0001/resource/Purchase_Order" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;/PurchaseOrder.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-125226229"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6. Add email notifications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can add email notification after the Purchase Order is successfully created and also for rejection scenario. The sample process looks like the following:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WholeProcess.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340196i25A8F4ECB23DBF9A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="WholeProcess.jpg" alt="WholeProcess.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-146884362"&gt;Execute the process:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Add a new employee in the SAP SuccessFactors application using "Add New Hire to Onboarding". This will create an event "New Hire Data Review Initiated" from the SAP Success Factors system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="acharyaw_0-1763046678307.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340217i635B3F084E9022E6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="acharyaw_0-1763046678307.png" alt="acharyaw_0-1763046678307.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. In SAP Build Process Automation Approve/reject the equipment and training assignment to the new hire that you have created in the previous step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ApprovalFormReview.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340223iB9EC47B1ED55915C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ApprovalFormReview.png" alt="ApprovalFormReview.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Purchase order will be created for the equipment approved in the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition and end users will be notified accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="acharyaw_1-1763046840407.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340219i38A842973CD8E3CE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="acharyaw_1-1763046840407.png" alt="acharyaw_1-1763046840407.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--49629143"&gt;Tips and Tricks:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To check if events are configured properly and are reaching SBPA, check the SAP Build Lobby -&amp;gt; Monitoring -&amp;gt; Acquired Events -&amp;gt; Business Events. Here you will find information on the business events that are received by SAP Build Process Automation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The SFSF system needs to be enabled for sending events.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The new hire event is dispatched only when all the steps are completed, i.e. all the OK windows are acknowledged by user.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Proper destination for APIs for SFSF needs to be configured in BTP with correct API user in SFSF system&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Proper destination for APIs for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Edition system should be configured with appropriate communication users.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SMTP Email destination needs to be created in BTP subaccount for the email tasks to work.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check that events and actions are working fine before using them in the project.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For any further queries, please feel to reach out ! &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to thank my co - author Rumen for his support in creating this content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy eventing !&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/supercharge-sap-automate-new-hire-events-with-sap-build-process-automation/ba-p/14268165"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:24:14.773000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mm43-restriction-of-finance-view-permerchandise-categories-without/qaa-p/14268264#M4231418</id>
    <title>Re: MM43 - restriction of finance view permerchandise categories without restricting material master</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:26:37.648000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>khalil2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1881895</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Maybe a non authorization configuration such as assigning Screen Sequences to users/material types is the solution ?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mm43-restriction-of-finance-view-permerchandise-categories-without/qaa-p/14268264#M4231418"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:26:37.648000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/bc-p/14268265#M186320</id>
    <title>Re: BTP Trial Update: CF Runtime Availability</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:26:58.157000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CarolinBoeke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44516</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2233258"&gt;@alrdh&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thank you for asking. Kyma is indeed not affected and can be an alternative.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Carolin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/bc-p/14268265#M186320"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:26:58.157000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-cpi-request-reply-org-apache-camel-component-cxf-converter/qaa-p/14268266#M4931642</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CPI Request-reply org.apache.camel.component.cxf....</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:29:12.280000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>philippeaddor</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/165304</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi there, it's a very old thread. But for the sake of completeness, here my possible reason for the issue:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;simply do&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;msg.getBody(String)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;And you should get the actual text back.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-cpi-request-reply-org-apache-camel-component-cxf-converter/qaa-p/14268266#M4931642"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:29:12.280000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-connect-sap-cloud-alm-and-a-test-automation-tool/bc-p/14268267#M186321</id>
    <title>Re: How to connect SAP Cloud ALM and a Test Automation Tool</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:30:00.190000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>XavierPicquart</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/164863</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/147458"&gt;@HemantVaswani6&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is valid for cloud solutions only or you have to develop a connector.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Xavier&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-connect-sap-cloud-alm-and-a-test-automation-tool/bc-p/14268267#M186321"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:30:00.190000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-custom-fields-for-pricing-in-sales-documents/bc-p/14268268#M62441</id>
    <title>Re: How to Use Custom Fields for Pricing in Sales Documents</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:30:20.386000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jens_Koyen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/133406</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1462395"&gt;@WesleyZhang&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, thank you for this insightful approach. Me and my customer were wondering if we can apply the same principles to purchasing pricing as well? More specifically we want to add standard SAP fields such as "WBS" and "Project" to the access sequence of purchasing pricing (previous MEK2 in ECC).&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Many thanks for any feedback!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-custom-fields-for-pricing-in-sales-documents/bc-p/14268268#M62441"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:30:20.386000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sales-order-bom-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-edition/qaa-p/14268269#M4231419</id>
    <title>Re: Sales Order BOM - SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:30:31.014000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Brinda911</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1430989</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/178534"&gt;@Suryaprakash13&lt;/a&gt; I’ve already completed all the necessary configuration steps, but I’m still encountering an issue with the Order BOM, which isn’t reflecting correctly in the Sales Order. The item category group for the header (kit) material is set to ERLA, and the subcomponents are using NORM. In the Sales Order, the system determines item category TAQ for the header item, which is pricing at the header level while the components appear at the item level. The issue is that the specific Order BOM I created using the “Manage Order BOM – Version 2” Fiori app for the kit material TG11 does not explode when I create or edit the Sales Order. Additionally, I’m unable to delete the material since the system returns the message “Order item is a bill of material.” If you do have any insights let me know as to why the Order BOM functionality in the Manage Order BOM – Version 2 app isn’t working as expected in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud, and whether there are additional steps or dependencies required for the BOM explosion to occur at the Sales Order level?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sales-order-bom-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-edition/qaa-p/14268269#M4231419"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:30:31.014000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/activity-type-confirmation-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-professional/qaq-p/14268270</id>
    <title>Activity type confirmation in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud Professional Services</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:35:00.468000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Francesco_Spaggiari1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1504423</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi gurus,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm facing an issue during actual confirmation of activity types in the Customer Project about Professional Services business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the fixed price contract, if I plan certain activity types on the work packages and then finalize them with different activity types , the system increases the value of planned costs by the amount I calculated with the activity type different from the planned one. Could anyone kindly explain to me why it behaves like this and if there is a way to ensure that the amount I calculate (with an activity type different from the planned one)&amp;nbsp; contributes to the progress of the project without being&amp;nbsp;added to the planned cost (and so without influencing the calculation of POC) ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/activity-type-confirmation-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-professional/qaq-p/14268270"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:35:00.468000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/cif-of-purchase-info-record-from-s-4-to-eppds/qaa-p/14268271#M208137</id>
    <title>Re: CIF of Purchase Info Record from S/4 to ePPDS</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:36:19.249000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>maturu_sravan14</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/787282</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;HI&amp;nbsp;SteevesSegura,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is the selection criteria when you create a IM?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please make sure all the materials which have advanced planning have the MRP type X0 / X*.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the IM is created give the selection criteria as MRP type that will solve your issue&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sravan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/cif-of-purchase-info-record-from-s-4-to-eppds/qaa-p/14268271#M208137"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:36:19.249000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/kba2963059/qaa-p/14268272#M4231421</id>
    <title>Re: KBA2963059</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:39:15.303000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, thank you for your question. It has been forwarded to the experts. Kind regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/kba2963059/qaa-p/14268272#M4231421"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:39:15.303000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/create-supplier-invoice-how-to-disable-the-post-button/qaq-p/14268273</id>
    <title>Create supplier invoice: How to disable the Post button</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:39:19.427000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;App id-F0859-Create supplier invoice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need to restrict this app from Posting, POST icon should be Disabled.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/create-supplier-invoice-how-to-disable-the-post-button/qaq-p/14268273"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:39:19.427000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/create-supplier-invoice-how-to-disable-the-post-button/qaa-p/14268274#M4231423</id>
    <title>Re: Create supplier invoice: How to disable the Post button</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:39:27.200000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In standard, the&lt;EM&gt; 'Post'&lt;/EM&gt; button can be disabled only via user authorization level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, authority object &lt;STRONG&gt;M_RECH_BUK&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be used for that kind of control.&lt;BR /&gt;Only users authorized for activity &lt;STRONG&gt;01&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;EM&gt;create&lt;/EM&gt;) can view the &lt;EM&gt;'Post'&lt;/EM&gt; button. Removing that activity from them would restrict the ability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If a user is authorized to park invoices, but not post them, you can disable activity &lt;STRONG&gt;01&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;EM&gt;create&lt;/EM&gt;) and keep activity &lt;STRONG&gt;77&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;EM&gt;park&lt;/EM&gt;) enabled.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Further information can be found in KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2931137" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2931137 - User authorizations in Supplier Invoice Apps (On Premise) - SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/create-supplier-invoice-how-to-disable-the-post-button/qaa-p/14268274#M4231423"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:39:27.200000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/clarification-on-e-r-key-diff-balance-field-in-fcv-app-s-4hana-cloud-public/qaa-p/14268276#M256386</id>
    <title>Re: Clarification on “E/R key diff. balance” Field in FCV App (S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:41:46.432000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, thank you for your question. It has been forwarded to the experts. Kind regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/clarification-on-e-r-key-diff-balance-field-in-fcv-app-s-4hana-cloud-public/qaa-p/14268276#M256386"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:41:46.432000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-handle-fixed-asset-impairment-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-us-gaap/qaa-p/14268278#M4231424</id>
    <title>Re: How to handle fixed asset impairment in S/4HANA Public Cloud (US GAAP)?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:42:55.817000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, thank you for your question. It has been forwarded to the experts. Kind regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-handle-fixed-asset-impairment-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-us-gaap/qaa-p/14268278#M4231424"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:42:55.817000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/coe-rfl01-what-is-the-difference-between-withholding-tax-jobs/qaq-p/14268280</id>
    <title>#COE#RFL01- What is the difference between withholding tax jobs?</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:46:35.306000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MounaAndre</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135575</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp; All,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I tried two jobs for the Withholding tax to better understand their usefulness and the scenarios in which they can be used:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1-&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recreate and Change Withholding Tax Data with 0% Witholding TaxRate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2-&amp;nbsp;Adjustment of Withholding Tax Information to Relevant Types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Despite the SAP documentation, it is still unclear to me because the result I am supposed to get is not really what I am getting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I suspect that it is me who does not fully understand how it works.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone explain the use cases and the difference between these two jobs to me, or point me towards some blogs, please?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many thanks!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mouna&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition+Finance/pd-p/66233466-fcd6-45d2-a9ae-2cba38c72e19" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="232-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Finance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/coe-rfl01-what-is-the-difference-between-withholding-tax-jobs/qaq-p/14268280"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:46:35.306000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/handling-long-field-names-in-odata-rap-api-s/bc-p/14268279#M176340</id>
    <title>Re: Handling Long Field Names in OData / RAP API's</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:46:39.343000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jaydeep</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179872</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Dinesh,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, what are the best practices to handle special characters in long string parameters?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/handling-long-field-names-in-odata-rap-api-s/bc-p/14268279#M176340"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:46:39.343000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cancel-maintenance-confirmation-to-an-order-with-several-confirmations-in/qaa-p/14268281#M4231426</id>
    <title>Re: Cancel maintenance confirmation to an order with several confirmations in cloud public edition 2</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:46:44.129000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, thank you for your question. It has been forwarded to the experts. Kind regards, Henrike</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cancel-maintenance-confirmation-to-an-order-with-several-confirmations-in/qaa-p/14268281#M4231426"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:46:44.129000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-tool-to-copy-configuration-data-to-clients-scc1n/bc-p/14268282#M186322</id>
    <title>Re: New Tool to Copy Configuration Data to Clients (SCC1N)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:49:30.878000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JaySchwendemann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/263</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are currently on a one production client setup over all the SAP landscape (all on-prem for the time being). This of course is a enviable state &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":beaming_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😁&lt;/span&gt; We are now considering to willfully create a second client in an EWM system and there, introduce as well a new warehouse number. Reasoning will be that we foresee different factors where that warehouse (site) might need to have it's own production instance in the future which then resides in that country to minimize latency. Customizing will be valid for all clients in such a scenario, because main differentiation will be on warehouse number, not on client.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That all being said we currently do not have much knowledge when it comes to dealing with multiple clients, so take the following with a (large) grain of salt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my (possibly wrong&amp;nbsp; or incomplete) opinion we might have like a setup like so:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;DEV | QAS | PRD System&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Client 100 (Main)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Client 200 (Country)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;We then would, for the sake of simplicity create all customizing in DEV.100 and after release of that TR will import it in DEV.200, too, as well as in QAS.100 and QAS.200 and so on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now the consultant or developer who would want to do some unit tests would need to utilize SCC1N to bring the changes from DEV.100 to DEV.200 without releasing the TR.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My fear is, that this overhead will hinder the developers and consultants that simply are not used working this way, resulting in lackluster performance or hidden or open rebellion &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":winking_face:"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;So here's my question&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is this envisioned setup / approach with a master customizing client and hence difficult unit test situation in DEV system a simple reality in multi client setup with only master customizing?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Will SCC1N be something scheduled (very) periodically in such a scenario or will it be moslty an on-demand process initiated by the developer or consultant&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In our simple scenario where we have one master client 100 and use the 200 client just for sake of future possible carveout: Are there better options than the one envisioned?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Jens&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-tool-to-copy-configuration-data-to-clients-scc1n/bc-p/14268282#M186322"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:49:30.878000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cancel-maintenance-confirmation-to-an-order-with-several-confirmations-in/qaa-p/14268283#M4231427</id>
    <title>Re: Cancel maintenance confirmation to an order with seve...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:49:50.494000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Good day&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2208418"&gt;@S0027154449&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Have a look at the following references for further details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/c0c54048d35849128be8e872df5bea6d/14ac8e7d688842a08e30125dfc025c07.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Maintenance Order Confirmation&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d35113ee62644d3abee1aaec148291d9/5cdf2067f4a2498d953d9e7a1242f291.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cancel Confirmation.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In public cloud, the IW45 transaction is a limited functional app wrapper for compatibility purposes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To summarise, if your order contains multiple confirmations, the public cloud version of IW45 does not allow you to select and cancel a specific one. The system mentioning that IW45 is not acting on the selected row is because the cancellation function is disabled for multiple confirmations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Due to the public cloud clean-core approach, some SAPGUI-style functions from technical transactions were removed. The IW45 cancellation in public cloud was replaced with Change Maintenance Order and Manage Maintenance Order Confirmations App. Single and multiple confirmations can be done when you select specific confirmation ID and then choose Functions à Cancel Confirmation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cancel-maintenance-confirmation-to-an-order-with-several-confirmations-in/qaa-p/14268283#M4231427"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:49:50.494000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/i-have-resolved-this-issue-myself-please-delete-it/qaa-p/14268288#M256387</id>
    <title>Re: I have resolved this issue myself. Please delete it.</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:53:25.031000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you very much for your question and great that you found the solution yourself. Thanks for letting us know!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Henrike&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/i-have-resolved-this-issue-myself-please-delete-it/qaa-p/14268288#M256387"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:53:25.031000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/accessing-ssam-data-using-services-and-actions-in-sap-dynamic-from-builder/qaa-p/14268289#M4931644</id>
    <title>Re: Accessing SSAM Data Using Services and Actions in SAP...</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:54:09.270000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Cliff_Carter</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1776873</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this case, the data is being retrieved from the local database on the mobile device. The same data is not available in the web browser environment, so the test tab will show a failure. This is a limitation of using the type of query shown here, that it will not work without SSAM. If you examine the action the &lt;STRONG&gt;fr:is-browser-environment()&lt;/STRONG&gt; formula is there to ensure the action only runs on the device.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want specifically the username, that can be available with the '&lt;STRONG&gt;fr:username()&lt;/STRONG&gt;' formula as the calculated value within a control and this function should return the current user's username as returned by the IDP. This functionality works in both online and offline environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cliff&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/accessing-ssam-data-using-services-and-actions-in-sap-dynamic-from-builder/qaa-p/14268289#M4931644"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:54:09.270000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
