<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-12-30T03:59:01.133817+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/navigating-consent-legal-and-ethical-perspectives-on-transparency/ba-p/14298028</id>
    <title>Navigating consent: legal and ethical perspectives on transparency</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T13:28:44.750000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GiselleGomezJolis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1956010</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="GiselleGomezJolis_2-1766792888079.jpeg" style="width: 633px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356209i60E862F9C043900C/image-dimensions/633x356/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="633" height="356" role="button" title="GiselleGomezJolis_2-1766792888079.jpeg" alt="GiselleGomezJolis_2-1766792888079.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1767534536"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In aviation, pre-flight checklists and safety briefings are non-negotiable—a point Abhishek emphasized in his recent post on AI safety ( &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/defining-safe-ai-transparency-within-ideation-and-validation/ba-p/14283700" target="_blank"&gt;Engineering AI Safety part 1&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/engineering-ai-transparency-from-build-to-operations-part-2/ba-p/14272798" target="_blank"&gt;Engineering AI Safety part 2&lt;/A&gt; ). For AI, the concept of “safety” extends beyond technical boundaries to include ethical and legal dimensions, and consent is a critical part of that equation. Just as pilots rely on checklists before takeoff, AI systems need transparent and robust consent mechanisms before engaging in digital interactions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In particular, consent in AI interactions presents a growing challenge: users often engage with intelligent systems without realizing it, and when consent is requested, it is frequently vague, overly technical, or legally insufficient. This lack of clarity can lead to unintended data use, privacy risks, and erosion of trust. Consider a common use case: a customer interacting with a virtual assistant that collects behavioral data to improve service. Without clear disclaimers or meaningful consent mechanisms, the user may unknowingly agree to data processing that affects their rights. This scenario highlights the urgent need for transparent, accessible, and informed consent structures that reflect the dynamic nature of AI and empower individuals to make conscious decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-2087351907"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1245424807"&gt;1. Safety instructions before takeoff: understanding consent, the foundation of agreement&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before any flight, it is imperative for passengers to comprehend the safety instructions, which are meticulously reiterated by flight attendants on every journey without exception. This is the basis to equip all passengers appropriately in any situation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly, consent in AI necessitates the same level of clarity and understanding before 'takeoff'—a clear explication is crucial to enable informed decision-making&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consent&lt;/STRONG&gt; can be defined as "to agree to something or give your permission for something" (&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://www.oed.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Oxford English Dictionary&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;) or as "permission or agreement; the state of agreeing with someone or something." (&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dictionary.cambridge.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Cambridge Dictionary&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;). Consent often involves synonyms such as accept, approve, and go along with, but it is not just that: it is a &lt;STRONG&gt;shared decision-making process&lt;/STRONG&gt;. However, the essence of consent lies not only in agreeing to something but in &lt;STRONG&gt;understanding precisely what is being accepted&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To ensure valid and informed consent, while each country has specific national regulations, there are &lt;STRONG&gt;universal requirements&lt;/STRONG&gt; that must be met in all cases, including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Capacity:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Individuals must be of legal age and possess the mental maturity to fully understand what they are consenting to.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Voluntary agreement:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Consent must be given freely, without any form of coercion, manipulation, or deception.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clear content:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The subject of consent must be clearly defined and easily understandable. This is crucial for ensuring that individuals fully grasp the nature and implications of what they are agreeing to.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Form:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Depending on the nature of what is being consented to, specific forms or procedures may be required according to applicable laws and standards, e.g. consent provided in the written form may be required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1694324897"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-852397797"&gt;2. Flight path and destination clarity: the scope of consent, what are you agreeing to?&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In aviation, it's crucial to define flight paths and destinations clearly before takeoff, ensuring a smooth and safe journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consent is a fundamental element in various contexts, ranging from traditional contracts and personal data processing including cookies, to modern interactions with AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The evolution of AI has introduced new dynamics in the realm of consent, often involving personal data that fuels AI models, leading to complex legal landscapes and ethical dilemmas. As AI technologies become increasingly integrated into our lives, individuals may &lt;STRONG&gt;unknowingly consent&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the use of their personal data, resulting in &lt;STRONG&gt;privacy breaches&lt;/STRONG&gt; and potential &lt;STRONG&gt;misuse of information&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Therefore, disclaimers play a crucial role by providing the necessary information for individuals to consciously decide what they are consenting to. Without effective disclaimers, individuals risk consenting to broad or vague terms that may allow their data to be used in unintended ways. For instance, personal data could be used to train AI models for purposes not originally agreed upon, leading to ethical concerns and legal repercussions. Consequently, legal professionals must offer clear guidance on how &lt;STRONG&gt;legal notices and disclaimers&lt;/STRONG&gt; must be structured and understood, ensuring they are comprehensible and that those consenting do so in a prior, free, and informed manner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-784967011"&gt;i. Aircraft documentation and permits: consent to personal data processing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Aircrafts require comprehensive documentation and necessary permits to fly, ensuring all safety and regulatory standards are met. In a similar vein, &lt;STRONG&gt;data processing&lt;/STRONG&gt; demands formalized and documented consent, safeguarding compliance with legal standards and securing data integrity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Before the rise of AI-specific regulations, the&lt;STRONG&gt; General Data Protection Regulation &lt;/STRONG&gt;(&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GDPR&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;) stood as a cornerstone for data protection in the EU, offering a robust framework for consent related to personal data processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Under GDPR, consent is defined in Article 4 as a "freely given, specific, informed and unambiguous indication of the data subject's wishes, signified by a statement or a clear affirmative action."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;And Article 7 elaborates on the conditions under which consent is valid, highlighting the importance of clarity, documentation, and the subject's right to withdraw consent with ease.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Further insights are provided in Recital 32, which underscores the need for a clear affirmative act to establish consent, cautioning against methods like silence or pre-ticked boxes.&amp;nbsp; Recital 42 insists on intelligibility, accessibility, and fairness in consent declarations, emphasizing the necessity for the data subject to have genuine choice and awareness of processing purposes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Details on SAP’s commitment to safeguarding data protection and privacy that goes beyond mere GDPR compliance can be found here &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center/data-privacy.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center/data-privacy.html&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-588453506"&gt;ii.&amp;nbsp; Autopilot vs. Human control: consent to interact with AI&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Users must know when AI is “piloting” decisions and what risks that entails.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The contemporary challenge lies in ensuring individuals understand interaction with AI. Several barriers exist to obtaining valid consent in this arena:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clarity in terms:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Terms and conditions must be clear, concise, and devoid of jargon. Ambiguous language can place individuals in a vulnerable spot, as most people tend to skim through agreements without thorough understanding.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Complexity of technology&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;Explaining AI technology—how data is captured and trained, the workings of algorithms for example—is inherently challenging. People interacting with AI are often not specialists and may struggle to fully comprehend the technicalities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic nature of AI:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;AI systems, especially those with machine learning capabilities, continually evolve. Static explanations cannot capture the adaptive nature of AI technologies, which may change the scope and impact of consent over time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Duration of consent:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Granting indefinite consent poses issues, given AI's evolving landscape. Consent today reflects current technological conditions, which could subsequently change. While periodic consents are recommended to account for technological advancements, it is crucial to ensure that re-confirming consent is not merely a formality without substance. The reasons and changes behind each request for consent should be explained clearly and meaningfully, so users understand the value and importance of their informed consent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Awareness of AI interaction:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Individuals should be clearly informed when they are interacting with an AI system. Without this awareness, users might misinterpret AI-generated content as being human-driven, which could lead to misunderstandings or misplaced trust.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Challenges when using AI that users should be aware of include: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI hallucinations:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;AI can produce false or misleading information, known as hallucinations. Users must be made aware of this possibility, ensuring that their consent to interact with AI includes acknowledgment of these risks to avoid confusion or manipulation, they accept a need to verify the system output before further use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bias in AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;AI systems can harbor biases, impacting the neutrality and fairness of outputs. Such biases can affect humans in significant ways, altering perceptions and decisions based on skewed information.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Decision-Making (ADM) and profiling: &lt;/STRONG&gt;individuals have the right not to be subjected to decisions made solely by automated processes, including profiling, that have legal or similarly significant effects. Consent to interact with AI can lead to serious legal and personal consequences if it involves ADM. Users should be aware that AI systems may make decisions impacting their rights, such as credit approvals or job evaluations, without human intervention. Ensuring informed consent means clearly explaining these potential outcomes and allowing individuals to opt-out or request human oversight where possible. Each of these aspects underscores the essential role of transparency in interactions with AI systems. Transparency not only fosters trust and understanding among users but also ensures that consent is informed, relevant, and reflective of the evolving nature of technology. By prioritizing clarity, awareness, and regular updates on AI functionality and potential risks, we uphold the principle of transparency, which is crucial for ethical and effective engagement with AI technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Understanding these complexities is pivotal for legal professionals guiding stakeholders through the intricacies of consent in digital and AI-driven environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Not only from a legal but also from an ethical perspective, the risks that AI automation and autonomy pose to individuals are important to consider: In SAP’s AI Ethics Governance process, use cases that involve automated decision making need to specifically prove that this doesn’t entail significant harm for individuals (see &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/03/7211ee96-647e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Ethics Handbook&lt;/A&gt;, chapter AI Ethics Assessment Process).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-908270877"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-66343777"&gt;3. International frameworks: navigating the regulation of AI consent&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Global aviation relies on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.icao.int/safety-management/standards-and-recommended-practices-sarps" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ICAO standards&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; to ensure safe flights across all skies—AI needs similar international frameworks to guarantee transparency and informed consent in any digital “airspace.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the rapidly evolving sphere of AI, numerous &lt;STRONG&gt;international regulations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, recommendations, and codes of conduct are shaping the landscape of consent. This comprehensive set of guidelines aims to ensure ethical AI interaction and transparency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some the most notable frameworks are &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://artificialintelligenceact.eu" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;EU AI Act&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000380455" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UNESCO's Recommendation on the Ethics of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://op.europa.eu/en/publication-detail/-/publication/d3988569-0434-11ea-8c1f-01aa75ed71a1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;EU's Ethics Guidelines for Trustworthy AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;OECD AI Principles&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/hiroshima-process-international-code-conduct-advanced-ai-systems" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Code of Conduct for AI Developers under the Hiroshima AI Process&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/contents-code-gpai?utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Code of Practice for the AI Act&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, among others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1087009"&gt;Summary of international requirements:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The global standards for consent in AI focus on several key principles:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensuring humans are aware they are &lt;STRONG&gt;interacting with AI systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;, such as chatbots or digital assistants, by clearly stating their AI nature.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Providing clear and distinguishable identification of AI upon first interaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Utilizing mechanisms such as &lt;STRONG&gt;labels or disclaimers&lt;/STRONG&gt;, akin to widely recognized symbols or logos.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Meeting &lt;STRONG&gt;accessibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; requirements for vulnerable populations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Aligning biometric data processing with GDPR protocols to safeguard emotions or intentions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Facilitating human interaction options when essential for upholding fundamental rights, particularly in the context of ADM processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recognizing exceptions, such as obviousness to informed users or for criminal investigations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These international guidelines establish a cohesive ethical and transparent framework for AI consent, paving the way for responsible AI deployment and fostering trust across diverse demographics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transparency &lt;/STRONG&gt;is a foundational principle across international AI ethics frameworks. While explicit consent is required in certain contexts, many regulations recognize that transparency obligations may be fulfilled through clear AI notices or disclosures. Guidelines from bodies such as &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.unesco.org/en/artificial-intelligence/recommendation-ethics#:~:text=The%20use%20of%20AI%20systems,may%20result%20from%20such%20uses.&amp;amp;text=Unwanted%20harms%20(safety%20risks)%20as,and%20addressed%20by%20AI%20actors." target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, the &lt;SPAN&gt;OECD&lt;/SPAN&gt;, and the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;European Commission&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; emphasize the importance of informing individuals when interacting with AI systems, explaining how decisions are made, and ensuring that AI processes are traceable and understandable. These measures aim to safeguard human rights and foster trust in AI technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId--1023958185"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-246543345"&gt;4. Recommendations: crafting effective disclaimers for valid consent&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;To achieve valid consent in AI interactions, it is crucial to address both the clarity of communication and user understanding, and therefore, it is necessary to be transparent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are key recommendations to ensure that disclaimers are effective and consent is valid:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--243373167"&gt;Prioritize clarity and simplicity&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use clear language: Employ straightforward, &lt;STRONG&gt;accessible language&lt;/STRONG&gt; that avoids technical jargon. The goal is to ensure that users of all backgrounds – the average person- can easily understand the information presented.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Concise disclaimers: Keep disclaimers brief but comprehensive. Focus on delivering &lt;STRONG&gt;essential information&lt;/STRONG&gt; that captures the nature of AI interactions and any implications they may have. A valuable initiative to consider is the proposal by the &lt;SPAN&gt;Consumer Affairs Advisory Council&lt;/SPAN&gt;, which suggests that terms of service be presented in a single page, containing no more than 500 words&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--439886672"&gt;Enhance transparency&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explain AI functionality: Clearly describe how the AI system processes data, makes decisions, and its intended use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify AI systems: Ensure that AI systems are&lt;STRONG&gt; explicitly identified as such&lt;/STRONG&gt;, confirming users are aware they are interacting with non-human technology.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--636400177"&gt;Facilitate informed consent&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide explanations on impact: Offer insights into how AI interactions might affect users, including potential impacts on rights or safety.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accessibility features: Consider accessible formats that cater to diverse populations, ensuring that all users, including vulnerable groups, can access and understand the information provided.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Nudging?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--832913682"&gt;Guarantee flexibility and options&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Offer alternatives: When possible, provide options for&lt;STRONG&gt; human interaction &lt;/STRONG&gt;to comply with fundamental rights and cater to user preferences.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Revisit consent periodically: AI technology evolves rapidly; regular reassessments of consent validity are recommended. Periodic renewal of consent ensures alignment with current technological conditions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1029427187"&gt;Address ethical standards&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Commit to transparency: Continuously update and refine the &lt;STRONG&gt;transparency measures&lt;/STRONG&gt; as outlined in international ethical guidelines to maintain trust and uphold accountability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Implementing these recommendations helps ensure that user consent, particularly in AI interactions, is valid, informed, and ethically sound. They are also used legally and in appropriate situations, forming the basis for crafting disclaimers that are both effective in legal contexts and respectful of user rights and autonomy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP employs two fundamental design patterns to uphold the transparency principle for end-users interacting with AI: (i) &lt;STRONG&gt;AI Acknowledgment&lt;/STRONG&gt; at SAP, which appears when a user accesses the AI feature and typically provides information about the service, terms, and conditions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GiselleGomezJolis_0-1766792072073.png" style="width: 206px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356207i70FE3B40E52F3D6A/image-dimensions/206x309/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="206" height="309" role="button" title="GiselleGomezJolis_0-1766792072073.png" alt="GiselleGomezJolis_0-1766792072073.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;and (ii) &lt;STRONG&gt;AI Notice&lt;/STRONG&gt; at SAP, located near every AI feature output within our cloud services, usually featuring the language: “Created with AI. Verify before use.”:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GiselleGomezJolis_1-1766792099967.png" style="width: 214px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356208i6D04E9DA3BED2136/image-dimensions/214x254/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="214" height="254" role="button" title="GiselleGomezJolis_1-1766792099967.png" alt="GiselleGomezJolis_1-1766792099967.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1225940692"&gt;Closing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every flight ends with a safe landing and a post-flight review—AI consent should follow the same principle: conclude with clarity and prepare for the next journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consent in AI is much more than a legal formality—it’s a dynamic process that requires &lt;STRONG&gt;clear communication&lt;/STRONG&gt;, genuine &lt;STRONG&gt;user understanding&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and ongoing &lt;STRONG&gt;transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt;. As AI systems become more integrated into daily life, it’s essential that users are fully aware when they interact with AI, understand the implications of their consent, and have real options to control their data and experiences. International standards and regulations increasingly reflect these priorities, making transparency and user empowerment central to &lt;STRONG&gt;responsible AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next post, we’ll continue exploring new challenges and practical solutions around transparency in AI—stay tuned for more insights, and keep_the_blue_side_up&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1422454197"&gt;References / further reading&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1912370709"&gt;AI Transparency Blogpost Series&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introductory Blogpost:&amp;nbsp; &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/keep-the-blue-side-up-building-trust-in-ai-through-transparency-responsible/ba-p/14269929" target="_blank"&gt;Keep the blue side up: Building trust in AI through transparency (Responsible AI blogpost series)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- SAP Community -&amp;nbsp;Laugwitz, Bettina&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explainability Blogpost: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/trustworthy-ai-how-to-make-artificial-intelligence-understandable/ba-p/13576857" target="_blank"&gt;Trustworthy AI: How to make artificial intelligence understandable&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;- SAP Community -&amp;nbsp;Laugwitz, Bettina&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Engineering AI Safety Blogpost (part 1):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/engineering-ai-transparency-ideation-and-validation-part-1/ba-p/14283700" target="_blank"&gt;Engineering AI Transparency: Ideation and validation (Part 1)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;- SAP Community - Pant, Abhishek&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Engineering AI Safety Blogpost (part 2):&amp;nbsp; &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/engineering-ai-transparency-from-build-to-operations-part-2/ba-p/14272798" target="_blank"&gt;Engineering AI Transparency: From Build to Operations (Part 2)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;- SAP Community - Pant, Abhishek&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1940700523"&gt;Regulations and governance frameworks&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EU AI Act. &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://artificialintelligenceact.eu" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://artificialintelligenceact.eu&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recommendation on the Ethics of Artificial Intelligence (UNESCO), &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000380455" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000380455&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EU Ethics Guidelines for Trustworthy AI. &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://op.europa.eu/en/publication-detail/-/publication/d3988569-0434-11ea-8c1f-01aa75ed71a1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://op.europa.eu/en/publication-detail/-/publication/d3988569-0434-11ea-8c1f-01aa75ed71a1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI principles (OECD) &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.oecd.org/en/topics/ai-principles.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AI principles | OECD&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Code of Conduct for AI Developers under Hiroshima AI Process. &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/hiroshima-process-international-code-conduct-advanced-ai-systems" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/hiroshima-process-international-code-conduct-advanced-ai-systems&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;UNESCO Ethics of Artificial Intelligence. The Recommendation &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.unesco.org/en/artificial-intelligence/recommendation-ethics#:~:text=The%20use%20of%20AI%20systems,may%20result%20from%20such%20uses.&amp;amp;text=Unwanted%20harms%20(safety%20risks)%20as,and%20addressed%20by%20AI%20actors" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.unesco.org/en/artificial-intelligence/recommendation-ethics#:~:text=The%20use%20of%20AI%20systems,may%20result%20from%20such%20uses.&amp;amp;text=Unwanted%20harms%20(safety%20risks)%20as,and%20addressed%20by%20AI%20actors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;European Commission &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;European Commission, The General-Purpose AI Code of Practice, &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/contents-code-gpai?utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/contents-code-gpai?utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Advisory Council for Consumer Affairs, “Digital Sovereignty”, Berlin, June 2017, ( &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.svr-verbraucherfragen.de/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Report_Digital_Sovereignty.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.svr-verbraucherfragen.de/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Report_Digital_Sovereignty.pdf&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--2137214028"&gt;SAP resources (redundant in a good way &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/03/7211ee96-647e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Ethics Handbook&lt;/A&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center/data-privacy.html." target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trust center: DPP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/navigating-consent-legal-and-ethical-perspectives-on-transparency/ba-p/14298028"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T13:28:44.750000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-bp-best-practice-payer-vs-bill-to-when-member-vat-must-appear-and/qaa-p/14298555#M4233960</id>
    <title>Re: SAP BP best practice: payer vs bill to when member VA...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T13:29:23.751000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LVC</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1463459</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello Edrilan, Thanks so much for your guidance! Your advice really helped me understand things better, and I appreciate you taking the time to share your knowledge. Best, Liz Vargas.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-bp-best-practice-payer-vs-bill-to-when-member-vat-must-appear-and/qaa-p/14298555#M4233960"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T13:29:23.751000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-durin-inventory/qaa-p/14298556#M4233961</id>
    <title>Re: Error durin inventory</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T13:31:58.911000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sergeloubry</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/878656</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I faced a similar issue : I had created an inventory document for multiple bins and, for any reason, one of the bins was not displayed from the LI11N. So the situation was the following : from the LS02N, the bin was displayed with a status "not counted" but it was impossible to add the counting from LI11N.&lt;BR /&gt;When I tried to use the "New item" from LI11N for this bin, I got the error L4 050 "Storage bin xxxx excluded from entry" : this was consistent because the bin was already in the inventory document.&lt;BR /&gt;I managed to solve the issue by using the old LI11 transaction : with that transaction, th not counted bin was displayed and I was able to enter the counting.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/error-durin-inventory/qaa-p/14298556#M4233961"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T13:31:58.911000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/migrate-outbound-b2b-ascx12-interfaces-from-sap-pi-po-to-ci-cpi-using-bima/bc-p/14298557#M187398</id>
    <title>Re: Migrate Outbound B2B ASCX12 interfaces from SAP PI/PO to CI(CPI) using BIMA Package</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T13:41:28.842000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vishal_Ingale</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1646874</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for sharing !&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/migrate-outbound-b2b-ascx12-interfaces-from-sap-pi-po-to-ci-cpi-using-bima/bc-p/14298557#M187398"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T13:41:28.842000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-dm-st2300-use-of-esef-transformation-registry-version-5/qaq-p/14298560</id>
    <title>SAP DM ST2300 - Use of ESEF transformation registry version 5</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:00:37.129000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>IOL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/619110</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135" target="_self"&gt;Marc_Kuipers&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a question regarding one guidelin from ESEF Reporting Manual Preparation of Annual Financial Reports in ESEF format (Update October 2025).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Guidance 2.2.3&lt;/STRONG&gt; Transformation of facts [last updated: October 2025] Whenever a string or numeric text used in an issuer’s report does not follow the format based on the predefined data type of taxonomy element used to mark up such string or numeric text, a transformation rule shall be applied.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For that purpose, ESMA recommends applying the &lt;STRONG&gt;Transformation Rules Registry 5&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as published by XBRL International on the dedicated website or any more recent versions of the Transformation Rules Registry provided with a ‘Recommendation’ status at XBRL International.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Question: When will the Registry 5 selection option be available in SAP DM?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;‘&lt;A href="https://www.xbrl.org/Specification/inlineXBRL-transformationRegistry/REC-2022-02-16/inlineXBRL-transformationRegistry-REC-2022-02-16.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.xbrl.org/Specification/inlineXBRL-transformationRegistry/REC-2022-02-16/inlineXBRL-transformationRegistry-REC-2022-02-16.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The manual indicates that the use of Registry 4 is still correct.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, the customer expects information on this subject.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are working on version ST2300.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Iwona&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-dm-st2300-use-of-esef-transformation-registry-version-5/qaq-p/14298560"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:00:37.129000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/quick-configuration-steps-for-bulk-creation-of-external-users-in-sap/bc-p/14298561#M176942</id>
    <title>Re: Quick Configuration Steps for Bulk Creation of External Users in SAP SuccessFactors LMS</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:01:04.420000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GK1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/22641</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you, Bharati, for sharing the detailed steps regarding the External Integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/quick-configuration-steps-for-bulk-creation-of-external-users-in-sap/bc-p/14298561#M176942"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:01:04.420000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mps-background-program/qaq-p/14298563</id>
    <title>MPS background program</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:03:32.139000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>johnsplit123</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/881810</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I run SAPMM61X program, I get error -&amp;nbsp;SAPMM61X is not executable program.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is the correct program name for MPS run (MD40 t code). Please suggest.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks and regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;JohnS&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mps-background-program/qaq-p/14298563"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:03:32.139000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/material-ledger-handling-for-group-valuation-4g-when-not-used-functionally/qaq-p/14298566</id>
    <title>Material Ledger handling for Group Valuation (4G) when not used functionally - S/4HANA Cloud, Public</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:07:32.825000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>edoymaner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17368</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are reviewing how Material Ledger should be handled when Group Valuation (5W2) is technically active but not required from a business or reporting perspective.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are aware that Group Valuation cannot be technically deactivated once it is activated.&lt;BR /&gt;However, we would like to clarify the behavior specifically from a &lt;STRONG&gt;Material Ledger perspective&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the current system, Group Valuation will not be used from a business or reporting perspective. There is only &lt;STRONG&gt;one company code&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the system, and no group-level valuation is required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our question is:&lt;BR /&gt;Is there any configuration or recommended approach in &lt;STRONG&gt;Material Ledger&lt;/STRONG&gt; to avoid operational processing for the &lt;STRONG&gt;4G (Group Valuation) ledger&lt;/STRONG&gt;, even though Group Valuation remains technically active?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More specifically:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can the Material Ledger be configured so that 4G does not require an &lt;STRONG&gt;actual costing run (CKMLCP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; in each period?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If CKMLCP must technically run for all ML valuation views, is there a way to execute it in a &lt;STRONG&gt;minimal or neutral way&lt;/STRONG&gt; for 4G (for example, without price differences or business impact)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="edoymaner_1-1767013289337.png" style="width: 796px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356456i2BFE2E8F39351AF9/image-dimensions/796x427/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="796" height="427" role="button" title="edoymaner_1-1767013289337.png" alt="edoymaner_1-1767013289337.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are looking for best practices to minimize period-end effort related to Group Valuation when it is not used functionally.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR,&lt;BR /&gt;Evrim&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/material-ledger-handling-for-group-valuation-4g-when-not-used-functionally/qaq-p/14298566"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:07:32.825000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sap-wm-pick-quantity-problem/qaq-p/14298568</id>
    <title>SAP WM Pick Quantity Problem.</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:12:49.293000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>berfin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491245</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;LQUA table as below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are records in thw Pick Qty. field; but there is no open TO. Also There are no Req. Numbers (Delivery number), cause they are deleted. How can we fix this problem? We want to use this storage units.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="berfin_0-1767013846404.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356459i77E76DC390A838E9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="berfin_0-1767013846404.png" alt="berfin_0-1767013846404.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sap-wm-pick-quantity-problem/qaq-p/14298568"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:12:49.293000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/managing-invoices-with-sap-ariba-central-invoice-management/bc-p/14298569#M2860</id>
    <title>Re: Managing Invoices with SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:13:26.103000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Punith_Oswal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148179</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Nice read&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13977"&gt;@Abhijit_Shinde&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;. Thanks for sharing&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/managing-invoices-with-sap-ariba-central-invoice-management/bc-p/14298569#M2860"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:13:26.103000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/ai-sap-fiori-elements-intelligent-app-development-at-scale/ec-p/14298570#M1253</id>
    <title>Re: 🟣 AI + SAP Fiori elements = Intelligent App Development at Scale</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:14:44.737000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoaoJorge</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2455</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;where can I find the presentation ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/ai-sap-fiori-elements-intelligent-app-development-at-scale/ec-p/14298570#M1253"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:14:44.737000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-cap-forum/sideeffect-is-not-refreshing-the-criticality-icon-after-bound-action-call/td-p/14298571</id>
    <title>SideEffect is not refreshing the criticality icon after bound action call</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:15:18.098000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abap_Explained</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/180944</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;TL;DR: After the bound action &lt;CODE&gt;changeStatus&lt;/CODE&gt;, Fiori Elements refreshes &lt;CODE&gt;status_code&lt;/CODE&gt; (value and text), but the criticality icon doesn’t update because it comes from the navigation property &lt;CODE&gt;status.criticality&lt;/CODE&gt;, which isn’t covered by the declared SideEffects. A full page refresh reloads the icon correctly.&lt;BR /&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;I’m using SAP CAP (Node.js) with Fiori Elements (OData V4). I have a &lt;CODE&gt;Books&lt;/CODE&gt; entity with a &lt;CODE&gt;status&lt;/CODE&gt; association to &lt;CODE&gt;BookStatus&lt;/CODE&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;entity Books : cuid, managed {
    status : Association to BookStatus;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;CODE&gt;BookStatus&lt;/CODE&gt; contains a &lt;CODE&gt;criticality&lt;/CODE&gt; integer which drives the criticality icon in FE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;entity BookStatus {
    key code        : String(1) enum {
            Available = 'A';
            Low_Stock = 'L';
            Unavailable = 'U';
        }
        criticality : Integer;
        displayText : String;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;After executing a bound action &lt;CODE&gt;changeStatus&lt;/CODE&gt;, the UI refreshes &lt;CODE&gt;status_code&lt;/CODE&gt;, the display text but the criticality icon does not change:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Abap_Explained_0-1767013556564.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356458i9B86E63B2E678AC8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Abap_Explained_0-1767013556564.png" alt="Abap_Explained_0-1767013556564.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is the action with the side effect.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;entity Books as projection on db.Books
    actions {
            @(Common.SideEffects: {TargetProperties: ['status_code']})
            action changeStatus(newStatus: String);
        };&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is the action logic:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    this.on('changeStatus', Books, async (req) =&amp;gt; {
      const bookId = req.params[0].ID
      const newStatus = req.data.newStatus
      await UPDATE(Books)
        .set({ status_code: newStatus })
        .where({ ID: bookId })
    })&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Field annotated as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
 $Type : 'UI.DataField',
 Value : status_code,
 Criticality : status.criticality,
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here the data used for my BookStatus entity:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;code&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;criticality&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;displayText&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;A&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Available&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;L&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Low Stock&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;U&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;Unavailable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;And the thing is that after refreshing the page, the icon is reloaded correctly. So that is just the side effect issue.&lt;BR /&gt;And here is the github repo, if anyone wants to reproduce this issue:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/Frontmaniaac/Bookstore-CAP-Tutorial" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Frontmaniaac/Bookstore-CAP-Tutorial&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I know that it should work. Based on:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/fiori-elements-feature-showcase" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-samples/fiori-elements-feature-showcase&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;But I cannot figure it out in my project.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-cap-forum/sideeffect-is-not-refreshing-the-criticality-icon-after-bound-action-call/td-p/14298571"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:15:18.098000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/program-settings-apply-gates-and-accelerators/qaa-p/14298575#M50065</id>
    <title>Re: Program Settings: Apply Gates and Accelerators</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:32:10.974000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DavidSomelofske</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Curves are used more often than gates or accelerators, however, the curves have and end point, which limits their functionality.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;The gates are used to ensure a minimum performance level to receive a bonus. Again, you can accomplish this via the curve as well.&amp;nbsp; This will save the company money on bonuses where they don't pay out for performance that does not meet a standard.&amp;nbsp; Accelerators are also not commonly used but can be more flexible than the curve in that there does not have to be as many data points and you can leave it more open ended unless you couple it with a cap.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my experience, curves are used more often than gates and accelerators&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/program-settings-apply-gates-and-accelerators/qaa-p/14298575#M50065"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:32:10.974000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-test-cloud-hotfolder-locally-in-sap-commerce-cloud/ba-p/14298576</id>
    <title>How to test Cloud Hotfolder locally in SAP Commerce Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:34:41.983000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>joris_quenee</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/173030</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1638456775"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This article describes how to test Cloud Hotfolder locally in order to facilitate integration and customisation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By default SAP Commerce Cloud zip file doesn't embed Cloud Hotfolder extensions. Those extensions can be found in this following KBA note :&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2817992" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/2817992&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Three extensions should be installed:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;azurecloudhotfolder&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;cloudcommons&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;cloudhotfolder&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="HowtotestCloudHotfolderlocally-Prerequisites" id="toc-hId-1441943270"&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;First thing is to install Azurite which will simulate azure blob storage in local filesystem&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ npm install -g azurite&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Then we can start the service&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ azurite -l /tmp
Azurite, Version 2.7.0
A lightweight server clone of Azure Storage

Azure Table Storage Emulator listening on port 10002
Azure Queue Storage Emulator listening on port 10001
Azure Blob Storage Emulator listening on port 10000&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Now we should install Microsoft Azure Storage Explorer:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/features/storage-explorer/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/features/storage-explorer/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open Microsoft Azure Storage Explorer and attach the local blob storage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AzureAttach.png" style="width: 464px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356460iE9FEA4BFFCC012DB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AzureAttach.png" alt="AzureAttach.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AzureLocalEmulator.png" style="width: 230px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356461iF6C6C2A8737A5094/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AzureLocalEmulator.png" alt="AzureLocalEmulator.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="HowtotestCloudHotfolderlocally-Installation" id="toc-hId-1245429765"&gt;Installation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Download latest SAP Commerce Cloud 2211 patched version from&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/softwarecenter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/softwarecenter&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unzip SAP Commerce Cloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Install electronics B2C accelerator&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Download Cloud Hotfolder extensions (pickup suitable version) :&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2817992" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/2817992&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Install those extensions in&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;hybris/bin/custom&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;folder&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add this following extension in &lt;STRONG&gt;localextensions.xml&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;extension name='azurecloudhotfolder' /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add this following settings in &lt;STRONG&gt;local.properties&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-java"&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Azure Blob Store: Remote (SandBox D1)
#azure.hotfolder.storage.account.connection-string=DefaultEndpointsProtocol=https;AccountName=...;AccountKey=...
#azure.hotfolder.storage.account.name=...

# Azure Blob Store: Local (Azurite or CCv2 env)
azure.hotfolder.storage.account.connection-string=UseDevelopmentStorage=true
# azure.hotfolder.storage.account.name=devstoreaccount1

# general setting
cluster.node.groups=integration,yHotfolderCandidate
azure.hotfolder.storage.container.hotfolder=master/hotfolder

# debug
log4j2.logger.azure.name = de.hybris.platform.cloud.azure.hotfolder
log4j2.logger.azure.level = DEBUG
log4j2.logger.azure.appenderRef.stdout.ref = STDOUT

log4j2.logger.cloud.name = de.hybris.platform.cloud.hotfolder
log4j2.logger.cloud.level = DEBUG
log4j2.logger.cloud.appenderRef.stdout.ref = STDOUT

log4j2.logger.cloud.name = de.hybris.platform.cloud.commons
log4j2.logger.cloud.level = DEBUG
log4j2.logger.cloud.appenderRef.stdout.ref = STDOUT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;Compile and Init the platform&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Start the platform, we should see this output every 6s&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;DEBUG [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [AzureBlobSession] Listing contents of container [hybris] on path [master/hotfolder].
DEBUG [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [AzureBlobInboundSynchronizer] 0 files transferred&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H1 id="HowtotestCloudHotfolderlocally-Testing" id="toc-hId-1048916260"&gt;Testing&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To test data import, we can use this following zip file template :&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;product-with-media-001.zip&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-29 at 14.26.54.png" style="width: 570px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356462iEB0EAF2389411463/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-29 at 14.26.54.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-29 at 14.26.54.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;product.csv&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;112233,,Test Product 2,Test Product 2 Description,ean,manufacturer,manufacturerAID,pieces,approved,jp-vat-full,&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;raw.impex&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$defaultPassword=1234
$setName=name[cellDecorator=de.hybris.platform.acceleratorservices.dataimport.batch.decorator.CustomerNameDecorator]

INSERT_UPDATE Customer;uid[unique=true];$setName;title(code);password[default=$defaultPassword]
;raw.impex@domain.com;Raw Impex;mr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;zip_media.csv&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;112233,y_logo.png&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Push this file into&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;hybris&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;container into folder&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;master&lt;/SPAN&gt;/hotfolder&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then we should have this log trace&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;DEBUG [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [BlobTransferredAspect] about to run method [read] on target [de.hybris.platform.cloud.azure.hotfolder.remote.session.AzureBlobSession@394dd2a9] with path [master/hotfolder/product-with-media-001.zip]
DEBUG [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [AzureBlobSession] Reading from container [hybris] on path [master/hotfolder/product-with-media-001.zip].
INFO  [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [LoggingMonitorRecorder] HOT_FOLDER:product-with-media-001.zip1544632066000 Status [IN_PROGRESS]
Step [DOWNLOADED] Node [0] Status [SUCCESS] Started [2018-12-12T17:28:29.344+01:00] Ended [2018-12-12T17:28:29.378+01:00] Duration [34]ms Message [Successfully read blob [master/hotfolder/product-with-media-001.zip] of size [247 KB]] Actions [none]
WARN  [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [BlobTransferredAspect] No MonitorHistory within the thread, cannot add successful Step [DOWNLOADED] started [2018-12-12T17:28:29.341+0100]
WARN  [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [BlobTransferredAspect] No MonitorHistory within the thread, cannot checkpoint
WARN  [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [BlobTransferredAspect] No MonitorHistory within the thread, cannot add successful Step [DOWNLOADED] started [2018-12-12T17:28:29.338+0100]
WARN  [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [BlobTransferredAspect] No MonitorHistory within the thread, cannot checkpoint
DEBUG [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [AzureBlobSession] Removing from container [hybris] on path [master/hotfolder/product-with-media-001.zip].
DEBUG [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [AzureBlobInboundSynchronizer] deleted remote file: master/hotfolder/product-with-media-001.zip
DEBUG [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [AzureBlobInboundSynchronizer] 1 files transferred
DEBUG [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [FileUnzippedAspect] about to run method [doTransform] on target [unZipTransformer]
DEBUG [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [BatchHeaderAspect] about to run method [executeZip] on target [de.hybris.platform.cloud.hotfolder.dataimport.batch.zip.task.ZipHeaderInitTask@d9475a6]
DEBUG [HybrisIntegrationTaskExecutorThread1] [BatchHeaderAspect] about to run method [executeZip] on target [de.hybris.platform.cloud.hotfolder.dataimport.batch.zip.task.ZipHeaderTransformerTask@47445751]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From /backoffice, we should see the new product&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;112233&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;imported with his media in&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;electronics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;staged catalog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-test-cloud-hotfolder-locally-in-sap-commerce-cloud/ba-p/14298576"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:34:41.983000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/managing-invoices-with-sap-ariba-central-invoice-management/bc-p/14298578#M2861</id>
    <title>Re: Managing Invoices with SAP Ariba Central Invoice Management</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:38:58.376000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abhijit_Shinde</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13977</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your support&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148179"&gt;@Punith_Oswal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_up:"&gt;👍&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/managing-invoices-with-sap-ariba-central-invoice-management/bc-p/14298578#M2861"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:38:58.376000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/ai-sap-fiori-elements-intelligent-app-development-at-scale/ec-p/14298581#M1254</id>
    <title>Re: 🟣 AI + SAP Fiori elements = Intelligent App Development at Scale</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:45:25.014000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Attila</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/129182</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2455"&gt;@JoaoJorge&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;not sure about the presentation, but it is shown along with the demo video.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/2ZyI6b81yLw?si=hiB5nRPh8rrzrG3P" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/live/2ZyI6b81yLw?si=hiB5nRPh8rrzrG3P&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR, Attila&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/ai-sap-fiori-elements-intelligent-app-development-at-scale/ec-p/14298581#M1254"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:45:25.014000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/email-notifications-not-triggered-for-pr-flexible-workflow/qaq-p/14298582</id>
    <title>Email notifications not triggered for PR Flexible Workflow</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:48:22.053000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are using &lt;B&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition&lt;/B&gt; and have configured &lt;B&gt;Flexible Workflow for Purchase Requisition (PR) approval&lt;/B&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Issue Description:&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The PR approval workflow is triggered correctly, and approver determination works as expected. Approvers receive approval tasks in &lt;B&gt;My Inbox&lt;/B&gt;, and workflow processing functions normally. However, &lt;B&gt;email notifications are not consistently triggered&lt;/B&gt;, and the &lt;B&gt;Notification / Email tab is not visible&lt;/B&gt; in the Flexible Workflow configuration for Purchase Requisitions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Expected System Behavior:&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When a PR is created and submitted for approval:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The approver should receive a workflow task in &lt;I&gt;My Inbox&lt;/I&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The approver should also receive an &lt;B&gt;email notification&lt;/B&gt; informing them of the pending approval.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After the PR is approved or rejected:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The PR initiator should receive a system notification.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The PR initiator should also receive an &lt;B&gt;email notification&lt;/B&gt; confirming the approval or rejection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Actual System Behavior:&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Workflow triggers correctly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Approval task is created and visible in &lt;I&gt;My Inbox&lt;/I&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Approver determination is correct.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;B&gt;Email notifications are not triggered&lt;/B&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;B&gt;Email tab is not available&lt;/B&gt; in the Flexible Workflow app for PRs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Steps to Reproduce:&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a Purchase Requisition that meets the workflow start condition.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Submit the PR.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Workflow is triggered and approval task is created.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Approver receives task in &lt;I&gt;My Inbox&lt;/I&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No email notification is received by the approver.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After approval, no email notification is received by the PR initiator.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;System Information:&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Deployment: SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Application: Flexible Workflow for Purchase Requisitions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fiori App: Manage Workflows for Purchase Requisitions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Request:&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly confirm:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Whether &lt;B&gt;email notifications for PR Flexible Workflow&lt;/B&gt; are supported in SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Whether the absence of the &lt;B&gt;Notification / Email tab&lt;/B&gt; in PR Flexible Workflow is standard system behavior.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If email notifications are supported, please advise the required configuration or prerequisites.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/email-notifications-not-triggered-for-pr-flexible-workflow/qaq-p/14298582"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:48:22.053000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/email-notifications-not-triggered-for-pr-flexible-workflow/qaa-p/14298583#M4233965</id>
    <title>Re: Email notifications not triggered for PR Flexible Wor...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:48:29.617000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly refer to KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3304179" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3304179&lt;/A&gt; - Email notification tab is missing for purchasing workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is first needed to create copies of the predelivered email templates so that the notification tab is shown and the email notification can be configured.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also refer to the below SAP Help page for more information on the general configuration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/af9ef57f504840d2b81be8667206d485/91ab576eaf58475f8934d2dcef16edb3.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;How to Configure the Flexible Workflow for Purchase Requisitions | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/email-notifications-not-triggered-for-pr-flexible-workflow/qaa-p/14298583#M4233965"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:48:29.617000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/email-notifications-not-triggered-for-pr-flexible-workflow/qaa-p/14298584#M4233966</id>
    <title>Re: Email notifications not triggered for PR Flexible Wor...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:49:04.409000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly refer to KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3304179" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3304179&lt;/A&gt; - Email notification tab is missing for purchasing workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is first needed to create copies of the predelivered email templates so that the notification tab is shown and the email notification can be configured.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also refer to the below SAP Help page for more information on the general configuration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/af9ef57f504840d2b81be8667206d485/91ab576eaf58475f8934d2dcef16edb3.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;How to Configure the Flexible Workflow for Purchase Requisitions | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/email-notifications-not-triggered-for-pr-flexible-workflow/qaa-p/14298584#M4233966"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:49:04.409000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-%E3%83%A9%E3%82%A4%E3%82%BB%E3%83%B3%E3%82%B9%E8%AA%AC%E6%98%8E%E3%81%8A%E3%82%88%E3%81%B3%E3%82%B7%E3%83%9F%E3%83%A5%E3%83%AC%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E6%A9%9F%E8%83%BD/ba-p/14228641</id>
    <title>SAP Analytics Cloud ライセンス説明およびシミュレーション機能</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:51:39.658000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yureshino</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44011</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;※2025年12月時点でのSAP Analytics Cloud(SAC)のライセンス形態についてご紹介します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)はビジネスインテリジェンス(BI), 予算管理、予測分析、予算管理を一つのプラットフォームでご利用いただける分析ツールです。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yureshino_0-1767016233277.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356463iD16F0AFE412DAE1D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="yureshino_0-1767016233277.png" alt="yureshino_0-1767016233277.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud を使用するには、使用する機能モジュール（BI、Planning）に応じたライセンスが利用ユーザー数分必要です。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ライセンスメトリックは指名ユーザ（NUL : NamedUser License）数です。指名ユーザーライセンスには&lt;STRONG&gt;BI、Planning Standard、Planning Professional&lt;/STRONG&gt;の3つのタイプがあり、利用できる機能に違いがあります。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAC機能&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning Standard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning Professional&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;計画モデルの作成&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;×　使用不可&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;×　使用不可&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;計画タスクの実行&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;×　使用不可&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;計画モデルの参照&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;分析モデルの作成&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;BI機能・データ探索の使用&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Excelアドインの使用&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;モバイルアプリケーションの使用&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;※ ライセンスタイプ別機能マトリックスの詳細については、&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/ja-JP/b51b338827764edc847a6c1d6b8d7ed5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;「分析モデル用の機能 &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/ja-JP/b51b338827764edc847a6c1d6b8d7ed5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;(&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/ja-JP/b51b338827764edc847a6c1d6b8d7ed5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;ライセンスタイプ別&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/ja-JP/b51b338827764edc847a6c1d6b8d7ed5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/ja-JP/b51b338827764edc847a6c1d6b8d7ed5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;」&lt;/A&gt;および&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/ja-JP/20d92cebb9f94699949f99bd54a169bd.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;「計画モデル用の機能 &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/ja-JP/20d92cebb9f94699949f99bd54a169bd.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;(&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/ja-JP/20d92cebb9f94699949f99bd54a169bd.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;ライセンスタイプ別&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/ja-JP/20d92cebb9f94699949f99bd54a169bd.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/release/ja-JP/20d92cebb9f94699949f99bd54a169bd.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;」&lt;/A&gt;を参照してください。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;また、SACには複数のシミュレーション機能・機械学習機能・AI機能がございますが、それらもユーザータイプによって利用できる機能に違いがあります。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="1281px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="87px" height="50px"&gt;No.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="432px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;機能&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="258px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning Standard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="272px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning Professional&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="87px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="432px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Just ask&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="258px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="272px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="87px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="432px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;スマートプレディクト&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="258px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="272px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="87px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="432px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;スマートインサイト&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="258px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="272px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="87px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;4&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="432px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Compass&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;×　使用不可&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="258px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="272px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="87px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;5&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="432px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;時系列予測 (チャート)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="258px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="272px" height="30px"&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="87px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;6&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="432px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;R ビジュアライゼーション&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="258px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="272px" height="50px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;○　使用可能&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;各シミュレーション機能の詳細については、&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/1fb1f4ce92f44fc983debc25ac1f2cc9.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SACのヘルプページ&lt;/A&gt;から各機能の詳細ページをご確認ください。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;今後Joule in SACなどのAI関連の機能も充実してくる予定ですが、そういった機能についてはライセンス体系が異なる可能性がございます。詳細な情報をご希望の場合は弊社営業へご連絡ください&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-%E3%83%A9%E3%82%A4%E3%82%BB%E3%83%B3%E3%82%B9%E8%AA%AC%E6%98%8E%E3%81%8A%E3%82%88%E3%81%B3%E3%82%B7%E3%83%9F%E3%83%A5%E3%83%AC%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B3%E6%A9%9F%E8%83%BD/ba-p/14228641"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:51:39.658000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/proration-based-on-month/qaa-p/14298586#M50066</id>
    <title>Re: Proration based on month</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:53:00.728000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DavidSomelofske</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Our standard functionality does not prorate based on months.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;We do have the functionality to shift the start date of an assignment to the first of a month or an end date to the last day of the month.&amp;nbsp; This gets you closer but not exact because someone who starts on 7/1 should get 50% (6 of 12 months) but the days even if you adjust start dates or end dates, is not exactly 50%.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;I am often successful in consulting the client the days are actually more precise and with adjusting start dates and end dates, we get really close.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you need the actual number of months, you will have to use custom fields to determine the payout using custom fields and the formulas will vary based on the rules the client will follow.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/proration-based-on-month/qaa-p/14298586#M50066"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:53:00.728000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/create-onboardee-using-api-in-onb-2-0/qaa-p/14298587#M4934289</id>
    <title>Re: Create Onboardee using API in ONB 2.0</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:54:08.571000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gopinath_Murugaiyan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17956</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/76518"&gt;@taqui-hadi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; kindly use below EC Entity call for person Field&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-platform/sap-successfactors-api-reference-guide-odata-v2/generatenextpersonid" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;generateNextPersonID | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Gopi&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/create-onboardee-using-api-in-onb-2-0/qaa-p/14298587#M4934289"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:54:08.571000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/using-common-activity-types-in-professional-services-and-service-management/ba-p/14298593</id>
    <title>Using Common Activity Types in Professional Services and Service Management in S/4HANA Cloud Public</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:55:54.870000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>varunvenkat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83606</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition for Professional Services, there are 20 default T-activity types that are delivered out of the box by SAP. In some companies, it could be the case that these activity types are required to be used in both the lines of business professional service as well as service order management. In professional service, the association between activity types and the bill rates are automatically maintained using the billing profile configuration settings. Please refer to the following &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/activity-types-and-service-materials-for-project-services/ba-p/13357383" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; by Tobias Schmidt for a deeper look into this topic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, I would like to demonstrate for the service management line-of-business, which configuration needs to be done to fulfill this requirement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_0-1767016504815.png" style="width: 425px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356465iD66D2F3C7BC4E56B/image-dimensions/425x374/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="425" height="374" role="button" title="varunvenkat_0-1767016504815.png" alt="varunvenkat_0-1767016504815.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The scenario I would like to illustrate in this blog post is the business need, wherein common activity types are used between the lines of business professional services and service order management in S/4HANA Cloud. This is common in certain industries&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create/rename the activity types: In the app “Manage Activity Types”, rename the standard activity types T001 to T020 according to your business needs. The standard T- activity types can be renamed to correspond If needed, create further activity types beyond the 20 default activity types delivered out-of-the-box.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_1-1767016504824.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356464i0CC9D8A6345A4429/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_1-1767016504824.png" alt="varunvenkat_1-1767016504824.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create the cost rates: next, in the “Manage Cost Rates – Services” app, maintain the individual cost rates for the different combinations of company code/cost center/activity type (and optionally Service Cost Level)&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_2-1767016504837.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356466i9004F24A7BF24A46/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_2-1767016504837.png" alt="varunvenkat_2-1767016504837.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create the service product master data: finally for the determination of the correct cost rates for the products used in the service orders, you will need to create separate product master data (with material type SERV and item category group SRVP), as the T-materials delivered out of the box can only be used in customer projects or internal projects due to the respective item category determination.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_3-1767016504847.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356468iBA977BC5F7BE6760/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_3-1767016504847.png" alt="varunvenkat_3-1767016504847.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;*Assign the activity types to service products: after creating the service products, you will need to assign these to the corresponding activity types in the configuration activity “Assign Activity Type to Service Product” (SSCUI &lt;SPAN&gt;102920)&lt;/SPAN&gt;. For the professional service projects, the assignment is done implicitly using the configuration activity “Maintain Billing Profile” (SSCUI &lt;SPAN&gt;103637&lt;/SPAN&gt;)&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_4-1767016504854.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356467i443F01DDBB0439B9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_4-1767016504854.png" alt="varunvenkat_4-1767016504854.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this setup, you can successfully use common activity types and cost rates and correctly determine them for the transactions in the different lines-of-business Professional Services and Service Management.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/using-common-activity-types-in-professional-services-and-service-management/ba-p/14298593"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:55:54.870000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14298594#M14646</id>
    <title>Re: Reimagining Certification for the Way We Work Today</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:56:52.326000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kasithunuguntla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/129345</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10529" target="_blank"&gt;@DianaRoesner&lt;/A&gt;, I have taken C_AIG exam today&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;and to my surprise the status shows “Failed.” I had thoroughly answered all the questions after extensive practice. However, I encountered an issue during Section 3.1 – Task 3.1: Perform Comparative Model Evaluation and Selection.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When I attempted to use "Mistral AI" for this task, the system threw an error. I retried multiple times but couldn’t get the expected output, so I selected what I believed was the best option from the remaining two models. I am not sure about other reasons why I couldnt succeed in the exam and there is no information whatsoever that gives me breakup details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I have raised a &lt;SPAN&gt;Case ID :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5000274123 to fix the issue and give me another chance. I hope my request will be honored.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kasi&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/bc-p/14298594#M14646"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:56:52.326000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mps-background-program/qaa-p/14298595#M4233967</id>
    <title>Re: MPS background program</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T14:57:13.744000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Try with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;RMMRP000&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mps-background-program/qaa-p/14298595#M4233967"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T14:57:13.744000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/negative-stock-in-wm/qaa-p/14298596#M208723</id>
    <title>Re: Negative stock in WM</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T15:03:59.592000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LFRANCISCO</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2272491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253375"&gt;@MOHAMMED_BASER&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I checked the situation in transaction LT24, but all transfers are complete. In transaction LX23, there is a negative difference in stock. I tried to execute an LT10/LT01, but I couldn't because I don't have stock to transfer (I can create a TO, but this generates a positive and a negative balance, and in the end, the total will only be the negative part).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I also checked transactions LX22/LX23, but how can I create only the positive stock in WM? When I tried to create a positive stock balance using LI01N, LI11N (count) and write it off in the inventory document, the system generated a positive and a negative stock balance... therefore, I can't correct my stock.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;LX23:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="LFRANCISCO_1-1767017137398.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356470i4E467C5ED521688E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="LFRANCISCO_1-1767017137398.png" alt="LFRANCISCO_1-1767017137398.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inventory adj:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="LFRANCISCO_0-1767017098401.png" style="width: 490px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356469i8821174F8C8A2943/image-dimensions/490x60/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="490" height="60" role="button" title="LFRANCISCO_0-1767017098401.png" alt="LFRANCISCO_0-1767017098401.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/negative-stock-in-wm/qaa-p/14298596#M208723"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T15:03:59.592000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-create-an-include-text-with-xml-schema-based-interface/qaq-p/14298603</id>
    <title>How to create an Include text with xml schema-based interface?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T15:08:56.671000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BergOff</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1816435</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, experts&lt;BR /&gt;How to create an Include text with xml schema-based interface?&lt;BR /&gt;There is no 'Context' tab, like in happens via generation with NACE&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1.jpg" style="width: 852px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356474iED1D9BF8A6DD6D05/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1.jpg" alt="1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2.jpg" style="width: 828px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356473i82265FC370D32968/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.jpg" alt="2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-create-an-include-text-with-xml-schema-based-interface/qaq-p/14298603"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T15:08:56.671000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/manual-initiation-of-onboarding-without-employee-central/qaa-p/14298604#M50067</id>
    <title>Re: Manual initiation of onboarding without Employee Central</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T15:17:28.456000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gopinath_Murugaiyan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17956</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47140"&gt;@syeapAB&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;it can happen because of Permission issue or any API call issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;kindly open network console and send error message while you loading this field&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Gopi&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/manual-initiation-of-onboarding-without-employee-central/qaa-p/14298604#M50067"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T15:17:28.456000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-debug-sap-cpi-groovy-scripts-locally-using-visual-studio-code/bc-p/14298634#M176944</id>
    <title>Re: How to Debug SAP CPI Groovy Scripts Locally Using Visual Studio Code.</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T15:34:04.802000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bruntjn</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1745098</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Got it up and running.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Be careful to use groovy major 2 release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Debug works like a charm.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My config:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;VS.Code: 1.107.1&lt;BR /&gt;Groovy: 2.5.23&lt;BR /&gt;Java:&amp;nbsp;OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM (Temurin)(build 25.472-b08, mixed mode)&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-debug-sap-cpi-groovy-scripts-locally-using-visual-studio-code/bc-p/14298634#M176944"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T15:34:04.802000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/how-to-make-sap-c4c-report-sorted-based-on-a-particular-characteristic/qaq-p/14298635</id>
    <title>How to make SAP C4C Report sorted based on a particular Characteristic (Column) when opened/ran</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T15:39:22.335000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chaitanya_Krishna</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1988260</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I need to know how to make a Custom SAP C4C Report created via Business Analytics sorted by default based on particular characteristic (Column). For example, lets say I have a column - Start Date in the report, the report needs to be automatically sorted as per choice - desc/asc order. when ran or opened without manually sorting via column headers.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I could also see only first column of the report has sorting facility. Can we get that for all columns?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/how-to-make-sap-c4c-report-sorted-based-on-a-particular-characteristic/qaq-p/14298635"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T15:39:22.335000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/how-do-i-configure-a-custom-sales-workflow-in-sap-sales-cloud-so-that/qaa-p/14298636#M458376</id>
    <title>Re: How do I configure a custom sales workflow in SAP Sal...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T15:42:33.970000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OTAREK</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2149336</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Greetings Fernando,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;the autflow in Sap Sles Cloud has event type for trigger as Created On/ Updated On even in scheduled flows, doesnt that mean that the flow will trigger and evaluate the condition at either creation or update ? also in the condition there is no way to add or substract upon any selected field, there is an offset scheduling of the action, but doesnt that happen after the evaluation of the condition which happens at either creation or update ?, doesnt that mean that the evaluation of the condition cannot simply happen at a later date ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/how-do-i-configure-a-custom-sales-workflow-in-sap-sales-cloud-so-that/qaa-p/14298636#M458376"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T15:42:33.970000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/one-single-email-to-be-sent-when-necessary-compliance-forms-are-signed/qaq-p/14298722</id>
    <title>one single email to be sent when necessary compliance forms are signed</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T15:53:15.720000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ssindhuja</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/142709</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have enabled two standard compliance forms I9 and W4 in our system. Right now every time one form is signed, an email is sent as per configured in email services.&amp;nbsp;The email configured is (ONB) Compliance Document Signature task completion Template.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As per our requirement, we need to send the email only once when both the forms have been completed and signed. (i9 section 1 and W4)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have tried to create a business rule and attach it to the email in email services, but it does not trigger the email at all.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please let me know if you have done something like this for any customer.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/one-single-email-to-be-sent-when-necessary-compliance-forms-are-signed/qaq-p/14298722"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T15:53:15.720000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/abap-meets-ai-my-hands-on-experience-with-sap-s-abap-sdk-for-llm/bc-p/14298723#M851</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP Meets AI: My Hands-On Experience with SAP’s ABAP SDK for LLM Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T15:57:08.417000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAP4VMG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1987324</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132462"&gt;@SreekanthKrishn&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;. Can see subscribing plan, creating service key, managing intelligent scenario and communication arrangement is basis part.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/abap-meets-ai-my-hands-on-experience-with-sap-s-abap-sdk-for-llm/bc-p/14298723#M851"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T15:57:08.417000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/balance-carry-forward-faglgvtr-behave-differntly-in-personas-and-rise/qaa-p/14298732#M4934290</id>
    <title>Re: Balance Carry Forward (FAGLGVTR) behave differntly in...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T16:05:27.821000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>deiamolina</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16032</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Tamas,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We&amp;nbsp; are on version&amp;nbsp;SCREEN PERSONAS 3.0 SP18 sap.com SAP SCREEN PERSONAS 3.0 and all the notes are applied. Any idea what's going on?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/balance-carry-forward-faglgvtr-behave-differntly-in-personas-and-rise/qaa-p/14298732#M4934290"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T16:05:27.821000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/balance-carry-forward-faglgvtr-behave-differntly-in-personas-and-rise/qaa-p/14298733#M4934291</id>
    <title>Re: Balance Carry Forward (FAGLGVTR) behave differntly in...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T16:05:32.951000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>deiamolina</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16032</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Tamas,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/balance-carry-forward-faglgvtr-behave-differntly-in-personas-and-rise/qaa-p/14298733#M4934291"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T16:05:32.951000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-tax-reporter-year-end-2025/bc-p/14298782#M62947</id>
    <title>Re: U.S Tax Reporter Year End 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T16:09:32.323000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>graziela</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/108973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/296947"&gt;@juli_thompson&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/491194"&gt;@joe_jones2&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3688712" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3688712&lt;/A&gt; - TR: Year End 2025 Phase III for U.S. Tax Reporter has been released today.&lt;BR /&gt;It was planned for last week, but some additional changes were included. So it was released today.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Kind regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Graziela&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-tax-reporter-year-end-2025/bc-p/14298782#M62947"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T16:09:32.323000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/it-s-possible-to-perform-a-reorg-in-all-tables-at-the-same-time-sap-ase/qaa-p/14298798#M4934292</id>
    <title>Re: It's possible to perform a reorg in all tables at the same time? - SAP ASE</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T16:11:24.206000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sladebe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/282098</uri>
    </author>
    <content>If you're doing a reorg rebuild that essentially makes a new copy of the table to reorg it, and if you have several big tables, then you would run out of space if you ran "reorg rebuild" on all the large tables at the same time</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/it-s-possible-to-perform-a-reorg-in-all-tables-at-the-same-time-sap-ase/qaa-p/14298798#M4934292"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T16:11:24.206000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/partial-gi-splitting-odo-in-s-4-hana-public-cloud-embedded-ewm/qaq-p/14298803</id>
    <title>Partial GI &amp; Splitting ODO in S/4 HANA Public Cloud Embedded EWM</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T16:13:36.684000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We have a S/4 HANA Public Cloud Embedded EWM on BOBM, is there a possibility of posting partial goods issue against the Outbound Delivery Order (ODO) in the manage outbound delivery orders screen or through warehouse monitor, wherein we pick only a portion of the quantity of the ODO through a warehouse task and try to post GI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is there a way to split the Outbound Delivery received from the ERP before creating the warehouse tasks in EWM. The Outbound deliveries are created from the Sales Schedule lines&lt;BR /&gt;Screenshots:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Issue 1: Trying to post Partial GI - When we pick partially and try to post partial Goods Issue, system is not allowing. Is there a work around to avoid this standard behavior and post partial GI for Outbound Delivery Orders in EWM?&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Issue 2: The current splitting functionality in EWM Warehouse Monitor is expecting me to create Warehouse Tasks for the entire ODO qty and then delete a task to create a split delivery. Is there a way to split the delivery before even creating the warehouse tasks in EWM.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;VLSP-Split Outbound Delivery transaction also can’t be used, as it creates an error since the delivery was already distributed to EWM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly suggest options/work arounds for Splitting Outbound Delivery Orders and Posting Partial Goods Issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/partial-gi-splitting-odo-in-s-4-hana-public-cloud-embedded-ewm/qaq-p/14298803"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T16:13:36.684000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/partial-gi-splitting-odo-in-s-4-hana-public-cloud-embedded-ewm/qaa-p/14298804#M4233970</id>
    <title>Re: Partial GI &amp; Splitting ODO in S/4 HANA Public Cloud E...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T16:13:44.211000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature is available in the Warehouse Monitor APP. You ca:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;"Split Open Quantity into new ODO" on the node of outbound delivery order (ODO) items:&lt;BR /&gt;You can select one or more items. Those items that have no warehouse task are split into a new ODO.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;"Split into new ODO" on the handling unit (HU) node of ODOs:&lt;BR /&gt;The selected HUs are split into a new ODO.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can use those features to remove parts of an outbound delivery order that, for example, are not ready to be shipped or for which there is no space on the transport, by splitting those parts into a new outbound delivery order. You can split the outbound delivery order either before or after warehouse processing has started with created or confirmed warehouse tasks. Access this feature through the Warehouse Monitor. Two new functions are available in the Warehouse Monitor for the following nodes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Outbound Delivery Order &amp;gt; Outbound Delivery Order Item &amp;gt; More Methods &amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; Split Open Qty into new ODO&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Documents &amp;gt; Handling Unit &amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; More methods &amp;gt; Split into new ODO&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please check the documents below for your reference:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/96a118600c854ce6b61cde6d36d38f84.html?version=2408.00" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help Portal - Delivery Split for Outbound Delivery Order&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67837800100800007389&amp;amp;BC=6EAE8B27FCC11ED892E91B6B24A440CC&amp;amp;range=FIRST-LAST#Q4%202025;INNO=3B40A46EFDB81EDDA5EA75F175317DAE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Roadmap Items - Warehouse-driven split of the outbound delivery order&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; 2408&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/264194/?section=sectionDetails" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Influence Request - Allow partial goods issue for outbound delivery + delivery-split&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please let us know if you have further questions!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Support.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/partial-gi-splitting-odo-in-s-4-hana-public-cloud-embedded-ewm/qaa-p/14298804#M4233970"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T16:13:44.211000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/is-it-possible-to-add-charts-to-compenstation-statement/qaq-p/14298899</id>
    <title>Is it possible to add charts to compenstation statement?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T16:22:48.371000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gabby</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/76288</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was requested to include a pie chart with total benefits in compensation statement including base salary, retirement contribution, Health &amp;amp; Life Benefits, Short-term incentives, etc.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I couldn't find any documentation and exploring options in SuccessFactors, so I would like to check in the community if anyone implemented a compensation statement with such dynamic charts?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/is-it-possible-to-add-charts-to-compenstation-statement/qaq-p/14298899"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T16:22:48.371000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-tax-reporter-year-end-2025/bc-p/14298917#M62948</id>
    <title>Re: U.S Tax Reporter Year End 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T16:36:24.649000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>juli_thompson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/296947</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/108973"&gt;@graziela&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for the message and we are in the process of applying this note now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Juli&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/u-s-tax-reporter-year-end-2025/bc-p/14298917#M62948"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T16:36:24.649000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/billing-plan-details-capturing-issue-against-the-contract-item-in-sap-ecc/qaa-p/14298921#M4934295</id>
    <title>Re: Billing plan details capturing issue against the cont...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T16:38:21.161000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NARAYAN-REDDY</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2272249</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi, Pls find the below inputs to execute the process on billing plan details insertion 1. BILLING_SCHEDULE_GENERATE o Fill field I_FPART, I_VEDA-VBELN, I_FKDAT, I_UPD_FPLA = 'X' and I_FPLA_ONLY = 'X' (for minimum input) o then copy tables FPLA_NEW dan GET E_FPLNR ($0000001) o Execute 2. BILLING_SCHEDULE_GET_NUMBER o Paste E_FPLNR to I_FPLNR ($0000001) o Fill I_VBELN o PASTE FPLA_NEW to FPLA_NEW o GET E_FPLNR and COPY RESULT FPLA_NEW o Execute 3. BILLING_SCHEDULE_SAVE o PASTE FPLA_NEW FPLNR FPART BEDAT VBELN PSPNR UPDKZ o PASTE FPLT_NEW FPLNR FPLTR FPTTP TETXT FKDAT FAKWR UPDKZ o Execute</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/billing-plan-details-capturing-issue-against-the-contract-item-in-sap-ecc/qaa-p/14298921#M4934295"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T16:38:21.161000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/billing-plan-details-capturing-issue-against-the-contract-item-in-sap-ecc/qaa-p/14298925#M4934296</id>
    <title>Re: Billing plan details capturing issue against the cont...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T16:40:53.896000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NARAYAN-REDDY</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2272249</uri>
    </author>
    <content>1. BILLING_SCHEDULE_GENERATE o Fill field I_FPART, I_VEDA-VBELN, I_FKDAT, I_UPD_FPLA = 'X' and I_FPLA_ONLY = 'X' (for minimum input) o then copy tables FPLA_NEW dan GET E_FPLNR ($0000001) o Execute 2. BILLING_SCHEDULE_GET_NUMBER o Paste E_FPLNR to I_FPLNR ($0000001) o Fill I_VBELN o PASTE FPLA_NEW to FPLA_NEW o GET E_FPLNR and COPY RESULT FPLA_NEW o Execute 3. BILLING_SCHEDULE_SAVE o PASTE FPLA_NEW FPLNR FPART BEDAT VBELN PSPNR UPDKZ o PASTE FPLT_NEW FPLNR FPLTR FPTTP TETXT FKDAT FAKWR UPDKZ o Execute</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/billing-plan-details-capturing-issue-against-the-contract-item-in-sap-ecc/qaa-p/14298925#M4934296"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T16:40:53.896000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/train-joule-ai-for-sap-ecc-step-by-step-guide-how-to-create-a-joule-skill/ba-p/14298941</id>
    <title>Train Joule AI for SAP ECC: Step-by-Step Guide: How to Create a Joule Skill for SAP ECC</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:00:13.747000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>STALANKI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13911</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="ember1409" id="toc-hId-1767543240"&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Joule is SAP’s AI copilot that helps users perform business tasks using natural language. A Joule skill is a defined capability that allows Joule to answer questions or trigger actions in SAP systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sap joule.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356755iD58AA0406600B7C0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sap joule.jpg" alt="sap joule.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Joule is not natively built for direct integration with SAP ECC (Enterprise Core Component). It is primarily designed as a cloud native AI copilot for SAP's cloud solutions, such as SAP S/4HANA Cloud and SAP SuccessFactors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;However, customers on ECC can still leverage some of Joule's capabilities through hybrid approaches using the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP).&amp;nbsp; This blog explains how to design and create a Joule skill that works with SAP ECC, using SAP’s recommended tools and architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1413" id="toc-hId-1571029735"&gt;Step 1: Understand What a Joule Skill Is&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A Joule skill consists of:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A user intent (what the user asks Joule)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business logic (what happens behind the scenes)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;System integration (ECC in this case)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A structured response back to the user&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;“Joule, show me the open sales orders for top problematic customer ABC.”&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1418" id="toc-hId-1374516230"&gt;Step 2: Identify the Use Case in SAP ECC&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Start with a simple, high value use case.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Good examples&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check sales order status of top 5 customers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer 360 degree snapshots&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Display open invoices&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get material stock levels&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which orders are delayed today?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which materials are at risk this week?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What is product costing for X product in last 5 years? Where am I spending more money?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Define clearly:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What data is needed from ECC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which transaction or table provides it&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Whether it’s read only or triggers an action&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Why it’s great:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales + Finance or Procurement+Finance in one answer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simple answers to today's painful questions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Very executive-friendly and great for planners without systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1426" id="toc-hId-1178002725"&gt;Step 3: Prepare SAP ECC for Integration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Joule does not connect directly to ECC. You need an API layer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Common integration options:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;OData services (via SAP Gateway)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;RFC / BAPI exposed through SAP Integration Suite&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IDocs (less common for Joule)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Actions:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify the ECC function module or BAPI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Expose it as an OData service or API&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test the API independently&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BAPI_SALESORDER_GETSTATUS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BAPI_CUSTOMER_GETDETAIL&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1434" id="toc-hId-981489220"&gt;Step 4: Set Up SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Joule skills are built and orchestrated on SAP BTP. You will need:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP account&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Build Process Automation or Build Apps&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP AI Core / AI Launchpad (if using advanced AI logic)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ensure:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ECC is connected securely to BTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Authentication (OAuth / Principal Propagation) is configured&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1439" id="toc-hId-784975715"&gt;Step 5: Create the Business Logic (Skill Backend)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Now you define what the skill actually does.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Options:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Build Process Automation (recommended)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Build Apps&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CAP (Cloud Application Programming) model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a process or service&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consume the ECC API&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Map input parameters (e.g., customer number)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Format the output clearly for Joule&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Example output:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales order number&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Status&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Delivery date&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1447" id="toc-hId-588462210"&gt;Step 6: Define the Joule Skill (Intent)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This is where Joule learns how users talk.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;You define:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Skill name&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User intent&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sample phrases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Examples:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;“Show open sales orders for customer 10001”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;“What is the status of sales order 4500001234?”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;“Check customer ABC orders”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;These help Joule understand variations in natural language.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1454" id="toc-hId-391948705"&gt;Step 7: Connect Joule to the Backend Logic&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Now connect:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The user intent&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To the backend service or process&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Actions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Map extracted parameters (order number, customer ID)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trigger the ECC API call&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Capture the response&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Return structured data to Joule&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1459" id="toc-hId-195435200"&gt;Step 8: Design the Response Experience&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Joule responses should be:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Short&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clear&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Actionable&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Examples:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Text summary&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bullet points&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Table Style&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Bad response:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;“Here is the data you requested.”&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Good response:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;“Customer ABC has 3 open sales orders. The next delivery is scheduled for 12 Oct.”&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1469" id="toc-hId--1078305"&gt;Step 9: Test the Joule Skill&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Testing is critical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Test scenarios:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Valid and Invalid input&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Missing parameters&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Incorrect values&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No data found&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Performance delays&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Test in:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Joule preview&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BTP logs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ECC backend logs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1475" id="toc-hId-149662547"&gt;Step 10: Secure and Authorize the Skill&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ensure:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Only authorized users can access ECC data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Role based access is enforced&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sensitive fields are masked if needed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Use:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Identity Authentication (IAS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Role collections in BTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ECC authorization objects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1480" id="toc-hId--46850958"&gt;Step 11: Deploy and Enable for Users&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Once tested:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Deploy the backend service&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Activate the Joule skill&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign it to user roles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable it in the SAP application where Joule is use&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember1483" id="toc-hId--243364463"&gt;Step 12: Monitor and Improve&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;After go live:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitor usage&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review failed queries&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Expand to new ECC use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Over time, Joule becomes smarter and more valuable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember1487" id="toc-hId--733280975"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Creating a Joule skill for SAP ECC involves:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clear business use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;API based ECC integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP orchestration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Well designed natural language interaction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;While ECC is a legacy system, Joule allows it to be used in a modern, conversational way.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/search/results/all/?keywords=%23sap&amp;amp;origin=HASH_TAG_FROM_FEED" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/search/results/all/?keywords=%23deloitte&amp;amp;origin=HASH_TAG_FROM_FEED" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#Deloitte&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/search/results/all/?keywords=%23aiinsap&amp;amp;origin=HASH_TAG_FROM_FEED" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#AIinSAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/search/results/all/?keywords=%23joule&amp;amp;origin=HASH_TAG_FROM_FEED" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/search/results/all/?keywords=%23sapecc&amp;amp;origin=HASH_TAG_FROM_FEED" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#SAPECC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/search/results/all/?keywords=%23sapjoule&amp;amp;origin=HASH_TAG_FROM_FEED" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#SAPJoule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/search/results/all/?keywords=%23sapbtp&amp;amp;origin=HASH_TAG_FROM_FEED" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#SAPBTP #EnterpriseAI #AI #Interim&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/train-joule-ai-for-sap-ecc-step-by-step-guide-how-to-create-a-joule-skill/ba-p/14298941"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:00:13.747000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/enable-a-custom-field-in-a-delivery-to-billing-document-scenario/bc-p/14298944#M62949</id>
    <title>Re: Enable a Custom Field in a Delivery to Billing Document Scenario</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:02:52.349000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AngelT</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146474</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131701"&gt;@former_member131701&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you so much for the information; it helped me a lot in enabling the custom field in a delivery document.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Question: I've created a Custom Business Object; can these also be added to a delivery document?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because I haven't been able to do it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would appreciate your comments.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/enable-a-custom-field-in-a-delivery-to-billing-document-scenario/bc-p/14298944#M62949"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:02:52.349000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/course-completed-but-badge-not-generated-sap-learning/qaa-p/14298945#M62418</id>
    <title>Re: Course Completed but Badge Not Generated – SAP Learning</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:03:29.842000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>K_Zakaria</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2272298</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I'm having the same problem, i've completed a bunch of courses, but even after successfully passing the quizes, i receive the mail but not the badge display.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/course-completed-but-badge-not-generated-sap-learning/qaa-p/14298945#M62418"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:03:29.842000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-calculate-vowd-value-of-work-delivered-in-sap-project-system/qaa-p/14298949#M4233971</id>
    <title>Re: How to calculate VOWD (Value of Work Delivered) in SA...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:10:40.822000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ken_Melching</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7218</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Look here for details on progress values that can be calculated in PS.&amp;nbsp; Look at Actual Earned Value, BCWP (Budgeted Cost of Work Performed).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ERP/cfff13ea14f3430488af41bbc02dbb69/1ddfc353b677b44ce10000000a174cb4.html?q=bcwp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ERP/cfff13ea14f3430488af41bbc02dbb69/1ddfc353b677b44ce10000000a174cb4.html?q=bcwp&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-calculate-vowd-value-of-work-delivered-in-sap-project-system/qaa-p/14298949#M4233971"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:10:40.822000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unable-to-generate-e-way-bill-through-fnr-no-for-rake-rail-invoicing/qaa-p/14298950#M4233972</id>
    <title>Re: Unable to generate e-way bill through FNR No for Rake...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:11:46.187000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;What is happening in your case is Error 4042: Invalid RR number is not an SAP error, but a NIC (Government E‑Way Bill portal) validation error. The NIC system has recently tightened validation rules for Railway Receipt (RR) / FNR numbers. Earlier, SAP allowed you to pass the 11‑digit FNR number directly in the FA Tracking No field of VT01N/VT02N, and NIC accepted it. In the last week, NIC has started rejecting numbers that don’t match the expected RR number format. I believe, it is 10 digits, sometimes with prefix rules depending on railway zones.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Check NIC’s latest specification. RR number must be exactly 10 digits. No alphabetic characters, spaces, or prefixes allowed. If you’re passing 11 digits, NIC will reject it.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In VT01N/VT02N, ensure the FA Tracking No field is populated with the correct 10‑digit RR number. If your FNR is 11 digits, confirm whether the first digit is a prefix that should be dropped.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;For GST specific, lot of SAP notes are there and check in Service Marketplace for the latest update&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unable-to-generate-e-way-bill-through-fnr-no-for-rake-rail-invoicing/qaa-p/14298950#M4233972"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:11:46.187000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/help-on-ra-costs-on-gr55/qaa-p/14298951#M4233973</id>
    <title>Re: Help on RA Costs on GR55</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:12:14.983000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ken_Melching</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7218</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Please provide more details on what you have tried so far. And your screenshots didn't come through.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/help-on-ra-costs-on-gr55/qaa-p/14298951#M4233973"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:12:14.983000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/permit-change-of-vbep-etdat-for-partial-deliveries-in-sales-order/qaa-p/14298956#M4233974</id>
    <title>Re: Permit Change of VBEP-ETDAT for partial deliveries in...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:17:38.532000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Standard SAP permits this behavior (manual date changes when WMENG ≠ order qty). To restrict it, you need enhancements (user exits/BAdIs) or screen control. Alternatively, you can track overrides instead of blocking them, so delivery performance reporting remains accurate.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/permit-change-of-vbep-etdat-for-partial-deliveries-in-sales-order/qaa-p/14298956#M4233974"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:17:38.532000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/vat-condition-based-billing-document-extraction-report/qaa-p/14298957#M4233975</id>
    <title>Re: VAT condition–based billing document extraction report</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:24:43.467000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Standard SAP does not provide a delivered report to filter billing documents by VAT condition number in PRCD_ELEMENTS. Compliance report like RFUMSV00 work at FI level, not SD condition level. You will need a custom development (ABAP report or CDS view) to achieve this requirement.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/vat-condition-based-billing-document-extraction-report/qaa-p/14298957#M4233975"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:24:43.467000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-project-manufacturing-management-optimization/bc-p/14298958#M62950</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S/4HANA Project Manufacturing Management &amp; Optimization</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:27:51.813000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hsgezgin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/294606</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148763"&gt;@RahulKini&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are planning to start a new project in related industry and are considering using SAP’s Project Manufacturing Management and Optimization (PMMO) functionality as part of our solution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, we have not been able to find any accessible PMMO demo systems so far. In order to better evaluate the solution and align it with our project needs, we would kindly like to ask if you could share any available PMMO demo content and demo scripts with us.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If possible, could you please send the relevant demo materials to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:zekeriya.akyildiz@bs.nttdata.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;zekeriya.akyildiz@bs.nttdata.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you very much in advance for your support.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-project-manufacturing-management-optimization/bc-p/14298958#M62950"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:27:51.813000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-calculate-vowd-value-of-work-delivered-in-sap-project-system/qaa-p/14298968#M4233976</id>
    <title>Re: How to calculate VOWD (Value of Work Delivered) in SA...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:31:20.509000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;SAP Project System does &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; provide a standard delivered report for VOWD (Value of Work Delivered). VOWD is a petroleum industry–specific metric based on commitments (purchase orders, contracts, services received), whereas SAP’s standard Earned Value (EV) reporting is based on planned values. To calculate VOWD in SAP PS, you typically need a custom development or reporting solution that reads commitments and actuals from PS/CO tables (e.g. EBAN, EKPO, CO commitments, PRCD_ELEMENTS) and applies VOWD rules. The SAP Help documentation on BCWP shared here, does not cover VOWD, because VOWD is not a standard SAP metric.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-calculate-vowd-value-of-work-delivered-in-sap-project-system/qaa-p/14298968#M4233976"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:31:20.509000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sf-story-reports-latest-rating-information-overall-objective-and-competency/qaa-p/14298969#M50070</id>
    <title>Re: SF Story Reports - Latest Rating Information (Overall Objective and Competency Rating + Potentia</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:31:29.184000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abdelrani1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/176609</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I'm trying to performance the same.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sf-story-reports-latest-rating-information-overall-objective-and-competency/qaa-p/14298969#M50070"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:31:29.184000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-s4-hana-public-cloud-create-custom-business-object-and-custom-reusable/qaa-p/14298970#M4934297</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S4/HANA Public Cloud- Create Custom Business Object and Custom Reusable Elements</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:33:23.037000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AngelT</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146474</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;@ Atilay&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you so much for the information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Question: I've created a Custom Business Object; can these also be added to a delivery document?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because I haven't been able to do it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would appreciate your comments.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-s4-hana-public-cloud-create-custom-business-object-and-custom-reusable/qaa-p/14298970#M4934297"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:33:23.037000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/customer-returns-scrapping-process-with-wm-storage-locations-in-s-4hana/ba-p/14298974</id>
    <title>Customer Returns Scrapping Process with WM storage locations in S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:35:05.872000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>varunvenkat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83606</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, I would like to detail the customer returns process (Scope Item ‘BKP’) when it comes to customers that are using warehouse managed (WM) storage locations. As the official scope item test script and official documentation covers the process using simple inventory managed storage locations, I would like to use this blog post to showcase which additional steps occur due to a WM storage location being used. As a specific example for this blog post, I’ll be using the follow up activity 0012 (Scrapping) in the customer returns process to show the steps necessary as a result of using WM storage locations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The process starts with the creation of a returns order (I will be using the advanced returns order with order type ‘CBAR’) and subsequent returns delivery. During the creation of the returns order, choose the follow-up activity “Receive Into Plant” (0001).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now comes the first step, where these is a slightly different process than described in the test script due to the usage of a WM managed storage location. The returns delivery created in the first step will be distributed to the WMS system and therefore cannot be processed using the standard app. You will here need to use the WM specific app “Change Inbound Deliveries – Deliveries”:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_0-1767025841656.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356764i10EDEDF586D567F7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_0-1767025841656.png" alt="varunvenkat_0-1767025841656.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, go into the delivery, post the goods receipt, and create the warehouse tasks, in this order.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_1-1767025841663.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356762iD7616579B3A3879A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_1-1767025841663.png" alt="varunvenkat_1-1767025841663.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After creating the warehouse tasks, go into them and confirm the picking:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_2-1767025841671.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356763i8AFFD5A10C8505EA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_2-1767025841671.png" alt="varunvenkat_2-1767025841671.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_3-1767025841677.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356766i551629654C3CBA1E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_3-1767025841677.png" alt="varunvenkat_3-1767025841677.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that the returns delivery is processed, the next step is to continue with the material inspection in the warehouse (App: Enter Inspection Results – From Warehouse). Here, select the returns delivery, maintain the inspection code, and select the follow-up activity 0012 Scrapping, before saving and confirming the inspection:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_4-1767025841689.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356765i56189AF5976E79E6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_4-1767025841689.png" alt="varunvenkat_4-1767025841689.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upon this, a new outbound delivery will be created in the returns overview, which is the basis for the scrapping. Now, two further important steps come into play, which also need to be executed additionally due to WM storage locations in place.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the app “Process Posting Change Item”, select the appropriate warehouse number and execute. For the outbound delivery item in question, select the item and create a WT in the background:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_5-1767025841697.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356767i271CA1719A8572A5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_5-1767025841697.png" alt="varunvenkat_5-1767025841697.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, double-click on the line, which will open up the created warehouse task in the screen half below. Select the Warehouse task and confirm the WT in the background:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_0-1767026072146.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356772iF7662DD00F32C65A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_0-1767026072146.png" alt="varunvenkat_0-1767026072146.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a final step after this, you will need to use another specific app for this process variant, which is the app “Post Goods Issue – Unplanned”. Here as well, enter the warehouse number, select the GI process “scrapping”, and select Run:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_1-1767026072156.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356773i0437B0E3EA7CD54E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_1-1767026072156.png" alt="varunvenkat_1-1767026072156.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After this, select the line, and execute Post GI. This finally posts the goods issue for scrapping, and the returned material is removed from the inventory of the plant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_2-1767026072161.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356771i38851E3552947A54/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_2-1767026072161.png" alt="varunvenkat_2-1767026072161.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this, the main part of the customer returns process is complete, and the user simply needs to parallelly proceed with the refund control steps (credit memo or replacement delivery). To summarize, when it comes to using WM managed storage locations in this process for the scrapping scenario, the additional apps need to be used on WM side are “Change Inbound Deliveries – Deliveries”, “Process Posting Change Item”, and “Post Goods Issue – Unplanned”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/customer-returns-scrapping-process-with-wm-storage-locations-in-s-4hana/ba-p/14298974"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:35:05.872000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/odata-service-of-business-partner-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud/ba-p/14278613</id>
    <title>OData Service of Business Partner in SAP S/4HANA Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:40:30.317000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Saranga</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1958698</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog provides a complete walkthrough on enabling the &lt;STRONG&gt;API_BUSINESS_PARTNER&lt;/STRONG&gt; OData service for maintaining Business Partner data in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, covering both &lt;STRONG&gt;Public Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Private Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The blog consolidates prerequisites, activation steps, and troubleshooting information into a single reference for technical consultants and integration teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;API_BUSINESS_PARTNER&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;API_BUSINESS_PARTNER&lt;/STRONG&gt; OData service enables &lt;STRONG&gt;CRUD&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;(Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations on supported Business Partner entities, making it a core interface for inbound integration scenarios. This API is intended exclusively for CRUD&lt;STRONG&gt; operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;and it cannot be used&lt;/SPAN&gt; for data replication purposes. For further information about API_BUSINESS_PARTNER, you can refer to the SAP Help Portal for S/4HANA Cloud &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/3c916ef10fc240c9afc594b346ffaf77/85043858ea0f9244e10000000a4450e5.html?version=2602.VAL" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Public Edition&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/44e06f22436c43e582db6ccd5250e29b/85043858ea0f9244e10000000a4450e5.html?version=2025.000" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Private Edition.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before enabling the service, ensure that the system has at least one active Communication Arrangement for the communication scenario &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_COM_0008&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: You do not need an existing SOAP replication service to enable or use this OData service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the scenario has not been configured yet, you can follow these steps –&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a communication user by following this &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/0377adea0401467f939827242c1f4014.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;link.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign the comm&lt;SPAN&gt;unication&lt;/SPAN&gt; user as your current S/4 system’s inbound communication user&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Communication Systems app&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click the &lt;STRONG&gt;Own SAP Cloud System &lt;/STRONG&gt;button&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-23 at 9.37.59 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355258i2B3A2C05E87FDF98/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-23 at 9.37.59 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-23 at 9.37.59 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Edit&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Make a note of the &lt;STRONG&gt;System ID &lt;/STRONG&gt;value, as it will be required for step 3.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Users for Inbound Communication&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab, click the plus button to add a new user.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the authentication method chosen for the user created in step 1.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the ID of the user created in step 1.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click the &lt;STRONG&gt;OK&lt;/STRONG&gt; button.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save your changes. This will also be the user ID to authenticate the OData service.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new Communication Arrangement.&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Communication Arrangements app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on the &lt;STRONG&gt;New &lt;/STRONG&gt;button.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_COM_0008 &lt;/STRONG&gt;as the &lt;EM&gt;Scenario&lt;/EM&gt;, and provide a concise, identifiable &lt;EM&gt;Arrangement Name&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Common Data&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab, choose the current SAP Cloud system (noted down in step 2) as the &lt;EM&gt;Communication System&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under the &lt;EM&gt;Inbound Communication &lt;/EM&gt;tab, choose the User Name as the user assigned to the current SAP System as per step 2.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Deactivate all the services under the &lt;EM&gt;Outbound Services &lt;/EM&gt;tab by unchecking the &lt;STRONG&gt;Service Status &lt;/STRONG&gt;checkbox for each service.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save your changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling the Service in Public Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, the OData service for API_BUSINESS_PARTNER is activated automatically as soon as the communication arrangement for SAP_COM_0008 is created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Locating the OData Endpoint&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Communication Arrangements app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the relevant communication arrangement.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to the Inbound Services tab.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Locate the entry &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Partner (A2X)&lt;/STRONG&gt; — the Service URL displayed here is your API endpoint.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-23 at 9.54.58 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355259i344F2DB26A1017F2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-23 at 9.54.58 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-23 at 9.54.58 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using the Endpoint&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This URL can be consumed through:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Any third-party API testing tool&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP API Sandbox&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;REST clients used in your existing landscape&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling the Service in Private Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition, some additional manual checks are required to activate and validate the service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Register or Verify the OData Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow these steps to ensure that API_BUSINESS_PARTNER is available in the SAP Gateway:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open Transaction: &lt;STRONG&gt;/IWFND/MAINT_SERVICE&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Service Catalog).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the &lt;EM&gt;External Service Name&lt;/EM&gt; filter, search for: &lt;STRONG&gt;API_BUSINESS_PARTNER&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If found → continue to Step 6&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If not → proceed to next step&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.42.03 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355288i319A73125C66820B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.42.03 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.42.03 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click Add Service.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.42.57 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355289i57242B1A3FBCAC3B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.42.57 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.42.57 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Search again using &lt;EM&gt;External Service Name&lt;/EM&gt;: &lt;STRONG&gt;API_BUSINESS_PARTNER&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;System Alias: &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;LOCAL&lt;/STRONG&gt;. If System Alias LOCAL doesn’t exist in the list of SAP System Aliases, press the button &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add System Alias&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and add the value LOCAL.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-23 at 10.08.54 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355290i16794CE6E92735F7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-23 at 10.08.54 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-23 at 10.08.54 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add the service via the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/68bf513362174d54b58cddec28794093/bb2bfe50645c741ae10000000a423f68.html?version=202510.000" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;standard provisioning steps&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check if the &lt;STRONG&gt;ICF Node &lt;/STRONG&gt;associated with the service is active in the Service Catalog (green traffic light). If not active, select the node → ICF Node dropdown menu → Activate. The service should now be active.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.47.39 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355292iB13A8D6F42EF5D57/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.47.39 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.47.39 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.48.06 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355291i3469B6F6478C8375/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.48.06 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.48.06 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;We can proceed to test our activated OData service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tip: &lt;/STRONG&gt;If the system shows the message “SAP System Message: User no longer logged on” when launching a /IWFND transaction, prefix it with &lt;EM&gt;/n&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example:&lt;/EM&gt; /n/IWFND/MAINT_SERVICE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Test the Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The service can be validated using the SAP Gateway Client:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Via the SAP Gateway Client button within the Service Catalog, or&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transaction: /IWFND/GW_CLIENT&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Issue: Service Active but Not Usable (Private Cloud)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even after registering and activating the service, you may encounter access issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Service Catalog entry for API_BUSINESS_PARTNER, ensure that the SAP System Alias is set to: &lt;STRONG&gt;LOCAL&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.49.04 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355270iBF759E19185C53AC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.49.04 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-12-12 at 2.49.04 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765693224"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569179719"&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you have successfully completed the setup steps outlined above for your respective S/4HANA Cloud edition, the API_BUSINESS_PARTNER OData service will be ready for integration into your landscape. For a comprehensive list of all supported entities and CRUD operations, refer to the SAP Business Accelerator for S/4HANA Cloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/API_BUSINESS_PARTNER/resource/Email_Address" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/OP_API_BUSINESS_PARTNER_SRV/resource/Email_Address" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Private Edition&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/odata-service-of-business-partner-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud/ba-p/14278613"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:40:30.317000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/end-to-end-buyer-and-supplier-flow-visualization-in-erp-systems/ba-p/14298976</id>
    <title>End to End Buyer and Supplier flow visualization in ERP systems</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:44:51.728000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>varunvenkat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83606</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Community,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;in this short blog post, I would like to share my insights over the last years on how I've personally come to understanding the intertwined perspectives and bidirectional data-flow between ERP systems. From the sales perspective, you have the standard document flow of the Quote-to-Cash process such as Sales Quotation, Sales Order, Outbound Delivery, Goods Issue, and Customer Invoice. The similar document flow goes for the Procure-to-Pay process involving Purchasing Requisition, Purchase Order, Supplier Confirmation, Inbound Delivery, Goods Receipt, and Supplier Invoice. I've decided to just put together a combined data flow which represents the document from one of the perspectives (seller) , and what this corresponds to from the perspective of the recipient (buyer) of the document. Hope this helps some of you in better understanding both sides of the coin &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_0-1767026586228.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/356774i351C467B24F5D3FF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_0-1767026586228.png" alt="varunvenkat_0-1767026586228.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/end-to-end-buyer-and-supplier-flow-visualization-in-erp-systems/ba-p/14298976"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:44:51.728000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/help-on-ra-costs-on-gr55/qaa-p/14298977#M4233977</id>
    <title>Re: Help on RA Costs on GR55</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T17:48:05.301000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;To answer your question "Where the RA Value Comes From (CJE0)", the figure you see (572,601.05) is calculated by the RA key assigned to the WBS element/network.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;RA derives values from:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Planned costs (from PS/CO planning)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Actual costs (from CO postings)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Commitments (POs, PRs)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Revenue recognition rules (depending on RA method: cost-based, revenue-based, percentage of completion, etc.)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;These values are stored in RA tables (e.g. COSB, COEP, COEJ, and summarized into COSP/COSS).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;So the number in CJE0 is not a “posted” cost, but a calculated RA value.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Why it doesn’t appear in GR55 is because, GR55 reports are based on Report Painter/Writer definitions, usually pulling from FI/CO totals tables (COSP, COSS, GL accounts). By default, GR55 shows posted actuals and plan values, not RA calculated values. RA values are valuation results, not automatically transferred into FI/CO totals unless you run settlement or RA transfer to FI. If RA results are not settled or transferred, GR55 will show “no cost recorded” because it only sees posted costs.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Ensure RA results are transferred to FI/CO (via transaction KKA2/KKA3 or settlement). Without transfer, GR55 won’t pick them up.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If you want RA values in GR55, you need to extend the report to include RA line items (from COSB/COEP). Standard GR55 does not include RA valuation results.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;For RA values, SAP recommends CJE0/CJEN or RA line item reports. GR55 is not intended to show RA valuation unless customized.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/help-on-ra-costs-on-gr55/qaa-p/14298977#M4233977"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T17:48:05.301000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-dm-st2300-use-of-esef-transformation-registry-version-5/qaa-p/14298978#M257180</id>
    <title>Re: SAP DM ST2300 - Use of ESEF transformation registry v...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T18:14:09.168000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marc_Kuipers</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Iwona&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I expect this to be included in the next SP, Stack 2301&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Will be released in Q1 of 2026 (probably in March)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Marc&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-dm-st2300-use-of-esef-transformation-registry-version-5/qaa-p/14298978#M257180"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T18:14:09.168000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-hyphen-supported-for-server-name-in-sap-data-services/qaq-p/14298979</id>
    <title>Is Hyphen supported for Server Name in SAP Data Services?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T18:14:52.872000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Using a &lt;STRONG&gt;hyphen (-)&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the hostname is fully supported for DS/IPS installation and operation?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-hyphen-supported-for-server-name-in-sap-data-services/qaq-p/14298979"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T18:14:52.872000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-hyphen-supported-for-server-name-in-sap-data-services/qaa-p/14298980#M4233979</id>
    <title>Re: Is Hyphen supported for Server Name in SAP Data Servi...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T18:15:01.487000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The hyphen ('-') is generally not treated as a special character, so it should not cause any issues in a server name.&lt;BR /&gt;The following special characters are not allowed for server name: &amp;amp;, &amp;lt;, &amp;gt;, ", ’, or _.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-hyphen-supported-for-server-name-in-sap-data-services/qaa-p/14298980#M4233979"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T18:15:01.487000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-load-cr-reports-after-upgrading-to-sp-13-39/qaa-p/14298981#M4934298</id>
    <title>Re: Cannot load CR reports after upgrading to SP 13_39</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T18:15:21.188000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SuperCoder</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/452221</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Can I revert back to 13_31? This version worked fine.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-load-cr-reports-after-upgrading-to-sp-13-39/qaa-p/14298981#M4934298"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T18:15:21.188000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/balance-carry-forward-faglgvtr-behave-differntly-in-personas-and-rise/qaa-p/14298982#M4934299</id>
    <title>Re: Balance Carry Forward (FAGLGVTR) behave differntly in...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T18:15:53.808000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tamas_Hoznek</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/182281</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SP18 is out of support by now, so if it turns out that there is an issue with Personas, you will need to upgrade.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is the problem only with Slipstream, or also present when using webgui?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/balance-carry-forward-faglgvtr-behave-differntly-in-personas-and-rise/qaa-p/14298982#M4934299"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T18:15:53.808000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-4hana-implementing-flexible-billing-document-numbering-with/bc-p/14299146#M72412</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S/4HANA: Implementing Flexible Billing Document Numbering with Configurable Parameters and F</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T18:28:27.287000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>WeekendVampire</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/180252</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Can this also be used to keep the FI document number the same as the SD number, even if the SD one is alphanumeric?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/sap-s-4hana-implementing-flexible-billing-document-numbering-with/bc-p/14299146#M72412"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T18:28:27.287000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/posting-into-previous-period-even-though-the-setting-in-mmrv-doesn-t-allow/qaq-p/14299157</id>
    <title>Posting into previous period even though the setting in MMRV doesn’t allow it</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T18:29:18.708000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Harini2706</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1422366</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Hello All, we are using S4. The current period in MMRV for my company code is 12 2025 and previous 11 2025. Allowing posting to previous periods is NOT marked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;However users are able to post a GR with document and posting date in 11 2025. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Finance periods are also from 12 2025 to 01 2026. Any idea why despite everything being correct, why is the posting into 11 2025 happening?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/posting-into-previous-period-even-though-the-setting-in-mmrv-doesn-t-allow/qaq-p/14299157"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T18:29:18.708000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/new-zealand-ird-bypass-on-compliance-form/qaq-p/14299276</id>
    <title>New Zealand IRD bypass on compliance form</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T18:43:59.081000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ashwik</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/181081</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have a business scenario where non-resident employees are being onboarded through SAP SuccessFactors in New Zealand. These individuals may not have an IRD number at the time of onboarding. However, they are still required to complete the compliance form, which currently has the IRD number set as a mandatory field.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone encountered a similar situation? If so, what approaches or best practices did you use to handle this requirement? We’re looking for ways to bypass or manage this mandatory field until the IRD number becomes available, while ensuring the compliance form is completed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any advice or recommendations would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;BR /&gt;Ashwik&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/new-zealand-ird-bypass-on-compliance-form/qaq-p/14299276"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T18:43:59.081000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-public-cloud-1jt-lockbox/qaq-p/14299282</id>
    <title>SAP Public Cloud_1JT_LOCKBOX</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T19:00:31.816000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sgurulingaiah</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2264369</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Client wants to 1JT_LOCKBOX to be activated in SAP Public cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could anyone provide step by step process and challenges.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAPLOCKBOX #LOCKBOX #1JT_LOCKBOX #1JT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-public-cloud-1jt-lockbox/qaq-p/14299282"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T19:00:31.816000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/custom-reusable-elements-and-custom-business-objects/qaa-p/14299283#M257182</id>
    <title>Re: Custom Reusable elements and Custom Business Objects.</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T19:08:15.700000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Good day&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146474"&gt;@AngelT&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarise, you are not missing a hidden switch or something. The scenario you see is expected in public cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Regarding Reusable Elements not appearing in the Code List based on CDS View, it is important you note that a Custom Code List created in Custom Reusable Elements is not a CDS view. Therefore, what you expect will never appear in the field type Code List based on CDS View because that value help expects a CDS View that fulfills specific requirements. See: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/46632054fa9d49a18b452ee287173aba.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/46632054fa9d49a18b452ee287173aba.html?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/acb2907f362944a5a9e1b5eb86e769dc.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/acb2907f362944a5a9e1b5eb86e769dc.html?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I suggest you instead use field type Code List (not “based on CDS View”) and select your published Custom Code List.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To answer your question regarding Manage Master Data app, you do not enable reusable element directly in Manage Master Data. You should rather enable a custom field for that app UI. See references &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/46632054fa9d49a18b452ee287173aba.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Before Getting Started with Custom Fields&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/3a713139e548434e8a50800e7a7c8172.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating Custom Fields&lt;/A&gt; for further insights.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Regarding your point/question on Custom Business Objects not appearing in Code List based on CDS View, note that CBO is also not a CDS view, so it will not show up in the value help view list for Code List based on CDS view. See &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/acb2907f362944a5a9e1b5eb86e769dc.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating a Field of the Type Code List Based on CDS View&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/b45696ca0d9143cba040797e9c71aa44.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Custom Business Objects&lt;/A&gt; for more insights.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I suggest you use a custom field type Association to Business Objects and build the value help through Custom CDS View as described here: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_MARKETING_CLOUD/e0cd7c1ecf3d4f2f9feb46ec1c5b68fb/93f6abd65d754b38b259ca6ae23f69e9.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_MARKETING_CLOUD/e0cd7c1ecf3d4f2f9feb46ec1c5b68fb/93f6abd65d754b38b259ca6ae23f69e9.html?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you really need a Code List based on CDS View, then create a Custom CDS View that reads the CBO data and use that Custom CDS View as the value help view. See &lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3124156" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KBA 3124156&lt;/A&gt; for some issues that may arise when you consider this option.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me know if you have further questions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/custom-reusable-elements-and-custom-business-objects/qaa-p/14299283#M257182"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T19:08:15.700000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/fm-document-is-not-generated-at-the-pr-po-level/qaq-p/14299290</id>
    <title>FM document is not generated at the PR/PO Level</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T19:28:19.775000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aftab_Ahmed65</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2215152</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am currently encountering an issue in PSM-FM regarding document generation. While the system does not appear to be generating a specific FM document at the time of PR or PO creation, the budget consumption is still being correctly updated and reflected in report &lt;STRONG&gt;FMRW_RP_BUDCON&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Could you please help investigate why the FM documents are missing despite the budget being consumed?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/fm-document-is-not-generated-at-the-pr-po-level/qaq-p/14299290"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T19:28:19.775000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/sap-customer-checkout-plugin-development-part-iv/bc-p/14299295#M6909</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Customer Checkout Plugin Development – Part IV</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T19:55:58.273000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GeekDev</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2208289</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Robert,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First of all I wanna thank you for your tutorial series, really have been pretty helpful for me for comprehending more about the world for developing plugins for SAP Customer Checkout.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to ask you if you know what can I do for rather than inserting the data in UDF's of the invoice, more like on the UDF's of the payment of that invoice? I tried at first just setting that extension step at&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;sap.POS.POSTInvoice_Payments&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;rather than on&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;sap.POS.POSTInvoice_Documents&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but it was giving me issues because of a value that didn't exist. Or should I make that action directly through ways like modifying the POSTInvoice step and its atoms?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/sap-customer-checkout-plugin-development-part-iv/bc-p/14299295#M6909"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T19:55:58.273000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-display-home-address-on-compensation-statement/qaa-p/14299296#M50072</id>
    <title>Re: How to display home address on compensation statement?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T19:58:21.779000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/integration-center-demo-for-the-compensation-module/ba-p/13501971" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/integration-center-demo-for-the-compensation-module/ba-p/13501971&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;it's the exact use case of the recording of this blog (and it came from a post on this community) ... you need to use MDF + Integration center if what &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721"&gt;@DavidSomelofske&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;@ proposed doesn't work for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Xavier&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-display-home-address-on-compensation-statement/qaa-p/14299296#M50072"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T19:58:21.779000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/delta-issue-in-stip-payout-in-variable-pay/qaa-p/14299299#M50073</id>
    <title>Re: Delta issue in STIP Payout % in Variable Pay</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T20:11:48.353000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1395772"&gt;@RituSingh12&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First of all you need to provide more screenshots because it's really hard to help without actually seeing the actual field you are talking about. For you STIP Target % makes sense but every customer calls this differently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now I think the issue here is what &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721"&gt;@DavidSomelofske&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;suggested (issue with number of decimals on one of the format) except you need to add the decimals NOT To the format tied to the STIP Target % field but to the AMOUNT fields used to determine that %.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Variable Pay uses amounts to derive % at almost every single level except the business goal itself if you use Direct Percent as payout metric.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is my advise: create a copy of your template. In the duplicated template, make ALL number formats end with .########### then run bonus calculation and launch worksheets and check whether the issue is fixed. If fixed, then revert number formats of the amount fields until you find the one that needs the extra decimals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If still not fixed then you might need to add a custom format to your basis fied directly in the succession data model like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="xavierlegarrec_0-1767035366919.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/357061i5561292C51B777A9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="xavierlegarrec_0-1767035366919.png" alt="xavierlegarrec_0-1767035366919.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="xavierlegarrec_1-1767035406590.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/357062iCF4C3F98FD1A22E9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="xavierlegarrec_1-1767035406590.png" alt="xavierlegarrec_1-1767035406590.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm pretty sure I've replied to this exact issue on a different thread in the past on this community......&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Xavier&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/delta-issue-in-stip-payout-in-variable-pay/qaa-p/14299299#M50073"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T20:11:48.353000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/display-in-progress-workflows-in-compensation-forms-during-annual-salary/bc-p/14299300#M7435</id>
    <title>Re: Display In-Progress Workflows in Compensation Forms during Annual Salary Review</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T20:13:36.124000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;That's right, I think your solution is sound, I just think it's our role to tell the business when requirements deviate from what the 90% of other organizations would do. And if they make it a showstopper and it gets approved as a requirement from up top then yes we'll try to find a workaround like yours for it. Thanks for documenting it !&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/display-in-progress-workflows-in-compensation-forms-during-annual-salary/bc-p/14299300#M7435"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T20:13:36.124000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/is-it-possible-to-add-charts-to-compenstation-statement/qaa-p/14299303#M50074</id>
    <title>Re: Is it possible to add charts to compenstation statement?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T20:15:23.435000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/q-a-forum-archive/dynamic-pie-or-donut-chart-on-comp-statements/m-p/171873#M6150" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/q-a-forum-archive/dynamic-pie-or-donut-chart-on-comp-statements/m-p/171873#M6150&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/is-it-possible-to-add-charts-to-compenstation-statement/qaa-p/14299303#M50074"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T20:15:23.435000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/disable-download-statement-button-in-compensation-worksheet/qaa-p/14299305#M50075</id>
    <title>Re: Disable download statement button in compensation wor...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T20:16:35.928000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Yes that's correct, the logo on top right corner is only activated with "Enable Bulk Print Statement" option in Plan Setup &amp;gt; Settings</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/disable-download-statement-button-in-compensation-worksheet/qaa-p/14299305#M50075"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T20:16:35.928000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/program-settings-apply-gates-and-accelerators/qaa-p/14299311#M50076</id>
    <title>Re: Program Settings: Apply Gates and Accelerators</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T20:19:27.515000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/21233"&gt;@MVEL&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is documented with lots of details and examples here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/gates-and-accelerators-in-variable-pay/ba-p/13530738" target="_blank"&gt;Gates and Accelerators in Variable Pay&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-interpolate-and-step-business-goals-calculations-in-variable/ba-p/13545232" target="_blank"&gt;Understanding Interpolate and Step business goals calculations in Variable Pay&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/bonus-caps-examples-in-variable-pay/ba-p/13504506" target="_blank"&gt;Bonus Caps examples in Variable Pay&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Xavier&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/program-settings-apply-gates-and-accelerators/qaa-p/14299311#M50076"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T20:19:27.515000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/proration-based-on-month/qaa-p/14299314#M50077</id>
    <title>Re: Proration based on month</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T20:20:53.014000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1431381"&gt;@Gunnar92&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Still not feasible as confirmed by David, here is the post:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-proration-calculation/qaq-p/12752317?search-action-id=460334924060&amp;amp;search-result-uid=12752317" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-proration-calculation/qaq-p/12752317?search-action-id=460334924060&amp;amp;search-result-uid=12752317&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was able to convince a customer switching from Workday to use our exact-date proration instead of month-based (which seems to be the standard in Workday according to that customer) without much hurdles once they crunches numbers. And if I remember correctly they said that workday forced them to re-run eligibility after every month end for payouts to be correct at the end of the year so they were happy not to have to do that anymore.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Xavier&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/proration-based-on-month/qaa-p/14299314#M50077"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T20:20:53.014000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/manage-production-orders-app-save-as-tile-dynamic-count-does-not-refresh/qaq-p/14299342</id>
    <title>Manage Production Orders app save as tile - Dynamic count does not refresh</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T20:37:18.967000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TDR4</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7116</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all. Question, we are in S4H 2023 Private Cloud. In app Manage Production Orders (F2336), you can execute the report and save the report as a Tile. The tile contains a live count similar to many other apps with the same function. The counts on the other apps do refresh, but the Manage Production Orders app does not. I've opened a note with SAP but they have not been helpful yet.&amp;nbsp;Does anyone else have issues with this? Is this function working for anyone else using S4H 2023? Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/manage-production-orders-app-save-as-tile-dynamic-count-does-not-refresh/qaq-p/14299342"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T20:37:18.967000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-there-any-standard-purchase-requisition-uploader-in-sap-s-4-hana-public/qaa-p/14299344#M4233980</id>
    <title>Re: Is there any Standard Purchase Requisition uploader i...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T20:38:36.509000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dawid90</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172309</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1399105"&gt;@aniruddhab&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Public Cloud there is no generic standard Excel uploader app for mass creation of Purchase Requisitions like a simple file-upload template. SAP even note that there is no suitable Migration Cockpit object mass-change option for PR bulk creation in Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3411702" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3411702&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IMPORTANT.&lt;/STRONG&gt; If you are running Central Procurement / Central Purchasing as a hub there is the standard Fiori app Schedule Import of Purchasing Documents which can import purchase requisitions from connected systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/5853c320b10a49228c1ca8bde17e3802.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/5853c320b10a49228c1ca8bde17e3802.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F3268')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F3268')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For building your own PR uploader, SAP provides a public API (recommended for Public Cloud)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;API name: API_PURCHASEREQUISITION_2&lt;BR /&gt;This is the OData V4 Purchase Requisition API and is the recommended successor. SAP Help also shows the typical OData V4 service pattern for this API (host-dependent)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/bb9f1469daf04bd894ab2167f8132a1a/43c43f584eff2160e10000000a44147b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/bb9f1469daf04bd894ab2167f8132a1a/43c43f584eff2160e10000000a44147b.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/bb9f1469daf04bd894ab2167f8132a1a/dad2402e2ff543e7971d788bf35b12c1.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/bb9f1469daf04bd894ab2167f8132a1a/dad2402e2ff543e7971d788bf35b12c1.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/bb9f1469daf04bd894ab2167f8132a1a/de371314a0fc46e5a54b0c1cdd0d8ce4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/bb9f1469daf04bd894ab2167f8132a1a/de371314a0fc46e5a54b0c1cdd0d8ce4.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/CE_PURCHASEREQUISITION_0001/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/CE_PURCHASEREQUISITION_0001/overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IMPORTANT.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Older API (deprecated)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dawid90_0-1767036875692.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/357091i82B15811DDB6279F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dawid90_0-1767036875692.png" alt="dawid90_0-1767036875692.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommendation for your PR uploader:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Build a small service/app (SAP BTP Integration Suite) that:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. reads Excel/CSV&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. validates data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. calls API_PURCHASEREQUISITION_2 to create PRs in bulk&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dawid&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-there-any-standard-purchase-requisition-uploader-in-sap-s-4-hana-public/qaa-p/14299344#M4233980"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T20:38:36.509000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/posting-into-previous-period-even-though-the-setting-in-mmrv-doesn-t-allow/qaa-p/14299345#M208725</id>
    <title>Re: Posting into previous period even though the setting in MMRV doesn’t allow it</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T20:41:22.282000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>WirkKarl</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2079878</uri>
    </author>
    <content>It sounds like there might be an override somewhere outside the MMRV settings, like a special authorization or tolerance for certain users. You could check if the users posting to 11/2025 have special period-end authorizations or if there’s a batch job that allows backdating. Sometimes SAP allows postings in previous periods if the user has the “Posting in Previous Period” authorization even if the checkbox in MMRV isn’t set.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/posting-into-previous-period-even-though-the-setting-in-mmrv-doesn-t-allow/qaa-p/14299345#M208725"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T20:41:22.282000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/call-derivations-on-custom-event-in-sap-mdg/qaa-p/14299346#M4934303</id>
    <title>Re: Call derivations on custom event in sap mdg</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T21:01:01.541000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VISHAL_JHA</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157848</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks for the response. The enrichment triggers when event Check is triggered however in my requirement enrichment should trigger on custom button and should not triggered on check. Please suggest</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/call-derivations-on-custom-event-in-sap-mdg/qaa-p/14299346#M4934303"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T21:01:01.541000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/ewm-bulk-storage-type-setup-putaway-and-picking-strategy/bc-p/14299347#M6317</id>
    <title>Re: EWM Bulk Storage Type Setup, Putaway and Picking strategy</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T21:13:26.518000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>23985754</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/811428</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot ! This is very clear and has helped us a lot to fix our issue.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/ewm-bulk-storage-type-setup-putaway-and-picking-strategy/bc-p/14299347#M6317"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T21:13:26.518000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-use-coois-cohv-as-a-production-cockpit/bc-p/14299348#M72413</id>
    <title>Re: How to use COOIS / COHV as a production cockpit</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T21:20:15.315000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>23985754</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/811428</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, To automatically have the button displayed, select the button in the mass tab of the selection screen with COHV.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-use-coois-cohv-as-a-production-cockpit/bc-p/14299348#M72413"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T21:20:15.315000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/which-sap-ias-tenant-should-be-used-for-sap-btp-when-configuring-joule-in-s/qaa-p/14299354#M4233981</id>
    <title>Re: Which SAP IAS tenant should be used for SAP BTP when...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T21:35:56.228000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dawid90</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172309</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122466"&gt;@oquijano0327&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answers for questions below:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dawid90_0-1767040148736.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/357098i9CE1A6750CA20BCB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dawid90_0-1767040148736.png" alt="dawid90_0-1767040148736.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re implementing Joule against &lt;STRONG&gt;non-production&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Connect the BTP subaccount used for that Joule setup to IAS Test if your system non-prod tenant is using IAS Test&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;That keeps the end-to-end chain consistent for that environment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re implementing Joule for &lt;STRONG&gt;production&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Connect the production Joule BTP subaccount to IAS Productive because production system should authenticate against that IAS tenant&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below in PDF (Integrating Joule with SAP Solutions):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/de3af3c0f81642dbaa4d36172ed57a72/CLOUD/en-US/79bfc83ab386450c8cd9c7937ce26a3a.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/doc/de3af3c0f81642dbaa4d36172ed57a72/CLOUD/en-US/79bfc83ab386450c8cd9c7937ce26a3a.pdf&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dawid90_1-1767040148739.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/357099iD7066819B61E6D97/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dawid90_1-1767040148739.png" alt="dawid90_1-1767040148739.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Answers for questions below:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dawid90_2-1767040148741.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/357100i09240B860D9E2C7A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dawid90_2-1767040148741.png" alt="dawid90_2-1767040148741.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP best practices&lt;/STRONG&gt; for Joule guide explicitly recommends operating each independent entity from its own dedicated SAP BTP subaccount, aligned to a single IAS tenant&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Typical landscape pattern:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BTP subaccount (DEV/TEST Joule): Trust to IAS Test, integrates system non-prod and Work Zone used for Joule in that landscape&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BTP subaccount (PROD Joule): Trust to IAS Productive, integrates system production&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This also fits how IAS tenants are meant to structure landscapes: SAP notes that test vs productive tenants are technically the same the tenant type is mainly landscape structuring&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/tenant-model-and-licensing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/tenant-model-and-licensing&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why this is usually the cleanest approach:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No cross-environment identity coupling&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Clear separation of administrator changes, troubleshooting and audits&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoids accidental user access from productive identities into non-prod apps or vice versa&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IMPORTANT.&lt;/STRONG&gt; The Global User ID is owned by IAS and is tenant-specific, so if you use IAS Test and IAS Productive the same person will typically have different Global User IDs in each environment which is fine as long as you treat them as separate Joule landscapes. It becomes a problem only if you try to mix systems from different IAS tenants into one Joule formation, which SAP explicitly warns against&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Public Cloud + Joule specifics to watch:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;OIDC trust in BTP to IAS (not SAML)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Same IAS domain across the integrated chain&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identity Provisioning (IPS) is typically needed especially because Joule uses SAP Build Work Zone for navigation scenarios and role-based access&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Don’t try to integrate multiple system tenants of the same product into one Joule formation use separate subscriptions/subaccounts if you must&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrating Joule with SAP Solutions (Guide PDF) prerequisites trust to IAS, constraints and the single IAS / single product-tenant per formation rules&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Global User ID in integration scenarios (Cloud Identity) explains tenant-specific ownership of the Global User ID&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services tenant model / tenant types clarifies test vs productive are functionally the same and mainly landscape structuring&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BTP trust to Identity Authentication&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity/system-integration-guide/global-user-id-in-integration-scenarios" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity/system-integration-guide/global-user-id-in-integration-scenarios&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/de3af3c0f81642dbaa4d36172ed57a72/CLOUD/en-US/79bfc83ab386450c8cd9c7937ce26a3a.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/doc/de3af3c0f81642dbaa4d36172ed57a72/CLOUD/en-US/79bfc83ab386450c8cd9c7937ce26a3a.pdf&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/tenant-types" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-identity-services/cloud-identity-services/tenant-types&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/managing-trust-from-sap-btp-to-identity-authentication-tenant?version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/managing-trust-from-sap-btp-to-identity-authentication-tenant?version=Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dawid&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/which-sap-ias-tenant-should-be-used-for-sap-btp-when-configuring-joule-in-s/qaa-p/14299354#M4233981"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T21:35:56.228000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/1h-2026-successfactors-onboarding-enhancement-smarter-more-flexible-form-i/bc-p/14299355#M9612</id>
    <title>Re: 1H 2026 SuccessFactors Onboarding Enhancement: Smarter, More Flexible Form I-9 Reverification</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T21:36:20.214000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JulieMcSwain</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/48597</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, This is very good news! I am currently in the midst of the above scenarios, and it has not been fun trying to get this completed in the system currently needing multiple SAP Support tickets.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To clarify, are these enhancements coming in the 1H or 2H 2026 release?&amp;nbsp; EDIT: I just re-read the title of this post, lol, and it says this is for the 1H 2026 release. Yeah! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;~Julie&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/1h-2026-successfactors-onboarding-enhancement-smarter-more-flexible-form-i/bc-p/14299355#M9612"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T21:36:20.214000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/documenting-decisions-and-exceptions-in-sap-business-workflow-using-onenote/ba-p/14296169</id>
    <title>Documenting Decisions and Exceptions in SAP Business Workflow Using OneNote</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T21:45:14.130000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>danielkeuch</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2271678</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Workflow provides powerful capabilities to model, execute, and monitor business processes across the SAP system landscape. Tasks, events, roles, and error reactions can be defined in a structured and repeatable way, making workflows especially valuable for approval processes and exception handling scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, while SAP Business Workflow describes &lt;EM&gt;what&lt;/EM&gt; happens and &lt;EM&gt;when&lt;/EM&gt;, it often does not capture &lt;EM&gt;why&lt;/EM&gt; certain decisions were made or how specific exceptions were intentionally handled. This contextual knowledge is usually created outside the system and can be difficult to retrieve later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This post describes a lightweight approach to documenting SAP Business Workflow decisions and exceptions using Microsoft OneNote as a complementary tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1767476040"&gt;What SAP Business Workflow Covers – and What It Doesn’t&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Workflow excels at orchestrating business processes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;triggering workflows based on events&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;routing tasks to responsible roles or positions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;reacting to errors and exceptional situations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;supporting repeatable and auditable process execution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;What it does not reliably capture is the surrounding context:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;why a certain approval rule was chosen&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;which alternatives were discussed and rejected&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;why a standard workflow was adjusted&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;which exceptions are intentionally tolerated&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This information is often discussed during workshops, design sessions, or incident resolution meetings and then disappears into emails or personal notes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1570962535"&gt;Typical Workflow Knowledge That Gets Lost&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In real SAP projects, workflow-related knowledge is created continuously, for example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;business assumptions behind approval steps&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;escalation logic agreed with stakeholders&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;decisions made to handle error-triggered workflows&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;reasons for deviating from standard SAP workflows&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;lessons learned after workflow failures&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;While none of this information is strictly required to &lt;EM&gt;run&lt;/EM&gt; a workflow, it becomes highly relevant months or years later when workflows are reviewed, extended, or questioned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1374449030"&gt;Using OneNote as a Lightweight Companion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;OneNote is not part of SAP Business Workflow, and it should not replace system documentation or configuration tools. Its value lies in capturing contextual knowledge quickly and close to the source. In practice, I have found that capturing these decisions immediately after discussions is far more effective than documenting them later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In practice, OneNote can be used to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;document decisions directly during workflow design discussions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;capture rationale while it is still fresh&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;collect screenshots or references without interrupting SAP work&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;keep workflow-related notes searchable over time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because OneNote is flexible and lightweight, it supports documentation “in the moment” instead of postponing it to formal documents that are often never completed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1177935525"&gt;Example: Documenting a Workflow Exception&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The example below illustrates how workflow-related context, decisions, and follow-up actions can be captured in a lightweight way without duplicating technical workflow configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot-OneNote.jpg" style="width: 889px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355164i98810C5CCDFC7D5C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot-OneNote.jpg" alt="Screenshot-OneNote.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-981422020"&gt;Why This Matters in an AI Context&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As AI-assisted tools become more common in enterprise environments, the quality of underlying information becomes increasingly important.&lt;BR /&gt;AI systems rely on structured, contextual input to summarize, search, or analyze knowledge effectively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While this approach does not focus on a specific AI solution, consistently documented workflow decisions and exceptions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;are easier to summarize automatically&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;can be searched semantically&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;can be reused across projects and teams&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this sense, lightweight documentation prepares SAP Business Workflow knowledge for future AI-assisted analysis without introducing additional complexity today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-784908515"&gt;Limitations and Considerations&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach has clear boundaries:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;it does not replace workflow configuration or monitoring tools&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;it is not official project documentation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sensitive or customer-specific data must be handled carefully&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;OneNote works best as a personal or small-team knowledge base that complements SAP Business Workflow rather than competing with it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-588395010"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Workflow is highly effective at executing business processes, but long-term understanding depends on capturing the context behind decisions and exceptions. By using a simple tool like Microsoft OneNote to document this information, workflow-related knowledge can be preserved in a practical and accessible way.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Over time, this helps maintain clarity, supports future changes, and improves confidence in how SAP Business Workflow solutions were designed and why they work the way they do.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/documenting-decisions-and-exceptions-in-sap-business-workflow-using-onenote/ba-p/14296169"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T21:45:14.130000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/discovery-first-ai-assessment-for-sap-landscapes-an-essay/ba-p/14297147</id>
    <title>Discovery‑First AI Assessment for SAP Landscapes, An Essay</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T21:46:13.323000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TrijoySaikia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1433645</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Artificial Intelligence in SAP environments has shifted from being an “external accelerator” to becoming an embedded capability across the SAP portfolio : especially in S/4HANA-centric landscapes and SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP).&amp;nbsp; In parallel, SAP’s AI operating model has matured through services and patterns such as SAP AI Core (runtime/orchestration), SAP AI Launchpad (central lifecycle management), the unified AI API, and Joule as the conversational copilot experience across SAP applications.&amp;nbsp; Yet, many SAP AI initiatives still stall after pilots because teams start by debating “how to implement” rather than validating “what is worth implementing” and “where AI is actually valuable and feasible” in the enterprise process fabric.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;A disciplined way to avoid this trap is a &lt;STRONG&gt;discovery‑first AI assessment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- a structured approach that stays implementation‑agnostic while still being technology‑aware, so outcomes remain valid regardless of later platform or deployment decisions.&amp;nbsp; This essay reframes a six‑step approach for SAP AI discovery into a technical, architect-friendly method. It also overlays SAP guidance and best-practice assets (Discovery Center, AI BTP Best Practices, AI Core/Launchpad, Joule, and RAG patterns with SAP HANA Cloud Vector Engine) to ensure the assessment aligns with SAP’s recommended adoption pathways.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This essay is based on the framework introduced on the original SAP Community article: &lt;A title="6 Steps to an AI Assessment in SAP: Discovery‑First Approach" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/6-steps-to-an-ai-assessment-in-sap-discovery-first-approach/ba-p/14294578" target="_blank"&gt;6 Steps to an AI Assessment in SAP: Discovery‑First Approach&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" data-unlink="true" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/6-steps-to-an-ai-assessment-in-sap-discovery-first-approach/ba-p/14294578" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="6 Steps to AI Discovery For SAP.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355585i034F2D4608D955A4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6 Steps to AI Discovery For SAP.png" alt="6 Steps to AI Discovery For SAP.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" data-unlink="true" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fig:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/6-steps-to-an-ai-assessment-in-sap-discovery-first-approach/ba-p/14294578" target="_blank"&gt;6 Steps to an AI Assessment in SAP: Discovery-First Approach&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1:&amp;nbsp;Frame the Assessment Scope&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define the Assessment Boundary in an S/4HANA‑Centric System Context&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Every AI assessment must begin with scope governance: identify the SAP domains (Finance, Supply Chain, Manufacturing, Sales, Asset Management, HCM, etc.), the adjacent applications, and the integration boundaries that matter - without drifting into build-versus-buy or tool comparisons.&amp;nbsp; In SAP programs, a reliable scoping abstraction is the &lt;STRONG&gt;business capability map&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;value-stream decomposition&lt;/STRONG&gt; because it remains stable even when the underlying SAP configuration varies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This discovery discipline mirrors the intent of SAP’s Discover phase practices - where structured discovery is separated from delivery execution - similar in spirit to the Digital Discovery Assessment (DDA) concept that captures scope and integration needs before implementation handover.&amp;nbsp; The key is to frame the AI assessment as a &lt;STRONG&gt;portfolio discovery exercise&lt;/STRONG&gt;, not an architecture design workshop.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Typical Discovery outputs :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Capability/value-stream boundary document (what’s in/out)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stakeholder map and process ownership inventory (who “owns” outcomes)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="DiscoveryFirstApproach.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355578iD9D19215FD9796FC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DiscoveryFirstApproach.png" alt="DiscoveryFirstApproach.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2:&amp;nbsp;Map Capabilities to Processes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Map Business Capabilities to S/4HANA Process Realization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;AI opportunities in SAP do not originate from modules or transactions; they emerge where a &lt;STRONG&gt;business capability is operationalized through an end‑to‑end process&lt;/STRONG&gt; and its associated decision points, exceptions, and data flows.&amp;nbsp; The technical architect’s job in discovery is to translate capability language (eg., “Forecast‑to‑Stock”, “Hire‑to‑Retire”) into S/4HANA process realizations (document flows, validations, approvals, master/transactional data dependencies).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This mapping also surfaces the “shadow steps” around SAP - manual spreadsheets, offline reconciliations, or email-based approvals - that frequently indicate automation or augmentation potential.&amp;nbsp; Importantly, the mapping step sets up a repeatable method: once you anchor AI discovery in processes, you can evaluate opportunities consistently across multiple LoBs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Typical Discovery outputs :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Capability process decomposition tree&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Process pain-point register (manual effort, exception hotspots, latency)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;A title="Business Capabilities Model" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/leanix/ea/business-capabilities-modeling-v3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="BusinessCapabilityMaps.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355580iE81FB42EBD6DE7D4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BusinessCapabilityMaps.png" alt="BusinessCapabilityMaps.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Fig: Business Capability Map Model from LeanIX&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;A title="Process Decomposition" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_INTEGRATED_BUSINESS_PLANNING/feae3cea3cc549aaa9d9de7d363a83e6/bea60e563f3e787fe10000000a441470.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ProcessDecomposition.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355581iB144BD9E2EB5FCDD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ProcessDecomposition.png" alt="ProcessDecomposition.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Fig: Representation of&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;End-to-End Planning &lt;/SPAN&gt;Process Decomposition&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3:&amp;nbsp;Identify AI Opportunity Areas&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apply SAP‑Relevant Heuristics to Identify AI Use‑Case Candidates&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;With process decomposition in place, candidate use cases can be detected using heuristics that align with SAP’s common AI scenario types:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High manual effort / repetitive validations&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: intelligent automation opportunities (e.g., checks, approvals, triage).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High exception rates&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: anomaly detection, recommendation, or guided resolution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Decision-intensive planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;: predictive/optimization scenarios (forecasting, risk scoring, demand signals).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Classification-heavy work &lt;/STRONG&gt;(documents, tickets, master data enrichment) : ML classification/extraction candidates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conversational access needs&lt;/STRONG&gt; : natural language interfaces over SAP process data and knowledge.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;A key technical nuance: discovery should consider &lt;STRONG&gt;evidence sources&lt;/STRONG&gt; - historical transactional data, exception logs, process mining signals, and operational telemetry-to quantify where work concentrates and where variance is high. This prevents “idea-based” AI and anchors the pipeline in measurable process reality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Typical Discovery outputs :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use‑case hypothesis cards (problem, trigger, decision, data anchors, KPI)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Candidate taxonomy (predictive vs classification vs GenAI assistant vs automation)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4:&amp;nbsp;Score Opportunities (Qualitative)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Qualitatively Score Value, Feasibility, and Adoption Readiness (Lightweight, Not a Full Business Case)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Discovery must prioritize, but it should do so with &lt;STRONG&gt;qualitative scoring&lt;/STRONG&gt; rather than prematurely engineering a full ROI model.&amp;nbsp; The practical approach is to score each candidate along three vectors:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business value&lt;/STRONG&gt; (cycle time reduction, compliance uplift, cost, working capital impact).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feasibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; (data availability in S/4HANA, integration complexity, process standardization, automation baseline).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adoption readiness&lt;/STRONG&gt; (change impact, user trust, ownership clarity, operating model maturity).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;In SAP programs, the feasibility discussion is still “discovery-grade,” but it can be informed by SAP adoption assets : such as SAP Discovery Center’s &lt;STRONG&gt;Discover &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Evaluate &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Adopt&lt;/STRONG&gt; structure and its estimators and missions that help teams understand effort patterns without locking design choices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Typical Discovery outputs :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scoring matrix (relative ranking, not absolute valuation)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Constraints register (data gaps, master data quality, authorization concerns)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/6-steps-to-an-ai-assessment-in-sap-discovery-first-approach/ba-p/14294578" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Qualitative Asessment.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355582iCAA9FBABCF00C355/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Qualitative Asessment.png" alt="Qualitative Asessment.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fig: Discovery First Approach: Qualitative Assessment Template&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5:&amp;nbsp;Build AI Impact Heatmap&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consolidate Findings into an “AI Impact Heatmap” Across SAP Processes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Once candidates are scored, the assessment should converge into a single portfolio artifact: an AI impact heatmap - a quadrant-style visualization that positions use cases by value vs feasibility (and optionally overlays adoption readiness).&amp;nbsp; In SAP engagements, this heatmap becomes a common language between business stakeholders, functional consultants, and enterprise architects because it translates process discussions into prioritization outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;The architectural strength of the heatmap is that it naturally forms a two-speed backlog:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High value / high feasibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; : prime candidates for early proof-of-value.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High value / lower feasibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; : strategic backlog tied to data/process remediation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Typical Discovery outputs :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Heatmap with quadrant logic and narrative rationale&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;“Dependency notes” for backlog items (data quality, process harmonization)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/6-steps-to-an-ai-assessment-in-sap-discovery-first-approach/ba-p/14294578" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Impact Heatmap.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355583iA02F7E9068492DCE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Impact Heatmap.png" alt="Impact Heatmap.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;Fig: Discovery First: Impact Heat Map template&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 6:&amp;nbsp;Select Top 3–5 Discovery Candidates&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Once Winners Use Cases are identified and backlog created, Explicitly End Discovery&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;The final discovery step is to select a small set of 3–5 prioritized candidates that have clear business relevance, process anchoring, and feasible starting points.&amp;nbsp; The &lt;STRONG&gt;discovery assessment should then stop&lt;/STRONG&gt;; solution architecture, tool enablement, and build plans belong to subsequent phases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP Discovery Center can then serve as the “bridge” into execution by providing guided missions and reference assets for moving from decision to adoption in a controlled way.&amp;nbsp; This ensures the discovery team does not overstep into engineering prematurely while still giving the delivery team a credible launchpad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/6-steps-to-an-ai-assessment-in-sap-discovery-first-approach/ba-p/14294578&amp;nbsp;" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="DiscoveryFirstWorkedExample.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/355586iB1FE818C6BCA8280/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DiscoveryFirstWorkedExample.png" alt="DiscoveryFirstWorkedExample.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Fig: Worked Example: “&lt;EM&gt;Facilitate Invoice Validation&lt;/EM&gt;” in S/4HANA Finance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What do we do next?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Best‑Practice Overlay (What to Reference Once Discovery Hands Off)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;While discovery remains implementation-agnostic, SAP best practices can (and should) shape the guardrails for what comes next:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use SAP Discovery Center as the adoption backbone&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: it is explicitly structured to “Discover, evaluate, and adopt” SAP BTP and SAP Business AI, and it provides missions, reference architectures, and estimators that help teams progress methodically.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operationalize AI via SAP AI Core + SAP AI Launchpad + AI API&lt;/STRONG&gt; : SAP positions AI Core as the execution engine for AI workflows and model serving, AI Launchpad as the central lifecycle management experience, and AI API as a standardized lifecycle interface across runtimes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apply SAP BTP AI Best Practices for GenAI patterns&lt;/STRONG&gt; : SAP provides repeatable patterns such as secure model access, prompt templating, data masking, content filtering, and vector-based RAG pipelines—explicitly designed to reduce risk and standardize enterprise implementation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adopt Joule where conversational augmentation fits&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Joule is positioned as SAP’s copilot for conversational interaction and process assistance across SAP applications, with enterprise readiness and compliance considerations (including GDPR and AI ethics) called out in SAP documentation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If grounded GenAI is required, use RAG with SAP HANA Cloud Vector Engine&lt;/STRONG&gt; : SAP documents vector engine capabilities and the role of vector databases in supporting RAG to improve response quality and mitigate hallucinations, and SAP Architecture Center provides a RAG reference architecture.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Discovery‑First Works in SAP Programs?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;A discovery-first assessment is effective because it treats &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI as a process portfolio problem, not a tool problem&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp; By scoping carefully, mapping capabilities to S/4HANA processes, applying consistent heuristics, ranking candidates with lightweight scoring, and consolidating into an impact heatmap, SAP architects create an evidence-based AI backlog that can survive platform changes and implementation debates.&amp;nbsp; Then, and only then, SAP’s adoption assets - Discovery Center missions, AI Core/Launchpad lifecycle governance, Joule where conversational augmentation fits, and SAP BTP AI Best Practices for secure GenAI design - can be activated to move from discovery to execution with reduced risk.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some quick references that you should go through before such a discovery first exercise:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/6-steps-to-an-ai-assessment-in-sap-discovery-first-approach/ba-p/14294578" target="_blank"&gt;6 Steps to an AI Assessment in SAP: Discovery‑First Approach&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Centre&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-ai-best-practices-your-ultimate-guide-for-building-ai-solutions/ba-p/14171864" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP AI Best Practices overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ai-launchpad/sap-ai-launchpad/sap-ai-launchpad-overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI Launchpad official overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-business-technology-platform/describing-sap-ai-core-and-sap-ai-launchpad_bba91b98-2df6-419d-93ab-f2a4eb741224" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning (AI Core &amp;amp; Launchpad concepts)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/serviceguide/enable-joule-in-sap-products" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule official description&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-vector-engine-guide/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Vector Engine guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/docs/ref-arch/e5eb3b9b1d/3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Architecture Center RAG reference architecture&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-cloud-erp/introducing-the-digital-discovery-assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning - Digital Discovery Assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/leanix/ea/business-capabilities-modeling-v3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP LeanIX Business Capabilities Model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/discovery-first-ai-assessment-for-sap-landscapes-an-essay/ba-p/14297147"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T21:46:13.323000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/joule-agent-and-an-async-joule-skill-are-not-yet-supported-together/qaa-p/14299361#M4934304</id>
    <title>Re: joule Agent and an async Joule skill are not yet supported together</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T22:57:39.187000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mateuszkwas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2261831</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi, it works for me. Make sure you have released (saved) Joule Skill and Joule Agent + all obligatory fields.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/joule-agent-and-an-async-joule-skill-are-not-yet-supported-together/qaa-p/14299361#M4934304"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T22:57:39.187000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-deploy-joules-skills-in-sap-bpa-clientnotfound/qaa-p/14299362#M4934305</id>
    <title>Re: Unable to Deploy Joules Skills in SAP BPA - ClientNot...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T23:11:58.299000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mateuszkwas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2261831</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Two things there:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;you must activate private environment (go to Control tower -&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;environment and there will be button next to search box)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;issue with the deployment is due to browser cache, you can change the browser or wait some time and check again&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Mateusz Kwasniewski&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-deploy-joules-skills-in-sap-bpa-clientnotfound/qaa-p/14299362#M4934305"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T23:11:58.299000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-setup-resource-group-in-the-joule-agent-builder/qaa-p/14299364#M4934306</id>
    <title>Re: how to setup resource group in the Joule Agent Builder</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T23:15:48.515000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mateuszkwas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2261831</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There were updates in this topic last week. Please check url&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/626498be11064953810a852535900ca7.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/Joule_Studio/45f9d2b8914b4f0ba731570ff9a85313/626498be11064953810a852535900ca7.html?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Mateusz Kwasniewski&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-setup-resource-group-in-the-joule-agent-builder/qaa-p/14299364#M4934306"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T23:15:48.515000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/editable-alv-report/qaa-p/14299370#M4934307</id>
    <title>Re: editable alv report</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T23:26:39.709000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nmirandaghn</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/42192</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I suggest using ABAP 7.5+ syntax:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Instead of this:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;DATA: it_ekpo TYPE TABLE OF ekpo,
      it_fcat TYPE slis_t_fieldcat_alv,
      wa_fcat LIKE LINE OF it_fcat.

SELECT * FROM ekpo INTO TABLE it_ekpo WHERE ebeln IN s_ebeln.

CLEAR wa_fcat.
wa_fcat-fieldname = 'EBELN'.
wa_fcat-seltext_l = 'PO Number'.
APPEND wa_fcat TO it_fcat.
" ...more lines&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Try this:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;SELECT ebeln, ebelp, txz01, menge, netwr
  FROM ekpo
  WHERE ebeln IN @s_ebeln
  INTO TABLE @DATA(it_ekpo).

DATA(it_fcat) = VALUE slis_t_fieldcat_alv(
  ( fieldname = 'EBELN' seltext_l = 'PO Number' )
  ( fieldname = 'TXZ01' seltext_l = 'Text' edit = 'X' )
  ( fieldname = 'MENGE' seltext_l = 'Quantity' edit = 'X' )
).&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Or you can use CL_SALV_TABLE :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;TRY.
    cl_salv_table=&amp;gt;factory(
      IMPORTING r_salv_table = DATA(lo_alv)
      CHANGING  t_table      = it_ekpo ).

    " Auto-optimize column width
    lo_alv-&amp;gt;get_columns( )-&amp;gt;set_optimize( abap_true ).

    " Make specific columns editable
    lo_alv-&amp;gt;extended_grid_api( )-&amp;gt;editable_restricted( )-&amp;gt;set_attributes_for_columnname(
      columnname = 'TXZ01'
      all_cells_input_enabled = abap_true ).

    lo_alv-&amp;gt;display( ).

  CATCH cx_salv_error INTO DATA(lx_err).
    MESSAGE lx_err-&amp;gt;get_text( ) TYPE 'E'.
ENDTRY.&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No manual field catalog needed (auto-detects structure)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cleaner, more maintainable code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Better aligned with S/4HANA standards&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;If you need complex editable grids with custom validations, &lt;CODE&gt;CL_SALV_TABLE&lt;/CODE&gt; can be limiting. For those cases, &lt;CODE&gt;CL_GUI_ALV_GRID&lt;/CODE&gt; is still more flexible.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Do you have any specific requirements for the report that are giving you trouble?&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/editable-alv-report/qaa-p/14299370#M4934307"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T23:26:39.709000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/define-selections-fiori-group-reporting-from-dev-to-qa-prd/qaq-p/14299373</id>
    <title>Define Selections (Fiori – Group Reporting) from DEV to QA/PRD</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T23:50:22.087000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Melis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1431234</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m using S/4HANA On-Premise Group Reporting and I defined several Define Selections in the DEV system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now need to create the same selections again in QA and PRD. Before doing everything manually, I wanted to ask:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there any import/export option for Define Selections, or do they have to be maintained separately in each system?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;thank you,&lt;BR /&gt;melis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/define-selections-fiori-group-reporting-from-dev-to-qa-prd/qaq-p/14299373"/>
    <published>2025-12-29T23:50:22.087000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-cpi-message-monitoring-logs-report/bc-p/14299375#M176948</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CPI Message Monitoring Logs Report</title>
    <updated>2025-12-30T00:17:30.811000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ShavezKhan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1480041</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1575627"&gt;@Starky83719&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;can you please confirm what will be the right URL - i am also facing the same issue -&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;WstxUnexpectedCharException error.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ShavezKhan_0-1767050238578.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/357110i05326D48C6D2F60C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ShavezKhan_0-1767050238578.png" alt="ShavezKhan_0-1767050238578.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-cpi-message-monitoring-logs-report/bc-p/14299375#M176948"/>
    <published>2025-12-30T00:17:30.811000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/ready-to-start-my-journey/td-p/14299378</id>
    <title>ready to Start my journey</title>
    <updated>2025-12-30T00:52:43.178000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>novriadedy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2272590</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Bismillah&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone, i am excited to SAP for 10 year ago, but not have much time to explore more.&amp;nbsp; today, i have a big want to join this hude community and learn more about sap, specially ABAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;hope all of you can help me to achieve my hope. thanks.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/ready-to-start-my-journey/td-p/14299378"/>
    <published>2025-12-30T00:52:43.178000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-with-sorting-in-sac-story-table-bw-live-model-view-mode-only/qaq-p/14299381</id>
    <title>Issue with Sorting in SAC Story Table - BW live model - View mode only</title>
    <updated>2025-12-30T01:00:03.845000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>igdulia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/547134</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Hi all,&lt;BR /&gt;We are facing an issue with sorting in SAC Story tables (both old and New Table Builder).&lt;BR /&gt;When more than two dimensions are used and sorting is applied by a measure, it works correctly in &lt;STRONG&gt;Edit mode&lt;/STRONG&gt; (and&amp;nbsp;we see on the top that one filter was applied)&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;However, in &lt;STRONG&gt;View mode&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the sorting does not work and multiple filters (e.g. 93) are applied automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please let us know if this is a known issue or if there is a recommended workaround.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Edit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="igdulia_1-1767052728935.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/357114i9808E33669CD6DF3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="igdulia_1-1767052728935.png" alt="igdulia_1-1767052728935.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;View:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="igdulia_0-1767052697315.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/357113i392344E977E73409/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="igdulia_0-1767052697315.png" alt="igdulia_0-1767052697315.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-with-sorting-in-sac-story-table-bw-live-model-view-mode-only/qaq-p/14299381"/>
    <published>2025-12-30T01:00:03.845000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-can-we-achieve-automatic-picking-as-delivery-quantity/qaq-p/14299382</id>
    <title>How can we achieve automatic picking as delivery quantity</title>
    <updated>2025-12-30T01:59:06.895000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP Team,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We need automatic picking as per delivery quantity; please guide us on how we can achieve this requirement. The out-delivery item category is picking relevant items; however, businesses don't want to manually enter items for picking. They want the system to be automatically triggered from delivery quantity. In this case, how can we achieve this?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-can-we-achieve-automatic-picking-as-delivery-quantity/qaq-p/14299382"/>
    <published>2025-12-30T01:59:06.895000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-can-we-achieve-automatic-picking-as-delivery-quantity/qaa-p/14299383#M4233984</id>
    <title>Re: How can we achieve automatic picking as delivery quan...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-30T01:59:14.973000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;SPAN&gt;Customer,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope you are doing well. Thank you for contacting us and the information you provided.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To help you implement your requirement, please kindly &lt;SPAN&gt;activate this feature in the SSCUI&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;102125&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define Shipping Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can kindly refer to the KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3435758" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3435758 - Activate Automatic Picking in the Outbound Delivery Process - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope my resolution can help you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Crane&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Support&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-can-we-achieve-automatic-picking-as-delivery-quantity/qaa-p/14299383#M4233984"/>
    <published>2025-12-30T01:59:14.973000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/impact-of-employee-central-on-performance-and-goals-management-retrofit/qaa-p/14299384#M50078</id>
    <title>Re: Impact of Employee Central on Performance and Goals M...</title>
    <updated>2025-12-30T03:00:05.022000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RajaThukiwakam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1420926</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There won't be any impact, but make sure the HRIS sync provides all data required by Performance and Goals Management, Succession Planning, Calibration, Mentoring, and the Career Worksheet.&amp;nbsp; As part of the retrofit, verify the HRIS Sync mapping and confirm that all attributes are mapped correctly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/implementing-employee-central-core/hris-sync-mappings" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/implementing-employee-central-core/hris-sync-mappings&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/impact-of-employee-central-on-performance-and-goals-management-retrofit/qaa-p/14299384#M50078"/>
    <published>2025-12-30T03:00:05.022000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-administrator-approval-process-input-activities/qaq-p/14299385</id>
    <title>SAC : Administrator Approval Process (Input Activities)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-30T03:25:09.049000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hjyoo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1573899</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While doing my project, there's a need to build a administrator Approval Process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Like, user1 input the data throught the story&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;and after that administrator reveiws the data and then publish it to the model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I thought throught the 'calendar' it can be possible, but now i think actually there's a no functionality like that..&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyone who dealt with this situation, please give me a good idea!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thank you so much!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-administrator-approval-process-input-activities/qaq-p/14299385"/>
    <published>2025-12-30T03:25:09.049000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
