<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-08-15T12:14:01.466530+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/can-we-set-multi-scaled-conditions-in-sap-tm-rate-table/qaa-p/14181507#M206170</id>
    <title>Re: Can we set multi scaled conditions in SAP TM Rate table?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T09:55:55.335000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2163135"&gt;@LINGLINGLING_CN&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, you are correct the grouping strategy is the grouping rule defined in the charge calculation sheet in SAP TM. To ensure you achieve daily aggregated pricing per lane or weight, while keeping the 1 FU = 1 FO structure, I advice you set up your calculation sheet as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are the steps to help you define the grouping rule:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, in your Calculation Sheet: Define grouping keys: From Location, To Location, and Calendar Day. Then set Calculation Rule to “Rate Based”, Aggregation Mode to “Day”, Calculation Base = “Weight”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Secondly, in the calculation sheet, ensure you assign the grouping rule to group Freight Orders by lane (From/To location) and shipping day. This ensures that all FOs for a given lane or day are aggregated and total weight is used to calculate the base rate charge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, Your rate table should have condition keys for From Location, To Location, Calendar Day, and scale for Weight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This setup will aggregate your daily charges for each lane based on the total FO weight, so even with separate FUs or FOs for each order, the pricing per lane or day is consolidated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/can-we-set-multi-scaled-conditions-in-sap-tm-rate-table/qaa-p/14181507#M206170"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T09:55:55.335000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/vat-number-doesn-t-print-on-invoice/qaq-p/14181509</id>
    <title>VAT number doesn't print on invoice</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T09:56:13.338000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ceciliajohansson7768</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/821640</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have an issue that the VAT number doesn't always print on the invoices.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It prints on invoices within the EU, Australia and Vietnam for example, but not on invoices to for example Japan, Indonesia and United Arab Emirates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What could be the issue and what is the way to solve it?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your support!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cecilia&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/vat-number-doesn-t-print-on-invoice/qaq-p/14181509"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T09:56:13.338000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/embedding-trust-watermarking-for-ai-compliance-and-lifecycle-management/ba-p/14180182</id>
    <title>Embedding Trust: Watermarking for AI Compliance and Lifecycle Management</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:01:29.832000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jiayu_Wang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2188863</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737744677"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As AI-generated content becomes deeply integrated into enterprise workflows, ensuring authenticity, traceability, and compliance is more critical than ever. AI-generated documents, reports, media files, and communication content are increasingly driving decisions, automation, and customer interactions. As a result, organizations are no longer just creating content—they're responsible for governing it across its entire lifecycle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watermarking—once a niche solution primarily used for digital rights management—is now emerging as a key enabler of AI content governance. By embedding information directly into content files—such as their creation source, generation method, AI model, or associated policy metadata—watermarks help ensure that AI outputs are verifiable, policy-aware, and audit-ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we explore the role of watermarking in enabling AI compliance, supporting lifecycle management, and building trusted AI content ecosystems at scale. We will cover the current challenges enterprises face, how watermarking works, and what’s needed for watermarking to evolve with generative AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541231172"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Compliance by Design: A Necessity for Watermarking AI-Generated Content&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI-generated content is increasingly subject to regulatory and corporate governance. Legal frameworks such as the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/reg/2024/1689/oj" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;EU AI Act&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billTextClient.xhtml?bill_id=202320240SB942" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;California AI Transparency Act&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.chinalawtranslate.com/en/ai-labeling/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;China Measures for Labeling of AI-Generated Synthetic Content&lt;/A&gt; and GDPR, alongside internal audit and information governance policies, now require that content produced by AI be:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explicitly labelled as AI-generated&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Traceable to its source&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Managed in line with legal retention policies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Auditable for integrity and responsible use&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Beyond legal compliance, enterprises must ensure that AI-generated content can be classified, archived, audited, and ultimately destroyed based on business rules. This is where information lifecycle management (ILM) comes in. From creation to retention, archiving to deletion, each stage of content use must be policy-driven and secure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Jiayu_Wang_0-1755138791801.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300588iB7B1F269181C0876/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jiayu_Wang_0-1755138791801.png" alt="Jiayu_Wang_0-1755138791801.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditional metadata alone is not sufficient to meet these goals—metadata can be stripped or altered. Watermarking offers a more durable, embedded approach to ensure content governance is inherently built into the content itself.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344717667"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Is Watermarking&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watermarking is the process of embedding additional information—either visible or invisible—into digital content. This information can be extracted later to verify origin, track usage, or enforce compliance. Watermarks can include model identifiers, timestamps, legal classifications, or lifecycle metadata.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1277286881"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Methods of Watermarking&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watermarks can be embedded in various ways depending on the content type:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Jiayu_Wang_1-1755138791801.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300590i9D3A9D80B2B69000/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jiayu_Wang_1-1755138791801.png" alt="Jiayu_Wang_1-1755138791801.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Images: Frequency‑domain methods such as Discrete Cosine Transform (DCT) and matrix‑factorization techniques like Singular Value Decomposition (SVD) enable imperceptible watermark embedding while preserving visual fidelity.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Jiayu_Wang_2-1755138791801.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300589i7B527BF337441632/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jiayu_Wang_2-1755138791801.png" alt="Jiayu_Wang_2-1755138791801.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Jiayu_Wang_3-1755138791801.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300591i6A95D89243E094EA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jiayu_Wang_3-1755138791801.png" alt="Jiayu_Wang_3-1755138791801.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Videos: Frame-based watermarks allow tracking across transformations and streaming.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Text: Emerging techniques embed watermarks in AI‑generated text by manipulating token‑selection patterns or introducing subtle semantic perturbations that remain imperceptible to readers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Audio: Watermarks can be applied in the frequency or time domain (e.g., using spread spectrum or echo hiding techniques), allowing resilient tracking through compression, filtering, and re-recording.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PDF files: Watermarks can be embedded in content streams or structure elements without altering visual layout.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tabular data: In structured data such as CSV or Excel files, watermarking can be applied by subtly modifying statistical properties or introducing pattern-based noise within numerical precision thresholds—enabling detection without compromising data utility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1080773376"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Categories of watermarking&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watermarks can be categorized in two main ways:&lt;STRONG&gt; visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; and&lt;STRONG&gt; resilience to&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;manipulation&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;1. By Visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visible watermarks: Logos, seals, or text overlays that indicate ownership or status.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Invisible watermarks: Algorithmically embedded data that is imperceptible to the human eye but can be detected programmatically.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 2. By Resilience to Manipulation&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Robust watermarks: Designed to survive edits like cropping, compression, scaling, or format changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fragile watermarks: Easily removed when content is altered, useful for detecting tampering or unauthorized modification.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Jiayu_Wang_4-1755138791801.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300592i2ADFB7A3D677100D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jiayu_Wang_4-1755138791801.png" alt="Jiayu_Wang_4-1755138791801.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-884259871"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Watermarks &amp;amp; Metadata&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;While both watermarking and metadata aim to enrich digital files with useful context, they serve different purposes and come with unique trade-offs. &lt;STRONG&gt;Metadata&lt;/STRONG&gt; is easily accessible and widely supported across systems, making it ideal for fast retrieval, tagging, and classification. However, it can be removed, altered, or lost during file transfers, format conversions, or malicious tampering.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the other hand, &lt;STRONG&gt;watermarking&lt;/STRONG&gt; embeds information directly into the content itself—making it more persistent and tamper-resistant. It remains intact even if a file is renamed, copied, or stripped of its metadata.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Used together, they form a powerful combination:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Metadata enables automation and policy-driven governance,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Watermarks provide long-term traceability and authenticity—even across systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-558663647"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-362150142"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-165636637"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Applications of AI Watermarking&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watermarking serves a wide range of compliance and security functions in the context of AI. It enables enterprises to embed critical information at the moment of content generation and retrieve it later to verify its legitimacy, origin, and policy alignment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-98205851"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content Provenance and Authentication&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the most impactful applications is &lt;STRONG&gt;authenticity verification&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Watermarks can confirm whether a piece of content—image, document, or video—was generated by AI, when it was created, and under what policy. This is essential for trust and transparency, especially in regulated industries or public-facing communications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watermarks are also crucial for verifying the authenticity and ownership of digital artworks, particularly in NFTs, protecting intellectual property. They can be also used to verify the integrity of legal, financial, and HR documents, ensuring compliance and audit trail reliability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--173539023"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watermarking for Lifecycle Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Beyond detection, watermarks help enforce &lt;STRONG&gt;Information Lifecycle Management (ILM)&lt;/STRONG&gt; policies automatically. At each stage of a file's life, watermarks enable smart, compliant handling:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Embed watermarks at the point of generation to record the origin and purpose.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Retention&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Encode legal tags or policy rules to guide how long a file must be kept.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Audit&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Watermarks track changes and access history, supporting audit trails.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Archiving&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Even in long-term storage, watermarks preserve authenticity and ownership.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Destruction&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Watermarks indicate when deletion is permitted and record that action as proof of compliance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--76649521"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Strategic Importance of Watermarking&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watermarking is more than a technical solution—it’s a strategic enabler for enterprise-grade AI governance. As organizations generate increasing volumes of AI content, ensuring &lt;STRONG&gt;responsibility, auditability, and control&lt;/STRONG&gt; becomes essential. Invisible watermarking provides the foundation for this shift, turning untraceable content into &lt;STRONG&gt;self-describing, policy-aware assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From a business perspective, watermarking brings several key advantages:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proactive Compliance with AI Regulations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Watermarks help enterprises meet emerging legal requirements, such as those outlined in the EU AI Act, by embedding model identity, generation source, and disclosure metadata directly into files. This enables content-level traceability and accountability at scale.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Data Integrity and Auditability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Embedded watermarks offer a tamper-resistant record of content origin, usage policy, and lifecycle events—supporting internal audits, external reporting, and security reviews.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless Integration with SAP ILM and IRM Workflows&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Watermarking aligns naturally with SAP's Information Lifecycle Management and Information Retention Manager systems. It enables automated decision-making for retention, archiving, or deletion based on metadata embedded at the time of creation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Metadata-Driven File Classification and Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Watermarked content can carry its own classification, such as document type or sensitivity level, enabling intelligent automation of compliance actions without relying solely on external metadata or manual tagging.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Self-Aware Content for Smarter Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Perhaps most importantly, watermarking empowers content to become &lt;STRONG&gt;self-aware&lt;/STRONG&gt;—capable of communicating its own identity, rules, and restrictions. This makes it possible to build more adaptive, intelligent document governance systems that respond in real time to compliance needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, watermarking transforms AI-generated content from a potential risk into a managed, compliant, and trustworthy asset—one that supports both operational efficiency and long-term governance goals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--273163026"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--469676531"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Outlook: The Evolution of Watermarking in the Generative AI Era&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As generative AI continues to advance, watermarking must evolve to meet the growing demands of scale, robustness, and interoperability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Future watermarking systems must support high-volume content generation and real-time applications such as streaming media and cloud-native pipelines.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Robustness&lt;/STRONG&gt;: As AI-generated content proliferates, watermarks must be resilient against a wide range of manipulations — from basic operations like compression, cropping, and format conversion, to more advanced challenges such as screenshots and adversarial attacks. Crucially, they must remain detectable across diverse content types and evolving AI output formats.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Standards and Interoperability&lt;/STRONG&gt;: One major challenge is the lack of unified, industry-wide standards. To address this, the adoption of open standards like &lt;STRONG&gt;C2PA (Coalition for Content Provenance and Authenticity)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is critical. Open-source solutions such as &lt;STRONG&gt;Meta’s VideoSeal&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;DeepMind’s SynthID for text/image watermarking&lt;/STRONG&gt; are also paving the way for broader adoption and transparency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, watermarking must become &lt;STRONG&gt;more intelligent, resilient, and standardized&lt;/STRONG&gt; to remain a trusted foundation for AI content governance across industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--666190036"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion: Authenticity Matters in the Age of AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As AI becomes a core part of enterprise systems, the ability to verify, trace, and govern content becomes essential. Watermarking provides a foundational layer of trust—ensuring that content is not only intelligent, but also accountable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the era of generative AI, authenticity is not optional—it’s a requirement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[References]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://c2pa.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://c2pa.org/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2023/10/30/executive-order-on-the-safe-secure-and-trustworthy-development-and-use-of-artificial-intelligence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2023/10/30/executive-order-on-the-safe-secure-and-trustworthy-development-and-use-of-artificial-intelligence/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/information-lifecycle-management" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/topics/information-lifecycle-management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1407.4735" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1407.4735&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2303.15435" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2303.15435&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2412.09492" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2412.09492&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.05891" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.05891&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2109.09712" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2109.09712&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/embedding-trust-watermarking-for-ai-compliance-and-lifecycle-management/ba-p/14180182"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:01:29.832000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unlimited-reversal-postings-on-original-journal-entry/qaa-p/14181514#M4222868</id>
    <title>Re: Unlimited reversal postings on original journal entry</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:03:04.170000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yuval</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131968</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you for your answer, Jacob , I am checking</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unlimited-reversal-postings-on-original-journal-entry/qaa-p/14181514#M4222868"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:03:04.170000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/where-can-i-add-the-tax-code-in-the-sap-public-cloud/qaq-p/14181516</id>
    <title>Where can I add the tax code in the SAP public cloud?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:03:11.202000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Zhijun_Xie</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2179086</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Could you please tell me if it's possible to freely add and set tax codes in the SAP public cloud? Also, could you provide the configuration points? Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/where-can-i-add-the-tax-code-in-the-sap-public-cloud/qaq-p/14181516"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:03:11.202000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/planned-inventory-active-in-ls03n-how-to-clear-yellow-triangle/qaq-p/14181517</id>
    <title>Planned Inventory active in LS03N, how to clear yellow triangle</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:05:31.375000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sumit07k</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2073627</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to fix this issue in LS03N , all inventory records are cleared, and I am not able to remove this yellow light??&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please help it is urgent and priority!!!!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sumit07k_0-1755244984766.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301316i8B39725EFA943957/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sumit07k_0-1755244984766.png" alt="Sumit07k_0-1755244984766.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is showing inventory is planned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any help is appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/planned-inventory-active-in-ls03n-how-to-clear-yellow-triangle/qaq-p/14181517"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:05:31.375000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/delivery-document-type-outb-has-the-wrong-document-category-pdo/qaa-p/14181519#M206171</id>
    <title>Re: Delivery document type OUTB has the wrong document ca...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:08:40.779000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/764870"&gt;@basha_shaik7&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The error message you received indicates that there is a mismatch in the document category assignment between ERP and EWM systems during delivery document integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Such error messages could be triggered by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP Extended Warehouse Management, delivery document types are mapped to specific document categories representing business scenarios e.g., shipping confirmation orders, physical delivery orders etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your ERP delivery type OUTB is currently configured or mapped to the document category PDO but EWM expects it to be SPC for your business process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The fact that it works in your sandbox but not development indicates a configuration difference or missing mapping in the IMG activity:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To locate the issue, this is what I advice you to verify and do:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check Configuration in Both Systems. Compare the document type to category mapping for OUTB in sandbox vs. development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make sure ERP delivery type OUTB is assigned document category SPC in EWM customizing for your development landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you need to adjust the Mapping, then consider the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Change or add the mapping so that OUTB is assigned to the expected SPC document category. This can be done in SPRO under the path above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check Business Configuration Sets or Switches. There might be Business Configuration sets or system parameters active in Sandbox but missing in Development controlling document type mappings or EWM integration behaviour. Verify your Business Configuration sets or transport requests related to EWM integration to ensure consistency across systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, check your Transport and Consistency. Please ensure that all related customizing and transport requests are moved correctly from Sandbox to Development to avoid configuration gaps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To summarize, the integration error arises because ERP delivery type OUTB’s document category mapping is inconsistent or incorrect for your EWM system. Adjust the mapping of document OUTB to the document category SPC in your Development system’s SPRO configuration for EWM integration delivery processing to fix the issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the necessary information. I am happy to help if you have further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/delivery-document-type-outb-has-the-wrong-document-category-pdo/qaa-p/14181519#M206171"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:08:40.779000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/how-to-get-available-stock-for-production-order-in-ewm-as-the-atp-commit/td-p/14181524</id>
    <title>How to get available stock for production order in EWM as the ATP commit quantity in SAP HAHA</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:17:19.235000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Muzilan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2231109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Dears; we meet a frequent situation that when we release the production order with all components have available stock after ATP check in SAP HAHA, especially for the production order type-PP01, however, we can not get fully components in EWM, as the wave read red light(have missing parts),&amp;nbsp; some components are reserved to the other production orders.&amp;nbsp; how to avoid the situation and what is the root cause?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/how-to-get-available-stock-for-production-order-in-ewm-as-the-atp-commit/td-p/14181524"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:17:19.235000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/ifp-opex-calculating-cctr-activity-quantities-inversely/qaa-p/14181531#M4923023</id>
    <title>Re: IFP OPEX Calculating CCTR Activity Quantities inversely</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:24:33.591000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Susanne_Helbig</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46410</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1696282"&gt;@SANA11&lt;/a&gt;, please have a look at our &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/fAWb5ht?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;demo script&lt;/A&gt; (page 22) here we're explaining the data action logic and how the activity qunatities are calculated. As MoonJun already said, the result is heavily depending on your transaction data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Susanne_Helbig_0-1755246322621.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301324i0A18C6C44406B4F2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Susanne_Helbig_0-1755246322621.png" alt="Susanne_Helbig_0-1755246322621.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;BR /&gt;Susanne&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/ifp-opex-calculating-cctr-activity-quantities-inversely/qaa-p/14181531#M4923023"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:24:33.591000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/the-voucher-splitting-zero-balance-account-failed-to-successfully-allocate/qaa-p/14181536#M4222871</id>
    <title>Re: The voucher splitting zero balance account failed to...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:29:56.725000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2179086"&gt;@Zhijun_Xie&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your zero balance clearing lines from document splitting aren’t generating a profit centre, it usually indicates that the inheritance and substitution rules for document splitting are not configured to populate that field for the technical clearing account. Check this SAP Documentation &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0fa84c9d9c634132b7c4abb9ffdd8f06/4911c9cc2a934a18e10000000a42189b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help – &lt;EM&gt;Document Splitting in SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Let me know if you need further support&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/the-voucher-splitting-zero-balance-account-failed-to-successfully-allocate/qaa-p/14181536#M4222871"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:29:56.725000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-convergent-mediation-by-digitalroute-public-cloud-edition-convergent/ba-p/14181529</id>
    <title>SAP Convergent Mediation by DigitalRoute, public cloud edition – Convergent Invoicing Connector</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:30:37.884000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mariano_maldonado</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/158543</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;SAP Convergent Mediation by DigitalRoute, public cloud edition – Convergent Invoicing Connector&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301317iD84C63C7519438EA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1.jpg" alt="1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;New Feature&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;August 2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737778133"&gt;What’s the New Feature?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A new out-of-the-box connector interfacing Component Convergent Invoicing of solution SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, contract accounting and invoicing (herein called Convergent Invoicing).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Providing connectivity for sending already-rated or already-priced transactions to Convergent Invoicing, for accounting and revenue recognition purposes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All configurable in graphical user interface, for ease of use and quick time to value.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Using standard SAP ODATAV4 interface and adapting to the APIs evolution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541264628"&gt;What Kind of Use Cases Does it Enable?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whenever there are sales events happening, for example at a Point of Sales, Service Delivery Platform, or E-commerce Platform there will be a need to match generated sales orders (priced or rated transactions) with the actual payments or payment confirmations (from credit cards/payment gateways, and banks). This matching is needed to properly recognize the revenue, make postings to the General Ledger and have proof of where each revenue instance came from for the tax authority auditors. While the actual matching is an accounting responsibility of the SAP S/4HANA system, it relies on the mediation system to provide accurate sales data originating in the ordering system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Convergent Mediation by DigitalRoute, public cloud edition, needs to collect the sales orders from any customer data sources (e.g., residing on the public internet or customer premises), validate the information and prepare the data before sending it to Convergent Invoicing as Billable Items (BITs).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Preparing typically involves identifying the responsible business partner/contract account(s) and retrieving the product definitions to determine which BITs have to be created - think of a bundled product that is sold as a single order but requires multiple BITs for accounting purposes. Enriching the raw input with this data allows mediation to then create the proper BIT(s) including any supplementary BITs for tax, payments, etc. which are to be sent to Convergent Invoicing. See chapter “Mediation Functions Overview” for a more comprehensive view of the preparations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example of customer landscape where sales orders are mediated as Billable Items into Convergent Invoicing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301318iD24E52568CF28831/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.jpg" alt="2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example of Billable Item contents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="3.jpg" style="width: 306px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301319iB8D4037AF584DB1B/image-dimensions/306x425/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="306" height="425" role="button" title="3.jpg" alt="3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344751123"&gt;How Can it Be Used in Real-Life Scenarios?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the function amongst the available SAP forwarding functions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4.jpg" style="width: 284px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301320i1DEFD23C086A82B5/image-dimensions/284x221/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="284" height="221" role="button" title="4.jpg" alt="4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Drag-and-drop it into the stream editor and connect to functions delivering prepared payloads.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="5.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301321i8CAB559B5D0140BA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.jpg" alt="5.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure your data structure and data mappings directly within the function, no code needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="6.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301322iA3C266AF80E90DEF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6.jpg" alt="6.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As per the Convergent Invoicing Billable Item API1 (Create Billable Item), the following BIT categories and structures are supported in the GUI: Main, Payment, RatedConsumption, Tax, Text and AdditionalParameter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1148237618"&gt;New Connector Technical Features&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The technical features below allow the implementer to focus on the functional side of the use case and leave the integration details to SAP Convergent Mediation by DigitalRoute, public cloud edition. These capabilities ensure the messages are sent reliably to the targets and with full flexibility to manage any exceptions, with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Built-in retry option.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;At-least-once transaction safety.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Respond-async option allows for immediate asynchronous acknowledgement from Convergent Invoicing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Management of response messages in separate stream via Response Handling feature.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Utilizes batch API for better performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Updated Preview capability allows testing the connection to Convergent Invoicing during development of the stream. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Overview of operational settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="7.jpg" style="width: 627px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301323iC7FF5E8EFD62ADCE/image-dimensions/627x247/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="627" height="247" role="button" title="7.jpg" alt="7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-951724113"&gt;Mediation Functions Overview&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below are some examples of processing steps that can be performed within SAP Convergent Mediation by DigitalRoute, public cloud edition streams to validate and enrich raw source data making it readily usable by downstream systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-884293327"&gt;Mapping of External Transaction Record Format to BIT Format&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Convergent Mediation by DigitalRoute, public cloud edition provides a flexible mapping layer where external protocol and data formats (e.g., CSV, Excel, XML, JSON) can be mapped to internal record format and then converted to other protocol and formats, in this case the BIT (Billable Item) format over ODATAV4.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-687779822"&gt;Master Data Enrichment&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To correctly categorize or group the BIT record, the record needs to be enriched based on external meta data. This could be done through lookups to database or external SOAP or REST APIs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-491266317"&gt;Record Splitting&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;An incoming transaction may contain multiple billable transactions, in which case the transaction needs to be split into several BITs so that they can be grouped, aggregated, and billed separately.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-294752812"&gt;Validation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Examples of validation rules: mandatory fields present, values within expected ranges, lookups have matches, consistency counts of records within files. Invalid records are sent to a built-in Data Correction facility, where a Data Steward can correct and reprocess the records.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-98239307"&gt;Aggregation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Where multiple partial transactions need to be correlated and aggregated into one BIT.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--173505567"&gt;Deduplication&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When duplicate transactions need to be removed prior to loading BITs into Convergent Invoicing. The deduplication functionality of SAP Convergent Mediation by DigitalRoute, public cloud edition is highly scalable&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--370019072"&gt;Scalable Creation of BITs&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Convergent Mediation by DigitalRoute, public cloud edition, provides a robust and performant solution for the creation of BITs. BIT creation can be scaled by parallel loading of BITs into Convergent Invoicing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--273129570"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This new feature enables a new family of industry-agnostic use cases for SAP Convergent Mediation by DigitalRoute, public cloud edition, by natively connecting to Convergent Invoicing. These use cases can be found across all industries, as they involve collecting and mediating priced/rated transactions downstream for revenue recognition purposes and compliance with tax authorities. Thus, significantly increasing the addressable market of SAP Convergent Mediation by DigitalRoute, public cloud edition and the value it can provide to customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key benefits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Faster Time to Value:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Deploy the connector rapidly due to its out-of-the-box design and user-friendly controls.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Standardization and Interoperability:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Built on SAP API standards, future-proofing your data integration architecture.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Assurance:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reliable transaction and delivery assurance eliminate critical data loss in complex, high-volume contexts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compliance and Audit Readiness:&lt;/STRONG&gt; All data is validated and auditable, supporting stringent regulatory and tax compliance requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Industry-Agnostic:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Applicable across any sector needing automated, compliant quote-to-cash processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--469643075"&gt;Further readings&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP CI/FICA Cloud Public Billable Item Creation API link1: &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/CABILLABLEITEM_0001/resource/Billable_Item" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/CABILLABLEITEM_0001/resource/Billable_Item&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Convergent Invoicing Connector Documentation (DigitalRoute InfoZone):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://infozone.atlassian.net/wiki/spaces/DAZ/pages/634945549/SAP+Convergent+Invoicing+in+S+4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA for convergent invoicing - Usage Engine Cloud Edition Documentation - InfoZone&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Convergent Invoicing Documentation (help.sap.com/s4_ce_brim):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/1a561330b0fe4990b9566655770746dd/c893d0eadc7e4c4a9123ee6b9502da85.html?version=latest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/1a561330b0fe4990b9566655770746dd/c893d0eadc7e4c4a9123ee6b9502da85.html?version=latest&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-convergent-mediation-by-digitalroute-public-cloud-edition-convergent/ba-p/14181529"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:30:37.884000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/notifications-from-sap-build-apps-to-work-zone/m-p/14181538#M2042306</id>
    <title>Re: Notifications from SAP Build Apps to Work Zone</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:41:29.401000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kazistov_v</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2174624</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi!&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I have got an update on that case.&lt;BR /&gt;I found and was following this documentation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-work-zone-standard-edition/sap-build-work-zone-standard-edition/developing-cloud-foundry-applications-with-notifications" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/build-work-zone-standard-edition/sap-build-work-zone-standard-edition/developing-cloud-foundry-applications-with-notifications&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;It’s more adaptive for the code solutions, but I understood how to implement it through SAP Build Apps (no-code).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;First of all, I turned on and generated credentials for the notifications in Work Zone. The first thing that was strange for me that it generated url for ANS, when in documentation there is cloud notifications url. So I was trying to do it with that url, but didn’t get succeed. So, I used the same url for my destination as in the documentation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-work-zone-standard-edition/sap-build-work-zone-standard-edition/enabling-notifications-for-custom-apps-on-sap-btp-cloud-foundry#prerequisites" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/build-work-zone-standard-edition/sap-build-work-zone-standard-edition/enabling-notifications-for-custom-apps-on-sap-btp-cloud-foundry#prerequisites&lt;/A&gt; (&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://notifications.cfapps.sap.hana.ondemand.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://notifications.cfapps.sap.hana.ondemand.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;), but with my credentials (clientId, clientSecret, Endpoint Token). It was much better, because I got 200 status code for POST Call to get access token, then with this token I was trying to do the GET call to get CSRF Token from header and cookies, but I always get 307 error (redirect). I was doing by the instructions from the documentation (Endpoint: /v2/NotificationType.svc). But the strange thing is that in Postman I get 200 and get all the cookies and CSRF Token.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GET Call details:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;url:&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://notifications.cfapps.&amp;lt;time-zone&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand.com/v2/NotificationType.svc&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Header:&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;x-csrf-token: fetch&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;Authorization:&amp;nbsp;Bearer &amp;lt;access_token from the previous call&amp;gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If somebody has an experience with that case, I would appreciate any help and instructions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Best regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Vladyslav&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/notifications-from-sap-build-apps-to-work-zone/m-p/14181538#M2042306"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:41:29.401000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/vat-number-doesn-t-print-on-invoice/qaa-p/14181539#M4222872</id>
    <title>Re: VAT number doesn't print on invoice</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:46:16.973000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/821640"&gt;@ceciliajohansson7768&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud, this typically occurs because the invoice form template is configured to display the VAT registration number only for specific countries, such as EU members, AU, VN, or when the tax ID is categorised under VAT Registration Number.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For countries such as Japan, Indonesia, and the UAE, the customer master often includes different tax ID categories like Corporate Number, NPWP, and TRN. If the form only searches for the VAT Registration Number, it won’t show these.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommended checks and fixes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Manage Business Partner Master Data, verify that the bill-to party has the correct tax number recorded under the appropriate tax number category for that country.y.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review the invoice form in Maintain Form Templates under form logic. If the script or binding limits output to certain countries or VAT-only categories, modify it to also include the relevant country-specific tax ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Template assignment – Make sure the correct form variant is selected for those countries in Output Management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check below SAP documentation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/4603118feda9495892abadbe8f8c3d14/9be322f0505a4aa3a7f1541f82b50979.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help – Tax Number Categories and VAT Registration Number&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a630d57fc5004c6383e7a81efee7a8bb/da488f76078447b0b42792226cfcf9b1.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Maintain Form Templates-SAP Help&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/6ab33fdcdccc4be6bb7ce69e8e87fff4/29bda604cf634021bc58e60618e26187.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Maintaining Tax Number for Business Partners-SAP Help&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/918bca53037f408f91a2295d04ac16bc/863815c6ecfa4aa283260b4a4b678a63.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating and Using a Custom Form Template-SAP Help&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me know if you need further support&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/vat-number-doesn-t-print-on-invoice/qaa-p/14181539#M4222872"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:46:16.973000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/iso27001-certs/qaq-p/14181541</id>
    <title>ISO27001 Certs</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:50:34.470000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>M1WXY</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1936951</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, Could somebody please point me to a ISO27001 Certificate covering the operation of SuccessFactors hosted on GCP in Google DC's in Japan.... if such a thing exists?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/iso27001-certs/qaq-p/14181541"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:50:34.470000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/the-third-party-procurement-process-in-dbm-system/qaa-p/14181542#M4222873</id>
    <title>Re: The third-party procurement process in DBM system</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:51:16.631000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin36</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1666227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Is there DBM order stock valuation function ? Similar to the sales order stock valuation in the ECC system.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/the-third-party-procurement-process-in-dbm-system/qaa-p/14181542#M4222873"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:51:16.631000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-sap-business-data-cloud-capacity-unit-estimator/ba-p/14181530</id>
    <title>How to use SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:52:07.448000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FernandaFroelich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1410810</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;**Updated August 2025**&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Welcome to our blog series focused on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://datasphere-estimator-sac-sacus10.cfapps.us10.hana.ondemand.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This guide provides a comprehensive, step-by-step approach to help you estimate the capacity units (CU) needed for your business case (before purchasing) or how you can distribute them across your solution components (after signing a contract).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remember that BDC is available only through the subscription commercial model, which means you pay a fixed price for a specific quantity of CU. The price varies on how many CU you need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Furthermore, once licensed, BDC offers flexibility in quota assignment. This means that, if you need to allocate more CU to SAP Datasphere, you can reduce the number of licenses in SAP Analytics Cloud, and vice-versa*.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This series has 4 parts as follows:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://datasphere-estimator-sac-sacus10.cfapps.us10.hana.ondemand.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator for SAP Analytics Cloud &lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;(coming soon)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator for SAP Datasphere&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;(coming soon)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator for SAP Databricks&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;(coming soon)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What's&amp;nbsp;SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;This estimator tool helps you calculate the number of capacity units required for each SAP BDC capacity service, as well as the total amount needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What are capacity units?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Capacity Units (CU) are the metric used to allocate storage and compute resources within the BDC solution. The criteria for calculating CU vary depending on the service component:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC), CU differs by license type and corresponding quantities (SAC BI, SAC Planning Standard, or SAC Planning Professional)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For SAP Datasphere, CU depends on multiple factors such as Data Lake usage, storage, memory, and more&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For SAP Databricks, CU is based on various measures including storage, serverless SQL compute, and SAP Object Store requests.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator Home Screen&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301329iE0A3E2ED00337635/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator.png" alt="SAP Business Data Cloud Capacity Unit Estimator.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;* Note: This does not apply to SAP Business Warehouse Private Cloud Edition, as its capacity unit quota is determined by your contract with SAP. Also, for SAP Databricks, although you assign a quota amount, usage can exceed this number since billing is based on actual consumption rather than the assigned quota.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Source: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/business-data-cloud/administering-sap-business-data-cloud/administer-sap-business-data-cloud?q=CAPACITY+UNIT" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Administer SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-sap-business-data-cloud-capacity-unit-estimator/ba-p/14181530"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:52:07.448000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/partial-customer-project-invoice-request/qaa-p/14181545#M253070</id>
    <title>Re: Partial Customer Project Invoice Request</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:56:32.659000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1683582"&gt;@KCPN&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, you can generate a partial customer project invoice request through various methods without editing each item individually.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create Billing Request app; Select the project/WBS item and specify the partial amount or percentage to bill.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Billing Plan at Sales Order level; If integrated with SD, define percentage or milestone billing in &lt;EM&gt;Manage Sales Orders&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;API-based partial billing; Use A_ProjectBillingRequest or A_CustomerProject to automate creation of partial billing requests.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Billing Profile configuration: In &lt;EM&gt;Maintain Billing Profiles&lt;/EM&gt;, set rules to support partial invoicing by default.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Revenue recognition milestones: If applicable, trigger partial invoice requests through milestone events.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/partial-customer-project-invoice-request/qaa-p/14181545#M253070"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:56:32.659000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mrp-generated-purchase-requisitions-to-have-source-determination-enabled-by/qaq-p/14181546</id>
    <title>MRP-generated purchase requisitions to have source determination enabled by default</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:57:03.049000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Haily</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1489983</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In S/4HANA Public Cloud, how can we set MRP-generated purchase requisitions to have source determination enabled by default?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We would like to have purchase requisitions generated by MRP automatically converted into purchase orders via scheduling. However, during testing, we observed that:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manually created purchase requisitions successfully include a source and can be converted into purchase orders.&lt;BR /&gt;MRP-generated purchase requisitions, even with the same material master data, do not include a source.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We suspect this is because source determination is not enabled by default for MRP-generated purchase requisitions. Could you advise how to configure the system so that this function is automatically enabled?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;請問在 S/4HANA Public Cloud 中，MRP 產生的請購單要如何預設開啟 自動決定貨源 功能？&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;我們希望將 MRP 產生的請購單透過排程自動轉換為採購單。但測試時發現：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;人工建立的請購單可以順利帶出貨源並轉換為採購單。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;MRP 產生的請購單雖然使用相同的物料主檔資料，卻沒有帶出貨源。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;我們推測這是因為 MRP 產生的請購單在建立時，並未預設勾選 自動決定貨源。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;請問該如何設定才能讓 MRP 產生的請購單自動開啟此功能？&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;謝謝。&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mrp-generated-purchase-requisitions-to-have-source-determination-enabled-by/qaq-p/14181546"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:57:03.049000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/btp-cloud-foundry-consumed-by-all-spaces-exceeds-any-running-applications/qaq-p/14181547</id>
    <title>BTP Cloud Foundry Consumed by all spaces exceeds any running applications</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T10:57:06.794000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CDN_Steve</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/699284</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We have only 1 space and only a couple applications with only 1 running consuming 1GB of memory.&amp;nbsp; Cloud Foundry shows 0MB available to all spaces and 12GB is consumed somewhere else.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can see this in the first screenshot where 13GB are allocated to the org and only 1GB is consumed by the only space but there is a total of 13GB consumed by all spaces.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CDN_Steve_0-1755247893975.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301330iE656E111ED8D795E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="CDN_Steve_0-1755247893975.png" alt="CDN_Steve_0-1755247893975.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CDN_Steve_1-1755247993380.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301331i62D2D937C318A9E4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="CDN_Steve_1-1755247993380.png" alt="CDN_Steve_1-1755247993380.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This has happened once before as well and it seemed to clear itself but we are unsure of why and SAP support has not found the issue yet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any ideas why this might be occurring steps we can take to release the consumed memory?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/btp-cloud-foundry-consumed-by-all-spaces-exceeds-any-running-applications/qaq-p/14181547"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T10:57:06.794000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/can-joule-ai-make-sap-readiness-check-amp-process-insights-smarter/qaa-p/14181548#M4923025</id>
    <title>Re: Can Joule AI Make SAP Readiness Check &amp; Process Insights Smarter?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:06:34.525000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stafenthomas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/164747</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Tommy,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for sharing this,&amp;nbsp; I’m looking after the Joule topic in SAP Signavio and would be very interested in the outcome of your research. Your exploration touches on some important areas for how Joule could evolve. To put it simply, Joule needs capabilities (features/skills) to be developed for each specific use case. Right now, Joule in Signavio is available only to a selected group of customers via our Early Adopter Care (EAC) program, with a defined set of features and skills.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On your points: Integrated approach – Joule embedded directly in tools for live Q&amp;amp;A and guidance&amp;gt; Could you elaborate more on the type of questions and the expected outcomes? If the goal is to ask about the product itself or its functionality, Joule can already do this via document grounding from the SAP Help Portal content. If the goal is to provide data-driven analysis or recommendations from those tools in real time, that would require dedicated features/skills tied to the relevant APIs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Standalone approach – Central Joule portal for uploading exported tool data for AI summaries&amp;gt; Joule recently introduced the ability to upload documentation (only when certain features are invoked), but as far as I know, it does not yet support processing arbitrary exported datasets from other tools for analysis. That would be a new capability to scope and design.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the other ideas you mentioned, like: Training Joule using Signavio Process Explorer as a knowledge source Enabling Joule to learn a customer’s processes over time to adjust benchmarks and avoid false alarms I’d be happy to connect so we can explore these in more detail. These touch on areas like personalised context, benchmark adaptation, and custom knowledge integration, which are highly relevant for Signavio’s long-term AI roadmap. Let’s sync up, I can share the current state of Joule in Signavio, and we can map your ideas to what’s technically possible now vs. what would require new feature development.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/can-joule-ai-make-sap-readiness-check-amp-process-insights-smarter/qaa-p/14181548#M4923025"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:06:34.525000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/where-can-i-add-the-tax-code-in-the-sap-public-cloud/qaa-p/14181549#M4222875</id>
    <title>Re: Where can I add the tax code in the SAP public cloud?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:14:49.727000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2179086"&gt;@Zhijun_Xie&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You cannot freely create tax codes like in on-premise systems, but you can add and configure them within the available scope for your country or region.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tax codes are country-specific and must comply with the country’s tax procedure delivered by SAP. Note, you can’t change the procedure itself&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can generate new tax codes for your company's country, but only within the tax procedure designated for that country.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The system enforces permitted tax type combinations, reporting codes, and percentage limits based on the local content provided.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration in S4HANA Public Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Define Tax Codes for Sales and Purchases&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to: &lt;EM&gt;Manage Your Solution&lt;/EM&gt; → &lt;EM&gt;Configure Your Solution&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Application Area: Financial Accounting → Tax on Sales/Purchases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SSCUI ID: &lt;EM&gt;Define Tax Codes for Sales and Purchases&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Steps:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the country.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new two-character tax code.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign tax type (input/output), percentage rate, and validity dates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For input tax, link to the appropriate tax account from SSCUI – &lt;EM&gt;Assign Tax Accounts&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save and transport (in Public Cloud, activation is immediate).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Check the documentations below&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/exploring-localization-as-a-self-service-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/defining-tax-codes_a56a56b1-efe2-4543-857b-387a547d239a" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning-Define Tax Codes (Public Cloud)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0fa84c9d9c634132b7c4abb9ffdd8f06/5a94c353b677b44ce10000000a174cb4.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Best Practice- Tax on Sales and Purchases&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/where-can-i-add-the-tax-code-in-the-sap-public-cloud/qaa-p/14181549#M4222875"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:14:49.727000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/advanced-intercompany-stock-transfer-in-sap-s-4hana-op-private-cloud/bc-p/14181550#M183766</id>
    <title>Re: Advanced Intercompany Stock Transfer in SAP S/4HANA OP/Private Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:16:18.246000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Weerakhan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132545</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/43898"&gt;@Kaz_Iwamoto&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is it possible if you could also describe the reversal process of this Intercompany Stock Transfer? I think It is not that very straight forward to reverse the incorrect posting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Weerakhan T.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/advanced-intercompany-stock-transfer-in-sap-s-4hana-op-private-cloud/bc-p/14181550#M183766"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:16:18.246000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/fiori-tile-perform-foreign-currency-valuation-is-not-updating-business-area/qaq-p/14181552</id>
    <title>Fiori Tile Perform foreign currency valuation is not updating Business area field</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:20:21.238000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S_Shukla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2053293</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;I am trying to populate business area (GSBER)value in line items.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Used Substitution but bseg entry is not created so substitution not called.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Implemented Badi AC_Documrnt that is called and in debug mode values are changed in exporting field.But when I see the document posted values are not populated in Acdoca record. Also fb03 that GSBER value is not reflecting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Any solution how to substitute/ Change business area&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/fiori-tile-perform-foreign-currency-valuation-is-not-updating-business-area/qaq-p/14181552"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:20:21.238000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/introduction-to-group-reporting-in-sap-s-4hana-part-i/bc-p/14181553#M5819</id>
    <title>Re: INTRODUCTION TO GROUP REPORTING IN SAP S/4HANA (PART I)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:20:55.844000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DanielMateo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/266870</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2111287"&gt;@Summit16&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your support.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Disclosure Management is primarily a&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.google.com/search?cs=0&amp;amp;sca_esv=0ca5cf9eb183326c&amp;amp;sxsrf=AE3TifMbRMqjl3J_Kt_CFZ2y1cRwt1dmXg%3A1755249498926&amp;amp;q=BTP+%28Business+Technology+Platform%29&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwigs_T2vYyPAxUnU6QEHSyfOnUQxccNegQIAhAB&amp;amp;mstk=AUtExfDgVWgYpNRiQ4kDJjfFQnSiFAKxzCogR6zQhME2HPBfGeEaEEnU5v77NYJzk3KGy6AgYSJCWjthVCv2cObv6HSeE17FHCOYZY55s0KJMf0gtEtnNGkdqJV4TZkgavXYixvH35W5hcVjkOgJhMkKEy7Bzf6NIIfAEAt7FX1gLUH7JGY&amp;amp;csui=3" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;BTP (Business Technology Platform)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;based application, but it integrates with&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.google.com/search?cs=0&amp;amp;sca_esv=0ca5cf9eb183326c&amp;amp;sxsrf=AE3TifMbRMqjl3J_Kt_CFZ2y1cRwt1dmXg%3A1755249498926&amp;amp;q=SAP+S%2F4HANA&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwigs_T2vYyPAxUnU6QEHSyfOnUQxccNegQIAhAC&amp;amp;mstk=AUtExfDgVWgYpNRiQ4kDJjfFQnSiFAKxzCogR6zQhME2HPBfGeEaEEnU5v77NYJzk3KGy6AgYSJCWjthVCv2cObv6HSeE17FHCOYZY55s0KJMf0gtEtnNGkdqJV4TZkgavXYixvH35W5hcVjkOgJhMkKEy7Bzf6NIIfAEAt7FX1gLUH7JGY&amp;amp;csui=3" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for financial consolidation and reporting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It is not embedded directly within S/4HANA itself.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Yes, it typically requires a separate license.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/introduction-to-group-reporting-in-sap-s-4hana-part-i/bc-p/14181553#M5819"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:20:55.844000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/delivery-creation-date-vl10/qaq-p/14181554</id>
    <title>Delivery Creation date VL10</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:22:57.889000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dwayne13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/885668</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;I’m encountering a problem while creating a Delivery Note (DN) using VL10. In the Delivery Schedule of the STO, both the "Material Available Day" and "Transport Plan Day" are&amp;nbsp; 15.08.2025. However, when I enter 15.08.2025 as the "Delivery Creation Date" in VL10 and execute the transaction, no items eligible for DN creation appear.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Strangely, if I adjust the condition to "less than or equal to 15.08.2025", the eligible items do appear, and I can create the DN normally. Conversely, if I set the condition to "less than or equal to 14.08.2025", no eligible items show up again.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;I would appreciate it if you could help clarify this issue. Thank you!&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Best regards&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/delivery-creation-date-vl10/qaq-p/14181554"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:22:57.889000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-data-movement-in-sap-datasphere-replication-flow-or-remote-table/bc-p/14181555#M183767</id>
    <title>Re: Optimizing Data Movement in SAP Datasphere: Replication Flow or Remote Table Replication?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:25:29.866000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ramravi_srinivas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/281252</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Very well written - captured the difference clearly&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-data-movement-in-sap-datasphere-replication-flow-or-remote-table/bc-p/14181555#M183767"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:25:29.866000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/payments-falling-in-line/qaa-p/14181557#M206172</id>
    <title>Re: payments falling in line</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:27:15.540000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2005232"&gt;@Weslei_WesleiRibeiro&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Passos Recomendados para Solucionar&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Verifique o Material no Cadastro:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use a transação&amp;nbsp;MM03&amp;nbsp;para buscar o material&amp;nbsp;PACAIN/XTST.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Confirme se o material existe e se possui a&amp;nbsp;visão Planta&amp;nbsp;para a planta&amp;nbsp;0045.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Se não existir, crie-o usando a transação&amp;nbsp;MM01&amp;nbsp;e informe as visões e dados necessários.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Verifique a Mapeamento de Integração:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Se essa for uma integração com outro sistema (por exemplo, PACAIN), verifique as tabelas de mapeamento ou configurações de customização.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Garanta que o material esteja corretamente mapeado entre os sistemas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Faça ajustes, se necessário, no sistema de origem ou nas regras de mapeamento do middleware.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reprocessar o Documento:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Após corrigir os dados mestre ou o mapeamento, reprocese o documento.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use a transação de monitoramento ou a transação&amp;nbsp;SMQ2&amp;nbsp;para gerenciar a fila de entrada e tentar o reprocessamento.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Espero que isso ajude. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Atenciosamente.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/payments-falling-in-line/qaa-p/14181557#M206172"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:27:15.540000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-store-long-supplier-invoice-reference-numbers-in-sap-s-4hana-erp/ba-p/14181567</id>
    <title>How to store long Supplier Invoice Reference Numbers in SAP S/4HANA ERP Products</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:35:18.154000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>christian_seelinger</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/819831</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How Official Document Numbers (ODN) Framework can help customers to store long Supplier Invoice Reference Numbers in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, SAP S/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⁠&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4HANA Cloud Private Edition &amp;amp; SAP S/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⁠&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_seelinger_0-1755250276587.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301335i4F10E463B20AC24E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_seelinger_0-1755250276587.jpeg" alt="christian_seelinger_0-1755250276587.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my last Blogposts I introduced you into &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-official-document-numbering-helps-to-fulfill-the-polish-ksef/ba-p/13639767" target="_blank"&gt;How Official Document Numbering helps to fulfil the Polish KSeF Requirements in &lt;STRONG&gt;S4HANA Public Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and also informed you about &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-you-can-manage-polish-ksef-requirement-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private/ba-p/14175579" target="_blank"&gt;How you can manage Polish KSeF Requirement in SAP ... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this new Blog I´d like to give you an example of how the new ODN Framework can help you to store Supplier Invoice Reference Numbers, larger than 16 digits, in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⁠&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4HANA Cloud Private Edition &amp;amp; SAP S/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⁠&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following example we will focus on Poland as country, as this is a common scenario there. But the new ODN Framework is not restricted to any country and can be used everywhere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1608695536"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;1.&amp;nbsp; Maintain Official Document Number Types - Transaction: “ODNTYP&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create the ODN Types (Examples):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ZLINV - Long Invoice Number&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_seelinger_1-1755250276588.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301332i356A018936CD9427/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_seelinger_1-1755250276588.png" alt="christian_seelinger_1-1755250276588.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1412182031"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp; Map Official Document Number Type to Internal Type&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;- Transaction: “ODNINTTYP”&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Map your custom official document number type to the SAP-delivered internal official document number type so that the system can correctly derive the official document number within your consuming application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Procedure&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your configuration environment, search for and open the Map Official Document Number Type to Internal Type activity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the ODN Country/Region field, type &lt;STRONG&gt;PL&lt;/STRONG&gt; and choose Apply.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose New Entries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the ODN Internal Type field, choose the SAP-delivered internal official document number type &lt;STRONG&gt;LIRN&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the ODN Type field, choose your custom official document number type; for example, &lt;STRONG&gt;LINV&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save your changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_seelinger_2-1755250276588.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301333i3356512CCE83FF10/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_seelinger_2-1755250276588.png" alt="christian_seelinger_2-1755250276588.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1215668526"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;3.&amp;nbsp; Configure Official Document Number Type Characteristics TA: “ODNTYPC”&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Set the properties of your custom official document number type, such as its length and how it is processed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Procedure&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your configuration environment, search for and open the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure Official Document Number Type Characteristics&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;activity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ODN Country/Region&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;field, type&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;PL&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and choose&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apply&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assign Official Document Number Types to Country&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;step, choose&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Entries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and add your custom official document number types from above.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose the new entry you have added for your custom official document number type and then go to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Interface Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ODN Length&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;field, enter the length you need, for example 200 digits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process Specific Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Entries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and add the following entry:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For &lt;STRONG&gt;ZLINV:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_seelinger_3-1755250276589.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301337i660F6155929A7F4C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_seelinger_3-1755250276589.png" alt="christian_seelinger_3-1755250276589.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_seelinger_4-1755250276591.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301338i463BE514D02B39A3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_seelinger_4-1755250276591.png" alt="christian_seelinger_4-1755250276591.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For MM_SUPPLIER_INV:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_seelinger_5-1755250276592.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301340iBA7E4C3692EAA494/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_seelinger_5-1755250276592.png" alt="christian_seelinger_5-1755250276592.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1019155021"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;4.&amp;nbsp; Example – Supplier Invoice via transaction MIRO&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the invoice relevant data and then press “&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional Fiscal Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_seelinger_6-1755250276595.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301342i09B80BEDD0417CC4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_seelinger_6-1755250276595.png" alt="christian_seelinger_6-1755250276595.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Now Enter the Official Document Numbers relevant for your business in Poland (KSeF and Long Invoice Number, if needed):&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_seelinger_7-1755250276597.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301341i49BD32A54168C1B5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_seelinger_7-1755250276597.png" alt="christian_seelinger_7-1755250276597.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Access via CDS Views:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CDS View&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SD Billing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;I_BillingDocumentODN&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;FI Customer/Supplier invoice&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;I_AccountingDocumentODN&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;MM Supplier Invoice&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;I_SupplierInvoiceODN&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Business Processes and SAP Help Documentation for our example in Poland can be found here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="104"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Area&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="231"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supported Business Processes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="104"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sourcing and Procurement&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="231"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/GLOBALIZATION/80a58aef89b3425f8c334dc588567789/6f4a0cdebe2043d298efd8a8d1483b83.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=DRAFT&amp;amp;version=Globalization" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring Long Invoice Number (PLLIN) for Supplier Invoices&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can manually maintain the official document number in supplier invoices. The system validates this value based on the properties maintained in the configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Availability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The solution shown above is available for:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⁠&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt; (current Release)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⁠&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4HANA Cloud Private Edition &amp;amp; SAP S/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⁠&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4HANA Versions 1709 – 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⁠&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4HANA Cloud Private Edition &amp;amp; SAP S/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;⁠&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;, there are two ways of consuming the solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can install the next feature Package for your S/4HANA Solution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can install the notes which have been released recently:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In this case refer to the note collection in &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3565339" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Note 3565339&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; for additional details and also note &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://i7p.wdf.sap.corp/sap/support/notes/3639622" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3639622 - ODN Internal Type - LIRN&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope that I was able to provide you a good overview about how use the new ODN Framework could support you to store long invoice references.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See you next time!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Christian Seelinger&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-store-long-supplier-invoice-reference-numbers-in-sap-s-4hana-erp/ba-p/14181567"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:35:18.154000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-to-configure-auto-po-creation-for-arc-oa/qaa-p/14181568#M206173</id>
    <title>Re: How to configure Auto PO creation for ARC/OA</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:36:39.239000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pratik_soni6</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2186680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks@Chris1973 for the valuable reply.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Will start working on this but i have huge amount of suppliers approx. 25k , so i want to put some validation of data as header and item text so is there any program have or i want create the customize the program.&amp;nbsp; can pls guide regarding this.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;PS&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-to-configure-auto-po-creation-for-arc-oa/qaa-p/14181568#M206173"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:36:39.239000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/upload-program-to-update-equipment-status-in-ie02-inconsistent-results-with/qaa-p/14181569#M4923026</id>
    <title>Re: Upload Program to Update Equipment Status in IE02 – I...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:37:15.137000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>janbuchmann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/190831</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You could run it in processing mode '&lt;EM&gt;A - Display all screens&lt;/EM&gt;' and to try to find where it fails. Could it be that you are using different status profiles for different equipment categories? If you do and your recording merely sets the 3rd status, you will get inconsistent results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To be honest, I would rather use a program with function module &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;STATUS_CHANGE_EXTERN&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;with a check on the status profile. Don't forget &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;COMMIT_WORK&lt;/FONT&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/upload-program-to-update-equipment-status-in-ie02-inconsistent-results-with/qaa-p/14181569#M4923026"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:37:15.137000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/question-about-powerpoint-importation-in-sen/qaa-p/14181570#M45746</id>
    <title>Re: Question about PowerPoint Importation in SEN</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:43:35.002000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mel1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1419244</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Dirk,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What would be your expertise/best practice advice re a PowerPoint template:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. To Create a new Template within Producer that will be used when any SEN content is generated into a PPT document format?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Import an existing PPT template as a PPT file in Resources or Toolbox, configuring a pathway, and when any simulation or book is generated as a PPT, the correct template is used?&lt;BR /&gt;The scenario is that one Project is being implemented for a client, but across different countries. And we are hoping that it would save time and resources to import the existing templates from one Workspace into the next, instead of having to develop all the necessary templates per country. This is specific for documentation outputs only. Meaning, when any Book or group or sim is generated into a BPP output, training guide, or PPT, the documentation template therefor is set.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Hope this makes sense.&lt;BR /&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Melissa&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/question-about-powerpoint-importation-in-sen/qaa-p/14181570#M45746"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:43:35.002000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/delete-ariba-ca-ses-in-sap-mm/qaa-p/14181571#M4222877</id>
    <title>Re: Delete ariba CA SES in SAP MM</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:43:43.795000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pratik_soni6</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2186680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Actually supplier submitted the SES through CA with SES releaser ID who have t-code rights ML81N but user left the organization and all creational deleted as per policy&lt;BR /&gt;Due to SES still pending in approval, so i want to delete the SES.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/delete-ariba-ca-ses-in-sap-mm/qaa-p/14181571#M4222877"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:43:43.795000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-data-movement-in-sap-datasphere-replication-flow-or-remote-table/bc-p/14181572#M183768</id>
    <title>Re: Optimizing Data Movement in SAP Datasphere: Replication Flow or Remote Table Replication?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:45:21.650000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>er_sharmasunil</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/399463</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Excellent blog to start a day with. Well done&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1480637"&gt;@HarishRatnala&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-data-movement-in-sap-datasphere-replication-flow-or-remote-table/bc-p/14181572#M183768"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:45:21.650000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/odata-service-data-retrieved-in-debug-but-http-500-error-after-execution/qaa-p/14181573#M4923027</id>
    <title>Re: OData Service — Data Retrieved in Debug, but HTTP 500...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:46:34.774000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2184036"&gt;@ashokkandel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In reference to the comment made earlier, the HTTP 500 error you see after pressing F8 to finish the request, despite correct data in debug, usually points to an issue occurring during the OData serialization or response handling phase.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are a few common causes and these include the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data type mismatch in metadata or runtime data. Even small discrepancies between your MPC metadata definitions and the actual runtime data can cause failures during response serialization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Null or unexpected values. If any field in your response data is null or contains unexpected values e.g., empty strings for numeric fields the OData framework might raise internal errors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Large payload or buffering issues. Very large datasets or inefficient buffering could cause memory exceptions leading to HTTP 500 errors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Incorrect method implementation. It is important to note that sometimes, not properly handling deep structure fields or associations in&amp;nbsp;GET_ENTITYSET&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;GET_ENTITY&amp;nbsp;can cause runtime errors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Backend system parameters. Parameters related to runtime memory and shared objects size e.g.,&amp;nbsp;abap or shared_objects_size_MB may be too low, which may cause internal issues when the service tries to serialize and deliver the data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would recommend that you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, check your&amp;nbsp;/IWFND/ERROR_LOG&amp;nbsp;as recommended by SAP Note 1797736 to get detailed error information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Validate that your MPC metadata exactly matches your underlying DDIC structure and that no incompatible types or missing fields exist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure you add runtime null checks and default values in your GET_ENTITY and GET_ENTITYSET method implementations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduce the size of the dataset returned for initial testing by limiting filter conditions and Increase runtime memory parameters if needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Test your OData service calls via external clients like Postman to confirm if the issue is related to UI/browser specifics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The summary is that this error is fairly common when metadata and runtime data are out-of-sync or when encountering unexpected data during serialization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/odata-service-data-retrieved-in-debug-but-http-500-error-after-execution/qaa-p/14181573#M4923027"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:46:34.774000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-data-movement-in-sap-datasphere-replication-flow-or-remote-table/bc-p/14181575#M183769</id>
    <title>Re: Optimizing Data Movement in SAP Datasphere: Replication Flow or Remote Table Replication?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:47:21.388000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HarishRatnala</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1480637</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/281252"&gt;@ramravi_srinivas&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/399463"&gt;@er_sharmasunil&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-data-movement-in-sap-datasphere-replication-flow-or-remote-table/bc-p/14181575#M183769"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:47:21.388000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/adaptation-project-select-application-blank/qaq-p/14181576</id>
    <title>Adaptation Project - Select application - Blank</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:48:23.280000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>krish96</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/597023</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;While I was trying to extend the Fiori App using Adaptation Project, the list of Applications appears empty. Let me know if I'm missing something.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 3.08.15 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301343iB47AB6CF7562FAA3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 3.08.15 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-15 at 3.08.15 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/adaptation-project-select-application-blank/qaq-p/14181576"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:48:23.280000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/consuming-sap-with-sap-build-apps-web-app-in-sap-build-work-zone-standard/bc-p/14181578#M183770</id>
    <title>Re: Consuming SAP with SAP Build Apps - Web App in SAP Build Work Zone, standard edition</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:54:07.629000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TS12</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1619673</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15040"&gt;@LudoNoens&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thanks for the blog, but how it would work when the build apps app is deployed to an other Subaccount as the Workzone is running.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For an custom development html5 with all in the code like app-host and app-runtime it works, but the deploy of the Build Apps tool only create in the Provider account an app-host and no runtime we can take as design and runtime destination example later on&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thorsten&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/consuming-sap-with-sap-build-apps-web-app-in-sap-build-work-zone-standard/bc-p/14181578#M183770"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:54:07.629000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/btp-cloud-foundry-consumed-by-all-spaces-exceeds-any-running-applications/qaa-p/14181579#M4923029</id>
    <title>Re: BTP Cloud Foundry Consumed by all spaces exceeds any...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T11:57:16.311000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/699284"&gt;@CDN_Steve&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This memory discrepancy likely points to one or more of the following causes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;It is important to note that sometimes, apps or service instances that are no longer active remain allocated memory without being visible in the current space stats. These can consume memory reserved by your org quota.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Memory may be reserved or consumed by other spaces in the org that are not visible in your current space view, or by the org-level quota that includes reserved buffers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Beyond user apps, Cloud Foundry runtime and platform components may reserve memory quota counted against the org quota but not attributed to individual spaces or apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;It is possible that the memory usage figures are stale or inconsistent due to cloud platform glitches; previously reported issues may clear themselves over time but require investigation by SAP support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would recommend you consider doing the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;List all spaces and apps across the org. Use CLI commands for example cf spaces,&amp;nbsp;cf apps –all or cloud platform console to verify if any other spaces or apps are consuming memory unexpectedly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check service instances:&lt;BR /&gt;Confirm if any bound service instances consume memory quota.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Review quota assignments. Ensure to verify the quota plans assigned at org and space levels and any reserved buffers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Restart or scale down unused apps. Please note, if orphaned apps exist, stop or delete them to release memory.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the issue still exists, provide logs and memory usage snapshots to SAP support for deeper platform investigation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the necessary information. I am happy to help if you have further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/btp-cloud-foundry-consumed-by-all-spaces-exceeds-any-running-applications/qaa-p/14181579#M4923029"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T11:57:16.311000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/where-can-i-check-the-real-time-cost-of-cal/qaa-p/14181581#M4923030</id>
    <title>Re: Where can I check the real-time cost of CAL?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:01:56.135000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/296411"&gt;@jewooklee&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To check the real-time cost of your SAP ABAP Trial 2023 on AWS deployed via SAP Cloud Appliance Library (CAL), use the&amp;nbsp;AWS Cost Explorer&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;AWS Billing Dashboard&amp;nbsp;in your AWS account. CAL itself does not provide real-time cost monitoring, so cost tracking is done through AWS’s native tools. You can also set up budgets and alerts in AWS to monitor your spending effectively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/where-can-i-check-the-real-time-cost-of-cal/qaa-p/14181581#M4923030"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:01:56.135000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/one-time-customer-in-sap-crm-c4c/qaq-p/14181582</id>
    <title>One Time customer in SAP CRM(C4C)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:03:20.853000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OlesiaHomol</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1661698</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Is there posibilities after release 2508 to have the feature onetime customer for sales order in SAP CRM (C4C). This functionelity (creation order for onetimecustomer with new addreses and Names )&amp;nbsp; is standart in SAP S4HANA . We have integration between SAP CRM and SAP S4HANA . And we would like to have such posibilities in SAP CRM. Mayve someone faced with the same requirement and can give the advice?&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;If there are no standatd posibilities, can some one advice the workaroud?&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;BR Olesia&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP CRM SALES ORDER&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/one-time-customer-in-sap-crm-c4c/qaq-p/14181582"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:03:20.853000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/supplier-and-purchasing-group-email-not-picked-in-po-output-message/qaq-p/14181584</id>
    <title>Supplier and Purchasing group email not picked in PO output message</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:12:21.077000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sudharmv</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1424185</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear All&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to send a email to purchase order supplier.&amp;nbsp; Output message is getting automatically determined in PO message as required.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In message details, we could see the Supplier code (200025) and Purchasing group code (004) instead of email ID maintained for supplier and purchasing group.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On coming out of the message screen following warning messages are shown,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Email address 004 is not valid (&lt;SPAN&gt;Message no. APOC_OR_MESSAGES105). Similarly&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Email address 0000200025 for email role 'TO' is not valid&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(Message no. APOC_OR_MESSAGES105). Also email is not send to vendor. Output message status is In Preparation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Email address maintained in supplier and purchasing group is correct. I double checked. Receiver and sender domain is maintained correctly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why email address is not shown instead of code? Why status is available In preparation?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kindly advice&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Suddy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/supplier-and-purchasing-group-email-not-picked-in-po-output-message/qaq-p/14181584"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:12:21.077000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sql-console-adt-fires-additional-query-which-takes-a-long-time-to-execute/qaa-p/14181585#M4923031</id>
    <title>Re: SQL Console (ADT) fires additional query which takes...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:15:22.554000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NemanjaSimovic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170312</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Anyhow, this issue is solved. Thanks ADT Team! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_up:"&gt;👍&lt;/span&gt; Going to close the topic.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sql-console-adt-fires-additional-query-which-takes-a-long-time-to-execute/qaa-p/14181585#M4923031"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:15:22.554000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-outbound-ip-ranges/qaa-p/14181588#M4923032</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud Outbound IP Ranges</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:18:02.073000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1480928"&gt;@dogukanpadel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To obtain the egress IP address ranges for your SAP Public Cloud instance needed for bank integration user and IP mapping, here is the recommended approach:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Public Cloud which includes Cloud Foundry egress IPs are managed by the underlying cloud infrastructure and IPs can change over time. Examples are the Hyperscalers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP provides region-specific IP ranges for some services and environments via official documentation and GitHub projects, for example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BTP Kyma Runtime egress IP utility scripts to discover live egress IPs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Help Portal pages listing SAP HANA Cloud and Integration Suite IPs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For your specific SAP Public Cloud tenant, you can check SAP Service Interfaces and Network documentation specific for your region.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You also have the option to contact SAP Cloud Operations or your SAP Account team to request the official IP ranges assigned to your tenant or landscape. Keep in mind these IPs may change with platform updates, so ongoing communication or subscription to SAP notices is advisable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have Kubernetes or Cloud Foundry access within your SAP environment, you can also run scripts or tools that query live egress IP addresses to capture current outbound IPs used by your applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the necessary information. I am happy to help if you have further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-outbound-ip-ranges/qaa-p/14181588#M4923032"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:18:02.073000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/planned-inventory-active-in-ls03n-how-to-clear-yellow-triangle/qaa-p/14181592#M4222878</id>
    <title>Re: Planned Inventory active in LS03N, how to clear yello...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:21:18.750000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The yellow triangle indicates that planned inventory is still active for the bin.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Even if all inventory records are cleared, the system may still show the bin as blocked for inventory due to:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Incomplete clearing of inventory documents&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Residual entries in tables like LAGP or LINP&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;System inconsistencies after manual or partial clearing&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Go to &lt;STRONG&gt;LX22&lt;/STRONG&gt;, tick the boxes Not counted or Partially counted bins so that, you may find an inventory document still linked to the bin even if LS03N shows it as cleared. Check table LAGP for the bin, field IVIVO (Inventory active indicator) may still be set. If IVIVO = X, the system considers the bin as planned for inventory. Check SAP note &lt;STRONG&gt;824904&lt;/STRONG&gt; which provides a correction report and it updates internal fields and clears the yellow triangle. But as cautioned in the note, you should be very careful before running the report. Also, check for SAP note &lt;STRONG&gt;2124215&lt;/STRONG&gt; which gives two resolutions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/planned-inventory-active-in-ls03n-how-to-clear-yellow-triangle/qaa-p/14181592#M4222878"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:21:18.750000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/mass-delete-credit-segment-data-from-bp/bc-p/14181593#M50234</id>
    <title>Re: Mass delete credit segment data from BP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:22:31.970000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shreekantkarkhile</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2073071</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It's deleting the segments correctly, and in case of locked data, it's skipping the deletion as expected. However, the issue is that no error or warning messages are being returned. We need an error message to be returned when the data is locked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I also debugged Tcode UKM_BP and observed the same behavior.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/mass-delete-credit-segment-data-from-bp/bc-p/14181593#M50234"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:22:31.970000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap/welcome-to-the-sap-expert-lecture-discussion-forum/td-p/14181596</id>
    <title>Welcome to the SAP Expert Lecture Discussion Forum</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:24:28.533000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>britta_radicke-schlinsog</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/192523</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dear course participants,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Welcome to the discussion forum for the SAP Expert Lecture &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap-integration-suite-on-suse-rancher" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerating Hybrid Integrations with SAP Integration Suite on SUSE Rancher&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We're pleased to have you join us.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This forum is the dedicated space to accompany your learning experience and connect with others taking part in the course. Whether you’d like to ask content-related questions, share reflections, or exchange ideas with peers and SAP experts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; this is the place to do it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I’m part of the SAP Learning team and worked closely with our subject matter experts to design and deliver this course. Special thanks to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shilpa, Finny, Jannis, Udo, and Piyush from SAP, and Richard from SUSE,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; who contributed their insights and expertise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;About the course:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Edge Integration Cell is an optional hybrid integration runtime available in SAP Integration Suite. It allows you to manage APIs and run integration scenarios within your private landscape based on SUSE Rancher Kubernetes Engine. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Estimated learning time&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: 2 hours&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s included&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Video lectures, downloadable resources and a final quiz&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Goal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Complete the quiz to earn your Record of Achievement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you’re new to this course format, we recommend watching the short video “&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_2b9mks57" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;What Are SAP Expert Lectures?&lt;/A&gt;” for an overview of how this learning experience is structured.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We hope you find the course both insightful and relevant to your work. Thank you for choosing SAP Learning, and we look forward to your participation in the forum.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Britta Radicke-Schlinsog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(SAP Learning)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap/welcome-to-the-sap-expert-lecture-discussion-forum/td-p/14181596"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:24:28.533000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/payment-schedule/bc-p/14181599#M71869</id>
    <title>Re: Payment schedule</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:26:53.282000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Volodymyr</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16431</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;UP&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/payment-schedule/bc-p/14181599#M71869"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:26:53.282000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap/i-like-i-wish-share-your-feedback/td-p/14181600</id>
    <title>I like, I wish – Share Your Feedback</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:27:26.021000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>britta_radicke-schlinsog</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/192523</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dear course participants,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We truly value your feedback, which helps us improve our courses and the learning experience on our platform.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you’ve completed the SAP Expert Lecture &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap-integration-suite-on-suse-rancher" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Accelerating Hybrid Integrations with SAP Integration Suite on SUSE Rancher&lt;/A&gt;”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, we invite you to share your thoughts using the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“I like, I wish”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; format. It’s a simple and helpful way to structure your input. Here are a few examples:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I like that the course content was broken down into smaller, manageable lessons.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I wish there were more examples specific to my industry.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please post your feedback directly here in the forum. While we’re not able to respond to each comment individually, rest assured that we read every post and review your suggestions as a team.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you again for learning with us!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Britta Radicke-Schlinsog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(SAP Learning)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap/i-like-i-wish-share-your-feedback/td-p/14181600"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:27:26.021000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-in-sap-mobile-start-v2-4-integrate-and-launch-sap-document-ai-on-mobile/bc-p/14181601#M183771</id>
    <title>Re: New in SAP Mobile Start V2.4: Integrate and Launch SAP Document AI on Mobile</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:28:53.666000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vincent00</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/773322</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2078707"&gt;@umairabbashayat&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the blog! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I just tried to follow the steps, but I'm having trouble with the point &lt;STRONG&gt;Configure Trust Relationship for API Access&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have the SuccessFactors Work Zone as well as the Document Information Extraction service, but they are in different subaccounts. So, I think that's why I can't connect both services:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="vincent00_0-1755253375259.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301350iB026019546CF9ADD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="vincent00_0-1755253375259.png" alt="vincent00_0-1755253375259.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there another way to integrate them? Or is the only way to do it, to setup the DOX service in the same subaccount?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Vincent&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-in-sap-mobile-start-v2-4-integrate-and-launch-sap-document-ai-on-mobile/bc-p/14181601#M183771"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:28:53.666000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/delivery-document-type-outb-has-the-wrong-document-category-pdo/qaa-p/14181603#M206175</id>
    <title>Re: Delivery document type OUTB has the wrong document ca...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:31:01.846000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;As per SAP note &lt;STRONG&gt;3499336&lt;/STRONG&gt;, for your item category, the field "Returns" should not be ticked and if return delivery is required, you have to execute /SCWM/PRDI in EWM to maintain PDI&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/delivery-document-type-outb-has-the-wrong-document-category-pdo/qaa-p/14181603#M206175"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:31:01.846000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/terminate-debug-session-button-disappeared-from-the-debug-perspective/td-p/14181606</id>
    <title>Terminate debug session button disappeared from the Debug Perspective toolbar</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:33:41.817000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NemanjaSimovic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170312</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ADT started to eat my debug toolbar buttons! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":fearful_face:"&gt;😨&lt;/span&gt; It seams to me that they started to disappear one by one. Now I'm left with only&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Run to line&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Jump to line&lt;/EM&gt;! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":downcast_face_with_sweat:"&gt;😓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NemanjaSimovic_1-1755253371027.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301349i556B56B04D5DC580/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="NemanjaSimovic_1-1755253371027.png" alt="NemanjaSimovic_1-1755253371027.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How it should be:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="NemanjaSimovic_0-1755253123870.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301347i7F096D9E3545B67E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="NemanjaSimovic_0-1755253123870.png" alt="NemanjaSimovic_0-1755253123870.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No I don't even have Terminate button anymore. I have to terminate applications with the right click in Debug view. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":frowning_face:"&gt;☹️&lt;/span&gt; I think it started with last ADT update. My ADT version is 3.52.1. I believe this is the last version at the time I'm writing this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone experienced same issue? Or know the solution. I tried to reset perspectives. It doesn't help. It just destroys my layout. Also I haven't found anything in &lt;EM&gt;Preferences&amp;gt;ABAP developement&amp;gt;Debug&lt;/EM&gt;. Strange... &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":crystal_ball:"&gt;🔮&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for reading this! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":revolving_hearts:"&gt;💞&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/terminate-debug-session-button-disappeared-from-the-debug-perspective/td-p/14181606"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:33:41.817000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/adaptation-project-select-application-blank/qaa-p/14181607#M4923033</id>
    <title>Re: Adaptation Project - Select application - Blank</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:35:30.715000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;HI&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/597023"&gt;@krish96&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The reason can related to various areas. A few of them are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It can refer to system or tooling limitations. Some apps cannot currently be configured or extended via Adaptation Projects in Business Application Studio and require SAP Web IDE instead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It can also be missing required SAP UI5 versions or platform components. The apps must meet minimum UI5 version requirements which is usually 1.56 or higher and run on supported SAP front-end framework versions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Workspace or project context can also be a trigger. Note that the Adaptation Project wizard only shows applications available in the current workspace that meet specific criteria.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Permissions or authorizations issues that can also prevent the loading of applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are some known UI or feature restrictions. Some new features in BAS may cause empty application lists, requiring updates or workarounds such as regenerating the entire project or adjusting config files.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, you can try solving that by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Verifying the app you want to adapt is compatible with Adaptation Projects. This can be Fiori elements Object Page or List Page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensuring your environment supports the UI5 version and system components.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can try using SAP Web IDE if your app is not visible in BAS Adaptation Projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Checking your workspace and system authorizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the necessary information. I am happy to help if you have further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/adaptation-project-select-application-blank/qaa-p/14181607#M4923033"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:35:30.715000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/vat-number-doesn-t-print-on-invoice/qaa-p/14181611#M4222879</id>
    <title>Re: VAT number doesn't print on invoice</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:42:34.721000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Some root causes are&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;SAP often uses country-dependent logic in the invoice form templates (SmartForms, Adobe Forms, or Output Management). Some countries (e.g., EU members) require VAT numbers on invoices by law, so the template includes them. For countries like Japan, Indonesia, UAE, the template may omit VAT numbers unless explicitly configured.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The Customer Master Record (BP) may not have the Tax Number 1 or VAT Registration Number maintained for these countries. If the field is blank or not mapped correctly, it won’t print.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;SAP’s localization content may control whether VAT numbers are considered relevant for invoice output in certain countries. For example, Japan uses a different tax ID format (Corporate Number), and UAE uses TRN (Tax Registration Number).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;So please check the below areas:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Go to BP transaction or Manage Business Partner Master Data app. Check if Tax Number 1 or VAT Registration Number is maintained for customers in Japan, Indonesia, UAE. If not, update it manually or via data migration.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Identify the form used for invoice output (e.g., SD_BIL_INV or custom Adobe Form). Review the logic in the Data Provider Class or Form Interface. Modify the condition to include all relevant countries or remove country filtering entirely.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In Output Management, check if the form variant or template differs by country. Ensure the same form logic applies across all countries where VAT number is required.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;SAP provides &lt;STRONG&gt;localized tax categories for Japan in the Business Partner master data like JP3 &amp;amp; JP4&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Similarly, for UAE, SAP supports TRN as a localized tax field&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/vat-number-doesn-t-print-on-invoice/qaa-p/14181611#M4222879"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:42:34.721000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/position-to-job-information-sync-is-not-working-during-position-data-import/qaa-p/14181612#M45747</id>
    <title>Re: Position to Job Information Sync is not working durin...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:45:25.490000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BhaskarNarayana</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171982</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Arun, At position object level activate the technical parameters field and while importing position data update this field as SYNC which will resolve the issue.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/position-to-job-information-sync-is-not-working-during-position-data-import/qaa-p/14181612#M45747"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:45:25.490000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-compare-sorted-class-methods-in-eclipse-has-a-bug/qaa-p/14181613#M4923034</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP Compare (Sorted Class Methods) in Eclipse has a bug</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:45:48.857000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NemanjaSimovic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170312</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I can confirm that ADT Team solved this. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; Bravo ADT Team! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":ok_hand:"&gt;👌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-compare-sorted-class-methods-in-eclipse-has-a-bug/qaa-p/14181613#M4923034"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:45:48.857000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/idnfbrj-1bnfagri-defen-missing/qaa-p/14181614#M4222880</id>
    <title>Re: IDNFBRJ_1BNFAGRI_DEFEN Missing</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:46:29.787000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FELIXALENCASTR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1589196</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I dia the same problem and, when make the login in english, the structure was created with the all fields. Follow the steps: 3.1.1. Access the Change Document Object (SCDO) transaction; 3.1.2. On the Object field, enter “NOTAFISCAL”; 3.1.3. Click on the change button (the Pencil icon); 3.1.4. Click on Add New Line; 3.1.5. On the new line, under Column table, enter the name “J_1BNFAGRI_DEFEN”; 3.1.6. Mark the Int. Table checkbox; 3.1.7. Click on the Save button; 3.1.8. Click on the Generate button; 3.1.9. In the pop-up window, click on the Function button; 3.1.10. Verify the entries (the fields that are automatically filled are the correct ones); 3.1.11. Check the affected objects by the process; 3.1.12. Activate the object.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/idnfbrj-1bnfagri-defen-missing/qaa-p/14181614#M4222880"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:46:29.787000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/tree-view-in-rap/bc-p/14181615#M50235</id>
    <title>Re: Tree view in RAP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:47:25.650000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dejuandro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/738462</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;do you know how to do the tree-view but multi field grouping ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/tree-view-in-rap/bc-p/14181615#M50235"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:47:25.650000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/delivery-creation-date-vl10/qaa-p/14181616#M4222881</id>
    <title>Re: Delivery Creation date VL10</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:50:27.787000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;VL10&lt;/STRONG&gt; transactions (like VL10B, VL10C, etc.) use &lt;STRONG&gt;delivery due date logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which is based on delivery creation date &lt;STRONG&gt;≤&lt;/STRONG&gt; planned delivery date. But here's the twist:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The Delivery Creation Date in VL10 is &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; a strict match filter. It’s a cutoff date.&amp;nbsp; SAP checks if the planned delivery date (from the schedule line) is less than or equal to this date.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;When you use &lt;STRONG&gt;“equal to 15.08.2025”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP interprets this as “planned delivery date = 15.08.2025”, which &lt;STRONG&gt;may not match&lt;/STRONG&gt; due to time stamps or internal rounding.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;When you use &lt;STRONG&gt;“less than or equal to 15.08.2025”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP includes all items with planned delivery dates up to and including 15.08.2025 and this should work.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;When you use &lt;STRONG&gt;“less than or equal to 14.08.2025”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the planned date is excluded.&amp;nbsp; So no items will be displayed.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Recommended approach is always use &lt;STRONG&gt;“less than or equal to”&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the &lt;STRONG&gt;Delivery Creation Date in VL10&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This ensures:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Items with planned delivery dates on or before the date are picked up.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;You avoid issues with time stamps or internal scheduling buffers.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/delivery-creation-date-vl10/qaa-p/14181616#M4222881"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:50:27.787000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/managing-subscriptions-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-as-a-software-reseller/qaa-p/14181617#M4222882</id>
    <title>Re: Managing Subscriptions in S/4HANA Public Cloud as a s...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:52:45.436000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>souvik_acuiti</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2036940</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2185638"&gt;@vasco_keizer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My name is Souvik and I am CTO and head of presales of Acuiti Labs (&lt;A href="https://www.acuitilabs.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.acuitilabs.com/&lt;/A&gt;) and we an expert consulting organization works only in SAP quote to cash covering billing, CPQ, EMS etc. We not only provide consulting services for SAP Q2C but also build our own products and IPR to address the white spaces in SAP Q2C.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your requirements are a great fit for Subscription Billing. We are currently implementing SAP's billing solution for another reseller. We have also developed our app on BTP to manage subscriptions in mass (creation/offers/renewals) which I think can be very useful for your business along with our Q2C Customer portal that can enable self service capabilities for your end customers. If you have some time next week we can have a quick call and I can explain you further. Feel free to drop me a mail at &lt;A href="mailto:souvik@acuitilabs.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;souvik@acuitilabs.co.uk&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/managing-subscriptions-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-as-a-software-reseller/qaa-p/14181617#M4222882"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:52:45.436000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/eclipse-sql-console-is-too-slow-takes-one-core-to-100/m-p/14181618#M2042308</id>
    <title>Re: [Eclipse] SQL Console is too slow. Takes one core to 100%</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:53:07.408000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NemanjaSimovic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170312</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Bravo ADT Team! This is solved! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/eclipse-sql-console-is-too-slow-takes-one-core-to-100/m-p/14181618#M2042308"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:53:07.408000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/executing-opensql-statement-takes-too-long-in-sql-console-in-eclipse/m-p/14181619#M2042309</id>
    <title>Re: Executing OpenSQL statement takes too long in SQL Console in Eclipse</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T12:57:53.915000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NemanjaSimovic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170312</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;It's working fine for some time. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":ok_hand:"&gt;👌&lt;/span&gt; Send regards to ADT team! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/executing-opensql-statement-takes-too-long-in-sql-console-in-eclipse/m-p/14181619#M2042309"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T12:57:53.915000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/supplier-and-purchasing-group-email-not-picked-in-po-output-message/qaa-p/14181620#M206176</id>
    <title>Re: Supplier and Purchasing group email not picked in PO...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:00:15.657000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Even if the email addresses are correct, SAP might still fail if:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;the sender email address is not mapped correctly in the Email Settings node.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The receiver email address is not being picked up due to missing or incorrect context mapping.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Go to Output Parameter Determination → Email Settings and verify Sender email is explicitly defined. Receiver email is mapped from the correct field (e.g., BusinessPartner.EmailAddress).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Check if the output type is configured to use EMAIL and not PRINT or XML by mistake.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;SAP performs strict validation. Even small issues can trigger APOC_OR_MESSAGES105. Extra spaces before/after the email.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Hidden characters (especially if copy-pasted). Multiple addresses in one field without proper separators. It is better to use transaction BP or SU01 and manually retype the email address. Avoid copy-paste.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Finally, Run &lt;STRONG&gt;SLG1&lt;/STRONG&gt; with:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Object: APOC&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Subobject: OR_MESSAGES&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Date/time of the failed output&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Check the full message context—it often includes the exact field or logic that failed.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Also try triggering the same output manually using Manage Output Items and see if the email is populated correctly. If it works manually but fails automatically, the issue is likely in the BRF+ determination logic.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/supplier-and-purchasing-group-email-not-picked-in-po-output-message/qaa-p/14181620#M206176"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:00:15.657000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/can-t-change-font-size-in-sap-when-i-run-transaction-from-eclipse/m-p/14181622#M2042310</id>
    <title>Re: Can't change font size in SAP when I run transaction from Eclipse</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:03:05.464000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NemanjaSimovic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170312</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This is obsolete now. It's possible to scale the font in SAP GUI Release 800. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":ok_hand:"&gt;👌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/can-t-change-font-size-in-sap-when-i-run-transaction-from-eclipse/m-p/14181622#M2042310"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:03:05.464000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/excited-to-join-the-sap-community/m-p/14181623#M10290</id>
    <title>Re: Excited to join the SAP Community!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:05:33.994000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GabrielaSoares</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2089515</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2119967"&gt;@JeanCh&lt;/a&gt;! We are happy to have you in the community. Where are you based? Please, check the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Location Groups" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/location-groups/ct-p/location" target="_self"&gt;Location Groups&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and join the one closer to you, to get in touch with members in your area. In case you can't find any, you are more than welcome to start one yourself &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/excited-to-join-the-sap-community/m-p/14181623#M10290"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:05:33.994000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-blogs/sap-service-cloud-v2-utilities-add-on-extending-utility-premise-object-gt/bc-p/14181624#M1420</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Service Cloud V2 Utilities Add-on - Extending Utility Premise Object -&gt; PART II</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:06:03.799000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jasper_cremers</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/662004</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/188482"&gt;@steen_hansen&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I can access blog I and II. But not blog III&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blogs/blogworkflowpage/blog-id/utilitiesblog-board/article-id/1414?prePageCrumb=BlogDashboardPage" target="_self"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part III&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mapping Extension Fields in Integration Flow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Jasper&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-blogs/sap-service-cloud-v2-utilities-add-on-extending-utility-premise-object-gt/bc-p/14181624#M1420"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:06:03.799000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-everyone/m-p/14181625#M10291</id>
    <title>Re: Hello Everyone!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:13:02.189000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GabrielaSoares</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2089515</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hola&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491699"&gt;@MatiasLemos&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you for joining, I am sure you will bring a lot of great insights for the SAP Community &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; Please, check the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/business-bydesign" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business ByDesign | SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;topic to find more about&amp;nbsp;SAP‘s cloud ERP solutions. But, also make sure to check other topics you might be interested about in our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/all-sap-managed-tags/ct-p/managed-tags" target="_blank"&gt;All SAP Managed Tags !&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-everyone/m-p/14181625#M10291"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:13:02.189000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-sap-note-3605421/qaq-p/14181627</id>
    <title>Error SAP note 3605421</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:17:35.892000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Liziane</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1677550</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Good morning,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are an error to apply the SAP Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;3605421:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Format of correction instructions 0020751259 1&lt;BR /&gt;0001597534 0001; unable to read corr. instruct.Message no. SCWN409"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Someone had the same error?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Liziane&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-sap-note-3605421/qaq-p/14181627"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:17:35.892000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-ase-money-data-type/qaa-p/14181629#M61951</id>
    <title>Re: SAP ASE money data type</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:22:58.495000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrisBaker</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189912</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Money datatype is based on Decimal/Numeric.&amp;nbsp; Like those, it is an exact/precision datatype, not an approximate datatype such as float/real.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-ase-money-data-type/qaa-p/14181629#M61951"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:22:58.495000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/finance-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/bc-p/14181630#M61492</id>
    <title>Re: Finance with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:23:44.561000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>eamonn_mcfadden</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/396971</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This summary of the enhancements is very useful, and the ensuing detail. It would be beneficial to make this available via email to the SAP's customer on Public Cloud's main contact on the SAP portal, when the changes are applied to the Test Systems and prior to go-live. Saves some of the time trawling through new features in the relevant scope items given under the RASD download. Una.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/finance-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/bc-p/14181630#M61492"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:23:44.561000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/a-breath-of-fresh-air/m-p/14181632#M10292</id>
    <title>Re: A breath of fresh air</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:23:49.024000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GabrielaSoares</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2089515</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1891960"&gt;@DimitarPlamenovStoev&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;! It is great to have you here and we are excited to see your contributions for the SAP Community &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt; Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/all-sap-managed-tags/ct-p/managed-tags" target="_blank"&gt;All SAP Managed Tags | SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to find more about the topics you are most passionate about and engage with others!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/a-breath-of-fresh-air/m-p/14181632#M10292"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:23:49.024000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/customizing-defect-creation-in-focused-build/bc-p/14181633#M183772</id>
    <title>Re: Customizing Defect Creation in Focused Build</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:23:50.013000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tmj_dk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1500</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Just saw this blok, but I hope this question finds you right&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How can we change the colors in the graphs, specificly in "Data aggreated by Defect" view from default&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="tmj_dk_0-1755256921282.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301360i6A20D79BFD0EC323/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="tmj_dk_0-1755256921282.png" alt="tmj_dk_0-1755256921282.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Very high = Red&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;High = Orange&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Medium = Light Yellow&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Low = Light gray&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/customizing-defect-creation-in-focused-build/bc-p/14181633#M183772"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:23:50.013000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/hyperlink-formulas/qaa-p/14181634#M4923036</id>
    <title>Re: Hyperlink formulas</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:24:19.225000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2223865"&gt;@Connor_Sullivan54&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are a few common causes to your error. It could be incorrectly formatted or inaccessible file path, the client viewing the report doesn’t have access to the network share or missing or incorrect escaping in the path string in your formula. Here are important points and steps to help you resolve that:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First, use the Format Field &lt;/SPAN&gt;à&lt;SPAN&gt; Hyperlink tab to select your text or formula field, open Format Field, then go to Hyperlink.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For the hyperlink type, Choose "A File" if linking to a file path. Use the formula editor to insert your dynamic path like&amp;nbsp;\\\\&amp;lt;myserver&amp;gt;\\Files\\_Customer_Files_New\\Municipality\\Projects\\Test.pdf.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Make sure to double backslash each folder separator (\\) so Crystal Reports interprets it correctly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Then verify the file path works on the client machine opening the report (the PC must have network access to that server path).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finally, you can format text with HTML links using&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;a href=""&amp;gt;link text&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;in a formula field, then set Text Interpretation to "HTML Text" under Format → Paragraph tab if you want custom text instead of the raw URL.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the necessary information. I am happy to help if you have further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/hyperlink-formulas/qaa-p/14181634#M4923036"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:24:19.225000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-sap-note-3605421/qaa-p/14181636#M4923037</id>
    <title>Re: Error SAP note 3605421</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:27:50.896000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Not sure in which version you are working. Normally, this error typically occurs due to one of the following:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The correction instructions are in a format not supported by your current SAP_BASIS release or Support Package level.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The note may contain newer syntax or metadata that your system cannot parse.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;There may be a missing prerequisite note or a program inconsistency in Note Assistant.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;So check SAP_BASIS and your Support Package Level. Alternatively, you can check SAP Note &lt;STRONG&gt;853524&lt;/STRONG&gt; which addresses SCWN409 errors and provides a fix for Note Assistant parsing issues.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-sap-note-3605421/qaa-p/14181636#M4923037"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:27:50.896000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-hide-or-block-listing-all-stock-list-to-users-from-item-master-data/qaa-p/14181637#M4222883</id>
    <title>Re: How to hide or block listing all stock list to users...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:27:54.970000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/240469"&gt;@siyadsalim&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addtion to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1413236"&gt;@Simo_Anddam&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;anwser,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that users can still view all items in marketing documents, such as Purchase Orders, by entering * in the Item No. field. This is standard behaviour in SAP Business One.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To limit visibility further, consider filtering by Item Groups/Properties or using queries/UDVs to restrict the item list.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-hide-or-block-listing-all-stock-list-to-users-from-item-master-data/qaa-p/14181637#M4222883"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:27:54.970000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/excited-to-be-part-of-sap-community/m-p/14181638#M10293</id>
    <title>Re: Excited to be part of SAP Community</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:28:32.836000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GabrielaSoares</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2089515</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1585085"&gt;@Archisha&lt;/a&gt;! Thank you for joining the SAP Community, is very nice to have you here. Make sure to check the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-successfactors-user-groups/ct-p/successfactors-user-groups" target="_blank"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;group, could be a great chance to collaborate and learn with other members!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/excited-to-be-part-of-sap-community/m-p/14181638#M10293"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:28:32.836000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-add-multiple-input-artifacts-in-sap-ai-core-serving-template/qaq-p/14181640</id>
    <title>How to add multiple input artifacts in SAP AI Core Serving template</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:28:52.995000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shashank_More</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2227137</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;BR /&gt;While deploying ML model on SAP AI Core , I can able pass model.gz as input artifact but when I pass another file in serving.yml template, that another file is not found.&lt;BR /&gt;Below is snippet of yml file&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;spec&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;inputs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;artifacts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;name&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;asopmodel&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;# placeholder name, do not add `-` in value use only alphanumeric chars&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;name&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;asoppredict&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;path&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/app/asop-predict/&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;# path where the artifact will be mounted in the container&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;template&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;apiVersion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"serving.kserve.io/v1beta1"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;metadata&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;annotations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;|&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;autoscaling.knative.dev/metric: concurrency # condition when to scale&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;autoscaling.knative.dev/target: 1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;autoscaling.knative.dev/targetBurstCapacity: 0&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;labels&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;|&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ai.sap.com/resourcePlan: starter # computing power&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;spec&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;|&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;predictor:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;imagePullSecrets:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- name: shashankmore-docker # your docker registry secret&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;minReplicas: 1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;maxReplicas: 5 # how much to scale&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;containers:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- name: kserve-container&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;image: docker.io/shashankmore25387/asop-predict:v8&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ports:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- containerPort: 8080 # customizable port&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;protocol: TCP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;command: ["/bin/sh", "-c"]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;args:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- &amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;set -e &amp;amp;&amp;amp; echo "Starting Gunicorn Server" &amp;amp;&amp;amp; gunicorn --workers 3 --bind 0.0.0.0:8080 --chdir /app/src serve:app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;env:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- name: STORAGE_URI # Required&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;value: "{{inputs.artifacts.asopmodel}}" # Required reference from artifact name, see above&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- name: ASOP_PREDICT_PATH&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;value: "/app/asop-predict" # Required reference from artifact name, see above&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Is this way of passing or mounting a file inside a container is correct?&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/523422"&gt;@vi-kas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/209738"&gt;@carlosbasto&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-add-multiple-input-artifacts-in-sap-ai-core-serving-template/qaq-p/14181640"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:28:52.995000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/essential-transfer-parameters-are-missing-in-record-000001-message-posting/qaa-p/14181641#M4222884</id>
    <title>Re: Essential transfer parameters are missing in record:...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:30:00.843000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tish4</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1391949</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Chris&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for your suggestions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I created a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;manual reservation&amp;nbsp;against a cost centre and was able to successfully post it using the&amp;nbsp;Post Goods Issue&amp;nbsp;app. This triggered the&amp;nbsp;Warehouse Management (WM) view, where I selected the bin holding the stock.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, when I added the&amp;nbsp;same material&amp;nbsp;to a&amp;nbsp;work order&amp;nbsp;and followed the same process (with sufficient stock available), I encountered the&amp;nbsp;same error. In this case, the&amp;nbsp;WM view did not appear, even though we are using&amp;nbsp;Extended Warehouse Management (EWM). The reservation details were identical to the manual one — same fields populated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do you have any further advice or suggestions on what might be causing this discrepancy?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tish&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/essential-transfer-parameters-are-missing-in-record-000001-message-posting/qaa-p/14181641#M4222884"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:30:00.843000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/deltastockrequest-payload-link-content/qaa-p/14181645#M180414</id>
    <title>Re: 'DeltaStockRequest' payload link content</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:32:18.478000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yaccoulibaly</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163691</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I thing this is just a Dummy from where system which runs these jobs.&lt;BR /&gt;and in anycase, this dummy is not sent to your backend system because you can clearly see that in the outbound payload it has been wiped out.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yaccoulibaly_0-1755255624930.png" style="width: 696px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301358i9AF3BB9DD31FC39B/image-dimensions/696x253/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="696" height="253" role="button" title="yaccoulibaly_0-1755255624930.png" alt="yaccoulibaly_0-1755255624930.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the same way, when the backend replied with IngestStock interface, than also your backend name is removed as well befor it reaches Ariba Buying.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="yaccoulibaly_1-1755257460381.png" style="width: 672px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301364i790C1ED8BB05906A/image-dimensions/672x356/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="672" height="356" role="button" title="yaccoulibaly_1-1755257460381.png" alt="yaccoulibaly_1-1755257460381.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I do not think there is a reason to worry here.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/deltastockrequest-payload-link-content/qaa-p/14181645#M180414"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:32:18.478000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/essential-transfer-parameters-are-missing-in-record-000001-message-posting/qaa-p/14181646#M4222885</id>
    <title>Re: Essential transfer parameters are missing in record: 000001 message posting a reservation</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:32:21.286000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;This error is usually triggered when mandatory fields for the movement type or reservation are missing or incomplete. Common causes include:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Missing plant, storage location, or movement type&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Incomplete account assignment (e.g., cost center, order)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Reservation created via a work order or custom process that didn’t populate all required fields&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Attempting to post a goods issue against a reservation without sufficient stock or proper reference&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Check the below areas&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Lakshmipathi_0-1755257713869.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301368i05CF975D8288BAC9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Lakshmipathi_0-1755257713869.png" alt="Lakshmipathi_0-1755257713869.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/essential-transfer-parameters-are-missing-in-record-000001-message-posting/qaa-p/14181646#M4222885"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:32:21.286000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mrp-generated-purchase-requisitions-to-have-source-determination-enabled-by/qaa-p/14181649#M4222886</id>
    <title>Re: MRP-generated purchase requisitions to have source de...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:34:28.926000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1489983"&gt;@Haily&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To have your MRP-generated purchase requisitions automatically include source determination in S/4HANA Public Cloud, you should ensure the following:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Make sure to maintain valid sources of supply like Purchasing Info Records with automatic sourcing enabled, Source Lists marked as MRP relevant, Contracts and Quota Arrangements for the materials and plants involved. The system assigns sources based on priority among these master data objects during the MRP run.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please note that properly maintained and active source data will enable MRP to assign sources automatically. Therefore, allowing purchase requisitions to be converted into purchase orders via scheduling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If no valid source is found, manual assignment or adjustment of master data may be necessary.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the necessary information. I am happy to help if you have further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mrp-generated-purchase-requisitions-to-have-source-determination-enabled-by/qaa-p/14181649#M4222886"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:34:28.926000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hi-sap-community/m-p/14181650#M10294</id>
    <title>Re: Hi, SAP Community!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:34:45.921000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GabrielaSoares</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2089515</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2230043"&gt;@PREMSINGHLKR&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;! Welcome to the SAP Community, we are very excited to have you here collaborating for meaningful insights and connections. Where are you based? Make sure to check the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/location-groups/ct-p/location" target="_blank"&gt;Location Groups.&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and find the closest to you. If you do not find any, please feel free to start one for your area!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hi-sap-community/m-p/14181650#M10294"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:34:45.921000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fg-to-rm-norms-consumption/qaa-p/14181652#M4222887</id>
    <title>Re: FG TO RM NORMS CONSUMPTION</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:35:43.837000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/840279"&gt;@gaudalvi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your question&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud Edition, you can report FG to RM consumption norms by using released CDS views for BOM data rather than accessing tables directly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommended Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Start from the FG material&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use CDS view I_MaterialBOMHeader to identify the BOM header for the FG, including usage, plant, and validity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get BOM components&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use CDS view I_MaterialBOMItem to retrieve the RM or SFG components, along with base quantities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recursive explosion for SFGs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If any component is a Semi-Finished Good, repeat steps 1–2 until you list all leaf-level RMs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apply consumption norms logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Incorporate unit of measure conversions and effective validity dates to ensure norms are accurate for the reporting period.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Develop Z-Report&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consume these CDS views in a custom RAP application or Analytical Query for reporting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check this SAP Documentation for your reference &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/7489fa08cede494cbdf08fa3651598af/261056c94ca24d38a8743d18aa1a53a3.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help – Bills of Material in S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/fg-to-rm-norms-consumption/qaa-p/14181652#M4222887"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:35:43.837000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap/welcome-to-the-sap-expert-lecture-discussion-forum/td-p/14181654</id>
    <title>Welcome to the SAP Expert Lecture Discussion Forum</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:36:00.141000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>britta_radicke-schlinsog</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/192523</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dear course participants,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Welcome to the discussion forum for the SAP Expert Lecture “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap-integration-suite-on-redhat-openshift" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerating Hybrid Integrations with SAP Integration Suite on Red Hat OpenShift&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;”. We're pleased to have you join us.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This forum is the dedicated space to accompany your learning experience and connect with others taking part in the course. Whether you’d like to ask content-related questions, share reflections, or exchange ideas with peers and SAP experts — this is the place to do it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I’m part of the SAP Learning team and worked closely with our subject matter experts to design and deliver this course. Special thanks to Shilpa, Finny, Jannis, Udo, and Piyush from SAP, and Markus and Joachim from Red Hat, who contributed their insights and expertise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;About the course:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Edge Integration Cell is an optional hybrid integration runtime available in SAP Integration Suite. It allows you to manage APIs and run integration scenarios within your private landscape based on Red Hat OpenShift.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Estimated learning time&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; hours&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s included&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Video lectures, downloadable resources and a final quiz&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Goal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Complete the quiz to earn your Record of Achievement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you’re new to this course format, we recommend watching the short video &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_2b9mks57" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;“What Are SAP Expert Lectures?”&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; for an overview of how this learning experience is structured.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We hope you find the course both insightful and relevant to your work. Thank you for choosing SAP Learning, and we look forward to your participation in the forum.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kind regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Britta Radicke-Schlinsog&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(SAP Learning)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap/welcome-to-the-sap-expert-lecture-discussion-forum/td-p/14181654"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:36:00.141000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/upload-program-to-update-equipment-status-in-ie02-inconsistent-results-with/qaa-p/14181655#M4923039</id>
    <title>Re: Upload Program to Update Equipment Status in IE02 – I...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:36:41.186000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alex_dsouza</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/823531</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194"&gt;@Sandra_Rossi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/190831"&gt;@janbuchmann&lt;/a&gt; I tried using STATUS_CHANGE_EXTERN i filled my equipment data in SE37 transaction for the given FM, but the FM always thew me a dump. Even after passing the correct values.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/upload-program-to-update-equipment-status-in-ie02-inconsistent-results-with/qaa-p/14181655#M4923039"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:36:41.186000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-sap-note-3605421/qaa-p/14181656#M4923040</id>
    <title>Re: Error SAP note 3605421</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:38:00.257000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Liziane</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1677550</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Lakshmipathi</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-sap-note-3605421/qaa-p/14181656#M4923040"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:38:00.257000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-sap-note-3605421/qaa-p/14181657#M4923041</id>
    <title>Re: Error SAP note 3605421</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:40:19.580000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Liziane</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1677550</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Lakshmipathi , I appreciate you answer, our SAP version is ECC EHP8 and the basis components attends the recommendation, but the error still to occur. Do you have any more idea? Best Regards, Liziane</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-sap-note-3605421/qaa-p/14181657#M4923041"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:40:19.580000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-sap-community-zabron-here/m-p/14181658#M10295</id>
    <title>Re: Hello SAP Community - Zabron here</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:40:52.311000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GabrielaSoares</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2089515</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2176855"&gt;@zabronm&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;! Welcome, we are very happy to have you joining the community! Please, always remember that "silly" questions do not exist, here is a place to learn, connect and find meaningful insights for your growth. Make sure to check the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/location-groups/ct-p/location" target="_blank"&gt;Location Groups | SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to find the closest one to you. Also, w&lt;SPAN&gt;e have an&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/sap-champions/ba-p/13988156" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Champions program&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;in SAP Community, feel free to reach out to some of our&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/bg-p/influencers-directory/label-name/sap%20champion" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Champions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;some of whom are SAP BTP experts!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-sap-community-zabron-here/m-p/14181658#M10295"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:40:52.311000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/condition-contract-delta-accrual/qaq-p/14181659</id>
    <title>Condition Contract - Delta Accrual</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:40:57.280000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HendryTj</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1609356</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am creating multi period Condition Contract and would like to perform accrual on monthly basis. However, the accrual document should be independent from each settlement calendar (do-not using cumulative approach).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;i found the configuration about cumulative and partial, however it did not work for accrual. looks like it only partial approach only works for partial settlement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any idea how to perform non-cumulative accrual via condition contract?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hendry&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/condition-contract-delta-accrual/qaq-p/14181659"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:40:57.280000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/managing-subscriptions-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-as-a-software-reseller/qaa-p/14181660#M4222889</id>
    <title>Re: Managing Subscriptions in S/4HANA Public Cloud as a s...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:42:51.519000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>boris_aljancic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/673486</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;in short: &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Subscription Billing is the perfect match to manage subscriptions for software and SaaS use cases&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Among many customers please find below the &lt;STRONG&gt;reference story for ROCHE&lt;/STRONG&gt;, who is extremely happy with their "Software Monetization Platform" based on SAP Subscription Billing and SAP Entitlements Management Solution :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2023/12/4ca1edba-9f7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2023/12/4ca1edba-9f7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Did you know that SAP has just released &lt;STRONG&gt;Industry Best Practice for Software and SaaS Use Cases&lt;/STRONG&gt; which enables customers to &lt;STRONG&gt;implement an end-2-end process&lt;/STRONG&gt; across SAP Subscription Billing, SAP Entitlements Management Solution and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition with &lt;STRONG&gt;very low Time-2-Market and TCO&lt;/STRONG&gt;? Please check out the new corresponding &lt;STRONG&gt;scope item 5SW&lt;/STRONG&gt; which needs to be activated in order to leverage all the example (master) data and example processes out of the box!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Boris&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/managing-subscriptions-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-as-a-software-reseller/qaa-p/14181660#M4222889"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:42:51.519000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/essential-transfer-parameters-are-missing-in-record-000001-message-posting/qaa-p/14181661#M4222890</id>
    <title>Re: Essential transfer parameters are missing in record:...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:46:06.495000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tish4</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1391949</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The Error message that i am getting is "Essential transfer parameters are missing in record: 0001.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tish4_0-1755258412675.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301370iEC50215A471A1289/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Tish4_0-1755258412675.png" alt="Tish4_0-1755258412675.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is the detail message, however there is no inbound or outbound delivery expected.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is no issue when posting against a cost centre&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tish4_1-1755258447253.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301371iFF1C276F35FC8099/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Tish4_1-1755258447253.png" alt="Tish4_1-1755258447253.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/essential-transfer-parameters-are-missing-in-record-000001-message-posting/qaa-p/14181661#M4222890"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:46:06.495000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap/i-like-i-wish-share-your-feedback/td-p/14181662</id>
    <title>I like, I wish – Share Your Feedback</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:46:42.984000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>britta_radicke-schlinsog</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/192523</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dear course participants,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We truly value your feedback — it helps us improve both our courses and the learning experience on our platform.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you’ve completed the SAP Expert Lecture &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap-integration-suite-on-redhat-openshift" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerating Hybrid Integrations with SAP Integration Suite on Red Hat OpenShif&lt;/SPAN&gt;t&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, we invite you to share your thoughts using the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“I like, I wish”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; format. It’s a simple and helpful way to structure your input. Here are a few examples:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I like that the course content was broken down into smaller, manageable lessons.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I wish there were more examples specific to my industry.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please post your feedback directly here in the forum. While we’re not able to respond to each comment individually, rest assured that we read every post and review your suggestions as a team.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you again for learning with us!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Britta Radicke-Schlinsog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(SAP Learning)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/accelerating-hybrid-integrations-with-sap/i-like-i-wish-share-your-feedback/td-p/14181662"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:46:42.984000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/i-m-getting-an-error-during-the-subscription-to-the-sbpa/qaq-p/14181666</id>
    <title>I'm getting an error during the subscription to the SBPA</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:48:12.004000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>moacir_goelzer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/268959</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;During the installation, I'm getting this error 'Subscription Failed'&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/i-m-getting-an-error-during-the-subscription-to-the-sbpa/qaq-p/14181666"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:48:12.004000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-sap-note-3605421/qaa-p/14181667#M4923043</id>
    <title>Re: Error SAP note 3605421</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:54:24.372000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;I could see lot of other SAP notes are listed under &lt;STRONG&gt;"Prerequisites"&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP note 3605421. Verify that all listed notes are implemented. Sometimes the system doesn’t flag missing prerequisites correctly. Please check with your Basis team (I have added the tag on your behalf) who are the right team to guide you on this issue.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error-sap-note-3605421/qaa-p/14181667#M4923043"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:54:24.372000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-generate-a-wrapper-for-function-modules-bapis-in-tier-2/bc-p/14181668#M183773</id>
    <title>Re: How to generate a wrapper for function modules (BAPIs) in tier 2</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T13:59:27.275000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MRobalinho</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140615</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for sharing&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-generate-a-wrapper-for-function-modules-bapis-in-tier-2/bc-p/14181668#M183773"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T13:59:27.275000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-retry-feature-for-http-receiver-adapter/bc-p/14181669#M183774</id>
    <title>Re: New Retry Feature for HTTP Receiver Adapter</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T14:00:43.043000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kostadin_terziev</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/753388</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Would be great if in addition to response codes, we can specify response body message conditions. For example the error message.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-retry-feature-for-http-receiver-adapter/bc-p/14181669#M183774"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T14:00:43.043000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/condition-contract-delta-accrual/qaa-p/14181670#M4222891</id>
    <title>Re: Condition Contract - Delta Accrual</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T14:01:20.801000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;You can use Accrual Engine with Periodic Accrual Runs. SAP’s Accrual Engine (or Accruals Management in S/4HANA) allows you to:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;define accrual objects linked to condition contracts&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Schedule monthly accrual postings&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Control posting logic independently of settlement&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;You can configure accruals to post fixed monthly amounts or percentage-based accruals based on contract value.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In the Accrual Object Type configuration, set Accrual Method to Periodic. This ensures each accrual run posts only for the current period, not cumulatively. This method is ideal for contracts with fixed monthly values or evenly distributed accruals.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;While the settlement calendar drives settlement timing, you can decouple accrual logic by not referencing the calendar in your accrual object. Instead, use posting date or period-based triggers in the accrual run. This ensures accruals are posted monthly regardless of settlement frequency.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If you're in S/4HANA Public Cloud, use the Manage Accruals app to:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;create accrual objects manually or via mass upload&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Schedule monthly accrual runs&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Monitor and reverse accruals as needed&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;With the above settings, while testing, you can validate by performing the below steps&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Create a condition contract with multiple validity periods&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Create an accrual object with periodic method&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Run accruals monthly and check that each posting is standalone, not cumulative&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Compare with settlement postings to confirm decoupling&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/condition-contract-delta-accrual/qaa-p/14181670#M4222891"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T14:01:20.801000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-outbound-ip-ranges/qaa-p/14181680#M4923044</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud Outbound IP Ranges</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T14:05:23.522000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BAM_21_ABAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1456131</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Chris1973, thanks for reply. Could you tell me, which scripts or tools we can use in Cloud Foundry? We have Cloud Foundry.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-outbound-ip-ranges/qaa-p/14181680#M4923044"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T14:05:23.522000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/where-can-i-add-the-tax-code-in-the-sap-public-cloud/qaa-p/14181681#M4222892</id>
    <title>Re: Where can I add the tax code in the SAP public cloud?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T14:09:17.216000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HenrikeGrtecke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47173</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Just a brief comment: The configuration steps described refer to the 2-system landscape. In the 3-system landscape, you configure the system in the Central Business Configuration (CBC). where you simply search for the name of the configuration activity.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/where-can-i-add-the-tax-code-in-the-sap-public-cloud/qaa-p/14181681#M4222892"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T14:09:17.216000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-green-token-onboarding-page-now-live/bc-p/14181682#M7605</id>
    <title>Re: 🚀 SAP Green Token Onboarding Page Now Live!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T14:11:30.304000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DorotaTuo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2009552</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;thank you&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1471776"&gt;@GJFigaroa&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-green-token-onboarding-page-now-live/bc-p/14181682#M7605"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T14:11:30.304000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/lac-spain-and-portugal-events/sap-talent-recruiting-days-s%C3%A3o-paulo-oportunidade-para-estudantes/ev-p/14181683</id>
    <title>SAP Talent Recruiting Days | São Paulo | Oportunidade para Estudantes</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T14:12:31.198000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AriadneRodrigues</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2046676</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;É com grande entusiasmo que anunciamos a próxima edição do &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Talent Recruiting Days – São Paulo&lt;/STRONG&gt;, um programa &lt;STRONG&gt;gratuito&lt;/STRONG&gt; e &lt;STRONG&gt;exclusivo&lt;/STRONG&gt; para estudantes de graduação que desejam acelerar sua carreira no universo da tecnologia e dos negócios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prepare-se para uma &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;imersão no ecossistema SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, com workshops interativos, networking e a oportunidade de se conectar diretamente com líderes da empresa. A jornada será &lt;STRONG&gt;híbrida&lt;/STRONG&gt;, combinando atividades online e um encontro presencial especial de &lt;EM&gt;speed connection&lt;/EM&gt; com gestores da SAP Brasil.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Durante o programa, você poderá:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Participar de workshops com profissionais de tecnologia e negócios&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explorar o ecossistema SAP e suas soluções inovadoras&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Desenvolver habilidades práticas e de carreira&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Receber certificado de participação&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conectar-se presencialmente com líderes da SAP Brasil&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Datas e Formato:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;08 a 12 de setembro&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Online&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;16 de setembro&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Presencial em São Paulo&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Requisitos:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inglês intermediário&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Estar cursando graduação a partir do 2º semestre (preferencialmente Administração ou áreas correlatas)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt; Não perca essa chance de transformar o seu futuro profissional com quem está liderando a inovação no mundo!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":memo:"&gt;📝&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Inscrições até 31 de agosto de 2025!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Garanta sua vaga: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Clique aqui" href="https://lnkd.in/eRPHwU52" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Clique aqui&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/lac-spain-and-portugal-events/sap-talent-recruiting-days-s%C3%A3o-paulo-oportunidade-para-estudantes/ev-p/14181683"/>
    <published>2025-08-15T14:12:31.198000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
