<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-08-26T16:44:01.524971+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/new-tables-of-tax-for-portugal-irs-to-be-applied-in-august-and-october/bc-p/14192870#M61617</id>
    <title>Re: New tables of tax for Portugal- IRS to be applied in August and October</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:46:42.005000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>henrique_fuhr</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/563594</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Boa tarde,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Obrigado por levantar esse ponto. Ainda não existe SAP Note tratando dessa situação. Você pode, por favor, criar um case para o componente PY-PT reportando a situação?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cumprimentos,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Henrique Führ&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;HCM Development&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/new-tables-of-tax-for-portugal-irs-to-be-applied-in-august-and-october/bc-p/14192870#M61617"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:46:42.005000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-everyone/m-p/14192872#M10319</id>
    <title>Re: Hello, Everyone</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:47:09.285000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MRobalinho</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140615</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Wellcome&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2078564"&gt;@FI_Kaushik&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-everyone/m-p/14192872#M10319"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:47:09.285000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/designing-value-help-services-for-the-situation-handling-extended-framework/ba-p/14184050</id>
    <title>Designing Value Help Services for the Situation Handling - Extended Framework</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:47:35.486000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>axel_spriestersbach</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/239489</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737862785"&gt;Understanding Value Help Services: What They Are and Why They Matter?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Value help services are a cornerstone feature in enhancing user experience by offering context-specific assistance. These services provide users with relevant suggestions and options based on the current situation, making tasks more intuitive and efficient. But what exactly are value help services, and how do they help users? Let's dive into their key functions and benefits.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Functions and Benefits of Value Help Services&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easing Data Entry&lt;BR /&gt;One of the primary goals of value help services is to simplify data entry. For instance, when inputting data like product lists or options that require predefined choices, these services provide a seamless way to select the appropriate data. This reduces the risk of errors and speeds up the data input process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use in Situation Handling&lt;BR /&gt;Value help services are particularly useful when it comes to defining condition filters for situation templates and types in the &lt;EM&gt;Manage Situation Types - Extended&lt;/EM&gt; app, as well as in the &lt;EM&gt;My Situations – Extended&lt;/EM&gt; app as part of the filter bar. By offering context-specific suggestions, they help users navigate and interact with the system more efficiently, turning complex tasks into manageable ones.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's take a closer look at how these services work with an example. &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; below shows how you can choose a plane type when defining a condition filter in the &lt;EM&gt;Manage Situation Types – Extended&lt;/EM&gt; app. Value help services ensure that when you don't have to manually input each plane type; instead, you can select from a list of predefined options. You also see additional information, such as the total seats of the plane, that help you choose the appropriate plane type.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Throughout this blog, we'll continue to use the plane type value help as an example to illustrate how value help services enhance user experience and streamline processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="axel_spriestersbach_0-1755864793221.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303913i0D09B54F9085528C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="axel_spriestersbach_0-1755864793221.png" alt="axel_spriestersbach_0-1755864793221.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;: Value Help for Plane Type in Condition Filter dialog in the Manage Situation Types - Extended app&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541349280"&gt;Designing an OData-Based Value Help Service&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this section, we explore the design of an OData-based value help service, breaking down its key components and steps. This will serve as a foundation for integrating these services into the extended framework for Situation Handling. We’ll use artifacts from the Flight situation object (&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;ID: SITDEMO_FLIGHT&lt;/FONT&gt;), which is included as a demo object in the extended framework. The main components and their relations are shown in &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Figure 2&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="axel_spriestersbach_0-1755863322830.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303892i3F88A8F2A6EE9B03/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="axel_spriestersbach_0-1755863322830.png" alt="axel_spriestersbach_0-1755863322830.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;: Overview on Artifacts for the Value Help Definition&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1473918494"&gt;Key Components of an OData-Based Value Help&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CDS Views&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Value Help Source CDS View:&lt;/EM&gt; Define the source entity that serves as the primary data source for the value help service. This view and its view entities are referenced from the situation object.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Value Help Provider CDS View(s)&lt;/EM&gt;: Design one or more CDS views specifically for the value help, which may include additional filters or joins to meet the value help requirements.&lt;BR /&gt;Both the base CDS view as well as the Value Help Provider Views contain annotations that are essential for enhancing the functionality and user experience of value helps.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;OData Service&lt;BR /&gt;Naturally, OData-based value helps must be exposed as OData services to be accessible to SAP Fiori applications including their respective &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-rap/service-definition" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Service Definition&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-rap/business-service" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Service&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Situation Object&lt;BR /&gt;Linking the source CDS view in a situation object in the &lt;EM&gt;Manage Situation Objects&lt;/EM&gt; app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1277404989"&gt;Steps to Design an OData-Based Value Help Service&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1339056922"&gt;1. Define the Value Help Source CDS View&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;Start by creating the source CDS view, which will serve as the primary data source for your value help. This view should include all relevant fields that users might need for filtering or searching. Below is an example based on the &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;Sitn2DemoFlightVH&lt;/FONT&gt; view provided by SAP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ObjectModel.viewType: #CONSUMPTION
@ObjectModel.dataCategory: #VALUE_HELP
define view entity C_Sitn2DemoFlightVH as select from R_Sitn2DemoFlight {
  @Consumption.valueHelpDefinition:[{entity: {name: 'C_Sitn2DemoPlaneVH', element: 'SitnDemoPlaneType'}}]  
      key cast( '' as sit2_demo_plane_type ) as SitnDemoPlaneType
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This view only serves to reference the value helps for the entity sets it contains – it is not necessary to actually retrieve all field values here, i.e., as shown in the above entity set, it is possible to simply hard-code the field value as ''. The important annotations in this view are the &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;@Consumption.valueHelpDefinition&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; annotations which define the Value Help Provider View (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;entity.name&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) and the element (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;entity.element&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) in the target entity that is linked to the respective fields (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;SitnDemoPlaneVH&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;SitnDemoPlaneType&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in the example above).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;For more details, check out the Consumption Annotations page in SAP Help Portal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1142543417"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;Create the Value Help Provider View&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, create a CDS view specifically for the value help.&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; This view may include filters, joins, or additional fields necessary for the value help functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ObjectModel.viewType: #CONSUMPTION
@ObjectModel.dataCategory: #VALUE_HELP
@ObjectModel.representativeKey: 'SitnDemoPlaneType'
define view entity C_Sitn2DemoPlaneVH as select from R_Sitn2DemoPlane
{
@Search.defaultSearchElement: true
@Search.ranking: #HIGH
key SitnDemoPlaneType,

@Search.defaultSearchElement: true 
@Search.ranking: #LOW
SitnDemoSeatsMaxQty,
... 
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Besides the &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;SitnDemoPlaneType&lt;/FONT&gt;, that was referenced by the &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;entity.element&lt;/FONT&gt; in the Source CDS View above and must be part of the Value Help Provider View, the view incorporates extra fields like the number of seats available. To enhance user experience, the view can also include optional search annotations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-946029912"&gt;3. Expose as OData Service&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, expose the value help CDS view as an OData service to make it accessible to SAP Fiori applications and other systems consuming OData services. Currently, only OData V2 services are supported that needs to be implemented by using &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-rap/business-service" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Service&lt;/A&gt;. Ensure the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-rap/service-definition" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Service Definition&lt;/A&gt; includes the Source CDS View and all referenced Value Help Provider Views, like in the example below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@EndUserText.label: 'Value help for Situation Demo'
define service C_SITN2DEMOFLIGHTVHSRV {
expose C_Sitn2DemoFlightVH as FlightVH;
expose C_Sitn2DemoPlaneVH as PlaneVH;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-rap/service-definition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;service definition&lt;/A&gt; is afterwards used for the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-rap/service-binding" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;service binding&lt;/A&gt;. Please use “OData V2 – UI” as binding type. The result should look like the service binding below:&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[2]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="axel_spriestersbach_1-1755863442433.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303893i76C6208EC24B4A64/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="axel_spriestersbach_1-1755863442433.png" alt="axel_spriestersbach_1-1755863442433.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 3&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Service Binding for Value Help Service&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-362268250"&gt;Extending a Situation Object with a Value Help&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We'll now guide you through the steps to add a value help service in the Manage Situation Objects app. To do so, open your situation object in the Manage Situation Objects app. We are again using the Flight situation object (ID: &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;SITDEMO_FLIGHT&lt;/FONT&gt;) that comes with the extended framework, but with a different service that got exposed using &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-rap/business-service" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Services&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-294837464"&gt;Add a Value Help Service in the Manage Situation Objects App&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a New Value Help Service&lt;BR /&gt;To add a new value help service, you'll start by clicking the "Create" button in your situation object in the &lt;EM&gt;Manage Situation Objects&lt;/EM&gt; app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure the Value Help Service&lt;BR /&gt;in the Value Help Services section, fill the following fields with the specified values:&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Service Protocol Version:&lt;/U&gt; Set this to &lt;EM&gt;V2&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Service Path:&lt;/U&gt; Choose &lt;EM&gt;Standard&lt;/EM&gt; - there are currently no other options available.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Service Binding:&lt;/U&gt; Enter the name of the service binding of the value help service you’ve created. In the example shown in &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 3&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;, this is &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;C_SITN2DEMOFLIGHTVHV2&lt;/FONT&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;Service Version:&lt;/U&gt; Use the latest service version from your service binding.In the example shown in &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 3&lt;/STRONG&gt;,&lt;/FONT&gt; this version is 1.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add Properties.&lt;BR /&gt;Add the entity set of the &lt;EM&gt;Source CDS View &lt;/EM&gt;here, not any of the Value Help Provider Views that are also included in the service. Please note that you have to use the name of the entity set as defined in the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-rap/service-definition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Service Definition&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, not the name of the CDS view, i.e. for our example use &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;FlightVH&lt;/FONT&gt; and not &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;C_Sitn2DemoFlightVH&lt;/FONT&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Add the name of the property that you want to use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The results should look like the figure below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="axel_spriestersbach_0-1755863784618.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303899i99A2F24BDA2DE393/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="axel_spriestersbach_0-1755863784618.png" alt="axel_spriestersbach_0-1755863784618.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 4&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Manage Situation Objects: add a Value Help Service&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-98323959"&gt;Mapping Value Help Entities in the Situation Object Structures&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To complete your value help setup, you provide a mapping between the fields of the CDS views you use in the structure of your situation object and the properties in the value help service entities. We'll walk you through the necessary steps to do this below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Structure in the Manage Situation Objects app&lt;BR /&gt;Navigate to the structure within your situation object that you wish to extend with value help functionality.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access the Value Help Mapping Section&lt;BR /&gt;Next, go to the "Value Help Mapping" section. This is where you will map the fields to the value help entities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a New Mapping&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on the "Create" button to add a new value help mapping.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select a Field: Choose the field from the structure that you want to enhance with a value help. For our example, we're using &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;SITNDEMOPLANETYPE.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign the Value Help&lt;BR /&gt;After selecting the field, use the value help to select the value help ID you modeled in the previous steps. Ensure you match the entity set and property correctly. For our example, the mapping should be:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Value Help ID:&lt;/U&gt; &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;VALUE_HELP_DEMO&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Entity Set:&lt;/U&gt; &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;FlightVH&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Property:&lt;/U&gt; &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;SitnDemoPlaneType&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The results should look like the figure below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="axel_spriestersbach_1-1755863830227.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303900i3BC7328CF58EBFDA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="axel_spriestersbach_1-1755863830227.png" alt="axel_spriestersbach_1-1755863830227.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 5&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;: Manage Situation Objects: mapping of Value Help Service and Structure fields&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By following these steps, you'll successfully add the value help service to your situation object, enhancing your ability to manage situations effectively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-119982092"&gt;Using the Situation Object Enhanced with Value Help Services&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you've created your situation objects and enhanced them with value help services, they're ready for use in situation scenarios, situation templates, and situation types. Most of your defined content is automatically propagated, making changes—even in value help services—immediately active.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, situation type updates are handled different due to performance caching. If you add value help services after creating a situation type, you'll need to refresh it by creating a new version of the situation type. You can do this by making a small change for example in the type description and saving afterwards. This will trigger the value help changes to become active. For any situation type you create after enhancing your situation objects, the changes will immediately be applied.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--76531413"&gt;Tips and tricks for testing and in case of problems&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--566447925"&gt;Testing your value help service&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To quickly test if your value help service works correctly, create a new situation template that makes use of the situation object&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[3]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; that you’ve defined and check the condition filters. Make sure to select the correct trigger or anchor object for the condition filter to see all fields and their value helps.&lt;BR /&gt;An example for the Demo Scenario is shown in &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Value Help for Plane Type in Condition Filter dialog in the Manage Situation Types - Extended app&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--762961430"&gt;Check the &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;$metadata&lt;/FONT&gt; of your value help service&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the value helps are not working, please check the &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;$metadata&lt;/FONT&gt; of your service. All fields with value help services should have the &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;&amp;lt;Annotation Term="Common.ValueList"&amp;gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; property.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An example is the &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;$metadata&lt;/FONT&gt; of the Demo Application&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;URL: …/sap/opu/odata/sap/C_SITN2DEMOFLIGHTVH_CDS/$metadata 

&amp;lt;Annotation Term="Common.ValueList"&amp;gt;
...
&amp;lt;Record&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;PropertyValue Property="CollectionPath" String="C_Sitn2DemoRegionVH" /&amp;gt;
...
&amp;lt;/Annotations&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similar annotation should be available in the OData Service defined in the Service Binding. Simply extend the service URL with &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;/$metadata&lt;/FONT&gt; and check the properties you annotated. There should be a &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;Common.ValueList&lt;/FONT&gt; annotation for each field annotated with &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;@Consumption.valueHelpDefinition&lt;/FONT&gt; in your &lt;EM&gt;Source CDS View&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--959474935"&gt;Creating or Updating Situation Types after Situation Object Changes&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;As mentioned earlier (section &lt;EM&gt;“Using the Value Help enhanced objects”&lt;/EM&gt;) remember that situation objects are cached for performance reasons in situation types when the situation type is created. This means that changes in the situation object are not reflected for the existing situation types, even if you might see them already in the situation template, unless they are updated.&lt;BR /&gt;So, whenever an update of situation objects was required, please remember to change or create new situation types to reflect the changes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1155988440"&gt;Update structure mapping after changing Value Help Services&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whenever you update a value help service in a situation object, , make sure to also update the value help mapping in the respective structure of the situation object.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 6&lt;/STRONG&gt; shows an example where the entity set is wrong (&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;ZAS_VH_BASE_VIRE&lt;/FONT&gt;) and should be changed to the correct name of the entity set as it’s exposed in the service (-&amp;gt; &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;FlightVH&lt;/FONT&gt;). Once this was changed in the Value Help section, it also needs to be changed in the Value Help Mapping in the Structure section(s).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="axel_spriestersbach_2-1755863894629.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303901i0719CB5C2E98B293/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="axel_spriestersbach_2-1755863894629.png" alt="axel_spriestersbach_2-1755863894629.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 6&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Manage Situation Object: Reflect changes in Value Help also to the Structure Mapping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1352501945"&gt;Popup “No authorization to access value help for &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;FIELDNAME&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; . Please define conditions”&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;While using the condition filter dialog, you might encounter the following error:&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="axel_spriestersbach_3-1755863959729.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303903iF189F82A49249F56/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="axel_spriestersbach_3-1755863959729.png" alt="axel_spriestersbach_3-1755863959729.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure 7&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;: Popup “No authorization to access value help for &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;FIELDNAME&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; . Please define conditions”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This error can arise from two primary issues:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Value Help Service Authorization: There may be an authorization problem with the value help service, which needs to be addressed in the backend – check the DCLs assigned to the views and the authorizations given to the user.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Service Issues: The service itself might be experiencing problems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Troubleshooting Steps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To diagnose if the issue is with the service, use the browser’s network tab in the debugging tools to check for a &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;/$metadata&lt;/FONT&gt; request related to your value help service.&lt;BR /&gt;Here’s what you might find:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Service Not Published: If the service URL is unavailable, it’s likely that the service hasn’t been published. Ensure that the service is properly published.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Wrong OData Version: If you see an error message similar to&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;/IWFND/MED/170&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;message xml:lang="en"&amp;gt;No service found for namespace '', name '...', version '0001'&amp;lt;/message&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;innererror&amp;gt;​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;it’s probable that the incorrect OData version was used. Ensure you are using “OData V2 – UI” as specified in the “Expose as OData Service” step in the section “Steps to Design an OData-Based Value Help Service.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By following these steps, you should be able to identify and resolve the underlying issue causing the error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1255612443"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modeling value help services for the extended framework for Situation Handling is a powerful way to enhance user experience by providing context-specific assistance. By following the principles and best practices demonstrated in the Flight Demo, experienced developers can create robust and effective value help services tailored to their projects.&lt;BR /&gt;Stay tuned for more advanced techniques and in-depth discussions as we continue to explore the capabilities of the extended framework for Situation Handling.&lt;BR /&gt;Happy coding!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1452125948"&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Multiple Value Help Provider Views need to be created when the source CDS view references several Value Help Provider Views in the annotations.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[2]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; Note -This service does not exist in the Flight situation object that uses a different mechanism. However, the target design is to use service bindings.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[3]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;When creating the situation template, you first need to create a situation scenario where the situation object that is enhanced with value help services is used as trigger or anchor object. The value help becomes visible in the value help for the field it got assigned to in the condition’s filters of the trigger or anchor object.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/designing-value-help-services-for-the-situation-handling-extended-framework/ba-p/14184050"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:47:35.486000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-filter-data-in-sap-build-apps-using-record-collection/bc-p/14192873#M175143</id>
    <title>Re: How to filter data in SAP Build Apps using record collection</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:47:49.195000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>WyattMury</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2119885</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;My filter condition is not filtering my data. Anyone have the same issue?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-filter-data-in-sap-build-apps-using-record-collection/bc-p/14192873#M175143"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:47:49.195000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B9%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%AF%E0%A4%BE-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192876#M4224287</id>
    <title>Re: पेटीएम से गलत ट्रांजेक्शन हो जाए क्या करें?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:48:31.525000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Usbsiz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242043</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;पेटीएम से गलत नंबर पर पैसे चले जाए तो क्या करें ग्राहक सेवा नंबर /062-042-55383/ यदि पेटीएम (पेटीएम ) से गलत ट्रांजेक्शन हो जाए तो, सबसे पहले पेटीएम ग्राहक सहायता से संपर्क करें +91--081-169//59261//और उन्हें पूरी जानकारी दें।&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B9%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%AF%E0%A4%BE-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192876#M4224287"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:48:31.525000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B9%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F-%E0%A4%A4%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%AF%E0%A4%BE-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192878#M4224289</id>
    <title>Re: पेटीएम से गलत ट्रांजेक्शन हो जाए तो क्या करें?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:51:21.598000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Usbsiz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242043</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;पेटीएम से पैसे वापस कैसे पाए अगर गलत ट्रांजेक्शन हो जाए? इसके लिए आपको `pay Tm™ टोल फ्री पेटीएम ग्राहक सेवा नंबर 00-620~4255÷383 पर कॉल करना होगा। पेटीएम से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं. इसके लिए आपको `PAY tm™ टोल फ्री नंबर {0811_~695÷9261) पर कॉल करना होगा।.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B9%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F-%E0%A4%A4%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%AF%E0%A4%BE-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192878#M4224289"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:51:21.598000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/rfc-connections-authorization-issue/qaa-p/14192879#M4224290</id>
    <title>Re: RFC connections authorization issue</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:51:47.495000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eya1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1482973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/rfc-connections-authorization-issue/qaa-p/14192879#M4224290"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:51:47.495000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F-%E0%A4%85%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B0-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B9%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F/qaa-p/14192885#M206508</id>
    <title>Re: पेटीएम से पैसे वापस कैसे पाए अगर गलत ट्रांजेक्शन हो जाए?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:56:41.156000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Usbsiz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242043</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;पेटीएम से पैसे वापस कैसे पाए अगर गलत ट्रांजेक्शन हो जाए? इसके लिए आपको `pay Tm™ टोल फ्री पेटीएम ग्राहक सेवा नंबर 00-8116~959÷261 पर कॉल करना होगा। पेटीएम से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं. इसके लिए आपको `PAY tm™ टोल फ्री नंबर {0620_~425÷5383) पर कॉल करना होगा।.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F-%E0%A4%85%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B0-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B9%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F/qaa-p/14192885#M206508"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:56:41.156000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/automate-pfcg-process/m-p/14192889#M2042376</id>
    <title>Re: Automate PFCG process</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:57:33.899000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dan_spitzig</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/210701</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In PFCG, the standard way of adding a transaction is by going to the Menu tab, click on Transaction dropdown and selecting "Transaction", which looks like what the MENU_ADD_TRANSACTION method seems to do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What I am trying to simulate in ABAP is adding a transaction via Menu tab, click on Transaction dropdown, and select "Authorization Default" rather than "Transaction".&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/automate-pfcg-process/m-p/14192889#M2042376"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:57:33.899000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B9%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%A8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B0-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192891#M253991</id>
    <title>Re: गलत ट्रांजेक्शन होने पर पेटीएम से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:58:06.809000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Usbsiz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242043</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;आप ऐप से संपर्क करने के लिए 00,8116--959√261//पर मीशो कस्टमर केयर को कॉल कर सकते हैं। आप help@.com पर ईमेल भी भेज सकते हैं&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B9%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%A8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B0-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192891#M253991"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:58:06.809000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/phone-pe-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192896#M4224292</id>
    <title>Re: Phone Pe में गलत ट्रांजेक्शन से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:59:48.128000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Usbsiz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242043</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Phone Pe में गलती से किसी गलत खाते में पैसे ट्रांसफर हो जाने पर, तुरंत Phone Pe ग्राहक सहायता &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":telephone_receiver:"&gt;📞&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hundred_points:"&gt;💯&lt;/span&gt;00,8116--959√261 से संपर्क करें और अपने बैंक को भी सूचित करें.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/phone-pe-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192896#M4224292"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:59:48.128000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-discussions/vamos-fazer-sair-do-papel-o-inside-track-em-joinville/m-p/14192899#M15</id>
    <title>Re: Vamos fazer sair do papel o Inside Track em Joinville?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:00:36.852000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GislaineFA</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1965155</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Caldelmo, muito bom poder contar com sua contribuição também. Logo volto por aqui para alinharmos os próximos passos&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":airplane:"&gt;✈️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-discussions/vamos-fazer-sair-do-papel-o-inside-track-em-joinville/m-p/14192899#M15"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:00:36.852000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-discussions/vamos-fazer-sair-do-papel-o-inside-track-em-joinville/m-p/14192910#M16</id>
    <title>Re: Vamos fazer sair do papel o Inside Track em Joinville?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:03:24.926000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GislaineFA</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1965155</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Cristiano, que bom contar com sua disposição para colaborar! Toda contribuição fortalece nossa comunidade.&lt;BR /&gt;Rumo ao SIT Joinville &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-discussions/vamos-fazer-sair-do-papel-o-inside-track-em-joinville/m-p/14192910#M16"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:03:24.926000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-discussions/vamos-fazer-sair-do-papel-o-inside-track-em-joinville/m-p/14192917#M17</id>
    <title>Re: Vamos fazer sair do papel o Inside Track em Joinville?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:04:20.678000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GislaineFA</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1965155</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Maravilha! A divulgação é essencial e vai ser ótimo contar com você Mathias!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-discussions/vamos-fazer-sair-do-papel-o-inside-track-em-joinville/m-p/14192917#M17"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:04:20.678000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-discussions/vamos-fazer-sair-do-papel-o-inside-track-em-joinville/m-p/14192919#M18</id>
    <title>Re: Vamos fazer sair do papel o Inside Track em Joinville?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:05:18.416000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GislaineFA</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1965155</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Agora sim, Robalinho! Com sua energia e experiência, esse evento tem tudo para ser especial &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face_with_big_eyes:"&gt;😃&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-discussions/vamos-fazer-sair-do-papel-o-inside-track-em-joinville/m-p/14192919#M18"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:05:18.416000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/jdbc-microsoft-sql-connectivity-issue-in-sap-cpi/qaq-p/14192921</id>
    <title>JDBC (Microsoft SQL) Connectivity issue In SAP CPI</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:05:48.244000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shreyas_01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1475822</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm trying to establish a connection to an on prem Microsoft SQL server via JDBC adapter in SAP CPI. I'm getting an error&lt;BR /&gt;org.springframework.jdbc.CannotGetJdbcConnectionException: Failed to obtain JDBC Connection; nested exception is com.microsoft.sqlserver.jdbc.SQLServerException: The TCP/IP connection to the host localhost, port 1106 has failed. Error: "The driver received an unexpected pre-login response. Verify the connection properties and check that an instance of SQL Server is running on the host and accepting TCP/IP connections at the port. This driver can be used only with SQL Server 2005 or later.". ClientConnectionId:1fe33d15-3b89-41fa-b211-672cb643ff12, cause: com.microsoft.sqlserver.jdbc.SQLServerException: The TCP/IP connection to the host localhost, port 1106 has failed. Error: "The driver received an unexpected pre-login response. Verify the connection properties and check that an instance of SQL Server is running on the host and accepting TCP/IP connections at the port. This driver can be used only with SQL Server 2005 or later.". ClientConnectionId:1fe33d15-3b89-41fa-b211-672cb643ff12&lt;BR /&gt;The driver I've installed in CPI is V8.4.1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shreyas_01_0-1756216505845.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305155iD1EEA39F63BBC47A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shreyas_01_0-1756216505845.png" alt="Shreyas_01_0-1756216505845.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My JDBC configuration is&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shreyas_01_1-1756216817830.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305157iEE20828A0DA529AB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shreyas_01_1-1756216817830.png" alt="Shreyas_01_1-1756216817830.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this the correct driver version I'm using, and in the error, it mentions port as&amp;nbsp;1106, I've not maintained that port, why is it coming in the error? How do I resolve this error?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;BR /&gt;Shreyas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/jdbc-microsoft-sql-connectivity-issue-in-sap-cpi/qaq-p/14192921"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:05:48.244000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/use-of-vba-macro-quot-workbook-beforesave-quot-in-sap-dm/qaq-p/14192924</id>
    <title>Use of VBA macro "Workbook_BeforeSave" in SAP DM</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:08:51.936000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sofia_Zago</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1919447</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;!--  StartFragment   --&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Hi,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;We&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;have&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; embedded a VBA macro in a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;module&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;within&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; an Excel file. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; macro &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;needs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;run&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;before&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the file &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;is&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;saved&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Consequently&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;we&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;inserted&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the following code &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;into&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ThisWorkbook&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;":&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Private Sub &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Workbook_BeforeSave&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;(&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ByVal&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SaveAsUI&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;As&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Boolean&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Cancel&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;As&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Boolean&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Call &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Primadichiudere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; 'Name of the macro&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;End Sub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;When&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;we&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; use the file &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;outside&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; of SAP DM, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;everything&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; works &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;correctly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;However&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;when&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;we&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; test the Excel file after &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;uploading&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;it&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to SAP DM, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;we&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;have&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;noticed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the following:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;If&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;we&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;run&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the macro &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;manually (F5)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;it&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; works and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;executes&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;correctly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;If&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;we&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;save&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the file &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;using&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the floppy disk &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;icon&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; (i.e., &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;not&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; in SAP DM), &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;it&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; works &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;correctly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;If we&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;try&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;save&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; with "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;apply&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;changes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;," the macro &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;doesn't&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; work. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;It&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;doesn't&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;give&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;any&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;error&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;messages&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, so &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;it's&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;not&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; a debug &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;issue&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;it&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;simply&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;fails&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to do &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;what&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;it's&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;supposed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to do (e.g. it doesn't copy or paste values)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Is&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;this&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;normal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, or are &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;we&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;doing&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;something&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;wrong&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Is&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;there&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; a way to solve &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;this&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;issue&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Thank you very much,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Sofia&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;!--  EndFragment   --&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/use-of-vba-macro-quot-workbook-beforesave-quot-in-sap-dm/qaq-p/14192924"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:08:51.936000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-blog-posts/sit-joinville-uma-data-especial-muito-conte%C3%BAdo-ui5-uix-e-grandes-trocas-de/bc-p/14192925#M166</id>
    <title>Re: SIT Joinville - Uma data especial, muito conteúdo UI5/UIX e grandes trocas de experiências</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:09:39.290000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MRobalinho</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140615</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;10 anos desse evento! Muito bom saber!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville-blog-posts/sit-joinville-uma-data-especial-muito-conte%C3%BAdo-ui5-uix-e-grandes-trocas-de/bc-p/14192925#M166"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:09:39.290000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-movie-theater-to-global-stage-how-a-quot-gully-boy-quot-moment-changed/ba-p/14185324</id>
    <title>From Movie Theater to Global Stage: How a "Gully Boy" Moment Changed Everything</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:10:06.098000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arabella</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145342</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In a darkened movie theater in Amsterdam, Nagesh Polu made a decision that would seem absurd to most people. Fifteen minutes into the film, he'd already guessed the ending (he is an avid movie goer, so this happens often). So, he did what any dedicated learner would do—he pulled out his phone and started studying SAP SuccessFactors materials instead.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"That's probably the weirdest place I've ever studied," Nagesh laughs, "but it perfectly captures who I am. I can't waste a moment when there's something new to learn."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Nagesh's story begins in Chirala, India, where he earned his bachelor's degree. His parents had instilled in him what he calls a "do-or-die mindset"—a philosophy that would prove prophetic.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Nagesh Polu_Preferred Picture.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303011i1828511F49F41F69/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Nagesh Polu_Preferred Picture.jpeg" alt="Nagesh Polu_Preferred Picture.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;"My father taught me that success isn't just about personal achievement," Nagesh reflects. "It's about lifting your family and extended family along with you. Living simply, staying cheerful, standing by our people—these weren't just values, they were survival strategies.” Those early years built something invaluable: resilience. Little did he know that this small-town foundation would eventually support a career spanning continents and transforming global enterprises.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Starting as a sales trainee, Nagesh eventually found himself at YASH Technologies, working with traditional SAP HCM presales teams and constantly hitting walls. During one particularly frustrating project estimations discussions, a senior consultant delivered advice that would change everything: "If you really want to shape the future, learn SAP—it's where the biggest challenges and opportunities are."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But it was SAP's acquisition of SuccessFactors that created Nagesh's true "lightbulb moment." While others saw a complex transition, he saw infinite possibility. What happened next was nothing short of extraordinary. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning Hub became Nagesh's compass—his "go-to resource for quickly building knowledge and completing prerequisites." The comprehensive training, hands-on exercises, and certification preparation materials became the foundation of his transformation. The breakthrough came during a late-night session in his Amsterdam home office. He was trying to build a complex report. Hours of trial and error had left him exhausted and frustrated. Then, using the detailed training materials and practical examples from SAP Learning Hub, it clicked. "I sat there thinking, 'I can build anything with this.' The rush was incredible”, he remembers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here's where Nagesh's story takes a surprising turn. He expected SAP learning to be purely technical—a skills upgrade to advance his career. Instead, it transformed something he never anticipated: his ability to think like a business leader. The intensive learning journey wouldn't have been possible without key support. Nagesh credits his wife as his anchor, whose unwavering support at home enabled his relentless pursuit of learning without interruption and his mentors across his journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Colleagues began noticing that Nagesh brought both big-picture strategy and hands-on expertise to projects. He wasn't just solving technical problems; he was solving business problems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As Nagesh accumulated SAP Certifications— through rigorous study with SAP Learning Hub—each one became what he calls "another layer of armor."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Every SAP Certification reinforced my ability not only to tackle complex projects but also to lead others through them," he shares. "They weren't just credentials—they were confidence multipliers."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Certifications opened doors to high-impact global assignments and helped him earn client trust more quickly. But the real transformation was internal: from a small-town graduate to a leader who could walk into any boardroom with complete confidence.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Then came the career-defining moment that validated years of relentless learning. A global client was facing a high-stakes SAP SuccessFactors implementation with a brutal deadline. Their previous attempts had failed. The pressure was immense. Nagesh delivered.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"When their CHRO told me that our solution had transformed how they manage talent worldwide, all those years of learning—including those movie theater study sessions—suddenly made perfect sense," he recalls. Today, Nagesh's learning journey continues to impact others in unexpected ways. He's mentored colleagues through their first SAP Certifications, elevated his entire team's capabilities, and regularly shares insights through blogs that help the wider SAP community.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;"My learning journey has been consistent, persistent, and purpose-driven," he notes. "It should be as natural as checking your messages or having your morning coffee."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When asked what movie would capture his learning journey, Nagesh's answer is immediate: "Gully Boy—Apna time aayega" (Our time will come). It perfectly captures his philosophy: that with persistent learning and unwavering commitment, anyone from anywhere can rise to extraordinary heights. From a movie theater in Amsterdam to global boardrooms, from a small coastal town to becoming a trusted advisor to multinational corporations, Nagesh's story proves a simple truth: learning isn't just about acquiring skills—it's about transforming your entire life.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to start your own transformation?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Benefit from tailored and self-paced learning opportunities that meet you when and where you learn best on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Get certified to demonstrate your expertise and boost your career.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-movie-theater-to-global-stage-how-a-quot-gully-boy-quot-moment-changed/ba-p/14185324"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:10:06.098000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/3-dimension-in-1-column/qaq-p/14192928</id>
    <title>3 dimension in 1 column</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:14:02.846000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>osariyurt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2063795</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I have a layout like the one on the right. Here, the rows named X and Z are hidden, and X, Y, and Z are grouped together using a break. I want to group it like the one on the left so that all the Z rows are consolidated at the bottom. What should I do? what is the trick?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="osariyurt_0-1756217485479.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305168iDC7FF5B192E7035B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="osariyurt_0-1756217485479.png" alt="osariyurt_0-1756217485479.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/3-dimension-in-1-column/qaq-p/14192928"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:14:02.846000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/universal-odata-mcp-bridge-or-how-i-accidentally-made-15-000-enterprise/bc-p/14192930#M175145</id>
    <title>Re: Universal OData ↔ MCP Bridge; Or: How I Accidentally Made 15,000 Enterprise Services Talk to AI</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:17:38.166000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Alice_V</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/609259</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/763508"&gt;@dariusz_michalczuk2&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;it is also supporting --cookie auth, so it would be good-enough to to test/play with dev system: you can login into the system via web (into Fiori) export cookie and then use this exported cookie for temporarily login.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For permanent solution some full SAML choreography would be required which is quite challenging. But simpler approach might be possible: enabling OAuth for particular OData service (?).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/universal-odata-mcp-bridge-or-how-i-accidentally-made-15-000-enterprise/bc-p/14192930#M175145"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:17:38.166000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/connecting-datasphere-to-salesforce-using-generic-http-connection-and-api/qaa-p/14192931#M4924141</id>
    <title>Re: Connecting Datasphere to Salesforce using Generic HTT...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:18:28.831000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PrabhithPrabhakaran</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/12003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2238821"&gt;@Dipankar_Sanyal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Were all the pre-requsites mentioned in the link met?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/c8a54ee704e94e15926551293243fd1d/9a8489ed7443436197fbd8b8ffba61ab.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/c8a54ee704e94e15926551293243fd1d/9a8489ed7443436197fbd8b8ffba61ab.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR, Prabhith&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/connecting-datasphere-to-salesforce-using-generic-http-connection-and-api/qaa-p/14192931#M4924141"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:18:28.831000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%B6%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%BF%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AF%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%A6%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%9C-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14192937</id>
    <title>मीशो में शिकायत कैसे दर्ज करें?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:23:22.715000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>amds</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242057</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;कस्टमर केयर नंबर का उपयोग करके शिपिंग के बाद मीशो पर ऑर्डर रद्द करें आप ऐप के माध्यम से मीशो पर शिप किए गए ऑर्डर को भी रद्द कर सकते हैं। शिप किए गए संदेश प्रदर्शित होने के बाद मीशो में ऑर्डर रद्द करने का तरीका इस प्रकार है: आप उनके हेल्पलाइन नंबर 91 811_69592÷61 पर डायल कर सकते हैं।&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%B6%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%BF%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AF%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%A6%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%9C-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14192937"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:23:22.715000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%B6%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%BF%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AF%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%A6%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%9C-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192938#M4224294</id>
    <title>Re: मीशो में शिकायत कैसे दर्ज करें?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:23:47.762000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>amds</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242057</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;कस्टमर केयर नंबर का उपयोग करके शिपिंग के बाद मीशो पर ऑर्डर रद्द करें आप ऐप के माध्यम से मीशो पर शिप किए गए ऑर्डर को भी रद्द कर सकते हैं। शिप किए गए संदेश प्रदर्शित होने के बाद मीशो में ऑर्डर रद्द करने का तरीका इस प्रकार है: आप उनके हेल्पलाइन नंबर 91 811_69592÷61 पर डायल कर सकते हैं।&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%B6%E0%A5%8B-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%BF%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AF%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%A6%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%9C-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192938#M4224294"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:23:47.762000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/query-on-advanced-return-management-for-service-and-nlag-items/qaa-p/14192943#M4224296</id>
    <title>Re: Query on Advanced Return Management for Service and N...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:25:29.001000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aravindrawat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/722200</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Chuma, thanks for the information, But I have resolved this issue, and we can create advanced return order for service and NLAG items as well, I just created new item category, copy of ren2 and with the help of this item category, it determined CX schedule line item category for the service and NLAG items, and after this config, Now I am able to create advanced return orders for service and nlag items.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/query-on-advanced-return-management-for-service-and-nlag-items/qaa-p/14192943#M4224296"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:25:29.001000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%81%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%82-%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AB%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14192946</id>
    <title>कुकू एफएम से पैसे कैसे वापस करें?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:27:05.641000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>amds</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242057</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;इसके लिए आपको ™Kuku Fm™ टोल फ्री नंबर 00,8116✓959—261पर कॉल करना होगा। कुकू एफएम से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं. इसके लिए आपको ™Kuku Fm™ टोल फ्री नंबर (06204—255✓383/*+} पर कॉल करना होगा।&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%81%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%82-%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AB%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14192946"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:27:05.641000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%81%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%82-%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AB%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192947#M253995</id>
    <title>Re: कुकू एफएम से पैसे कैसे वापस करें?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:27:33.465000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>amds</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242057</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;इसके लिए आपको ™Kuku Fm™ टोल फ्री नंबर 00,8116✓959—261पर कॉल करना होगा। कुकू एफएम से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं. इसके लिए आपको ™Kuku Fm™ टोल फ्री नंबर (06204—255✓383/*+} पर कॉल करना होगा।&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%81%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%82-%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AB%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192947#M253995"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:27:33.465000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AB%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%A8%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14192955</id>
    <title>फोनपे में गलत ट्रांजेक्शन से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:32:32.599000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>amds</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242057</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Phone Pe में गलती से किसी गलत खाते में पैसे ट्रांसफर हो जाने पर, तुरंत Phone Pe ग्राहक सहायता 00811--6959√261से संपर्क करें और अपने बैंक को भी सूचित करें.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AB%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%A8%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14192955"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:32:32.599000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AB%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%A8%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192958#M4224298</id>
    <title>Re: फोनपे में गलत ट्रांजेक्शन से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:33:07.908000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>amds</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242057</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Phone Pe में गलती से किसी गलत खाते में पैसे ट्रांसफर हो जाने पर, तुरंत Phone Pe ग्राहक सहायता 00811--6959√261से संपर्क करें और अपने बैंक को भी सूचित करें.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E0%A4%AB%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%A8%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192958#M4224298"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:33:07.908000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/after-sending-a-customer-invoice-e-invoice-to-a-yahoo-mail-account-i-can/ba-p/14192967</id>
    <title>After sending a customer invoice e-invoice to a yahoo mail account I can not download attachments</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:35:57.581000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dieter_haensch2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/307666</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;After sending an e-invoice to the mentioned web browser email application you can only see the attachment content as raw data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As this is the browser application&amp;nbsp; concept from yahoo, aol and similar (XML are not meant for humans), we recommend as a workaround to use&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;outlook, thunderstorm or similar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here you are able to download all xml attachments&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/after-sending-a-customer-invoice-e-invoice-to-a-yahoo-mail-account-i-can/ba-p/14192967"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:35:57.581000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/phone-pe-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14192970</id>
    <title>Phone Pe में गलत ट्रांजेक्शन से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:37:54.444000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>amds</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242057</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Phone Pe में गलती से किसी गलत खाते में पैसे ट्रांसफर हो जाने पर, तुरंत Phone Pe ग्राहक सहायता &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":telephone_receiver:"&gt;📞&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hundred_points:"&gt;💯&lt;/span&gt;00,6204--255√383 से संपर्क करें और अपने बैंक को भी सूचित करें.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/phone-pe-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14192970"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:37:54.444000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/phone-pe-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192971#M4224300</id>
    <title>Re: Phone Pe में गलत ट्रांजेक्शन से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:38:17.539000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>amds</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242057</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Phone Pe में गलती से किसी गलत खाते में पैसे ट्रांसफर हो जाने पर, तुरंत Phone Pe ग्राहक सहायता &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":telephone_receiver:"&gt;📞&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hundred_points:"&gt;💯&lt;/span&gt;00,6204--255√383 से संपर्क करें और अपने बैंक को भी सूचित करें.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/phone-pe-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14192971#M4224300"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:38:17.539000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/create-custom-tab-with-custom-controller-in-business-partner-in-general/qaa-p/14192974#M4924142</id>
    <title>Re: create custom tab with Custom Controller in Business...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:39:16.138000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>prasanth_kasturi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/188656</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;hi Lakshmipathi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I created a new screen 1002 in custom namespace and changed the screen number in BUPT as suggested.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="prasanth_kasturi_0-1756219173215.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305181i41CC089123621DAA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="prasanth_kasturi_0-1756219173215.png" alt="prasanth_kasturi_0-1756219173215.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;and in the table data I see the below&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="prasanth_kasturi_1-1756219274281.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305182iC637DF95631CFDCE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="prasanth_kasturi_1-1756219274281.png" alt="prasanth_kasturi_1-1756219274281.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;automatically changed to 7002&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;please help&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/create-custom-tab-with-custom-controller-in-business-partner-in-general/qaa-p/14192974#M4924142"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:39:16.138000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/working-with-determination-in-the-service-cloud-v2-using-code-blocks/bc-p/14192978#M6834</id>
    <title>Re: Working with Determination in the Service Cloud V2 Using Code Blocks</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:41:54.441000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rajkumar_Balasubramanian</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1457921</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Prasad,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, I want to pull the Employee entity that I created.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-members/working-with-determination-in-the-service-cloud-v2-using-code-blocks/bc-p/14192978#M6834"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:41:54.441000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-analytical-queries-as-an-alternative-for-lis-in-sap-s-4hana/bc-p/14192979#M61619</id>
    <title>Re: Custom Analytical Queries as an alternative for LIS in SAP S/4HANA Production Planning (PP)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:47:08.953000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aagya</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/180268</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;How do we use drill through functionality (Navigating to Display Group Journal Entries with Reporting logic screen) for CAQ reports?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/custom-analytical-queries-as-an-alternative-for-lis-in-sap-s-4hana/bc-p/14192979#M61619"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:47:08.953000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/business-partner-relationship-webservice-inbound/qaq-p/14192981</id>
    <title>Business Partner Relationship WebService Inbound</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:50:20.407000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Simon</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5649</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;i am working on an interface between Salesforce and SAP and i am using the Inbound Business Partner/Business Partner Relationship Service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because of the format of the SalesForce ID( e.g.&amp;nbsp;003bY00000lm0NyQAI ) it is not possible to fill the field "&lt;SPAN&gt;InternalID" in the Request for Business Partner Creation. So im am using the field "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ExternalID" which works in general and the key mapping is created.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But when i try to use the external keys for the relationship:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Simon_0-1756218785024.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305178iF1CF00E02D13F861/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Simon_0-1756218785024.png" alt="Simon_0-1756218785024.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;the following error occours:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Simon_1-1756218844088.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305179i60EFCE39A0100D7C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Simon_1-1756218844088.png" alt="Simon_1-1756218844088.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I tried it with the fields&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;ReceiverBusinessPartnerInternalID/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ReceiverRelationshipBusinessPartnerInternalID and it works. But if the contact is not created yet, i do not have the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;ReceiverRelationshipBusinessPartnerInternalID at that time.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To my understanding this should work with the external keys aswell, where SAP is searching for the Internal Business Partner Numbers in the Key Mapping Table.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would appreciate any hints on this topic &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simon&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/business-partner-relationship-webservice-inbound/qaq-p/14192981"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:50:20.407000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/use-transaction-stats-fe-to-analyze-the-performance-of-your-web-application/bc-p/14192986#M184048</id>
    <title>Re: Use Transaction STATS_FE to Analyze the Performance of your Web Application</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:54:47.918000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>timhoffmann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/592692</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;nice content, thanks!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/use-transaction-stats-fe-to-analyze-the-performance-of-your-web-application/bc-p/14192986#M184048"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:54:47.918000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/in-my-btp-account-want-to-create-free-trail-account-in-order-to-get-sap-ai/qaq-p/14192989</id>
    <title>in my BTP account want to create Free Trail account in order to get SAP AI core access</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:56:33.817000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pancherupula1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/892883</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;in my BTP account want to create Free Trail account in order to get SAP AI core access&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/in-my-btp-account-want-to-create-free-trail-account-in-order-to-get-sap-ai/qaq-p/14192989"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:56:33.817000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-community-members/m-p/14192990#M10320</id>
    <title>Re: Hello Community members!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:59:14.365000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>modish</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1983</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the links&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/328"&gt;@KatherineKenneally&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;! I'm already part of these groups &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-community-members/m-p/14192990#M10320"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:59:14.365000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-add-business-processes-folder-into-development-branch-in-solution/qaq-p/14192992</id>
    <title>Cannot add Business Processes Folder into Development Branch in Solution Documentation.</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:59:28.980000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Steve_Tieman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1500663</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am working to add a business process to the Development Branch of SMD; however, there does not seem to be a way to do that.&amp;nbsp; The structures in the Maintenance Branch are working as expected.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-add-business-processes-folder-into-development-branch-in-solution/qaq-p/14192992"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:59:28.980000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/b2b-outbound-idoc-to-as2-connection-reset-issue/qaa-p/14192994#M4924146</id>
    <title>Re: B2B Outbound Idoc to AS2 – Connection Reset Issue</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:00:24.483000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EDIGURU</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1741139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I have the same issue / error message with my connection to a AS2 server.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/b2b-outbound-idoc-to-as2-connection-reset-issue/qaa-p/14192994#M4924146"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:00:24.483000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/production-process/qaa-p/14192998#M254004</id>
    <title>Re: Production process</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:02:40.540000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Angel,thank you for your feedback,Glad the issue is solved</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/production-process/qaa-p/14192998#M254004"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:02:40.540000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/b2b-outbound-idoc-to-as2-connection-reset-issue/qaa-p/14192999#M4924147</id>
    <title>Re: B2B Outbound Idoc to AS2 – Connection Reset Issue</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:03:50.634000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EDIGURU</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1741139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I have the same issue / error message with my connection to a AS2 server. All the ports are open but nothing is coming out of SAPPO to the port. I pick up with the sFTP adapter in a flow with no translations and send to a AS2 receiver. It appears the sFTP is trying to pass to the JCA adapter but isn't that still sFTP though.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/b2b-outbound-idoc-to-as2-connection-reset-issue/qaa-p/14192999#M4924147"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:03:50.634000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-ui5-pdfviewer-with-flag-istrustedsource-true-gives-error/qaq-p/14193001</id>
    <title>SAP UI5: PDFViewer with flag isTrustedSource=true gives error</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:05:23.348000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Floatjitsu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/162078</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we have an application which uses PDFViewer with the property isTrustedSource="true". However the PDF does not load, instead I can see an error in the console saying "Error: Underlying iframe was not found in DOM.".&amp;nbsp; The application is running inside a Launchpad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I already searched the forums, everyone is suggesting setting isTrustedSource to true, which we did. However the error is showing. Is there another cause which I can take a look at?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-ui5-pdfviewer-with-flag-istrustedsource-true-gives-error/qaq-p/14193001"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:05:23.348000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/successfactors-employee-central-hcm-certification/qaq-p/14193002</id>
    <title>SuccessFactors Employee Central HCM Certification</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:05:25.043000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>j0henley2691</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2194633</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Where do I find the curriculum and cost to obtain my SAP&amp;nbsp;SuccessFactors Employee Central HCM Certification?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/successfactors-employee-central-hcm-certification/qaq-p/14193002"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:05:25.043000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-s4-hana-cloud-public-j78-cash-flow-reconciliation/qaa-p/14193003#M254005</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S4/HANA Cloud Public J78 Cash Flow reconciliation</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:06:07.463000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>flombardo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2192186</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hi,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;This is not an answer but more insight provided in the absence of Reka.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please, find more details below in the application of the &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;J78 test script&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The user ID is : CB9980000022&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Perform a Cash flow reconciliation :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Client needs to use the manual Cash Flow reconciliation, so we applied the J78 test script to do so and used the app “Reconcile cash flow”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The process specifies that we need a bank statement flow and a memo record.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First, in the Reprocess bank statement app you can see there are many bank statements, but these items don’t appear in the reconcile cash flow app :&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_3-1756219998895.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305185iF40DBE1F56AEA1DB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_3-1756219998895.png" alt="flombardo_3-1756219998895.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So we created a memo record to make sure there is at least one :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we used the "&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage Memo Records "&amp;nbsp;app.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_2-1756219927545.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305184i50F1B4D274684187/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_2-1756219927545.png" alt="flombardo_2-1756219927545.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The credit memo displayed properly on the right table :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_4-1756220152533.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305187iE529F0A6F05927EE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_4-1756220152533.png" alt="flombardo_4-1756220152533.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The memo record appears in the intraday cash flow reconciliation, however, I didn’t have the left part and could not perform any reconciliation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So we called the app&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;STRONG&gt;Reconcile cash flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chose "Adapt Filters if selection fields are hidden".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Made the following entries and chose Go:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Value Date: &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;lt;current date&amp;gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Exchange Rate Type: &lt;STRONG&gt;M&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reconciliation Profile: &lt;STRONG&gt;EOD_PROF/INTRA_PROF&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Company Code: &lt;STRONG&gt;DE0&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bank Account: For example, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://my419598.s4hana.cloud.sap/ui" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;221597028&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No pending reconciliation appeared :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_6-1756220464870.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305190i19C304D609FCBB72/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_6-1756220464870.png" alt="flombardo_6-1756220464870.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;when clearing the filter "reconciliation status", two records appear but still not the one expected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_7-1756220729238.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305191iDC03EFDC6C070067/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_7-1756220729238.png" alt="flombardo_7-1756220729238.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does anyone have an idea about what we dis wrong?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-s4-hana-cloud-public-j78-cash-flow-reconciliation/qaa-p/14193003#M254005"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:06:07.463000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-build-issues-with-s-4-hana-attachments-for-controlling-documents/qaq-p/14193004</id>
    <title>SAP Build Issues with S/4 HANA Attachments for Controlling Documents</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:07:02.621000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DustinJonesKYN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2119711</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We've found a potential bug with the SAP Build attachments process with S/4 HANA (version 2020).&amp;nbsp; When we use the POST AttachmentContentSet method for accounting documents (BusinessObjectType = BKPF) we are able to see the attachments after the process runs.&amp;nbsp; We check them in SAP GUI or Fiori.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, when we attempt to use the same method with FIN Controlling documents (BusinessObjectType = BUS2072), we are only able to see the attachments in SAP GUI or Fiori if someone creates an attachment through the GUI or Fiori first.&amp;nbsp; If no attachment is created through the GUI or Fiori, the attachments created by SAP Build through the POST AttachmentContentSet method are not visible in the GUI or Fiori.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;MS Copilot reports that this is because there is no&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;!-- ScriptorStartFragment --&gt;BINARY_RELATION_CREATE_COMMIT with BusinessObjectType = BUS2072, but there is with BusinessObjectType = BKPF.&amp;nbsp; While I cannot confirm this, I was hoping an expert in the community might be able to confirm if this is a bug?&lt;!-- ScriptorEndFragment --&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-build-issues-with-s-4-hana-attachments-for-controlling-documents/qaq-p/14193004"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:07:02.621000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/install-sap-build-process-automation-desktop-agent-for-macos/qaq-p/14193005</id>
    <title>Install SAP build process automation desktop agent for macOS</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:07:09.250000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>juanesteban_marriaga</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/202540</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I want to install desktop agent for macOS but I can't find a way to get the installer. I've followed instructions in SAP help (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-process-automation/sap-build-process-automation/install-macos-agent-3?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/build-process-automation/sap-build-process-automation/install-macos-agent-3?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt;) but the installer doesn't appear on the download page of build process automation -&amp;gt; control tower -&amp;gt; agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Captura de pantalla 2025-08-26 a la(s) 9.57.47 a.m..png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305188iB422DCF20FA045C1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Captura de pantalla 2025-08-26 a la(s) 9.57.47 a.m..png" alt="Captura de pantalla 2025-08-26 a la(s) 9.57.47 a.m..png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am working on a BTP trial account, macOS version Sequoia 15.6.1, chip Apple M3 max.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I appreciate any help you can give me.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/install-sap-build-process-automation-desktop-agent-for-macos/qaq-p/14193005"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:07:09.250000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/how-to-create-a-user-group-with-limited-permissions-in-sap-customer-data/qaq-p/14193006</id>
    <title>How to create a user group with limited permissions in SAP Customer Data Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:07:16.392000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stefaniaZ</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/141529</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I need to create a user group with limited permissions in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Customer Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The requirements are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The user group should be able to &lt;STRONG&gt;view registered users&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;edit their profile data&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The user group should also be able to &lt;STRONG&gt;edit the email templates&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the user management part, I was able to configure the permissions successfully. However, for the &lt;STRONG&gt;email template editing&lt;/STRONG&gt;, I am not sure which permissions need to be assigned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I even tried granting &lt;STRONG&gt;all available permissions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but I still receive an error when attempting to edit the templates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could anyone provide guidance on which exact role or permission setup is required for this use case?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stefania&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/how-to-create-a-user-group-with-limited-permissions-in-sap-customer-data/qaq-p/14193006"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:07:16.392000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/gurugram-blog-posts/sap-tech-night-in-gurgaon-friday-5th-september-2025/bc-p/14193009#M86</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Tech Night in Gurgaon - Friday, 5th September 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:11:39.651000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vaibhavkansal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125148</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great initiative&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140633"&gt;@ravigrover&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, Lets catch-up on&amp;nbsp; Sep 5.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/gurugram-blog-posts/sap-tech-night-in-gurgaon-friday-5th-september-2025/bc-p/14193009#M86"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:11:39.651000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-for-sap-s-4hana-updated-moving-from-standalone-to-embedded/bc-p/14193011#M184049</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Fiori for SAP S/4HANA – [Updated] Moving from Standalone to Embedded Deployment in SAP Fiori</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:16:54.076000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>frederic_happ</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/776328</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Important to know (and unfortunately, this took several days of self-study and support from SAP): Transporting the catalogs from the standalone Fiori server to the embedded backend system is language-dependent! In other words, despite successfully exporting the catalogs to the backend system, none of the exported catalogs and groups were displayed in the target system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"While there are xxx FLP relevant CUST Webdynpro component configurations in table WDY_CONF_USER, only for y of them, there are entries in table WDY_CONF_USERT. FLP cannot work with WDY_CONF_USER entries not having at least one corresponding WDY_CONF_USERT entry.&amp;nbsp; The transports WDY_CONF_USER keys are all English but entries in WDY_CONF_USERT are in German.&amp;nbsp;You may create the transports again when having logged in in German."&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-for-sap-s-4hana-updated-moving-from-standalone-to-embedded/bc-p/14193011#M184049"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:16:54.076000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/is-there-a-quot-dark-mode-quot-for-sap-community-pages/qaa-p/14193012#M62010</id>
    <title>Re: Is there a "Dark Mode" for SAP Community pages</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:17:36.965000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MateuszAdamus</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/205384</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you for letting me know &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36"&gt;@AnnePetteroe&lt;/a&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/is-there-a-quot-dark-mode-quot-for-sap-community-pages/qaa-p/14193012#M62010"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:17:36.965000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/new-tables-of-tax-for-portugal-irs-to-be-applied-in-august-and-october/bc-p/14193015#M61620</id>
    <title>Re: New tables of tax for Portugal- IRS to be applied in August and October</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:19:12.208000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pmapinto</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/859117</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Boa tarde Henrique,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Criei o Case&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;976633/2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Obrigado&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/new-tables-of-tax-for-portugal-irs-to-be-applied-in-august-and-october/bc-p/14193015#M61620"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:19:12.208000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193021#M4924149</id>
    <title>Re: Seeing "Bad Installation" error while loading the ret...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:21:29.966000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ayman_salem</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/254691</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Ensure the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;sl_sdk.jar&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;file is added to your project Libraries.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;• Verify that the&amp;nbsp; -&lt;SPAN&gt;Dbusinessobjects.connectivity.directory&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;is correctly set as follows:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; -Dbusinessobjects.connectivity.directory=&lt;STRONG&gt;"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;lt;bip-install-dir&amp;gt;\SAP BusinessObjects Enterprise XI 4.0\dataAccess\connectionServer&lt;STRONG&gt;"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;• Confirm that your client is properly configured to access the database defined in the connection.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;• Make sure the Connection Server binaries directory is included in your system PATH environment variable.&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;set PATH=&amp;lt;bip-install-dir&amp;gt;\SAP BusinessObjects Enterprise XI 4.0\win64_x86;%path%&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;...&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;hope that helps!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193021#M4924149"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:21:29.966000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14193023</id>
    <title>Solution Order Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:24:51.592000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Greg_Hutcheon1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131650</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Welcome to the 2508 update for everyone looking to grow their revenues with solution-based business models&amp;nbsp; powered by SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition! As always, there’s a lot to get excited about with this release of the cloud ERP and you can &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/highlights-of-the-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-release/ba-p/14163726" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;find out about a few of the spotlight features from head of Cloud ERP Product Success Bert Schulze&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. In this blog we’ll zoom in on new features in the Solution Order Management area which you can put straight into use to grow your solution selling prowess.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you’re short on time, my AI alter-ego gives a quick summary of the key highlights in the below video….&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_9n6b9c6j" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let's dive into the details of each feature.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introducing Service Bundles in Solution Orders&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/advanced-solution-bundling-for-solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/13779621" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution bundles&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; have been supported since 2024, enabling the sale of pre-defined stand-alone packages which consist of a mixture of multiple item types, such as physical goods, services and subscription products. With 2502, we expanded on this capability more with the introduction of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2502/ba-p/14017340" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;bundle pricing for greater flexibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and now in 2508, we again grow the bundle selling capability of Solution Order Management by supporting Service Bundles. From this release, users can benefit from the inclusion of service bundles, either with a fixed-price or time-and-material service bundles, in their solution orders.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By selling pre-defined packages that can be automatically exploded into their individual components, you not only reduce manual maintenance effort but also minimize the risk of input errors. These service bundles offer robust capabilities similar to a standard service order, including contract determination, price calculation, and more. Once you release a service bundle—or a broader solution bundle containing one—the system automatically generates the corresponding follow-up service order, streamlining the entire fulfilment process from delivery of products to executing the service.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_ug72qy8p" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Flexible Quantity for Subscription Billing Items&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A key facet of solution orders is the ability to sell subscriptions alongside further item types in a single solution order. However, a significant limitation in previous releases was the inability to specify a quantity greater than one for subscription-based items in a solution order. If a customer wished to purchase 20 licenses for 20 different pieces of equipment in a solution order, the highly inefficient process of creating 20 separate subscription line items was required to record and bill corresponding usage data. This not only created excessive manual data entry but also resulted in bloated order documents and complex reporting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the 2508 release, we address this operational bottleneck. Within the `Manage Solution Orders` app, the quantity field for any line item categorized for subscription billing is no longer restricted. Users can now simply enter the desired quantity—for instance, 20—in a single line item. In the item view, you’ll see both the aggregated net price for all subscriptions in that item and a detailed breakdown for each individual subscription. Managing them is easier than ever, too: every generated subscription is clearly listed in the transaction history and fully visible in the progress monitor, so you can track execution from order entry through fulfillment with complete transparency. This simple yet critical change radically streamlines the sales process for multi-unit subscriptions and reduces the potential for data entry errors.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_8gp6ju5a" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution Bundle Pricing for Subscription Products&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whilst we’re on the subject of subscriptions, another key feature being rolled out with the 2508 builds on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2502/ba-p/14017340" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;bundle pricing functionality linked above&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. With this release, we now support subscription products with bundle specific pricing meaning subscription products can now have special bundle-specific prices maintained directly in your Subscription Billing tenant, based on solution bundle information. Using the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage Lookup Table Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; app in master data, you can define tailored pricing for subscription items sold as part of a bundle and easily compare it to the price of the same product sold standalone. This flexibility lets you create more attractive offers that encourage customers to choose bundled solutions—driving higher revenue for your solution business. When you release a solution order containing a bundle, the follow-up subscription is generated automatically, with the bundle ID retained for accurate pricing application and easy tracking throughout the subscription lifecycle.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_j061qlkz" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Flexible determination of dates in solution order processing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With 2508, we have enhanced the flexibility of solution selling by enabling the adjustment of certain date parameters in a solution order.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;In many industries, particularly those with long sales cycles or international operations, a single order date is insufficient. For example, a contract might be signed in one fiscal period, but delivery and invoicing occur in the next, requiring a different posting date for accurate operational reporting. Similarly, pricing might be fixed based on a promotional period that has already passed, or a customer may request a specific future delivery date that dictates logistics planning. Without the ability to set these dates independently, organizations resort to manual overrides or complex workarounds which could introduce a higher risk of errors in revenue recognition, customer billing, and supply chain execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With this in mind, we’ve enabled more flexible date entry within the `Manage Solution Orders` application. Users can now explicitly set and manage several key dates at the solution order header level and under the new enhanced date profile on the sales item level.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Posting Date: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Used for reporting and search purposes in the solution order.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pricing Date: Determines the exact date for which price conditions, exchange rates, and taxes are applied, allowing for precise control over contract profitability&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Billing Date: Sets the baseline date for generating billing documents, providing flexibility in scheduling customer invoices.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Requested Delivery Date: The date communicated by the customer for when goods or services should be received. This date is now a primary input for the Available-to-Promise (ATP) check and subsequent delivery scheduling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This granularity ensures that each downstream process—from logistics to finance—is driven by the correct temporal data, leading to greater accuracy and process automation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2508_datefields.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305195i7FF136F807B61A7B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2508_datefields.png" alt="2508_datefields.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tolerant Handling of Incomplete Sales Orders: Incompleteness Checks for Sales Orders from &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution Orders&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By using sales order type OR, you can create sales orders directly from a solution order even when some mandatory information is missing, thanks to built-in incompleteness checks. This means follow-up documents can still be generated, while the system flags any missing data for review. In the progress monitor, these sales orders appear in a distinct red status, making it clear that action is needed. Incompleteness procedures help you identify and address gaps before further processing, and any orders with incomplete information are clearly listed in the SAP Fiori app “List Incomplete Sales Documents”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2508_incompletenessChecks.png" style="width: 816px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305193iE2CBCD2819CC8AF8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2508_incompletenessChecks.png" alt="2508_incompletenessChecks.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Contract Accounts Supported for Service Contract Items&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the 2508 release, service contract items in Solution Order Management now support FI-CA (Contract Accounts Receivable and Payable)—a specialized subledger for high-volume billing and receivables. Building on functionality first introduced in 2502 for sales and subscription items, contract accounts can be maintained at both header and item levels, transferred to follow-up documents on release, and posted directly to FI-CA for streamlined invoicing, payment handling, and financial tracking. This integration centralizes financial data, improves billing accuracy, and provides a clear, consolidated view of customer transactions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pricing Analysis in Solution Orders&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the 2508 release of Solution Order Management, a new price analysis capability makes it easier than ever to verify that pricing has been executed correctly on sales order items, service order items, and service contract items. A newly added Analyze button in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Price Details&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; view lets you drill down into a comprehensive price breakdown for each solution order item, with full visibility into how each price condition was determined. This gives you greater transparency, control, and confidence in your pricing—right where you need it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2508_PricingAnalysis.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305192i2DC3D8D96DFC5076/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2508_PricingAnalysis.png" alt="2508_PricingAnalysis.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Partner data enabled on item level for sales items&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A solution sale can often involve multiple stakeholders. With this in mind, in 2508, we enable the partner determination procedure `SAI00003` for sales item categories within solution orders. This enhancement allows users to navigate to any sales line item in the `Manage Solution Orders` app and specify unique partner functions. You can now have one line item with a specific ship-to party and end-user, and another line item within the same order with completely different partners. This information then flows seamlessly to all follow-up documents generated from the solution order, ensuring that deliveries are routed to the correct addresses and invoices are sent to the appropriate contacts, all while maintaining the integrity of the single, comprehensive solution order.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution Order Management OData API V4 Enhancements&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the previous release, we introduced the enhanced solution order OData V4 API. This updated API optimizes communication, reduces data transfer payloads, and enhances request handling for faster processing and lower resource use, leading to quicker response times and a better user experience. It supports full CRUD operations for managing solution order items, so with 2508 we have expanded its scope to include the new functions described above, including subscription items with greater quantities, and service bundles. Importantly, we have rounded-off the ability to create a solution order touch-free by now supporting subscription billing items via the API operations, enabling specialists to generate solution orders entirely via API containing all possible item types. Additionally, it is easier to identify the documents created from the solution order for further processing and set this up without manual intervention.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A further API enhancement we are excited to introduce with this release enables you to simulate a solution order in an external quotation system to get accurate and up-to-date values. This is a big step towards more seamless order entry, enabling customers to generate quotes with minimal revisions, delivering a faster turn-around time for quotation conversion and order fulfilment. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2508_API_Simu.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305194i8FEEC4BA8F339AE3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2508_API_Simu.png" alt="2508_API_Simu.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1276484453" id="toc-hId-1609673706"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;If you are interested in the latest and greatest blog posts on Manufacturing, please have a look at my&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-the/ba-p/13627530" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;collection blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and also take a look at the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud/solution-business" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;community page for solution business.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1756221650040.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305196i3659EA0C62E8FC3E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1756221650040.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1756221650040.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the Replays of Our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;  &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From July 21 to July 25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for Enterprise Portfolio and Project Management as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– anywhere, anytime.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1756221650043.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305197i5785B72CB3839359/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1756221650043.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1756221650043.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find All of Our Assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;  &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1756221650040.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305198i12870BB66CD356E4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1756221650040.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1756221650040.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14193023"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:24:51.592000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/successfactors-employee-central-hcm-certification/qaa-p/14193024#M46470</id>
    <title>Re: SuccessFactors Employee Central HCM Certification</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:28:11.508000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>paddykoltsaklis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/37649</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You should be able to find all that information via the SAP Learning link below. That should allow you to search courses and details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/my-learning/certifications" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/my-learning/certifications&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You should also be able to purchase a license through there as well as you will need that to be able to access the courses and get exam attempts.&amp;nbsp; I think you can get either (2) or (4) attempts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this helps. Good luck with the certification!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/successfactors-employee-central-hcm-certification/qaa-p/14193024#M46470"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:28:11.508000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/manual-bank-reconciliation-start-to-end-to-process-in-sap-public-cloud/qaa-p/14193025#M254007</id>
    <title>Re: Manual Bank Reconciliation Start to End to Process in...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:31:11.824000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DilanLatifSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235274</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1764273"&gt;@TAMS1&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manual bank statements&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP S/4HANA Cloud are created directly in the system using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Bank Statements&lt;/STRONG&gt; app when electronic statements are unavailable or unsupported. Instead of importing files, users enter the data manually or upload it using a &lt;STRONG&gt;spreadsheet template&lt;/STRONG&gt; provided within the app to streamline the process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to go through the end-to-end process for performing manual bank reconciliation, check the following SAP Help links&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more about the difference between a manually created and an electronically created bank statement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/918bca53037f408f91a2295d04ac16bc/b5d81b1c737247f9887d3db456938fbc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manual vs. Electronic Bank Statements | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read here for step-by-step instructions to create a manual bank statement via a spreadsheet template.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/918bca53037f408f91a2295d04ac16bc/e1023a10330847c0b04561c40f7dfe26.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;How to Upload Bank Statements with a Spreadsheet File | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here for clearing process in AR accounting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/918bca53037f408f91a2295d04ac16bc/a21af993466648b994144cdd15ab1a39.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Clearing Process | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you need more information or further details, please let me know.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you and BR&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dilan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/manual-bank-reconciliation-start-to-end-to-process-in-sap-public-cloud/qaa-p/14193025#M254007"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:31:11.824000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/real-time-payment-in-sap-business-bydesign/qaq-p/14193026</id>
    <title>Real Time Payment in SAP Business ByDesign</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:31:53.917000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tA41</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1407950</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;With real-time transfers, also known as instant payments, transfers can be made within seconds. Following the switch to the SEPA transfer procedure, cashless payments in Europe have been further accelerated.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;How can we create automatic payments with real-time-transfers in SAP Business ByDesign?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/real-time-payment-in-sap-business-bydesign/qaq-p/14193026"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:31:53.917000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193033#M4924150</id>
    <title>Re: Seeing "Bad Installation" error while loading the ret...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:40:04.287000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sanjay_thiyagarajan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2234935</uri>
    </author>
    <content>If I add sl_sdk.jar, this error is thrown: Caused by: java.lang.SecurityException: class "org.eclipse.core.runtime.IExtensionPoint"'s signer information does not match signer information of other classes in the same package</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193033#M4924150"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:40:04.287000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/an-invalid-xml-character-was-found-in-the-value-of-attribute-quot/qaa-p/14193041#M4924151</id>
    <title>Re: An invalid XML character was found in the value of at...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:42:13.176000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ayman_salem</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/254691</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;You can update the defect object's description using BO SL_SDK and Java.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/an-invalid-xml-character-was-found-in-the-value-of-attribute-quot/qaa-p/14193041#M4924151"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:42:13.176000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/j58-accounting-and-financial-close-run-foreign-trade-regulation-z4-report/qaa-p/14193044#M254012</id>
    <title>Re: J58 Accounting and Financial close - Run Foreign Trad...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:44:51.326000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>flombardo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2192186</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, this is not an answer but more details provided in the absence of Reka :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;J58 test script&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The user ID :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CB9980000022&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Balance Sheet Validation results :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First, we have run the Schedule Balance Validation Jobs - G/L Accounting app and Chose Create.&lt;BR /&gt;we performed the below entries and chose "step 2":&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/* Job Template: &lt;STRONG&gt;Balance Validation for G/L Accounting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Job Name: &lt;STRONG&gt;Balance Validation for G/L Accounting&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Make the following entries and choose Step 3:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start Immediately: &lt;STRONG&gt;Selected&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Make the following entries and choose Schedule:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Rule Group: &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;lt;rule group&amp;gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ledger: &lt;STRONG&gt;0L&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Currency: &lt;STRONG&gt;EUR&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiscal Year: &lt;STRONG&gt;2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiscal Period: &lt;STRONG&gt;7&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;*/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open the app:&lt;STRONG&gt; View Balance Validation Results&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;performed the following entries and chose Go:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/*Company Code: &lt;STRONG&gt;DE0&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ledger: &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;lt;ledger you used in prior step&amp;gt;. &amp;nbsp; */&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We then entered the additional required filtered.&lt;BR /&gt;Clicked anywhere in the row for one of the job results.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Rules that ran successfully are hidden by default. In the Result filter above the Result pane, chose the "Success" checkbox to view rules that ran successfully.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For one of the rows, I chose &amp;gt; (Details) at the right of the row and then "Back", which gave me the below result :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_0-1756222670722.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305199i3475B1D8F878B3B4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_0-1756222670722.png" alt="flombardo_0-1756222670722.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Comparing with the results in the BS/Income statement app :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_1-1756222772186.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305200iA335A1836505FCE9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_1-1756222772186.png" alt="flombardo_1-1756222772186.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result is different and cannot find the root cause.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We have checked the Balance validation rules and group app – here the standard GL hierarchy is FSV 1799.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The FSV 1799 wasn’t in the system so we copied an existing FSV and created the 1799 USA Financial statement version&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In the test script there is a note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Caution&lt;/SPAN&gt; Sample rules and groups using Financial Statement Version (FSV) 1799 are defined and attached to SAP Note &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3322100" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3322100&lt;/A&gt;. If you are using that FSV, you can download the file from the note and upload it using this procedure. If you use a different FSV for your country/region, you can either import the rules and change the values before you activate, or create your own testing rules from scratch using the guidance in the next note.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I have downloaded the attachment excel file from SAP page and uploaded it o our system, based on the uploaded rules in excel and the newly created FSV1799, we still weren’t able to create the balance validation results, the faild status appeared again.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since we are working in the German DE0 company code, we also tried to use the German FSV, DE99, however, here we got an error about &lt;STRONG&gt;contra node.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Could you please tell me what a contra node is and how to fix this issue?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_2-1756222908335.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305201i9652CA503A2EDB68/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_2-1756222908335.png" alt="flombardo_2-1756222908335.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarize, we could not find the root cause of the issue. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We do believe that the setup is good, having thoroughly followed the process. Still, it somehow still does not work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Can you please help us?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/j58-accounting-and-financial-close-run-foreign-trade-regulation-z4-report/qaa-p/14193044#M254012"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:44:51.326000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-solution-manager-charm-charm-customizing-inserting-new-user-status/qaa-p/14193049#M4924152</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Solution Manager - ChaRM - ChaRM Customizing: Ins...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:48:33.185000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dave_S30</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/201476</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;A partial answer, which I hope is helpful …&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The status number, lowest, and highest, represent the sequence in which the status values are displayed, and the range within the next status value can be set.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, 70, Test Successful in Pre-Prod, appears after 60, Imported to Pre-Prod, and before 80, Authorized for Import to Production. Also, when the document has status 70, it can only be set to a new status between 60 and 80 (inclusive).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What these values should be for the new user status will depend on the use case. Or put another way, if the status is "SIT testing is approved", what can the next user status be?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sorry, I don’t have answers for the other columns (Status and Transaction); although I do remember “FINI” marks a final status, after which the document can no longer be changed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If I’ve misstated anything, please feel free to post a correction.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-solution-manager-charm-charm-customizing-inserting-new-user-status/qaa-p/14193049#M4924152"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:48:33.185000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-track-the-person-responsible-or-custodian-of-the-asset-in-sap-s4hana/qaa-p/14193053#M4224307</id>
    <title>Re: How to track the person responsible or custodian of t...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:51:25.858000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1439309"&gt;@nithin_pranesh&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can effortlessly connect S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition with SuccessFactors using SAP’s ready-made scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Workforce data (employees) flows from EC to S/4HANA through Master Data Integration (MDI).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost centers flow from S/4HANA to EC so that HR can assign them.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you use Employee Central Payroll, payroll postings are transferred from ECP to S/4HANA Finance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;No custom coding is required; simply activate the communication setup, connect via MDI, and run the test flows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Here's some helpful SAP Documentation for your references.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/53e36b5493804bcdb3f6f14de8b487dd/d19821fecf514ff591deff3fa224902d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help – Integrating SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central with SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central-integration-to-business-suite/replicating-cost-centers-from-sap-s-4hana-on-premise-to-employee-central/introduction-to-cost-center-replication" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help – Cost Center Integration between S/4HANA Cloud and SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/6b39bd1d0e5e4099a5b65d835c29c696/25d820f179854df1ac53c0dd50fb1c12.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help – Integration with SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central Payroll&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-track-the-person-responsible-or-custodian-of-the-asset-in-sap-s4hana/qaa-p/14193053#M4224307"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:51:25.858000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/white-space-begone-new-pilot-removes-widgets-column-from-blog-posts/bc-p/14193055#M773</id>
    <title>Re: White Space, Begone! New Pilot Removes Widgets Column from Blog Posts</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:51:55.279000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe_Lima</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Having a hide/show option would be the best approach.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/white-space-begone-new-pilot-removes-widgets-column-from-blog-posts/bc-p/14193055#M773"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:51:55.279000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%81%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%82-%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AB%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14193057#M254015</id>
    <title>Re: कुकू एफएम से पैसे कैसे वापस करें?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:52:40.797000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>raju58277722khan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242615</uri>
    </author>
    <content>इसके लिए आपको ™Kuku Fm™ टोल फ्री नंबर 00,9279✓607—325पर कॉल करना होगा। कुकू एफएम से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं. इसके लिए आपको ™Kuku Fm™ टोल फ्री नंबर (08084—541✓543/*+} पर कॉल करना होगा।</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%81%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%82-%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AB%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14193057#M254015"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:52:40.797000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193058#M4924153</id>
    <title>Re: Seeing "Bad Installation" error while loading the ret...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:52:54.531000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ayman_salem</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/254691</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Ensure that sl_sdk.jar is referenced from the SL_SDK directory, since it retrieves its classes from the eclipse directory nested under SL_SDK</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193058#M4924153"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:52:54.531000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/dynamic-mass-upload-report-on-month-amp-year/qaa-p/14193061#M4924154</id>
    <title>Re: Dynamic Report</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:54:41.615000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SanketGode45</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1859849</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348"&gt;@Lakshmipathi&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;As I was working on this requirement, I initially found it a bit confusing to implement. However, I’ve now understood the approach and I have explained the steps I followed along with the code I used.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/dynamic-mass-upload-report-on-month-amp-year/qaa-p/14193061#M4924154"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:54:41.615000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193064#M4924155</id>
    <title>Re: Seeing "Bad Installation" error while loading the ret...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:57:15.117000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sanjay_thiyagarajan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2234935</uri>
    </author>
    <content>My path looks like this - C:\Users\username\Downloads\SL SDK\java\sl_sdk.jar</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193064#M4924155"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:57:15.117000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/create-custom-tab-with-custom-controller-in-business-partner-in-general/qaa-p/14193065#M4924156</id>
    <title>Re: create custom tab with Custom Controller in Business...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:57:55.815000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;This issue typically falls under the &lt;STRONG&gt;technical development team&lt;/STRONG&gt; with expertise in:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;BDT framework&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Business Partner enhancements&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Screen programming (dynpro)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Function group and controller logic&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;To ensure your custom tab functions reliably in &lt;STRONG&gt;BDT&lt;/STRONG&gt; transactions, please follow these key steps:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Explicitly Assign Your Screen in BDT Configuration &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Use transaction BUS3 or BUS4 to assign your screen number directly to the relevant view. This prevents SAP from auto-generating a screen (e.g., 7002) which can cause runtime errors or data inconsistencies.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Create Your Screen Manually via SE80 or SE51 &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Avoid relying on BUPT to generate screens. Instead, manually create your screen using SE80/SE51 to maintain control over its layout and logic. Recommended screen numbers: 1000–1999 or 5000–5999.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Avoid Using BUPT for Screen Creation &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;While BUPT is useful for configuration, using it to create screens can lead to unexpected overrides or auto-generated screens that conflict with your setup.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Following these steps ensures your custom tab integrates smoothly with the BDT framework and avoids common pitfalls.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Again, if you are a Functional Consultant, take the help of your technical team who is responsible to carry out the above activities.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/create-custom-tab-with-custom-controller-in-business-partner-in-general/qaa-p/14193065#M4924156"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:57:55.815000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193071#M4924157</id>
    <title>Re: Seeing "Bad Installation" error while loading the ret...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:59:45.501000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sanjay_thiyagarajan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2234935</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Adding to that, I have actually added as many JARs as I can find since there was no definite list anywhere on which JARs are specifically needed. Is it logical to suspect that some could conflict ? If so, do you by any chance have that specific list of JARs needed ?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193071#M4924157"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:59:45.501000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/payment-block-on-down-payment-not-automatically-removed-even-after-linked/qaq-p/14193080</id>
    <title>Payment block on down payment not automatically removed even after linked with Vendor Invoice</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:02:42.893000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vidhya3</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1557477</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Payment block "A" is not removed automatically on the down payment even after the Vendor invoice has been linked.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/payment-block-on-down-payment-not-automatically-removed-even-after-linked/qaq-p/14193080"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:02:42.893000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-s4hana-cloud-public-j59-ar-manage-payment-advice-notifications/qaa-p/14193081#M254019</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S4HANA Cloud Public, J59- AR: Manage Payment Advi...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:03:45.491000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>flombardo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2192186</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, in the absence of Reka, please, find below the process we followed :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;J59 test script&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;User ID :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CB9980000022&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Payment advice notifications :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We followed the setup script thoroughly : The scope item&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;31N is activated&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the app &amp;nbsp;"manage situation types", We chose&amp;nbsp; the "payment advice invoice skipped and enabled"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_0-1756223620788.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305202i097E2427160FBA12/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_0-1756223620788.png" alt="flombardo_0-1756223620788.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Being the Accounting Clerk, notifications should notify me back.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;invoices: using the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;app: "Create outgoing invoices", I can find the document&amp;nbsp;no: 1800000025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;payment advice&lt;/STRONG&gt;: using the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;app "Manage payment advices", I can see it too :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Payment advice created with 600 EUR, invoice amount 1000 EUR&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_1-1756223795894.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305203i234A6FCC87B74868/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_1-1756223795894.png" alt="flombardo_1-1756223795894.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_2-1756223972707.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305204i062CEB681B573DF6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_2-1756223972707.png" alt="flombardo_2-1756223972707.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There isn’t any notification by the system.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Everything is set up properly in my settings :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_3-1756224055952.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305205i1EFA171EC1306CB7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_3-1756224055952.png" alt="flombardo_3-1756224055952.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But the tiny little bell never rang...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_4-1756224136273.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305206i43B34808BA525C05/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="flombardo_4-1756224136273.png" alt="flombardo_4-1756224136273.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does anyone have a hint for us ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-s4hana-cloud-public-j59-ar-manage-payment-advice-notifications/qaa-p/14193081#M254019"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:03:45.491000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-s4-hana-cloud-public-j58-financial-close-balance-validation/qaa-p/14193090#M254023</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S4/HANA Cloud Public, J58: Financial close - Bala...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:09:34.317000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>flombardo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2192186</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, this is not an answer but more details provided in the absence of Reka :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;J58 test script&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The user ID :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CB9980000022&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Balance Sheet Validation results :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First, we have run the Schedule Balance Validation Jobs - G/L Accounting app and Chose Create.&lt;BR /&gt;we performed the below entries and chose "step 2":&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/* Job Template: &lt;STRONG&gt;Balance Validation for G/L Accounting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Job Name: &lt;STRONG&gt;Balance Validation for G/L Accounting&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Make the following entries and choose Step 3:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start Immediately: &lt;STRONG&gt;Selected&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Make the following entries and choose Schedule:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Rule Group: &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;lt;rule group&amp;gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ledger: &lt;STRONG&gt;0L&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Currency: &lt;STRONG&gt;EUR&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiscal Year: &lt;STRONG&gt;2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiscal Period: &lt;STRONG&gt;7&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;*/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open the app:&lt;STRONG&gt; View Balance Validation Results&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;performed the following entries and chose Go:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/*Company Code: &lt;STRONG&gt;DE0&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ledger: &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;lt;ledger you used in prior step&amp;gt;. &amp;nbsp; */&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We then entered the additional required filtered.&lt;BR /&gt;Clicked anywhere in the row for one of the job results.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Rules that ran successfully are hidden by default. In the Result filter above the Result pane, chose the "Success" checkbox to view rules that ran successfully.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For one of the rows, I chose &amp;gt; (Details) at the right of the row and then "Back", which gave me the below result :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_0-1756224549407.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305208i98833C090FED4CF7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_0-1756224549407.png" alt="flombardo_0-1756224549407.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Comparing with the results in the BS/Income statement app :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_1-1756224549482.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305209i7DF7D7FC9A02CE45/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_1-1756224549482.png" alt="flombardo_1-1756224549482.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result is different and cannot find the root cause.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We have checked the Balance validation rules and group app – here the standard GL hierarchy is FSV 1799.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The FSV 1799 wasn’t in the system so we copied an existing FSV and created the 1799 USA Financial statement version&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In the test script there is a note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Caution&lt;/SPAN&gt; Sample rules and groups using Financial Statement Version (FSV) 1799 are defined and attached to SAP Note &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3322100" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3322100&lt;/A&gt;. If you are using that FSV, you can download the file from the note and upload it using this procedure. If you use a different FSV for your country/region, you can either import the rules and change the values before you activate, or create your own testing rules from scratch using the guidance in the next note.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I have downloaded the attachment excel file from SAP page and uploaded it o our system, based on the uploaded rules in excel and the newly created FSV1799, we still weren’t able to create the balance validation results, the faild status appeared again.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since we are working in the German DE0 company code, we also tried to use the German FSV, DE99, however, here we got an error about &lt;STRONG&gt;contra node.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Could you please tell me what a contra node is and how to fix this issue?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flombardo_2-1756224549514.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305211i4B6F0F30018E930B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flombardo_2-1756224549514.png" alt="flombardo_2-1756224549514.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarize, we could not find the root cause of the issue. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We do believe that the setup is good, having thoroughly followed the process. Still, it somehow still does not work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Can you please help us?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-s4-hana-cloud-public-j58-financial-close-balance-validation/qaa-p/14193090#M254023"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:09:34.317000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193093#M4924158</id>
    <title>Re: Seeing "Bad Installation" error while loading the ret...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:11:00.829000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sanjay_thiyagarajan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2234935</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I managed to find the problematic JARs (just 2) and removed them. But now it's back to Bad Installation and I still have the sl_sdk.jar imported.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193093#M4924158"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:11:00.829000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193094#M4924159</id>
    <title>Re: Seeing "Bad Installation" error while loading the ret...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:11:05.402000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ayman_salem</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/254691</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Refer to the "BI Semantic Layer Java SDK Developer Guide"—it contains everything you need to work with the SL SDK. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_BUSINESSOBJECTS_BUSINESS_INTELLIGENCE_PLATFORM/4359a0ef221e4a1098bae432bdd982c1/45f210476e041014910aba7db0e91070.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_BUSINESSOBJECTS_BUSINESS_INTELLIGENCE_PLATFORM/4359a0ef221e4a1098bae432bdd982c1/45f210476e041014910aba7db0e91070.html?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193094#M4924159"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:11:05.402000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/payment-block-on-down-payment-not-automatically-removed-even-after-linked/qaa-p/14193098#M4224315</id>
    <title>Re: Payment block on down payment not automatically remov...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:14:32.923000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Some of the possible reasons could be&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If the down payment is linked but not fully cleared (e.g., partial clearing or parked document), the block may persist. Ensure the clearing document is posted and not just simulated or parked.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Verify if the vendor master has a default payment block set under the “Payment Transactions” tab. If so, it may override document-level settings during posting.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Some document types may be configured to retain payment blocks by default. Check if the down payment or invoice document type has any such settings in &lt;STRONG&gt;OBY6&lt;/STRONG&gt; / &lt;STRONG&gt;OBU1&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Perform the below steps to cross-check where the issue is&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Run transaction &lt;STRONG&gt;FBL1N&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the vendor and check the clearing status and document flow.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Review the clearing document in &lt;STRONG&gt;FB03&lt;/STRONG&gt; to confirm if the block was removed or retained.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If needed, manually remove the block in FB02, but only after confirming compliance with your internal controls.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/payment-block-on-down-payment-not-automatically-removed-even-after-linked/qaa-p/14193098#M4224315"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:14:32.923000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sap-ewm-cycle-count-indicator-update-from-erp/qaa-p/14193102#M206509</id>
    <title>Re: SAP EWM cycle count indicator update from ERP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:15:17.571000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EWM_Learner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1974537</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Sandeep,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Did you find any details for the tcode&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;/SCWM/CCIND_MAINTAIN.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;I was expecting there is some way we can collect the CC indicators from s/4 side and fill directly using the tcode.&lt;BR /&gt;please let me know if you find any way.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Amar&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sap-ewm-cycle-count-indicator-update-from-erp/qaa-p/14193102#M206509"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:15:17.571000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/stop-ai-model-disasters-the-application-owner-s-guide-to-bulletproof/bc-p/14193106#M184050</id>
    <title>Re: Stop AI Model Disasters: The Application Owner's Guide to Bulletproof Deployments</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:16:53.496000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>achab</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1357</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Much welcome &amp;amp; insightful blog. Thanks &amp;amp; kudos&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8085"&gt;@HadiHares&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/stop-ai-model-disasters-the-application-owner-s-guide-to-bulletproof/bc-p/14193106#M184050"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:16:53.496000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-synchronize-production-order-dates-back-to-network-activities-nwa-in/qaa-p/14193108#M4224317</id>
    <title>Re: How to Synchronize Production Order Dates Back to Net...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:17:20.735000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/889258"&gt;@mlasya85&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;in Public Cloud, there is no manual process for 'transfer dates.' When a production order is linked to a network activity, changing the date on the order automatically updates the network after saving. You can verify this in the Assignments section of the order and then in Project Control.&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/2bba750d1e124e1ea2a039bb1cd9b6c5/57fcbf5d6d1f484db58a2df42be4f63d.html?q=+Project+Manufacturing+Management+(35E)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help –Strategy for Engineer-to-Order&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-synchronize-production-order-dates-back-to-network-activities-nwa-in/qaa-p/14193108#M4224317"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:17:20.735000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/loan-radar-app-customer-care-helpline-number-7856843256-0785-6843256-all/qaa-p/14193109#M254027</id>
    <title>Re: What is that that that I your life life I</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:17:39.078000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ramukumarkhans64</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2241398</uri>
    </author>
    <content>That that I real name name and the best</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/loan-radar-app-customer-care-helpline-number-7856843256-0785-6843256-all/qaa-p/14193109#M254027"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:17:39.078000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/where-can-i-start-learning-data-integrations-within-sap-digital/ba-p/14193111</id>
    <title>Where can I start learning data integrations within SAP Digital Manufacturing for Insights?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:20:44.805000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Margit_Wagner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;recommend to access our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Enabling Data Integrations within SAP Digital Manufacturing for Insights" href="https://learning.sap.com/preview/learning-journeys/enabling-data-integrations-within-sap-digital-manufacturing-for-insights" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enabling Data Integrations within SAP Digital Manufacturing for Insights&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp; learning journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This learning journey empowers IT professionals with the skills to configure and manage technical data integration across SAP Digital Manufacturing (DM) within key SAP Analytics tools. This includes enabling the embedded SAP Analytics Cloud, establishing a live connection to SAP Datasphere, configuring the OData interface with SAP Analytics Cloud, and integrating manufacturing data into SAP Signavio.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning objectives&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Understand the Manufacturing Data Objects (MDOs) and the underlying data architecture in SAP Digital Manufacturing for Insights (DMi).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable the embedded SAP Analytics Cloud (eSAC) within SAP Digital Manufacturing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Establish a Live Connection between SAP Digital Manufacturing and SAP Datasphere.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Utilize the OData service of SAP Digital Manufacturing for Insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transfer manufacturing data via OData service to SAP Analytics Cloud for advanced analytics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transfer manufacturing data via OData service to SAP Signavio, leveraging its Value Accelerators for process optimization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Basis knowledge of SAP Business Transformation Platform (BTP), SAP Identity Provider, and SAP Analytics Applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please post you question related&amp;nbsp;to the digital learning Journey in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/qa-p/learningqanda-board" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q&amp;amp;A area&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Our SAP Learning Experts will get back to you as soon as possible!&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;We are here to support you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I appreciate your feedback and we will make sure to continue sharing interesting topics.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Kind regards&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Margit&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/where-can-i-start-learning-data-integrations-within-sap-digital/ba-p/14193111"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:20:44.805000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193112#M4924160</id>
    <title>Re: Seeing "Bad Installation" error while loading the ret...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:21:48.013000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ayman_salem</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/254691</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;To set up your environment, copy the entire SL SDK directory from the server to your client, and include only the sl_sdk.jar file in your project's library references. That’s all you need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ayman_salem_0-1756225551079.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305218i88F2F40401049951/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ayman_salem_0-1756225551079.png" alt="ayman_salem_0-1756225551079.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/seeing-quot-bad-installation-quot-error-while-loading-the-retrieved/qaa-p/14193112#M4924160"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:21:48.013000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/automate-pfcg-process/m-p/14193113#M2042377</id>
    <title>Re: Automate PFCG process</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:21:59.699000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dan_spitzig</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/210701</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;To add a transaction to the Role Menu, you can use CL_PFCG_MENU_MODIFY-&amp;gt;MENU_ADD_TRANSACTION.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This will be displayed the user's SAP Menu in SAP GUI.&amp;nbsp; However, I did not want it to appear in the user's SAP Menu in SAP GUI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SOLUTION is to use&amp;nbsp;CL_PFCG_MENU_MODIFY-&amp;gt;MENU_ADD_SERVICE.&amp;nbsp; It works like a charm!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/automate-pfcg-process/m-p/14193113#M2042377"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:21:59.699000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/loan-radar-app-customer-care-helpline-number-7856843256-0785-6843-256-all/qaa-p/14193115#M254029</id>
    <title>Re: That that that I what what I this is a a</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:22:51.306000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ramukumarkhans64</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2241398</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;What what time you know what is not a lot lot and and the way of it I this is that was was&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/loan-radar-app-customer-care-helpline-number-7856843256-0785-6843-256-all/qaa-p/14193115#M254029"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:22:51.306000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/loan-radar-app-customer-care-helpline-number-7856843256-0785-6843-256-all/qaa-p/14193116#M254030</id>
    <title>Re: That that that I what what I this is a a</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:23:10.962000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ramukumarkhans64</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2241398</uri>
    </author>
    <content>This to do that I that that is not my mom said she was the</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/loan-radar-app-customer-care-helpline-number-7856843256-0785-6843-256-all/qaa-p/14193116#M254030"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:23:10.962000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-community-members/m-p/14193117#M10321</id>
    <title>Re: Hello Community members!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:23:59.255000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KatherineKenneally</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/328</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;That's great to hear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1983"&gt;@modish&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;!! Happy engaging!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/hello-community-members/m-p/14193117#M10321"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:23:59.255000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/knowledge-graphs-for-llm-grounding-and-avoiding-hallucination/bc-p/14193122#M184051</id>
    <title>Re: Knowledge graphs for LLM grounding and avoiding hallucination</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:26:03.941000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FelixSasaki</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1384825</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Sorry, but the guidance on this topic is still the same. Connectors also will not change that.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/knowledge-graphs-for-llm-grounding-and-avoiding-hallucination/bc-p/14193122#M184051"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:26:03.941000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/3-dimension-in-1-column/qaa-p/14193125#M62011</id>
    <title>Re: 3 dimension in 1 column</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:28:31.750000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>It's not a "Question about SAP Websites". You may post to Technology Q&amp;amp;A instead (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/qa-p/technology-questions" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/qa-p/technology-questions&lt;/A&gt;).</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/3-dimension-in-1-column/qaa-p/14193125#M62011"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:28:31.750000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/add-franklincovey-courses-to-learning/qaa-p/14193127#M46471</id>
    <title>Re: Add FranklinCovey Courses to Learning</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:30:46.130000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PL1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1916069"&gt;@evanbrough&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;here you can find a table mentioning if the field is required, along with a description of it:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-learning/importing-courses-with-learning-item-connector/course-item-data-connector-file-columns?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Course (Item) Data Connector File Columns&lt;/A&gt;. Templates can be downloaded via the Learning Administration UI (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-learning/importing-courses-with-learning-item-connector/downloading-learning-connector-templates?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Downloading&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Learning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Connector Templates&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/add-franklincovey-courses-to-learning/qaa-p/14193127#M46471"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:30:46.130000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/send-dunning-letters-to-cpi/qaa-p/14193129#M4224319</id>
    <title>Re: Send Dunning Letters to CPI</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:31:25.739000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Define a &lt;STRONG&gt;custom output type&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Output Parameter Determination. Use &lt;STRONG&gt;BRFplus rules&lt;/STRONG&gt; to trigger this output for dunning documents. Link it to a communication arrangement that sends the payload to CPI (via REST/SOAP). This setup is similar to how outbound delivery documents are routed to CPI in other scenarios.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;On the CPI side, you will design an iFlow that accepts the incoming payload (PDF/XML), optionally transforms or enriches it and routes it to your desired destination (e.g., archive, external system, print service)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In short, you need to build the logic as follows&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Lakshmipathi_0-1756225863297.png" style="width: 355px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305221i34DEB0ED5340EE42/image-dimensions/355x125/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="355" height="125" role="button" title="Lakshmipathi_0-1756225863297.png" alt="Lakshmipathi_0-1756225863297.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/send-dunning-letters-to-cpi/qaa-p/14193129#M4224319"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:31:25.739000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/that-that-that-was-just-want-want-me-a-good-morning-and/qaa-p/14193132#M254032</id>
    <title>Re: That that that was just want want me a good morning and</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:32:05.881000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ramukumarkhans64</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2241398</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;इसके लिए आपको ™Kuku Fm™ टोल फ्री नंबर 0785-6843-256पर कॉल करना होगा। कुकू एफएम से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं. इसके लिए आपको ™Kuku Fm™ टोल फ्री नंबर (078√5684√32,56/*+} पर कॉल करना होगा।Y&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/that-that-that-was-just-want-want-me-a-good-morning-and/qaa-p/14193132#M254032"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:32:05.881000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/prevent-administrator-from-scheduling-a-class-wih-an-instructor-who-is-not/qaa-p/14193151#M46472</id>
    <title>Re: prevent administrator from scheduling a class wih an...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:36:08.051000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PL1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1448673"&gt;@user116&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;the Instructor record could be set to "Inactive" or have its "Security Domain" set to something the Learning Administrator doesn't have access to (in a scenario where permission restrictions are in place). Other than that, I understand it, it'd require an enhancement request (KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2090228" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2090228&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/prevent-administrator-from-scheduling-a-class-wih-an-instructor-who-is-not/qaa-p/14193151#M46472"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:36:08.051000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/polluted-by-many-questions-not-about-sap-websites-in-community-2024/qaa-p/14193152#M62012</id>
    <title>Re: Polluted by many questions NOT about SAP Websites in...</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:36:18.673000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>As of August 2025, I still see many people posting incorrectly to "Questions about SAP Websites". These people will continue to post to any group containing the word "SAP", so that would be great to have one group with the word "SAP" dedicated to people not able or not willing to find an adequate group (to which I wouldn't subscribe), and "Community/KBA", without the word "SAP" (to which I would subscribe).</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/polluted-by-many-questions-not-about-sap-websites-in-community-2024/qaa-p/14193152#M62012"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:36:18.673000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/%E0%A4%AB%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%A8%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14193154</id>
    <title>फोनपे में गलत ट्रांजेक्शन से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:36:28.491000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vvcxx</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2240636</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Phone Pe में गलती से किसी गलत खाते में पैसे ट्रांसफर हो जाने पर, तुरंत Phone Pe ग्राहक सहायता 00709--1011√025से संपर्क करें और अपने बैंक को भी सूचित करें.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/%E0%A4%AB%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%A8%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AE%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14193154"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:36:28.491000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14193158</id>
    <title>पेटीएम गलत ट्रांजेक्शन से पैसे कैसे वापस करें?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:37:15.975000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sahil255khandh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242634</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;इसके लिए आपको `pay Tm™ टोल फ्री पेटीएम ग्राहक सेवा नंबर 00-8084~541÷543 पर कॉल करना होगा। पेटीएम से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं. इसके लिए आपको `PAY tm™ टोल फ्री नंबर {0808_~454÷1543) पर कॉल करना होगा।.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaq-p/14193158"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:37:15.975000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/use-table-order-endpoints-from-sap-customer-checkout-manager-api/qaq-p/14193160</id>
    <title>Use Table Order endpoints from SAP Customer Checkout manager api</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:37:34.100000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RicardoRenteria</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/248336</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I want to use some of the table order endpoints availables in the documentation of CCO Manager&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="RicardoRenteria_0-1756225613039.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305220iA627F370AD8D82F7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="RicardoRenteria_0-1756225613039.png" alt="RicardoRenteria_0-1756225613039.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, when I tried to use them (for example GET opentables, GET tableorder, GET tableareas) I get this message:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;{&lt;/SPAN&gt;  &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"errorCode"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"214011"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;  &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"errorMessage"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"User assignment not found"&lt;/SPAN&gt;
}&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;The user is logged in and has permission allowed on the Table order API&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="RicardoRenteria_1-1756225960502.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305223iB74C396328A10BF9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="RicardoRenteria_1-1756225960502.png" alt="RicardoRenteria_1-1756225960502.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What could be the reason of the error?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot, I appreciate your help.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/use-table-order-endpoints-from-sap-customer-checkout-manager-api/qaq-p/14193160"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:37:34.100000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14193159#M254035</id>
    <title>Re: पेटीएम गलत ट्रांजेक्शन से पैसे कैसे वापस करें?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:37:37.447000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sahil255khandh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242634</uri>
    </author>
    <content>इसके लिए आपको `pay Tm™ टोल फ्री पेटीएम ग्राहक सेवा नंबर 00-8084~541÷543 पर कॉल करना होगा। पेटीएम से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं. इसके लिए आपको `PAY tm™ टोल फ्री नंबर {0808_~454÷1543) पर कॉल करना होगा।.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14193159#M254035"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:37:37.447000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14193161#M254036</id>
    <title>Re: पेटीएम गलत ट्रांजेक्शन से पैसे कैसे वापस करें?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:37:57.469000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sahil255khandh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2242634</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;इसके लिए आपको `pay Tm™ टोल फ्री पेटीएम ग्राहक सेवा नंबर 00-8084~541÷543 पर कॉल करना होगा। पेटीएम से पैसे कैसे वापस पाएं. इसके लिए आपको `PAY tm™ टोल फ्री नंबर {0808_~454÷1543) पर कॉल करना होगा।.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%8F%E0%A4%AE-%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%A4-%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B0%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%B6%E0%A4%A8-%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%AA%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%95%E0%A5%88%E0%A4%B8%E0%A5%87-%E0%A4%B5%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%B8-%E0%A4%95%E0%A4%B0%E0%A5%87%E0%A4%82/qaa-p/14193161#M254036"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:37:57.469000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/documentation-for-ddic-tables-of-the-drc-module/qaa-p/14193166#M254037</id>
    <title>Re: Documentation for DDIC tables of the DRC module</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:39:31.124000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>martin_lehmann4</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/195040</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello Chris, Thank you for your explanation! It is good to know that we are correct in using the identified table SRF_REP_RUN_DATA as the data source for the DRC transaction data. However, we have noticed that, for example, the run ID that appears in the detail view of F1515 is not stored there, nor do we know how this transaction data table is linked to the other DRC master data. Is there any information about this?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/documentation-for-ddic-tables-of-the-drc-module/qaa-p/14193166#M254037"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:39:31.124000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/esocial-nota-t%C3%A9cnica-04-2025-entrega-conclu%C3%ADda-e-pr%C3%B3ximos-passos/ba-p/14193153</id>
    <title>eSocial - Nota Técnica 04/2025: Entrega Concluída e Próximos Passos!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T18:42:20.146000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndersonMarques</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/498333</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="banner.png" style="width: 720px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305222iB71F72213BE9F051/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="banner.png" alt="banner.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Olá pessoal,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Temos o prazer de anunciar que todos os requisitos da Nota Técnica 04/2025 do eSocial, antes da revisão publicada em 21/08/2025, foram&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;entregues&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Esta atualização traz mudanças e melhorias importantes para garantir a conformidade com as mais recentes especificações legais e técnicas. Abaixo, resumimos as principais soluções já disponíveis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1867840198"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Notes Entregues&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Para atender aos requisitos da Nota Técnica 04/2025, as seguintes SAP Notes foram disponibilizadas:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3641035" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3641035&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: eSocial S-1.3 NT 04/2025 - New wage type natures and absence reasons&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3644046" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3644046&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: eSocial S-1.3 NT 04/2025 - S-1010 - New rule REGRA_VALIDA_CODINCCP_EXC_SEGURADO&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3645482" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3645482&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Prerequiste objects for SAP Note 3645453&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3645453" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3645453&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: eSocial S-1.3 NT 04/2025 - S-1200, S-2299 and S-2399 - Transformation objects for payroll events&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recomendamos que todos os clientes revisem essas SAP Notes e realizem as atualizações necessárias para garantir total conformidade com os requisitos mais recentes do eSocial.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1671326693"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Principais Soluções Entregues&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validação da Tabela de Tipos de Verbas (SAP Note 3644046)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Evento S-1010&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementada a validação com mensagem de erro para o campo&amp;nbsp;{codIncCP}, conforme a nova regra&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;REGRA_VALIDA_CODINCCP_EXC_SEGURADO&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Apenas os valores&amp;nbsp;{codIncCP}&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;[15, 16]&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;são aceitos para naturezas compatíveis com essa situação, conforme especificado na coluna "{codIncCP} no S-1010 = [15, 16]" da Tabela 03 - Natureza das Rubricas da Folha de Pagamento.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Atualizações na Transformação XML (SAP Notes 3645482 e 3645453)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;O campo&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;notAFT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;foi inserido na transformação XML para os seguintes eventos:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S-1200&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Remuneração do trabalhador vinculado ao Regime Geral de Previdência Social&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S-2299&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Desligamento&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S-2399&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Trabalhador sem vínculo - desligamento&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Atualizações na Tabela de Especificação de Rubricas Salariais (SAP Note 3641035)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Na visão&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Especificação rubricas salariais acumulação p/subaplicações (V_T596G/SOCN)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as seguintes entradas foram inseridas ou atualizadas:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9912&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Desconto de assistência médica ou odontológica - Plano diferente de coletivo empresarial&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;(nova)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6129&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Outras verbas não remuneratórias (indenizatórias ou multas)&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;(alterada)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9219&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Desconto de assistência médica ou odontológica - Plano coletivo empresarial&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;(alterada)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Atualizações no Mapeamento de Códigos para o eSocial (SAP Note 3641035)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Na visão&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mapeamento de códigos para o eSocial (V_T7BREFDMEVENTS)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as seguintes entradas foram inseridas ou atualizadas:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;21&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Licença não remunerada ou suspensão contratual decorrente de obrigação legal incompatível com a continuação do serviço&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;(alterada)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;44&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Suspensão contratual decorrente de ajuizamento de reclamação trabalhista pleiteando rescisão indireta do contrato&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;(nova)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;45&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Suspensão contratual para ajuizamento de inquérito para apuração de falta grave&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;(nova)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1474813188"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Próximos Passos&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Com a revisão do governo sobre a Nota Técnica, atualizamos nosso planejamento de entregas. Confira o novo cronograma para se organizar:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cronograma planejado para a entrega da NT S-1.3 04/2025 (rev) do eSocial:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fase 1 -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Entregue!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fase 2 -&lt;/STRONG&gt; Revisão da regra REGRA_VALIDA_CODINCCP_EXC_SEGURADO no evento S-1010:&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;19/09/2025&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fase 3 - &lt;/STRONG&gt;Revisão das naturezas de rubrica:&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;17/10/2025&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Confira o planejamento completo publicado no &lt;A href="https://app.main.regulatory-change-manager.cloud.sap/index.html#/detail/GSREQAMER-14141" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Regulatory Change Manager&lt;/A&gt;, bem como as SAP Notes já disponíveis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reforçamos a importância de revisar as SAP Notes entregues e atualizar seus sistemas para garantir total conformidade com os requisitos mais recentes do eSocial. Nossa equipe está à disposição para apoiar com quaisquer dúvidas ou esclarecimentos adicionais.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Compartilhe este importante aviso com seus colegas e não se esqueça de seguir a tag&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;HCM Payroll Brazil&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;na SAP Community para se manter sempre atualizado.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fique à vontade para deixar seu feedback, comentário ou pergunta sobre este blogpost no espaço abaixo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Atenciosamente,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Anderson Marques&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/esocial-nota-t%C3%A9cnica-04-2025-entrega-conclu%C3%ADda-e-pr%C3%B3ximos-passos/ba-p/14193153"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T18:42:20.146000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
