<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-09-23T03:14:01.388436+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-composable-storefront-problem-getting-current-user-with-asm/qaq-p/14224572</id>
    <title>Sap Composable Storefront problem getting current user with ASM</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T19:29:21.571000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yasbet_Alvarez</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/893731</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am trying to retrieve the current customer for whom the ASM agent has initiated a session. I have tested a few OOTB services, but none of them worked:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-java"&gt;&lt;code&gt;userService.getCurrentUser(); // returns the Employee user
assistedServiceService.getAsmSession().getEmulatedCustomer(); // returns null
getAssistedServiceFacade().isAssistedServiceAgentLoggedIn() // return false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Yasbet_Alvarez_0-1758561953137.png" style="width: 612px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318172iFC14C0E73554A83B/image-dimensions/612x74/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="612" height="74" role="button" title="Yasbet_Alvarez_0-1758561953137.png" alt="Yasbet_Alvarez_0-1758561953137.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The environment is Spartacus ASM with Hybris 2011.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any guidance or suggestions would be greatly appreciated.&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-composable-storefront-problem-getting-current-user-with-asm/qaq-p/14224572"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T19:29:21.571000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/rehire-with-old-employment-failing-replication/qaa-p/14224573#M48141</id>
    <title>Re: Rehire with Old Employment Failing Replication</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T19:34:25.250000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>emily_nagengast</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/25731</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/866961"&gt;@holly_sandvold&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- The system is working as designed. To help filter out rehires showing up in integrations, please use t&lt;SPAN&gt;he OnboardingInfo object. It is a read-only MDF object that integrates with other SAP SuccessFactors modules, such as Employee Central, to track onboarding, offboarding, internal hiring, or rehiring activities. It is automatically created when the onboarding process for a candidate is initiated and is mapped to the employmentInfo entity in Employee Central.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A common use case for adding the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;OnboardingInfo&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;object to an integration is when using Rehire with Old Employment. This object ensures rehires don't replicate downstream before completing Manage Pending Hires. It leverages the hiring status within the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;OnboardingInfo&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;object.&amp;nbsp;Use only the&amp;nbsp;OnboardingInfo&amp;nbsp;object to filter onboardees. Do not use the&amp;nbsp;HiringNotCompleted&amp;nbsp;flag.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;More information can be found here. -&lt;A title="Onboarding Info Object" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-onboarding/implementing-onboarding/onboarding-info-object?version=2505" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Onboarding Info Object&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/rehire-with-old-employment-failing-replication/qaa-p/14224573#M48141"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T19:34:25.250000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/a-comprehensive-user-guide-and-test-plan-for-sap-s-4hana-integrated-asset/ba-p/14224575</id>
    <title>A Comprehensive User Guide and Test Plan for SAP S/4HANA: Integrated Asset and Lease Management</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T19:38:35.852000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mickaelquesnot</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150004</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Comprehensive User Guide and Test Plan for SAP S/4HANA: Integrated Asset and Lease Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Welcome to this comprehensive guide for SAP S/4HANA. This document is designed for a wide range of users, from business end-users and key users new to the system, to experienced consultants seeking a structured overview of modern asset and lease management processes. We will transform complex procedures into a clear, end-to-end business process flow, making SAP's powerful functionalities accessible to everyone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purpose of This Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The primary goal of this guide is twofold:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;To Educate:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To provide a clear, conceptual understanding of the entire lifecycle of assets within an organization—from their initial procurement or lease to their eventual retirement. We will demystify core concepts and explain the "why" behind each process step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;To Enable:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To offer practical, step-by-step instructions on how to execute these processes in a modern SAP S/4HANA environment. This includes detailed walkthroughs of master data creation, transactional processing, and period-end activities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who Should Use This Guide?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;End Users:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Individuals who will perform daily tasks like creating purchase requisitions for assets or managing contract data. This guide provides clear "how-to" instructions for your role.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Users:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Business process owners who need a deeper understanding of the end-to-end flow to support their teams and drive process improvements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consultants:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Functional and technical consultants can use this guide as a reference for standard business processes (SAP Best Practices), configuration touchpoints, and as a foundation for designing test plans and training materials.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Beginners ("Dummies"):&lt;/STRONG&gt; If you're new to SAP, this guide breaks down the processes into logical, easy-to-understand steps with real-world examples.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Business Processes Covered&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will navigate through three critical, interconnected business areas:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Procure-to-Pay for Fixed Assets (P2A):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The complete process of identifying a need for an asset, purchasing it, receiving it, paying for it, and seeing it capitalized on the company's books.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Lifecycle Management:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The management of an asset throughout its useful life, including depreciation, value adjustments, transfers, and eventual retirement from service.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lease-In Contract Management:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The modern approach to leasing assets (like buildings or vehicles) according to international accounting standards (IFRS 16 and US GAAP), which involves recognizing Right-of-Use (RoU) assets and Lease Liabilities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The SAP Fiori Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Throughout this guide, we will focus on the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Fiori launchpad&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP's modern, role-based user experience. Fiori provides a simple, intuitive interface with apps tailored to specific tasks. For certain advanced or configuration-related activities, we may also refer to the classic SAP GUI, but the primary focus remains on the modern Fiori apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 1: The Comprehensive Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Chapter 1: Foundational Concepts &amp;amp; Master Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before we can transact in SAP, we must first establish the foundational data that defines our organization and the business objects we interact with. This master data is created once and used across many transactions, ensuring consistency and accuracy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.1. Organizational Structure: The Backbone of Your Company in SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The organizational structure in SAP is a digital representation of your enterprise. The data we will use in our examples is based on a standard model company.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Company Code (e.g., 1010):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The most important organizational unit. It represents a legal entity for which a complete set of financial statements (Balance Sheet and Profit &amp;amp; Loss statement) is created. All our asset and lease transactions will be posted within a company code.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plant (e.g., 1010):&lt;/STRONG&gt; An operational unit within a company, such as a factory, a warehouse, or a regional office. In our asset procurement scenario, the asset will be delivered to a plant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchasing Organization (e.g., 1010):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The unit responsible for procuring materials and services. It negotiates pricing and conditions with vendors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Chart of Depreciation (e.g., 1010):&lt;/STRONG&gt; A corporate-level structure that manages the valuation of assets for different accounting principles. A company code is assigned to one chart of depreciation. It contains various &lt;STRONG&gt;Depreciation Areas&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.2. Core Master Data for Integrated Processes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.2.1. Business Partner (Vendor)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In S/4HANA, both customers and vendors are managed centrally as &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Partners (BP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. A single BP master record can have different roles assigned to it. For our processes, we need a Business Partner with a &lt;EM&gt;Supplier (FI)&lt;/EM&gt; role to act as the vendor from whom we purchase or lease an asset.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How-To: Create a Vendor Business Partner&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Log in&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the SAP Fiori launchpad with the &lt;STRONG&gt;Accounts Payable Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt; role.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Business Partner Master Data&lt;/STRONG&gt; app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Create &amp;gt; Organization&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the &lt;EM&gt;Create Organization&lt;/EM&gt; screen, fill in the essential details:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BP Role:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Start with 000000 (General).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Name:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Global Office Supplies Inc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Search Term:&lt;/STRONG&gt; GLOBALOFFICE&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Address:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enter a full address, including street, city, postal code, and country. This is crucial for tax calculations and logistics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The system will create the BP and assign a number. Note this number.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Now, we extend the BP to the necessary roles. Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Edit&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the &lt;EM&gt;BP Role&lt;/EM&gt; dropdown, select &lt;STRONG&gt;Supplier (Financial Accounting)&lt;/STRONG&gt; (FLVN00) and choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A new section for &lt;EM&gt;Company Code&lt;/EM&gt; data will appear. Select it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter your &lt;STRONG&gt;Company Code&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., 1010) and press Enter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the &lt;STRONG&gt;Reconciliation Account&lt;/STRONG&gt; for payables (e.g., the standard domestic payables account).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the &lt;EM&gt;Payment Transactions&lt;/EM&gt; tab and enter the &lt;STRONG&gt;Payment Terms&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt; the changes. The Business Partner is now ready to be used as a vendor in our procurement and leasing processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.2.2. Cost Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A Cost Center is an organizational unit that incurs costs. When we acquire an asset, we must assign it to a cost center responsible for the costs associated with that asset, such as depreciation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How-To: Create a Cost Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in to the Fiori launchpad as a &lt;STRONG&gt;General Ledger Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Cost Centers&lt;/STRONG&gt; app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the following information:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Controlling Area:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is typically linked to your company code (e.g., A000).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cost Center:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 10101301 (Example: IT Department)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validity Period:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enter a start and end date (e.g., from today to the end of time 31.12.9999).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Press Enter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the &lt;EM&gt;Basic Data&lt;/EM&gt; tab:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Name:&lt;/STRONG&gt; IT Department&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Information Technology Department&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Person Responsible:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enter the name of the department manager.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cost Center Category:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Select an appropriate category, like H (Service cost center).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchy Area:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Assign it to a node in the standard cost center hierarchy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Company Code:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1010&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The cost center is now active and can be assigned to assets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.2.3. Asset Master Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The asset master record is the central repository for all information about a fixed asset. It is structured to support different valuation requirements simultaneously.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Concepts:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Class:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The primary classification for an asset (e.g., Buildings, Vehicles, Computers). The asset class serves as a template, providing default values for depreciation terms and defining which G/L accounts are posted to when transactions occur.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Depreciation Areas:&lt;/STRONG&gt; These represent different valuation methods for a single asset. A company typically needs multiple depreciation areas to comply with different accounting standards. For example:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Area 01:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Book Depreciation (Local GAAP)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Area 32:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Depreciation according to IFRS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Area 33:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Depreciation according to US GAAP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Useful Life:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The estimated period over which an asset will be used. This is a key factor in calculating depreciation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How-To: Create an Asset Master Record&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This process is typically performed as part of the asset acquisition process itself, but it can also be done standalone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in to the Fiori launchpad as an &lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Asset&lt;/STRONG&gt; Fiori app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the initial dialog, enter:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Class:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 3000 (Example: Machinery and Equipment)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Company Code:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1010&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Number of similar assets:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Master Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On the &lt;EM&gt;General&lt;/EM&gt; tab:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Executive Conference Room Projector&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Capitalized on:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This date will be filled automatically upon the first acquisition posting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the &lt;EM&gt;Time-Dependent&lt;/EM&gt; tab:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Add Interval&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the &lt;STRONG&gt;Cost Center&lt;/STRONG&gt; you created earlier (e.g., 10101301).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the &lt;EM&gt;Valuation&lt;/EM&gt; tab:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The system will propose depreciation terms based on the asset class. Review the &lt;STRONG&gt;Depreciation Key&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., LIN.) and the &lt;STRONG&gt;Useful Life&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., 5 years) for each depreciation area. You can modify these if needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The system creates the asset and displays the new asset number. &lt;STRONG&gt;Make a note of this number&lt;/STRONG&gt; as it will be used in the procurement process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Chapter 2: The Asset Lifecycle - From Procurement to Retirement (Scope Item J62)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This chapter details the journey of a tangible fixed asset, starting from its purchase through its operational use and concluding with its removal from the company's books.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.1. Acquiring an Asset via Procurement (The "P2A" Process)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The most common way to acquire a new asset is through the standard procurement process. This ensures proper approvals, tracking, and financial integration. This process integrates Materials Management (MM) with Asset Accounting (FI-AA).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conceptual Overview:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you purchase a standard inventory item, the value goes into an inventory account. When you purchase a fixed asset, the value must be "capitalized"—meaning it's recorded on the balance sheet as an asset, not expensed immediately. The key to this process is the Account Assignment Category 'A' (for Asset), which tells the system to post the value to a specific asset master record instead of an expense or inventory account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical Exercise: Purchasing a New Projector&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Create a Purchase Requisition (The Need)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A manager in the IT department identifies the need for a new high-end projector for the main conference room. They create a purchase requisition to formally request this purchase.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Purchaser&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Fiori app &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Purchase Requisition - Advanced&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Transaction ME51N).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the &lt;EM&gt;Item Overview&lt;/EM&gt; section, enter the following details:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A (Account Assignment Cat.):&lt;/STRONG&gt; A (Asset). This is the crucial step!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Short Text:&lt;/STRONG&gt; New 4K Conference Room Projector&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quantity:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unit of Measure:&lt;/STRONG&gt; PC (Piece)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Matl Group:&lt;/STRONG&gt; YBFA08 (Office Equipment)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plant:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1010&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Valuation Price:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 3000 (The estimated price in EUR)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Press Enter. The system will open the &lt;EM&gt;Item Detail&lt;/EM&gt; section below.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the &lt;EM&gt;Account Assignment&lt;/EM&gt; tab in the item details.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the &lt;STRONG&gt;Asset&lt;/STRONG&gt; number you created in Chapter 1.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Check&lt;/STRONG&gt; at the top of the screen. The system should show a message "No messages issued during check."&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The system will create the Purchase Requisition and provide a number. Note it down.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Convert Requisition to Purchase Order (The Order)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The purchasing department reviews the requisition and converts it into a formal Purchase Order to send to the vendor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Purchaser&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Fiori app &lt;STRONG&gt;Process Purchase Requisitions&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F1048).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Search for your purchase requisition number.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the line item for your requisition and choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Purchase Order&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The system will carry over most of the data. You must enter the &lt;STRONG&gt;Vendor&lt;/STRONG&gt; (the Business Partner you created, e.g., 10300001).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify the price and other details. The Account Assignment 'A' and the asset number will be carried over automatically.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt; the Purchase Order. The system will generate a PO number. Note it down.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Post Goods Receipt (The Delivery)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The vendor delivers the projector. The warehouse clerk receives the item and records its arrival in the system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Warehouse Clerk&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Fiori app &lt;STRONG&gt;Post Goods Receipt for Purchasing Document&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F0843).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the Purchase Order number from the previous step and press Enter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The system displays the details from the PO.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the &lt;STRONG&gt;Item OK&lt;/STRONG&gt; checkbox to confirm the receipt.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Post&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The system confirms the goods receipt with a Material Document number.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Financial Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Because this is a non-valuated goods receipt for an asset, there is typically no financial posting at this stage. The asset is not capitalized yet. The value is "in transit" on a technical clearing account.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Post Supplier Invoice (The Capitalization)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The vendor sends the invoice for the projector. The Accounts Payable accountant receives it and posts it against the purchase order, which triggers the capitalization of the asset.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as an &lt;STRONG&gt;Accounts Payable Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Fiori app &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Supplier Invoice - Advanced&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Transaction MIRO).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the following header data:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Invoice Date:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Today's date&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reference:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The vendor's invoice number (e.g., INV-PJ-5567)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Amount:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 3000 (The total amount from the invoice)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the &lt;EM&gt;PO Reference&lt;/EM&gt; section, enter your Purchase Order number and press Enter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The system will pull in the line item details from the PO and the goods receipt. The amount should match.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The balance at the top right should be green (zero).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Simulate&lt;/STRONG&gt; to see the resulting accounting entry before posting. You will see a debit to the asset's reconciliation account and a credit to the vendor's account.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Post&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The system posts the invoice and the asset is now officially capitalized.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Verification:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Fixed Assets&lt;/STRONG&gt; app to display your asset. You will now see the acquisition value of €3,000 on the capitalization date (the invoice posting date).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.2. Managing the Asset During Its Life&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Depreciation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depreciation is the systematic allocation of an asset's cost over its useful life. It represents the "using up" of the asset's value. SAP S/4HANA automates this process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Concept:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Based on the depreciation key (LIN. for straight-line) and useful life (5 years) in the asset master, the system calculates the annual depreciation (€3,000 / 5 years = €600) and breaks it down into monthly amounts (€50).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Execution:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The depreciation is not posted one by one, but as a periodic batch job for all assets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as an &lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the app &lt;STRONG&gt;Schedule Asset Accounting Jobs&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F1914).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the Job Template &lt;STRONG&gt;Depreciation Posting Run&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Give the job a name, like Depr_Run_1010_Period_XX.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;EM&gt;Step 2&lt;/EM&gt; and schedule it to run immediately.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In &lt;EM&gt;Step 3&lt;/EM&gt;, enter the parameters:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Company Code:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1010&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fiscal Year:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Current Year&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Posting Period:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The period you want to post.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Run:&lt;/STRONG&gt; It's a best practice to first run it as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Run&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The log will show any errors or the planned postings without actually creating documents.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Actual Run:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Once the test run is successful, schedule the job again with the &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Run&lt;/STRONG&gt; checkbox deselected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Financial Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The system posts a journal entry:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Debit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Depreciation Expense Account&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Credit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Accumulated Depreciation Account (a contra-asset account that reduces the net book value of the asset).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.3. Asset Retirement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After 5 years, the projector is obsolete and is sold for €100.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as an &lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Fiori app &lt;STRONG&gt;Post Asset Retirement&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F7107).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Other Posting Transaction &amp;gt; Post Retirement &amp;gt; Retirement with Revenue&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the General Information:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Company Code:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1010&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Main Asset Number:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Your projector's asset number.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Journal Entry, Posting, and Asset Value Date:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Today's date.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the &lt;EM&gt;Posting Information&lt;/EM&gt; section:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Revenue Amount:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 100&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Retirement Type:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Complete Retirement&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Simulate&lt;/STRONG&gt; to review the posting. The system will automatically calculate the Net Book Value (NBV), compare it to the revenue, and calculate the gain or loss on the sale.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Post&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The asset is now retired, and the gain/loss is posted to the P&amp;amp;L.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Chapter 3: Lease Accounting - Right-of-Use Assets (Scope Items 5YU &amp;amp; 63Q)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modern accounting standards like IFRS 16 and ASC 842 (US GAAP) have fundamentally changed how companies account for leases. Gone are the days of simple operating leases that were just an expense on the P&amp;amp;L. Now, most leases must be brought onto the balance sheet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.1. Introduction to Modern Lease Accounting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Core Concept:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you sign a long-term lease (e.g., for a building), you have acquired the right to use that asset for the lease term. This "right" is itself an asset. Simultaneously, you have created an obligation to make future lease payments, which is a liability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Right-of-Use (RoU) Asset:&lt;/STRONG&gt; An intangible asset representing your right to use the leased item. It is capitalized and depreciated over the lease term.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lease Liability:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A financial liability representing the present value of all future lease payments you are obligated to make.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP's Contract and Lease Management module automates the complex calculations and postings required for this process. The main difference between IFRS (5YU) and US GAAP (63Q) lies in how leases are classified and how the expense is recognized, but the initial creation of the RoU asset and liability is similar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.2. Setting the Stage: Real Estate Objects &amp;amp; Contracts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before we can have a lease, we need something to lease. We'll lease an office floor for our company.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisite:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A Real Estate object must exist. This is typically managed by a Real Estate Specialist. For this guide, we assume a building BUILDING-01 with a floor FLOOR-02 has been created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Enable a Real Estate Object for Use&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need to make FLOOR-02 available for our company code 1010 to use and assign costs to.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Real Estate Specialist - Location Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the app &lt;STRONG&gt;Group Real Estate Object for Use&lt;/STRONG&gt; (F5397).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Search for your BUILDING-01.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select FLOOR-02 from the structure and choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Group&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the dialog box, enter:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Usage Enablement Type:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Lease-in&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Controlling Object Type:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Leading Object for Controlling&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leading Cost Object ID:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Select a cost center that will bear the costs for this floor (e.g., 10101101 - Administration).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Group&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The floor is now enabled for use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Create the Lease-In Contract&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, we create the legal contract in the system that governs this lease.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Specialist - Leasing&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the app &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Contract&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Transaction RECN).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Object&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter &lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Type&lt;/STRONG&gt; Lease In Real Estate and &lt;STRONG&gt;Company Code&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1010. Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Continue&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On the &lt;EM&gt;General Data&lt;/EM&gt; tab:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Name:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 5-Year Lease for Rouen Office Floor 2&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Valuation relevance:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Leasing Valuation (This is critical to trigger the RoU process).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the &lt;EM&gt;Partners&lt;/EM&gt; tab:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Assign New Partner&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Select the role Supplier(Fin.Accounting).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Search for and assign your landlord's Business Partner number (e.g., 10300001).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the &lt;EM&gt;Term&lt;/EM&gt; tab:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Contract start date:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The first day of next month.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1st Contract End:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 5 years from the start date.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the &lt;EM&gt;Objects&lt;/EM&gt; tab:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Assign&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Select &lt;EM&gt;Real Estate Object&lt;/EM&gt; and find the usage group for FLOOR-02 that you created.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the &lt;EM&gt;Conditions&lt;/EM&gt; tab:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This is where you define the payments. Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Insert Condition(s)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select a condition type for basic rent.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the payment details:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unit Price:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 5000&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Currency:&lt;/STRONG&gt; EUR&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under &lt;EM&gt;Terms&lt;/EM&gt;, check the payment frequency (e.g., Monthly in Advance).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The system saves the contract in a Created status.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review all data, then choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Activate&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The contract is now legally and systemically active.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.3. The Heart of the Process: Contract Valuation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With an active contract, the system can now perform the valuation to generate the RoU Asset and Lease Liability. This is often triggered automatically upon activation but can also be run manually.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Valuation Specialist - Leasing&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Contract&lt;/STRONG&gt; (RECN) app again and go to your contract.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the &lt;EM&gt;Valuation Parameters&lt;/EM&gt; tab.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Here you will assign a &lt;STRONG&gt;Valuation Rule&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The system might propose one based on your configuration. For our example, we select a rule relevant for &lt;STRONG&gt;IFRS 16&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The rule requires an &lt;STRONG&gt;Interest Rate&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This is the incremental borrowing rate. Enter a rate, for example, 3.5%.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once the rule is complete, choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To see the result, open the &lt;STRONG&gt;Display Contract Valuation&lt;/STRONG&gt; (RECESH) app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter your contract number and execute. The system will display the cash flow, the calculated Present Value (which is the initial value of your Lease Liability and RoU Asset), and the planned postings for interest, payments, and depreciation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Financial Impact (Initial Recognition):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The valuation triggers a posting:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Debit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Right-of-Use Asset (Balance Sheet)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Credit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Lease Liability (Balance Sheet)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;An asset master record is automatically created in the background for this new RoU asset, linking it directly to the processes in Asset Accounting (FI-AA).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.4. The Ongoing Lease Lifecycle&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Periodic Posting (Making the Rent Payment)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each month, the rent payment needs to be posted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as an &lt;STRONG&gt;Accounts Payable Accountant - Leasing&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the &lt;STRONG&gt;Periodic Posting: Contracts&lt;/STRONG&gt; (RERAPP) app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the selection criteria:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Company Code:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1010&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Contract:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Your contract number&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Month for Posting Run:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The month of the first payment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Posting Run Mode:&lt;/STRONG&gt; First, run a &lt;STRONG&gt;Simulation&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Execute. The system shows the planned posting. It will be a debit to the vendor and a credit to a bank clearing account.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once verified, run it again in &lt;STRONG&gt;Update Run&lt;/STRONG&gt; mode to create the actual financial document.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Post Contract Valuation (Interest &amp;amp; Liability Reduction)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Along with the payment, the monthly valuation posting must occur. This recognizes the interest expense and reduces the lease liability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Valuation Specialist - Leasing&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the &lt;STRONG&gt;Post Valuation for Contracts&lt;/STRONG&gt; (RECEEP) app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter similar selection criteria as the periodic posting (contract, month, etc.).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run a &lt;STRONG&gt;Simulation&lt;/STRONG&gt; first, then an &lt;STRONG&gt;Update Run&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Financial Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The system posts a journal entry:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Debit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Interest Expense (P&amp;amp;L)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Debit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Lease Liability (Balance Sheet - reduction of the liability)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Credit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Clearing Account&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: RoU Asset Depreciation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The RoU asset is depreciated just like the projector we purchased. This happens during the standard asset depreciation run explained in Chapter 2. The system automatically includes the new RoU asset in this run.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Chapter 4: Customizing and Configuration Highlights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This chapter provides a high-level overview of the key configuration settings that drive the processes described above. These activities are performed by consultants during system implementation using either SAP Central Business Configuration (CBC) for Cloud or the Implementation Guide (SPRO) for On-Premise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4.1. Asset Accounting (FI-AA)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Manage Your Solution &amp;gt; Configure Your Solution &amp;gt; Finance &amp;gt; Asset Accounting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Activities:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assign Chart of Depreciation to Company Code:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The fundamental link between the company code and asset accounting rules.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define Asset Classes:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is where you configure the different types of assets. For each class, you set default values, screen layouts, and most importantly, the &lt;STRONG&gt;Account Determination&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Account Determination links the asset class to the specific G/L accounts used for APC, accumulated depreciation, depreciation expense, gain/loss, etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define Depreciation Keys:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is where the calculation methods for depreciation are defined (e.g., straight-line, declining-balance, multi-level methods).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Make Company Code Settings - Asset Accounting-Specific:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Used to set the status of a company code (e.g., for testing, productive), define legacy data transfer parameters, and perform the year-end close.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4.2. Contract and Lease Management (RE-FX)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Manage Your Solution &amp;gt; Configure Your Solution &amp;gt; Finance &amp;gt; Contract and Lease Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Activities:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define Contract Types:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Set up different types of contracts (e.g., Lease-In, Lease-Out) and their properties.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define Condition Types:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Define the different financial streams in a contract (e.g., Basic Rent, Service Charge, etc.) and their calculation and posting characteristics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Valuation Rule:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is the core of lease accounting configuration. Here you define rules for different accounting principles (IFRS, US GAAP). Within the rule, you specify:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which condition types are relevant for the present value calculation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The G/L accounts for posting the RoU asset and liability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The interest calculation method.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The asset class to be used for the automatically created RoU assets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 2: The Comprehensive Test Plan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section provides structured, end-to-end test scenarios that you can execute in a test or quality system to practice and validate the processes described in this guide.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction to Testing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To ensure that the system is configured correctly and that business processes run smoothly from start to finish, including all integration points.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Before starting, ensure you have the necessary user roles assigned and that the foundational master data (vendors, cost centers, G/L accounts) exists in your test system. The sample data used in the guide (Company Code 1010, etc.) should be available.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Scenario 1: End-to-End Procure-to-Retire for a Purchased Asset&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To test the complete lifecycle of a fixed asset acquired through standard procurement.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Roles Required:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Purchaser, Warehouse Clerk, Accounts Payable Accountant, Asset Accountant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Test Step Name&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instruction&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expected Result&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pass/Fail&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create Asset Master&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Asset&lt;/STRONG&gt; app. Use Asset Class 3000 (Machinery &amp;amp; Equipment), Company Code 1010. Enter Description: Dell Laptop Model 9520. Assign it to a Cost Center.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Asset master record is created. Note the asset number: ______________.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create Purchase Requisition&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Purchaser&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Purchase Requisition - Advanced&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Enter Account Assignment 'A', Description 'Dell Laptop Model 9520', Plant 1010, Quantity 1, Price 2200. In Account Assignment tab, enter the asset number from Step 1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Purchase Requisition is created. Note the number: ______________.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create Purchase Order&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;STRONG&gt;Process Purchase Requisitions&lt;/STRONG&gt; app, find your PR and convert it to a Purchase Order. Assign a Vendor (e.g., 10300001). Save.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Purchase Order is created. Note the number: ______________.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;4&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Post Goods Receipt&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Warehouse Clerk&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Post Goods Receipt for Purchasing Document&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Enter your PO number. Select 'Item OK' and Post.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Material document is posted. Note the number: ______________. Check the asset values; there should be no acquisition value yet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;5&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Post Supplier Invoice&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;AP Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Supplier Invoice - Advanced&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Enter invoice details, Amount 2200, and reference your PO number. Post the invoice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Invoice is posted. The asset is capitalized. Note the document number: ______________.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;6&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Verify Asset Values&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Fixed Assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Display your asset. Verify that the Acquisition Value is 2200 EUR.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The asset values are correct in all depreciation areas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;7&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Run Depreciation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;STRONG&gt;Schedule Asset Accounting Jobs&lt;/STRONG&gt; app, create a &lt;STRONG&gt;Depreciation Posting Run&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the current period. Run it first in &lt;STRONG&gt;Test Mode&lt;/STRONG&gt;, then in &lt;STRONG&gt;Update Mode&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depreciation is posted successfully. The Net Book Value of the asset is reduced.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;8&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Retire Asset via Sale&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;After a few periods, log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Post Asset Retirement&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Select Retirement with Revenue. Enter your asset, a revenue amount of 500 EUR, and select Complete Retirement. Post the transaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The asset is retired. The system correctly posts the transaction, clearing the asset's APC and accumulated depreciation, and posts the gain or loss on sale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Scenario 2: End-to-End Lease-in and Management of a Right-of-Use Asset (IFRS 16)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To test the creation, valuation, and ongoing management of a leased property under IFRS 16.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Roles Required:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Real Estate Specialist, Contract Specialist, Contract Valuation Specialist, AP Accountant, Asset Accountant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Step&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Test Step Name&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instruction&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expected Result&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pass/Fail&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enable Real Estate Object&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Real Estate Specialist&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Group Real Estate Object for Use&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Select a building/floor to lease. Create a new Usage Enablement Group of type 'Lease-in', assigning a Cost Center.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The object is enabled for use and has a group ID. Note the ID: ______________.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create Lease-In Contract&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Specialist&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Contract&lt;/STRONG&gt; (RECN). Create a new Lease In Real Estate contract. Assign a landlord (Vendor), a term (e.g., 3 years), the object from Step 1, and a monthly rent condition of 2000 EUR. Set Valuation Relevance to Leasing Valuation. Save and Activate the contract.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The contract is created and active. Note the number: ______________.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Perform Contract Valuation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Valuation Specialist&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open the contract in &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Contract&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Go to &lt;EM&gt;Valuation Parameters&lt;/EM&gt;. Assign an IFRS 16 valuation rule. Enter an interest rate (e.g., 4%). Save.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system calculates the Net Present Value. An RoU Asset master record is created automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;4&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Verify Initial Recognition&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Display Contract Valuation&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Verify the NPV calculation. Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Fixed Assets&lt;/STRONG&gt; and find the new RoU asset. Verify its acquisition value matches the NPV. Check the corresponding journal entry.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;RoU asset and Lease Liability are correctly recognized on the balance sheet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;5&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Post Monthly Payment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;AP Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Periodic Posting: Contracts&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Run the posting for the first month for your contract in Update Mode.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The payment to the vendor is posted correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;6&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Post Monthly Valuation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Valuation Specialist&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Post Valuation for Contracts&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Run the posting for the first month for your contract in Update Mode.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The interest expense is recognized, and the lease liability is reduced.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;7&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Post Monthly Depreciation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Accountant&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Run the standard &lt;STRONG&gt;Depreciation Posting Run&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The RoU asset is included in the run, and its depreciation is posted correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;8&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Early Termination&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in as &lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Specialist&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Open the contract in &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Contract&lt;/STRONG&gt;. On the &lt;EM&gt;Term&lt;/EM&gt; tab, change the 1st contract end date to an earlier date. On the &lt;EM&gt;Valuation Parameters&lt;/EM&gt; tab, add a new time slice for the day after the new end date and complete the rule. Save. Then, as &lt;STRONG&gt;Contract Valuation Specialist&lt;/STRONG&gt;, run the valuation posting for the termination period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system correctly remeasures the liability and the RoU asset, posting the gain/loss on termination. The asset is fully depreciated/retired.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Appendix&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A.1. Key Fiori Apps and Transactions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Process&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fiori App&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP GUI Transaction&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Business Partner&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Business Partner Master Data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;BP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Cost Center&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Cost Centers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;KS01 / KS02&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Asset Master&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create Asset / Manage Fixed Assets&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;AS01 / AS02 / AW01N&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create Purchase Req.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create Purchase Requisition - Advanced&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;ME51N&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Purchase Order&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Purchase Orders&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;ME21N / ME22N&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Post Goods Receipt&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Post Goods Receipt for Purchasing Document&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;MIGO&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Post Supplier Invoice&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create Supplier Invoice - Advanced&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;MIRO&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Schedule AA Jobs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Schedule Asset Accounting Jobs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;AFAB&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage RE Contract&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Contract&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;RECN&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Periodic RE Posting&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Periodic Posting: Contracts&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;RERAPP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Post RE Valuation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Post Valuation for Contracts&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;RECEEP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A.2. Glossary of Terms&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;APC (Acquisition and Production Costs):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The original cost of an asset.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Class:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The main criterion for classifying assets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Partner (BP):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The central object for managing master data of persons and organizations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CBC (Central Business Configuration):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The tool used to configure SAP S/4HANA Cloud systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Depreciation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The systematic reduction in the recorded cost of a fixed asset.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FI-AA (Asset Accounting):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The SAP module for managing fixed assets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IFRS 16:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The international financial reporting standard for lease accounting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MM (Materials Management):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The SAP module for procurement and inventory.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;NBV (Net Book Value):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The value of an asset on the balance sheet (APC minus Accumulated Depreciation).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RE-FX (Flexible Real Estate Management):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The SAP module for managing real estate portfolios, including lease contracts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RoU (Right-of-Use) Asset:&lt;/STRONG&gt; An asset that represents a lessee's right to use an underlying asset for the lease term.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/a-comprehensive-user-guide-and-test-plan-for-sap-s-4hana-integrated-asset/ba-p/14224575"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T19:38:35.852000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/determination-of-the-newest-latest-record-for-non-effective-dated-objects/bc-p/14224576#M9213</id>
    <title>Re: Determination of the newest = latest record for non-effective dated objects</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T19:41:20.865000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chriscolbert63</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109639</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17855"&gt;@FrankErle&lt;/a&gt;! This has helped me report on 9 Box values where we have multiple Performance Trend and Potential values throughout the year due to calibration sessions etc, and I could use a max of the sum of the sequence IDs behind these records in the way you laid out. Fantastic!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/determination-of-the-newest-latest-record-for-non-effective-dated-objects/bc-p/14224576#M9213"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T19:41:20.865000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/curriculum-requirements-with-retraining/qaa-p/14224577#M48142</id>
    <title>Re: Curriculum Requirements with Retraining</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T19:46:56.625000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrisMayAtDelta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/63087</uri>
    </author>
    <content>We usually make a new item with a new ID each year. That allows us to use the same content object, or make updates or even use brand new content. I will also acknowledge we only manage 50-60 items this way, any more and that would be very burdensome.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/curriculum-requirements-with-retraining/qaa-p/14224577#M48142"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T19:46:56.625000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-get-date-filter-as-calendar-format/qaa-p/14224585#M4927088</id>
    <title>Re: How to get Date Filter as Calendar format</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T19:55:51.372000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1394811"&gt;@Vasu_Sac&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This has been created as part of some cumulative calculation using date ranges where you can select custom date. Something like below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_0-1758563648184.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318175i5178FEAFAF5DA951/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_0-1758563648184.png" alt="N1kh1l_0-1758563648184.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_1-1758563734283.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318177i7A7B6BF6490D9443/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_1-1758563734283.png" alt="N1kh1l_1-1758563734283.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: Only a single custom date can be defined in a story. Your normal story filters for date will not look like calendar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nikhil&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-get-date-filter-as-calendar-format/qaa-p/14224585#M4927088"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T19:55:51.372000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-table-title-mirrored-to-the-next-cell/qaa-p/14224588#M4927089</id>
    <title>Re: SAC - table title mirrored to the next cell</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:01:25.118000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2042267"&gt;@sateixeira&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;not sure but try un ticking the highlighted options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_0-1758564066621.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318178i53C2EB4B827B6A25/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_0-1758564066621.png" alt="N1kh1l_0-1758564066621.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nikhil&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-table-title-mirrored-to-the-next-cell/qaa-p/14224588#M4927089"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:01:25.118000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/does-pullic-cloud-support-connecting-to-corresponding-banks-for-payment-in/qaa-p/14224590#M4227773</id>
    <title>Re: Does PULLIC CLOUD support connecting to corresponding...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:10:59.855000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Juwin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/169790</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Read about Multi-Bank Connectivity here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/financial-management/multi-bank-connectivity.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/financial-management/multi-bank-connectivity.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/does-pullic-cloud-support-connecting-to-corresponding-banks-for-payment-in/qaa-p/14224590#M4227773"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:10:59.855000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/starting-process-chains-in-bw-bridge-from-datasphere-taskchains-csrf-issue/qaa-p/14224593#M4927090</id>
    <title>Re: Starting Process chains in BW Bridge from Datasphere Taskchains CSRF issue</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:25:05.571000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dominik_Graus</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40140</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1418661"&gt;@NauwelaertA&lt;/a&gt;: This could be caused by the setting for 'User Mapping Claim'. You could try one of these options: 'email' Verified, 'email' Unverified, and 'user_name'.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/starting-process-chains-in-bw-bridge-from-datasphere-taskchains-csrf-issue/qaa-p/14224593#M4927090"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:25:05.571000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-rap-custom-entity-unmanaged-how-to-update/qaa-p/14224594#M4927091</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud RAP Custom entity unmanaged how to u...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:26:27.339000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JamesG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1281</uri>
    </author>
    <content>If i used this code:</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-rap-custom-entity-unmanaged-how-to-update/qaa-p/14224594#M4927091"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:26:27.339000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-rap-custom-entity-unmanaged-how-to-update/qaa-p/14224596#M4927092</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud RAP Custom entity unmanaged how to u...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:27:30.404000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JamesG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1281</uri>
    </author>
    <content>If I use this code, it will enter an infinite loop.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-public-cloud-rap-custom-entity-unmanaged-how-to-update/qaa-p/14224596#M4927092"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:27:30.404000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sap-sf-time-tracking-time-valuation-count-events-on-each-day-with-threshold/qaa-p/14224597#M48143</id>
    <title>Re: SAP SF Time Tracking - Time Valuation Count Events on...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:39:22.219000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>charlottejiang18</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/68580</uri>
    </author>
    <content>You may use the cardinality function in a time validation rule to restrict the occurance per day.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/sap-sf-time-tracking-time-valuation-count-events-on-each-day-with-threshold/qaa-p/14224597#M48143"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:39:22.219000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/print-to-local-printer-from-fiori/qaa-p/14224598#M4927093</id>
    <title>Re: Print to local Printer from Fiori</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:43:01.432000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Juwin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/169790</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Many problems are incredibly easy to solve if you use NWBC Client to login, instead of a generic browser. Please try that. NWBC Client has capabilities to avoid the usage of WebGUI page whenever a GUI transaction is detected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/print-to-local-printer-from-fiori/qaa-p/14224598#M4927093"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:43:01.432000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/new-or-not-to-the-sap-community-share-your-story/m-p/14224599#M10374</id>
    <title>Re: New or not to the SAP Community, share your story!</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:47:47.545000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>anjanat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253836</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am a new comer, aspiring in Finance, GRC, GTS web security using Agentic AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/new-or-not-to-the-sap-community-share-your-story/m-p/14224599#M10374"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:47:47.545000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/sap-community-where-are-you-from/m-p/14224601#M10375</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community - Where are you from?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:50:39.175000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>anjanat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253836</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am Anjana from USA, California.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/sap-community-where-are-you-from/m-p/14224601#M10375"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:50:39.175000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/can-you-remember-the-first-time-you-heard-of-sap/m-p/14224603#M10376</id>
    <title>Re: Can you remember the first time you heard of SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:53:32.841000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>anjanat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253836</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Yes, clearly SAP was recognized as a safe and secured business intelligence high value ERP software. I woulds say infrastructure as well.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/can-you-remember-the-first-time-you-heard-of-sap/m-p/14224603#M10376"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:53:32.841000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/rehire-with-old-employment-failing-replication/qaa-p/14224605#M48144</id>
    <title>Re: Rehire with Old Employment Failing Replication</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:57:57.498000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>holly_sandvold</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/866961</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/25731"&gt;@emily_nagengast&lt;/a&gt;. We are using the standard EC to ECC replication solution delivered by SAP (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/r/602c38f7400b4d2693602a178c2bf028" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/r/602c38f7400b4d2693602a178c2bf028&lt;/A&gt;), which uses CompoundEmployee API to pickup employees to be replicated. Based on the document here: (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/employee-central-compound-employee-api/hiringnotcompleted-employment-filter?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-employee-central/employee-central-compound-employee-api/hiringnotcompleted-employment-filter?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt;), The hiringNotCompleted filter is used by standard integrations to prevent the replication of incomplete employments. As this is a SAP standard solution, please advise how to use onboarding info to filter out rehired employee in standard solution.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/rehire-with-old-employment-failing-replication/qaa-p/14224605#M48144"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:57:57.498000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-it-possible-to-add-custom-fields-in-quot-create-incoming-invoices-quot/qaq-p/14224607</id>
    <title>Is it possible to add Custom Fields in "Create Incoming Invoices" app?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:59:43.795000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi SAP,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to add a custom field in the application "Create Incoming Invoices".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How can I do this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-it-possible-to-add-custom-fields-in-quot-create-incoming-invoices-quot/qaq-p/14224607"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:59:43.795000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/maintain-tax-rate-with-reference-to-control-code-hsn-for-procurement-india/bc-p/14224606#M61894</id>
    <title>Re: Maintain tax rate with reference to Control Code/HSN for Procurement (India Localization) in SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:59:45.663000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Miguel_Figueiredo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1917734</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;hello,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;tax rates change constantly, is there a procedure to speed up the this change in mass? every week we receive several HSN to update tax rates relation.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/maintain-tax-rate-with-reference-to-control-code-hsn-for-procurement-india/bc-p/14224606#M61894"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:59:45.663000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-it-possible-to-add-custom-fields-in-quot-create-incoming-invoices-quot/qaa-p/14224608#M4227775</id>
    <title>Re: Is it possible to add Custom Fields in "Create Incomi...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T20:59:50.905000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Customer,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system does not support the creation of Custom Fields in Create Incoming Invoices app.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For your reference, check KBA &lt;A href="http://me.sap.com/notes/3555532/e" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3555532 - Adding Custom Fields in FB60 and FB70&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-it-possible-to-add-custom-fields-in-quot-create-incoming-invoices-quot/qaa-p/14224608#M4227775"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T20:59:50.905000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/can-we-put-materials-directly-in-psa-and-consume-it-against-process-order/qaq-p/14224613</id>
    <title>can we put materials directly in PSA and consume it against process order without EWM staging</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:05:45.996000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaghavanKathamuthu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17050</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Business needs the process of producing HALB and keeping it in PSA directly in EWM Storage location. Later they will consume these HALB for FERT production as components from the PSA. Is it possible to consume the HALB to FERT from PSA without staging.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/can-we-put-materials-directly-in-psa-and-consume-it-against-process-order/qaq-p/14224613"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:05:45.996000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/manage-cancellations-app-to-cancel-quantity-confirmations/qaa-p/14224615#M84346</id>
    <title>Re: 'Manage Cancellations' app to cancel quantity confirm...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:11:31.769000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManoelCosta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/175657</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, are you using Order POD? In my understanding, Quantity Confirmation cancellation in Manage Cancellations app is only available for confirmation posted via Order POD using Quantity Confirmation POD Plugin. If you are using that, but Manage Cancellations still don´t show the Quantity Confirmation posting, I suggest you raise a ticket for further investigation. Br, Manoel&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/manage-cancellations-app-to-cancel-quantity-confirmations/qaa-p/14224615#M84346"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:11:31.769000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/rmk-dates-are-refreshing-and-going-on-top-of-the-list-of-job-requisitions/qaq-p/14224616</id>
    <title>RMK Dates are refreshing and going on top of the list of Job Requisitions.</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:16:15.614000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MathieuR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1900541</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently, the dates on the career site RMK shows the reference date and each month they go on top of the list.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am just trying to see if we can change that and always just show the RCM dates from the posting date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/rmk-dates-are-refreshing-and-going-on-top-of-the-list-of-job-requisitions/qaq-p/14224616"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:16:15.614000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/round-up-to-2-decimal-places-compensation-worksheets/qaa-p/14224617#M48146</id>
    <title>Re: Round up to 2 decimal places - Compensation Worksheets</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:19:41.080000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/62583"&gt;@AJFelix&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;I will test and confirm but I do believe that the standard Up rating always round to the full number, not to two decimals. which is the reason for all the examples in my blog. What's stopping you from using a custom formula here ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/round-up-to-2-decimal-places-compensation-worksheets/qaa-p/14224617#M48146"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:19:41.080000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-change-login-screen-design-in-sap-b1/qaa-p/14224619#M4227777</id>
    <title>Re: How to change Login screen design in SAP B1</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:22:39.747000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ana2001</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2105617</uri>
    </author>
    <content>how?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-change-login-screen-design-in-sap-b1/qaa-p/14224619#M4227777"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:22:39.747000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sap-digital-manufacturing-transfer-erp-personnel-number-in-complete-sfc/qaa-p/14224621#M207221</id>
    <title>Re: SAP DIGITAL MANUFACTURING - TRANSFER ERP PERSONNEL NU...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:24:57.150000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManoelCosta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/175657</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Antonio,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Indeed Order POD and Work Center POD Plugins, APIs and overall execution flow are different, and sometimes you will not find the same functionality both here and there... Quantity Confirmartion is an Order POD Plugin/API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That said, during Work Center POD execution flow, once you Complete the Operation,&amp;nbsp;Production Order Yield Confirmation integration is triggered back to ERP which contains&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;ns2:enteredByExternalUser&amp;gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P000300&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;lt;/ns2:enteredByExternalUser&amp;gt; field:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ManoelCosta_0-1758584832185.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318224iC2F2F68D8C6FD24D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ManoelCosta_0-1758584832185.png" alt="ManoelCosta_0-1758584832185.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;which is captured in the confirmation back in ERP (using co14), see:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ManoelCosta_0-1758568967702.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318188i16462DDCE7637CB4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ManoelCosta_0-1758568967702.png" alt="ManoelCosta_0-1758568967702.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, perhaps you can evaluate extending / customizing this integration to map the user badge to 'enteredByExternalUser' field, instead of the user id.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By the way, if you are using Badge Access capability to access POD Pages, please be aware that it is now deprecated since 2508 release, check What’s New for details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope it helps, Manoel&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sap-digital-manufacturing-transfer-erp-personnel-number-in-complete-sfc/qaa-p/14224621#M207221"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:24:57.150000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/blueprints-for-success-landscape-setup-recommendations-for-sap-integration/bc-p/14224623#M184765</id>
    <title>Re: Blueprints for Success: Landscape setup recommendations for SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:25:40.929000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DG</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3313</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;It is interesting to see the evoltion of landscapes over time. I think most people I talk with want to have it all done today, and have the perfect landscape setup.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We see quite a number of customers exploring reusing Non prod for both development and QA, in a virtual tenant. Here they add a QA prefix for all integration. For sure not ideal but it is about saving cost. I guess that probably 50% of customers have this in some format. This messes up your governance unless you have a tool like Figaf to manage it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The same is true with line of business where customers also use prefixes for the different LOB and then use the access controls to the different teams to manage it. There may be a time where an area is too big and then needs it own tenants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Daniel Graversen Figaf.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/blueprints-for-success-landscape-setup-recommendations-for-sap-integration/bc-p/14224623#M184765"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:25:40.929000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/manage-cancellations-app-to-cancel-quantity-confirmations/qaa-p/14224625#M84347</id>
    <title>Re: 'Manage Cancellations' app to cancel quantity confirm...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:28:18.466000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jasantos</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1842253</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello Manoel. Thank you for your response. I’m using the Work Center POD. Is there another way to cancel the confirmed quantity?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/manage-cancellations-app-to-cancel-quantity-confirmations/qaa-p/14224625#M84347"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:28:18.466000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ad-hoc-compensation-planning-step-report/qaq-p/14224626</id>
    <title>Ad hoc Compensation Planning Step Report</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:31:04.795000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pbrandi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/22977</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have a client that tracks step status using the Compensation Planning report.&amp;nbsp; The step field on the report shows the step label except for completed forms. That shows as blank, not "Completed". Is that expected behavior? We added a Completed label to that Route Map step but still does not show.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;pbrandi&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ad-hoc-compensation-planning-step-report/qaq-p/14224626"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:31:04.795000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/your-spreadsheet-on-steroids-6-powerful-new-features-for-the-sac-excel-add/ba-p/14224630</id>
    <title>Your Spreadsheet on Steroids: 6 Powerful New Features for the SAC Excel Add-in</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:40:30.186000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;For data analysts and planners, the debate between the flexibility of Microsoft Excel and the governed power of enterprise platforms like SAP Analytics Cloud is a familiar one. Excel offers unparalleled freedom for ad-hoc analysis, while SAC provides a single source of truth, robust security, and collaborative scale. This often creates a clunky workflow, forcing users to manually rebuild analyses as they move between environments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Recent updates to the SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) add-in for Microsoft Excel are fundamentally changing this dynamic, bridging the gap between these two worlds in powerful and surprising ways. This post highlights four of the most impactful new features that are transforming the add-in from a simple data connector into an indispensable tool for serious analysis and planning.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;1. From Polished Story to Powerful Spreadsheet in a Single Click&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;A significant update in the Q3 / 2025.17 release introduces the ability to transfer a table directly from an SAP Analytics Cloud story into Excel. This isn't just a static copy-paste of values; the transferred table is fully functional within the add-in. It retains the same data source, navigation state (including all dimensions, measures, rows, and columns), filters, and variables that were configured in the story.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This creates an immediate, frictionless pivot from a high-level presentation in a Story to a granular, what-if analysis in Excel. Analysts can now investigate an anomaly they spot in a dashboard without losing a moment of momentum or context rebuilding the query.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Note: You need to migrate your table to the New table experience available from 2025 QRC3 release. The option to open the story in a Excel Add-in needs to be enabled in Table properties in the Builder Panel.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_0-1758567035587.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318181i5C8E87482998B6FA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_0-1758567035587.png" alt="N1kh1l_0-1758567035587.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;This enables Open in Excel Add-in option in Table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_1-1758567141816.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318182i3E9D3D7B67947986/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_1-1758567141816.png" alt="N1kh1l_1-1758567141816.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Eureka, Story opens in Excel with structure and calculations migrated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_2-1758567306206.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318183iB00D7B0002A4BE0A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_2-1758567306206.png" alt="N1kh1l_2-1758567306206.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2. Your Data Now Has a Voice: In-Cell Conversations Arrive&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The 2025.15 release brings collaboration directly to your data cells with the introduction of data point comments. Users can now view and create comments on specific data cells within their Excel tables. Critically, these comments are fully synchronized with SAP Analytics Cloud, meaning a comment added in Excel is immediately visible in the web application, and vice versa.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;To make this even more powerful, the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP.GETDATACOMMENT&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;formula (introduced in version 2025.17) allows you to retrieve these comments programmatically. If multiple comments exist for a data point, the formula returns the last comment of the thread. This development marks a shift from static reporting to true collaborative analysis. The addition of the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP.GETDATACOMMENT&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;formula elevates these comments from simple annotations to query able metadata. This unlocks the ability to build exception reports, dashboards, or even KPIs based on the presence and content of commentary, creating a powerful new layer of qualitative analysis.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Enable data point comments from the Table Option in Designer Panel&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_3-1758567589816.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318184iCF72295D1573280C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_3-1758567589816.png" alt="N1kh1l_3-1758567589816.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will enable a comment widget to add comments&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_4-1758567773862.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318185i4FFA3250B782A731/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_4-1758567773862.png" alt="N1kh1l_4-1758567773862.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;The comments are in sync and can be viewed in web stories also and vice versa.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;3. Enterprise-Grade Guardrails for Your Planning Spreadsheets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;For organizations using the add-in for financial planning, the 2025.17 release delivers a crucial governance enhancement. Data Access Controls (DCS) and Validation Rules that are defined in the central SAP Analytics Cloud model are now automatically applied and visualized directly within the Excel add-in.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This is a critical update because it de-risks the use of Excel for enterprise planning. It allows finance teams to leverage the full flexibility of their preferred tool while ensuring that every input automatically inherits the security, data integrity rules, and governance defined in the central SAC model. The "Wild West" spreadsheet is officially tamed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;4. A Faster, More Intuitive Way to Build Your Analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;A pair of recent user experience enhancements have combined to make the process of building and modifying analyses significantly faster and more intuitive. First, version 2025.13 introduced a resizable builder panel that features a permanent pane listing all available dimensions and measures. This allows for easy browsing and searching of the data source objects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Building on that foundation, version 2025.19 added drag-and-drop functionality. Users can now simply drag objects from the permanent list and drop them into the desired pane (e.g., rows or columns) to build out their table. These&amp;nbsp; updates work together to reduce clicks and streamline the entire analysis design process, letting users get to insights more quickly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_5-1758568798554.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318187iCED6CF6B92DB8847/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_5-1758568798554.png" alt="N1kh1l_5-1758568798554.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;5. Make your sheets colorful&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Now you can add styling and thresholds to your Excel tables. This helps applying corporate colors or creating a more visual appealing layouts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;You can use a list of SAC predefined cell styles or create custom cell styles by duplicating and existing cell styles.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_6-1758569109764.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318189i18B6782C99E760F6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_6-1758569109764.png" alt="N1kh1l_6-1758569109764.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can choose the styling as well as the area of the table layout where it should be applied.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_7-1758569244763.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318190iED9B27D54B3AF3A1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_7-1758569244763.png" alt="N1kh1l_7-1758569244763.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;6. Create Calculated Measure ( Episode 1 : Restricted Measure support)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The long awaited feature of the ability to create calculated measures for your business calculation is now available also in Excel. As a first feature set, only restricted measures are supported. The steps are very similar to how we define calculations in web story. Currently only value based restrictions are supported ( both dimension and attributes). No support for dynamic restrictions for date dimensions like Current Period, prior Period etc. readily available in web stories. Never the less its a good start and I wish to see the remaining features soon. Both restricted accounts and restricted measures are supported.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_8-1758569572788.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318191i8DB2E570DC228C3D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_8-1758569572788.png" alt="N1kh1l_8-1758569572788.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_9-1758569674780.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318192iC6515F06B3A7B8E0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_9-1758569674780.png" alt="N1kh1l_9-1758569674780.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;Already defined Calculations can also be edited if required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Conclusion: A Final Thought&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The SAP Analytics Cloud add-in for Excel is rapidly evolving. It's moving beyond its origins as a simple data connector to become a fully-featured, collaborative, and secure extension of the core platform. By bringing enterprise governance and modern collaboration features into the familiar grid of a spreadsheet, it offers a powerful new paradigm for analysis and planning.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;With these new capabilities fusing the best of Excel and the cloud, what established workflow are you now ready to rethink?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks for reading. I hope you enjoyed the blog.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check the SAP Analytics Cloud topic page for more up to date information&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/cloud-analytics" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/topics/cloud-analytics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;follow and read other informative blog posts on SAC browse the below link&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/tags/67838200100800006884/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://blogs.sap.com/tags/67838200100800006884/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Nikhil&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/your-spreadsheet-on-steroids-6-powerful-new-features-for-the-sac-excel-add/ba-p/14224630"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:40:30.186000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/work-instruction-upload-file-standard-api-example/qaa-p/14224631#M207222</id>
    <title>Re: Work Instruction Upload file standard API Example</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:44:51.066000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManoelCosta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/175657</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, I never tried that one. Have you tried from Business Accelerator Hub (&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/sapdme_workinstruction_file/tryout" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/sapdme_workinstruction_file/tryout&lt;/A&gt;) to see if it works from there? Otherwise, I suggest you raise a ticket for proper investigation and support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Br, Manoel&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/work-instruction-upload-file-standard-api-example/qaa-p/14224631#M207222"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:44:51.066000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-intelligent-search-available-in-beta-phase/bc-p/14224632#M868</id>
    <title>Re: New Intelligent Search Available in Beta Phase</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:48:36.876000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>maher_aljubaily</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255877</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/235"&gt;@LauraPD&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36"&gt;@AnnePetteroe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The new beta search feature significantly improves content discovery across SAP platforms by integrating multiple sources and adding valuable filters, promising a more efficient user experience.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Best Wishes.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-intelligent-search-available-in-beta-phase/bc-p/14224632#M868"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:48:36.876000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/tm-ppf-output-management-for-business-partners-partner-dependent-action/qaa-p/14224633#M207223</id>
    <title>Re: TM PPF Output Management for Business Partners (partn...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:51:19.428000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MatSz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1495883</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Ronald,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/tm-ppf-output-management-for-business-partners-partner-dependent-action/qaa-p/14224633#M207223"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:51:19.428000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/business-partner-role-for-manufacturer/qaa-p/14224635#M4227778</id>
    <title>Re: Business Partner Role for Manufacturer</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:58:36.536000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>WilderPrieto</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1441300</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1480621"&gt;@KeLaw&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, BBP000 role is an old role that most likely will not exist in the current S4 Hana systems. What we did is making a copy of the FLVN01 role to create the Vendor or supplier side general view only, without having to extend it to a purchasing view.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wilder&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/business-partner-role-for-manufacturer/qaa-p/14224635#M4227778"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:58:36.536000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-public-cloud-margin-analysis/qaa-p/14224637#M255342</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public cloud margin analysis</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:59:51.297000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1944157"&gt;@rekafulop&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since your Reference Data &amp;amp; Mapping does not find any records for each sender item, no tracing factors are calculated. This helps clarify why the process doesn't produce results, ensuring it is easier to understand and troubleshoot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fix the Reference Data (source/period/base key figure) and Reference Data Mapping to ensure each sender is mapped to at least one reference record, then re-run in Test.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/sap-public-cloud-margin-analysis/qaa-p/14224637#M255342"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:59:51.297000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/tm-ppf-output-management-for-business-partners-partner-dependent-action/qaa-p/14224638#M207224</id>
    <title>Re: TM PPF Output Management for Business Partners (partner dependent action)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:02:36.319000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MatSz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1495883</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Ronald, You have rised good point. It a pity that such standard conditioning from configuration point of view is not possible like nast or standard BRF+ decision table like we have in purchasing or even better like EWM ppf config options. Right now in most of the cases you need ABAPer. Contact me directly if you want to discuss some other TM relevant topics.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/tm-ppf-output-management-for-business-partners-partner-dependent-action/qaa-p/14224638#M207224"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:02:36.319000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/odata-call-to-rodps-repl-odp-get-detal-for-std-cds-view-gets-cs-sy-move/qaa-p/14224639#M4927094</id>
    <title>Re: ODATA call to RODPS_REPL_ODP_GET_DETAL for std CDS view gets cs_sy_move_cast_error</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:09:03.211000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Janet2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423079</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Continued debugging a bit today - Appears to be here where it fails: lr_hierodp ?= lr_odp. LR_HIERODP is initial and LR_ODP is {O:83*\CLASS-POOL=CL_RODPS_SIMPLE_CONTEXT\CLASS=LCL_ODP}</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/odata-call-to-rodps-repl-odp-get-detal-for-std-cds-view-gets-cs-sy-move/qaa-p/14224639#M4927094"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:09:03.211000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/round-up-to-2-decimal-places-compensation-worksheets/qaa-p/14224640#M48148</id>
    <title>Re: Round up to 2 decimal places - Compensation Worksheets</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:10:47.244000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/62583"&gt;@AJFelix&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Update: through provisioning/xml I was able to enter 1, but seems like nothing lower than 1 is accepted. Had a chat internally and everybody is aligned on the fact that 1 doesn't do what you need here then You'll need to switch your finSalary column to a custom one and use the examples from the blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="xavierlegarrec_0-1758571885373.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318194iF0F2513E785E8454/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="xavierlegarrec_0-1758571885373.png" alt="xavierlegarrec_0-1758571885373.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/round-up-to-2-decimal-places-compensation-worksheets/qaa-p/14224640#M48148"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:10:47.244000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/round-up-to-2-decimal-places-compensation-worksheets/qaa-p/14224642#M48149</id>
    <title>Re: Round up to 2 decimal places - Compensation Worksheets</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:14:02.711000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I feel like I already mentionned this limitation in the blog here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="xavierlegarrec_0-1758572056497.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318195i57B818302E902938/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="xavierlegarrec_0-1758572056497.png" alt="xavierlegarrec_0-1758572056497.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/round-up-to-2-decimal-places-compensation-worksheets/qaa-p/14224642#M48149"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:14:02.711000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ad-hoc-compensation-planning-step-report/qaa-p/14224645#M48150</id>
    <title>Re: Ad hoc Compensation Planning Step Report</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:15:37.677000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/22977"&gt;@pbrandi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;yes that's expected behavior.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ad-hoc-compensation-planning-step-report/qaa-p/14224645#M48150"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:15:37.677000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/odata-call-to-rodps-repl-odp-get-detal-for-std-cds-view-gets-cs-sy-move/qaa-p/14224648#M4927095</id>
    <title>Re: ODATA call to RODPS_REPL_ODP_GET_DETAL for std CDS view gets cs_sy_move_cast_error</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:17:25.759000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Janet2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423079</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I did find OSS notes on that ( lr_hierodp ?= lr_odp.) - however already in our environment</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/odata-call-to-rodps-repl-odp-get-detal-for-std-cds-view-gets-cs-sy-move/qaa-p/14224648#M4927095"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:17:25.759000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/adding-a-hyperlink-to-invoices-and-statements/qaq-p/14224649</id>
    <title>Adding a Hyperlink to invoices and statements</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:20:39.158000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mbennett1268</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255880</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We have recently set up a credit card/ach portal for our customers to make payments.&amp;nbsp; We want to include a hyperlink on our invoices and statements but we are being told that we can't add a hyperlink, it would need to be the full URL or a Tiny URL.&amp;nbsp; It just doesn't look professional and from some research I have done it looks like it is possible to add a hyperlink.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Does anyone have any suggestions or have experience with this?&amp;nbsp; Any help would be greatly appreciated.....thanks!&amp;nbsp; We are currently using SAP S4 HANA 2021 and will be upgrading to 2023 in 2026.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/adding-a-hyperlink-to-invoices-and-statements/qaq-p/14224649"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:20:39.158000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/fiori-app-stock-single-material-stock-columns-missing/qaa-p/14224650#M4927096</id>
    <title>Re: Fiori App Stock - Single Material Stock columns missing</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:28:36.789000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AdelRihan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1507707</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi, I’m facing the same issue, did you manage to solve it?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/fiori-app-stock-single-material-stock-columns-missing/qaa-p/14224650#M4927096"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:28:36.789000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/easy-to-get-in-sap/qaq-p/14224653</id>
    <title>Easy to get in SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:39:15.645000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>maher_aljubaily</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255877</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt; 3 Simple Steps to Break Into the SAP World (No Overwhelm!)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Want to join the $300B+ SAP ecosystem but don’t know where to start? Here’s how to dive in without complexity:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_1:"&gt;1️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Start with FREE Learning&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- Explore SAP Learning Hub (free tier): Bite-sized courses on ERP, S/4HANA, and cloud solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;- Try SAP Community: Tutorials, forums, and real-world use cases. No cost, just curiosity!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_2:"&gt;2️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Pick Your Path&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- For Tech Folks: Learn ABAP (coding) or SAP BTP (low-code/no-code tools).&lt;BR /&gt;- For Business Roles: Focus on Finance (FI), Supply Chain (MM), or HR (HCM) modules.&lt;BR /&gt;- Tip: Start with one module (e.g., SAP S/4HANA Cloud) instead of boiling the ocean.*&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_3:"&gt;3️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Get Hands-On FAST&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- Use SAP Free Trials: Test real systems via GROW with SAP (for new users) or RISE with SAP sandbox.&lt;BR /&gt;- Join SAP’s Partner Ecosystem: Many offer free workshops and certifications (e.g., SAP Learning Journeys).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt; Key Mindset Shift &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;"SAP isn’t just for IT pros—it’s for *problem-solvers. If you understand business processes (finance, logistics, sales), you’re already halfway there."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; Your First Move Today: &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Bookmark: [SAP Learning](&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Join: [SAP Community](&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Try: Free SAP S/4HANA Cloud trial (search "SAP Free Trials").&lt;BR /&gt;and don't forget to look at Youtube&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face_with_big_eyes:"&gt;😃&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You don’t need a Ph.D. in tech—just a structured start. What’s your SAP goal? Let’s chat below! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_down:"&gt;👇&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Warm Wishes&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkling_heart:"&gt;💖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/easy-to-get-in-sap/qaq-p/14224653"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:39:15.645000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/cascading-budget-and-planner-hierarchy/qaa-p/14224654#M48151</id>
    <title>Re: Cascading Budget and Planner Hierarchy</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:40:10.875000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1474092"&gt;@atulei&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Sorry but what do you mean by "the approach" ? if you mean how to configure, then you simply need to change the hierarchy in plan setup &amp;gt; define planners, then it works the same for budget cascading.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/cascading-budget-and-planner-hierarchy/qaa-p/14224654#M48151"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:40:10.875000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-avoid-the-unnecessary-js-calls-in-the-sap-fiori-custom-application/qaa-p/14224655#M4927097</id>
    <title>Re: how to avoid the unnecessary js calls in the sap fior...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T22:44:23.096000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>boghyon</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/273</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;There are multiple possible reasons for the behavior described in the question. Try following all steps mentioned in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/49819099/5846045" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/a/49819099/5846045&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;which addresses the same issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the issue is reproducible only in FLP despite using the same SAPUI5 version during the development time in BAS, create an &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/getsupport" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP support&lt;/A&gt; ticket as the issue might be in the FLP code.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-avoid-the-unnecessary-js-calls-in-the-sap-fiori-custom-application/qaa-p/14224655#M4927097"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T22:44:23.096000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/journal-entry-reverse-api/qaa-p/14224656#M255344</id>
    <title>Re: Journal Entry Reverse Api</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T23:02:02.571000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2024165"&gt;@gulcinakcay1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An HTTP 500 error on the Journal Entry, Reverse (SOAP) service is almost always caused by a payload or envelope problem. In Public Cloud, the reversal request must utilise the Reverse service endpoint/WSDL, and specify the original document using CompanyCode, AccountingDocument, and FiscalYear separately, not as a single combined value. Go through the information on this SAP Documentation below&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/b978f98fc5884ff2aeb10c8fdeb8a43b/57b40036b71f4825adad70a0a5b91573.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Journal Entry – Reverse&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the Minimal working envelope (example)-in the box&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me know if it works&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/journal-entry-reverse-api/qaa-p/14224656#M255344"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T23:02:02.571000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-cpi-jdbc-on-premise-database-connectivity-error/qaa-p/14224657#M4927098</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CPI: JDBC On-premise database connectivity error</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T23:16:59.037000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ostosjuan99</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/161186</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Kiran, did you find the solution?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-cpi-jdbc-on-premise-database-connectivity-error/qaa-p/14224657#M4927098"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T23:16:59.037000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-how-to-seamlessly-upgrade-your-tenant-to-a-higher/bc-p/14224658#M184766</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Integration Suite - How to seamlessly upgrade your tenant to a higher service plan</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T23:29:18.141000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>manubhutani</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17674</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the informative blog. I understand that all artifacts stay intact when upgrade from starter to standard edition is done. We don’t need to export artifacts as a back up. Could you please confirm the understanding?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-how-to-seamlessly-upgrade-your-tenant-to-a-higher/bc-p/14224658#M184766"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T23:29:18.141000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/implementation-of-a-taxable-entity-across-system-boundaries-public-cloud/qaa-p/14224659#M255345</id>
    <title>Re: Implementation of a taxable entity across system boundaries (public cloud ↔ private cloud) using</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T23:31:17.107000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>martinlitalin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/576792</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi, there is no such thing as a hybrid solution using Lobster for the submission substituting for CPI or BTP. All DRC scenarios are architected, developed and delivered with SAP middleware only, anything else would a "Frankenstein" solution. Please feel free to contact me if you need more information. Thank you.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/implementation-of-a-taxable-entity-across-system-boundaries-public-cloud/qaa-p/14224659#M255345"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T23:31:17.107000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/setting-default-values-in-rap-entity-creation-default-values-functions/bc-p/14224661#M175597</id>
    <title>Re: Setting Default Values in RAP Entity Creation: Default Values Functions, Actions, and Augmentati</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T23:33:39.152000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MioYasutake</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/789</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6604"&gt;@vishnucta&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For setting key fields, you need to use either the Late Numbering or Early Numbering method.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/setting-default-values-in-rap-entity-creation-default-values-functions/bc-p/14224661#M175597"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T23:33:39.152000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-from-provisioning-to-intelligent-applications/ba-p/14224669</id>
    <title>SAP Business Data Cloud - From Provisioning to Intelligent Applications</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T23:57:28.150000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hkaur</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83605</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction to SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we will try to go over the Introduction to SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) and then the Components and Building Blocks of SAP BDC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BDC is a fully managed software-as-a-service (SaaS) offering from SAP designed to address this need of managing vast volumes of data originating from diverse systems. It consolidates and governs all SAP data while seamlessly integrating third-party sources, delivering contextualized, trusted data to business leaders for more impactful decision-making. By harmonizing mission-critical data into a unified semantic layer, the platform eliminates the overhead of data extraction and replication.&amp;nbsp; Supporting a wide range of use cases across industries and business functions, SAP BDC ensures that data is consistently accessible, secure, and ready for advanced analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Aspects of SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Intelligent Applications:&lt;/EM&gt; AI-driven apps that leverage your data and business context to automate processes, adapt dynamically, and drive transformative outcomes in real time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Data Products&lt;/EM&gt;: Prebuilt, customizable, and governed data assets that come enriched with business semantics, documentation, and APIs—accelerating deployment across a wide range of use cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Business Data Fabric&lt;/EM&gt;: A comprehensive data and analytics foundation that integrates SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, modernized SAP Business Warehouse, data engineering capabilities, and AI/ML innovations through SAP Databricks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;AI-Enriched Decision Making:&lt;/EM&gt; Enterprise-grade tools that deliver responsible, context-aware AI for reporting and analytics —empowering smarter, faster decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Components of SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Source Systems:&lt;/EM&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP BDC connects seamlessly to various source systems—such as SAP S/4HANA—to identify and extract key business data entities. These include tables, views, and other structures that contain mission-critical data across domains like HR, finance, supply chain. By integrating with these systems, SAP BDC ensures that foundational business data is readily available for analytics, governance, and intelligent application development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Foundational Services in SAP Business Data Cloud:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Within SAP BDC, data extracted from source systems flows into the Foundation Services layer. This foundational component is responsible for ingesting, integrating, cleansing, and harmonizing both structured and unstructured data. It ensures that the data is properly aligned and enriched as part of SAP-managed Data Products, forming the backbone of trusted, analytics-ready information across the SAP BDC landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Datasphere:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Datasphere serves as the modeling and governance layer atop the BDC Semantic Layer. It provides a robust set of tools for designing analytical data models, defining business logic, managing data lineage, enforcing governance and security.&amp;nbsp;In addition to its core modeling capabilities, SAP Datasphere supports machine learning and AI extensions, making it a foundational component for advanced analytics and intelligent decision-making.&amp;nbsp;Datasphere acts as the data engine behind SAP Analytics Cloud, feeding it with both prebuilt and custom insights for reporting and visualization.&amp;nbsp;It also enables customers to create custom data products using the SAP Datasphere Object Store, which supports zero-copy data access via the Delta Sharing Protocol - ensuring efficient, secure, and scalable data sharing across the enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Databricks:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Databricks is a specialized integration of the Databricks platform embedded directly within SAP BDC. It combines industry-leading capabilities in AI, machine learning, data science, and data engineering with semantically rich, business-ready data from SAP applications.&amp;nbsp;This component significantly enhances analytics by enabling generative AI scenarios—without the need for complex data pipelines. Through zero-copy Delta Sharing, SAP Databricks connects directly to SAP Data Products, allowing seamless access and enrichment of data without replication.&amp;nbsp;By bridging enterprise-grade SAP data with the flexibility of Databricks, organizations can accelerate innovation, streamline operations, and unlock deeper insights across their business landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt; SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/EM&gt; empowers business analytics by directly consuming integrated data from the SAP Datasphere component within BDC. It supports rich visualization, reporting, and AI-driven analytics across the enterprise—all within a unified, cloud-based SaaS environment.&amp;nbsp;By leveraging semantically aligned data from Datasphere, SAC enables organizations to generate actionable insights, build dynamic dashboards, and drive informed decision-making at scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP BW and SAP BW/4HANA Integration:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; To support legacy compatibility, SAP BW and SAP BW/4HANA objects can be technically onboarded into SAP BDC. This integration enables organizations to migrate data and maintain hybrid use cases—bridging traditional data warehousing with modern cloud-based analytics—until the official end-of-support timeline for BW systems.&amp;nbsp;By incorporating BW artifacts into BDC, businesses can preserve existing investments while gradually transitioning to a unified, governed, and AI-ready data landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building Blocks of SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Provisioning an SAP Business Data Cloud Tenant&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An SAP BDC tenant is provisioned via the SAP for Me portal using a guided, self-service workflow. This process enables organizations to activate and configure the components of SAP Business Data Cloud according to their commercial entitlements. The provisioning journey begins with the BDC Core Component or Cockpit, which serves as the central management interface for the entire SAP BDC landscape.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2.png" style="width: 936px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318201i2A1FD77C8913CE6C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.png" alt="2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the BDC cockpit is provisioned, the next step is to provision (from SAP for Me) the core capabilities and applications, including: SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Databricks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="3.png" style="width: 936px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318202iA5701E426BFF6EA2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.png" alt="3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After these systems are successfully provisioned through SAP for Me, users can&amp;nbsp; begin creating Formations—structured configurations that define how data products and applications are orchestrated across the landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Formation in SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A Formation in SAP Business Data Cloud is a logical grouping of SAP systems and related components designed to support specific business scenarios or integration use cases. Formations simplify connectivity and provide a unified view of all systems, making it easier to manage integrations, extensions, and orchestrate data across the SAP BDC landscape.&amp;nbsp; Formations are created by selecting the required SAP systems—these must first be provisioned via the SAP for Me portal. Once provisioned, they appear in the Systems tab of the portal and can be included in one or more formations.&amp;nbsp;Each formation can consist of multiple systems such as SAP BDC Core, SAP S/4HANA Cloud, SAP BW, SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Databricks.&amp;nbsp;These systems are synchronized within the formation to enable streamlined operations and cohesive business processes. Multiple formations can be created to support extended or complex business scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4.png" style="width: 624px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318203i511CFE0F987849C2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4.png" alt="4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Benefits of Using Formations&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simplified Integration: Centralizes the grouping and management of systems required for a business scenario.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scalability and Flexibility: Easily add or remove systems as organizational needs evolve.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Governance and Control: Enables centralized configuration and oversight, improving compliance and reducing maintenance overhead.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Data Products in Business Data Cloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An SAP Data Product is a curated and refined dataset derived from data ingested from SAP solutions. It encompasses a Business Data Set that includes master data, transactional records, analytics datasets, and configuration data—all semantically aligned to ensure consistency and usability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These datasets are enriched with meaningful metadata and documentation, making them easily consumable and understandable. Within the SAP BDC, Data Products serve as the core building blocks for Intelligent Applications, enabling advanced analytics and decision-making.&amp;nbsp; SAP delivers and manages these Data Products as part of its SaaS offering, maintaining full lifecycle ownership. However, customers can customize them to suit specific business needs. Each Data Product includes all necessary artifacts—such as CDS views, connectors, flows, jobs, and lifecycle management tools—required to support its associated use cases within SAP BDC. They are easily discoverable through the SAP BDC product catalog.&amp;nbsp;These products are designed by line-of-business experts to help organizations maximize the value of their data.&amp;nbsp;Types of Data Products&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Primary Data Products: Directly sourced from applications, representing original data from systems like SAP S/4HANA. They are not derived from other data products.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Derived Data Products: Built by SAP using existing datasets or APIs. This offer added value by combining or transforming data from multiple sources.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Custom or Customer Managed Data Products :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;SAP BDC also supports custom data products, which can be curated within SAP Datasphere. These leverage the Datasphere Object Store and Delta Sharing Protocol, enabling zero-copy data access for efficient and secure data sharing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="5.png" style="width: 936px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318204iDAF60D3D21DD512B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.png" alt="5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Intelligent Applications in SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Intelligent Applications are AI-driven, visualization-centric solutions designed to address specific business scenarios. Unlike general-purpose analytics tools, these applications are built with SAP-managed analytical assets and functionalities that deliver value through process, domain, or analytical intelligence. They typically include data products, semantic models, and SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) stories.&amp;nbsp;These applications foster collaboration between analytics and data science teams by providing ready-made dashboards enriched with AI-generated insights. Their embedded business logic and contextual data models eliminate the need for organizations to build complex analytical frameworks from scratch—saving time and resources.&amp;nbsp;The core structure of Intelligent Applications includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAC Stories&lt;/EM&gt;: Serve as the front-end interface, offering rich visualizations tailored to specific analytics use cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Datasphere Models and Views&lt;/EM&gt;: Includes the backend logic and data orchestration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Semantic Models and Story Templates&lt;/EM&gt;: Combined to deliver reusable, customizable dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These applications are cataloged within the SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC), making them easy to discover, deploy, and extend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Installation and Customization&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To explore and install Intelligent Applications:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in to the SAP BDC Cockpit. Browse the available applications and their documentation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Upon installation, a suite of artifacts is deployed across SAP Datasphere and SAP Analytics Cloud, including Data Products, Replication Flows, Tables and Views, Analytic Models, Roles and Dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Customization Guidelines&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP-managed applications and their dependencies are read-only, but users can copy and adapt components.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC Stories can be duplicated and tailored to meet specific business needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For advanced scenarios, users may replicate and modify the underlying analytic models ( within SAP Datasphere).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Changes to models will affect both the original and copied stories, so version control and impact analysis are recommended.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Key Differentiation between Business Content and Intelligent Applications&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Content provides a set of pre-built models and other artifacts, but customers manage the implementation, configuration and maintenance of these solutions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intelligent Applications are fully managed and curated by SAP and delivered as software-as-a-service designed to cater specific business use cases or scenarios.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="6.png" style="width: 631px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318206i3E791D381E766A91/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6.png" alt="6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps you understand the basics and get started on SAP Business Data Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-from-provisioning-to-intelligent-applications/ba-p/14224669"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T23:57:28.150000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/profit-center-difference-in-round-off-difference-g-l-when-incoming-payment/qaa-p/14224670#M255346</id>
    <title>Re: Profit center Difference in Round off Difference G/L...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T23:59:45.708000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>divyeshSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1949499</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1945152"&gt;@Dasun_T&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Did you try 3KEH for assigning a default center and then 3KEI for company code level?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="1041"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113"&gt;Transaction Code&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Purpose&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Account Type&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Usage / Example&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Outcome&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113"&gt;3KEH&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Automatic account assignment of Revenue &amp;amp; Cost Elements&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;P&amp;amp;L Accounts (Primary cost elements, Revenues, Expenses)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Assign default profit centers to revenue/cost G/Ls (e.g., Sales, COGS, Rent Expense)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Ensures P&amp;amp;L postings flow into Profit Center Accounting even if no profit center is provided&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113"&gt;3KEI&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Automatic account assignment of Balance Sheet Accounts&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Balance Sheet Accounts (Assets, Liabilities, Inventory, GR/IR, Banks)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Assign default profit centers to balance sheet accounts (e.g., Fixed Assets, Inventory, Payables, Bank)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="232"&gt;Keeps Balance Sheet postings complete in Profit Center Accounting and prevents imbalances&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you find my response helpful, kindly accept the answer and award a Kudos. This motivates me to serve you better.&lt;BR /&gt;Appreciate your feedback.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Divyesh&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/profit-center-difference-in-round-off-difference-g-l-when-incoming-payment/qaa-p/14224670#M255346"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T23:59:45.708000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/asset-good-receive-reverse-miss-asset-document/qaa-p/14224671#M255347</id>
    <title>Re: Asset good Receive Reverse miss asset document</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:03:38.306000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>divyeshSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1949499</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2052045"&gt;@sap_ecs91&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;MIGO 102 only handles the logistics/FI side → no asset impact.&lt;BR /&gt;To see corrections in AW01N, you must reverse the invoice (MR8M) or asset posting (AB08). Below is the summary how each process impacts MM/FI and Asset accounting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="832"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="184"&gt;Process Step&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="77"&gt;Transaction&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185"&gt;Impact in FI (Accounting Document)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Impact in AA (Asset Document / AW01N)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Remarks&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="184"&gt;Goods Receipt for Asset (AuC)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="77"&gt;MIGO 101&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185"&gt;GR/IR cleared, asset clearing posted&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Asset updated (asset document created, AuC value increases)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Standard integration works&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="184"&gt;Goods Return / Cancellation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="77"&gt;MIGO 102&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185"&gt;FI reversal only (GR/IR reversed)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;No update in Asset Accounting&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Standard SAP behavior – asset not reversed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="184"&gt;Invoice Receipt&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="77"&gt;MIRO&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185"&gt;Vendor &amp;amp; GR/IR updated&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Asset updated (AuC value increases if assigned)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Links logistics &amp;amp; AA&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="184"&gt;Invoice Reversal&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="77"&gt;MR8M&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185"&gt;FI reversal&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Asset reversed (asset document reduces value)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Needed if MIRO already done&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="184"&gt;Asset Posting Reversal&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="77"&gt;AB08&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185"&gt;FI reversal&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Asset document reversed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Used if acquisition posted directly in AA&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="184"&gt;Movement Type Settings&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="77"&gt;OMJJ&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185"&gt;Controls FI postings&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;Can control AA integration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="193"&gt;By default, 102 does not update assets&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you find my response helpful, kindly accept the answer and award a Kudos. This motivates me to serve you better.&lt;BR /&gt;Appreciate your feedback.&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Divyesh&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/asset-good-receive-reverse-miss-asset-document/qaa-p/14224671#M255347"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:03:38.306000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-handle-tax-included-items/qaa-p/14224672#M255348</id>
    <title>Re: How to handle tax-included items</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:23:49.945000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2023369"&gt;@yahaha&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your question,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA public cloud can handle tax-included gross pricing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check this SAP KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3107122" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3107122 - How to avoid errors caused by very small gross prices when using gross pricing procedures - SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me know if you need further information&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/how-to-handle-tax-included-items/qaa-p/14224672#M255348"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:23:49.945000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-from-provisioning-to-intelligent-applications/bc-p/14224673#M184768</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Business Data Cloud - From Provisioning to Intelligent Applications</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:28:55.289000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Afshin_IR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1488791</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83605"&gt;@hkaur&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Great Blog as an introduction . Keep them coming.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Afshin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-from-provisioning-to-intelligent-applications/bc-p/14224673#M184768"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:28:55.289000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/changing-database-connection-via-applylogoninfo/qaq-p/14224677</id>
    <title>Changing Database connection via ApplyLogonInfo</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:39:51.566000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bernhardz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1920580</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I need to change a Crystal Report Template originally created in V10 using the native Btrieve database access to use a Pervasive ODBC connection and all my attempts to programmatically change the template have failed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am using Crystal Report for Visual Studio 2022 and the associated x64 runtime. I have my x64 ODBC connection configured and connect successfully to the Pervasive SQL database via the ODBC driver.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I can manually change the Report Template in Crystal 2020 and revise the connection parameters, save the template and the report connects correctly. Since the parameters are saved with the report, when I then go through my runtime configuration, nothing changes, and the report connects to the database correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have attempted:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Creating a ConnectionInfo object and setting its properties. Then I loop through all tables, obtain the LogonInfo object from the table and assign the ConnectionInfo. Then I call the Table.ApplyLogonInfo. The table's connection info is not changed, and the old, no longer compatible information is still present, resulting in an error when connection to the database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. My second approach was looping through all tables, retrieving the LogonInfo and settings its ConnectionInfo properties manually, then applying the Table.ApplyLogonInfo. Same result.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have read various posts with the same issue without any clear solution. One of my guesses is that if the ApplyLogonInfo fails for some reason, it reverts back to the original parameters in the template. One of my questions is also regarding the parameter values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My ODBC connection DSN name = PF_WORK, the database name = WORKBERNHARD and the physical server = PF1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Where should these above parameters applied to the ConnectionInfo?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please advise,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;TIA&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bernhard&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/changing-database-connection-via-applylogoninfo/qaq-p/14224677"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:39:51.566000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/do-we-need-a-separate-company-code-for-hungarian-subsidiary/qaa-p/14224689#M255349</id>
    <title>Re: Do We Need a Separate Company Code for Hungarian Subs...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:57:06.053000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1649552"&gt;@Wayne10&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your questions. If a Hungarian legal entity subsidiary exists, you should set up a separate Hungarian company code. In SAP, a company code is a self-contained statutory accounting unit. You will need one for each legal entity to maintain separate books, currencies, and country-specific requirements settings. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/6b39bd1d0e5e4099a5b65d835c29c696/3a27d153c9684608e10000000a174cb4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Company Code&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If there is no Hungarian legal entity,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;the German entity trades in HU under a HU VAT ID, you can retain the German company code and use RITA (Registration for Indirect Taxation Abroad) to calculate and report Hungarian VAT under a foreign tax registration. Activate RITA for the company code and keep the Tax Registration Countries/Regions updated for Hungary. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/f86dc2eb1f8b48c880a7607213104b27/3679262219a14fed9f715143ead46a86.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Registration for Indirect Taxation Abroad (RITA) in Product Master Data&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;E-invoicing and reporting in Hungary:&lt;/EM&gt; Hungary mandates real-time invoice reporting (RTIR) through the tax authority. SAP provides this feature in Document and Reporting Compliance (DRC) for Hungary. If you will issue invoices reportable in Hungary, ensure you set up DRC Hungary and verify whether your process involves a HU company code or a foreign VAT registration scenario. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/e3843957b79a4b828c4187f3c45df09a/57daab41d13142fa88981c02a7acfc51.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Document and Reporting Compliance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Summary of best practices&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;HU subsidiary becomes a separate HU company code. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/6b39bd1d0e5e4099a5b65d835c29c696/3a27d153c9684608e10000000a174cb4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Company Code&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No HU entity → Use DE company code together with RITA and HU VAT registration. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/f86dc2eb1f8b48c880a7607213104b27/3679262219a14fed9f715143ead46a86.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Registration for Indirect Taxation Abroad (RITA) in Product Master Data&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure or update organisational data in SAP Central Business Configuration when adding a new country or company code. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/b249d650b15e4b3d9fc2077ee921abd0/e7183d8af1444a249411f8bdcbc23ea9.html?q=Central+Business+Configuration+in+Public+Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Adding New Company Code to Country&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Other useful SAP Learning materials&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/implementing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/defining-scope-and-localizations" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning-Defining Localizations and Scope&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/unlocking-tax-transformation-with-sap/indirect-tax-and-sap-s-4hana_LE_2e76974c-c226-4c98-b0ed-c5a75142ad1b" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning-Indirect tax and SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me know if you need further support&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/do-we-need-a-separate-company-code-for-hungarian-subsidiary/qaa-p/14224689#M255349"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:57:06.053000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introduction-to-alert-rule-sets-in-sap-hana-cloud-central/ba-p/14223552</id>
    <title>Introduction to Alert Rule Sets in SAP HANA Cloud Central</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:57:50.208000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Hai</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160136</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud has advanced its monitoring and alerting capabilities by introducing Alert Rule Sets. Building on previous &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/mastering-alert-configuration-in-sap-hana-cloud-central-a-comprehensive/ba-p/14134933" target="_self"&gt;alert configuration methods&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/streamlining-alert-management-in-sap-hana-cloud-leveraging-rest-apis-for/ba-p/14081496" target="_self"&gt;REST API-based bulk management&lt;/A&gt;, Alert Rule Sets offer a graphical interface for bulk alert configuration accessible to all administrators without API expertise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890008545"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Are Alert Rule Sets?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable configuration of multiple alert rules at once and apply them across one or more HANA Cloud instances.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create reusable alert configurations usable across different environments such as development, testing, and production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Each user can maintain up to 20 alert rule sets for better organization and flexibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693495040"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Efficiency:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Bulk management reduces manual configuration effort.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scalability:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Supports large enterprise deployments with complex environments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified Maintenance:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Updating an alert rule set updates all associated instances.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496981535"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Create and Manage Alert Rule Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1429550749"&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Requires SAP HANA Cloud administrator role for creating or updating alert rule sets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud viewer role suffices for read-only access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alert rule sets cannot be created or modified for Data Lake instances, which only support read-only alert viewing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1233037244"&gt;Configuration Steps&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Alert Rules Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt; page and choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Alert Rule Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Then select &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Alert Rule Set&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="create rule set.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317600i6EE4A3B047B0EAD5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="create rule set.png" alt="create rule set.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new alert rule set by naming it and providing a description. Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Next&lt;/STRONG&gt; to configure alert rules.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="step 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317601iACD9A1866DA6881A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="step 1.png" alt="step 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure alert rules by selecting which alerts to include, adjusting thresholds, and setting their status. Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Next&lt;/STRONG&gt; to configure instance. Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Now&lt;/STRONG&gt; to save the set and jump to the review page without configuring instances that apply this alert rule set.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="step 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317610iB721A829D6538B71/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="step 2.png" alt="step 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select target HANA Cloud instances to apply the rule set. Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Review&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="step 3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317603iB6BA60E59418F333/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="step 3.png" alt="step 3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review and apply the configuration to deploy.&amp;nbsp;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Save and Apply&lt;/STRONG&gt; to create the set and apply it. If the process is successful, the time stamp of the application will be visible under the Last Applied field. Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt; to create the set without applying it to one or more instances.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="step 4.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317604i38359073586C2235/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="step 4.png" alt="step 4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1036523739"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;View Alert Rule Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Alert Rules Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt; page, choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Alert Rule Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt; to see a list of your sets. Select a row to see more information about the set, including its name, description, status, and alert rules that are part of the set.&amp;nbsp;In the Instances section you can see if the set is Applied or Not Applied to the instances you chose. There are several reasons why an instance appears under the Not Applied section:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You have saved the set without applying it to the chosen instances.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;There has been an error during the application, for example, a server problem.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You (or another user) have modified alert rules that are part of the set elsewhere, for example, in the basic configuration or in another set. For more information, see &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud/sap-hana-cloud-administration-guide/alerts" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using Alerts in SAP HANA Cloud Central&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rule set manage.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317605iF74A77326F788DE8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rule set manage.png" alt="rule set manage.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="manage set.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317606i514BF2A88CB43B6E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="manage set.png" alt="manage set.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-840010234"&gt;Modify Alert Rule Sets&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;You can edit, rename, and delete the set from the details page or from the list page, choosing &lt;STRONG&gt;... (More)&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the Actions column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="edit set.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317608i805F23C85BB0A577/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="edit set.png" alt="edit set.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;After modifying alert rules in a set, reapply the set to your selected instances to incorporate the latest changes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="apply change.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317609iF110B8B9B6162AB7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="apply change.png" alt="apply change.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-514414010"&gt;Best Practices for Alert Rule Sets&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use descriptive, consistent naming conventions (e.g., PROD-HighPerf-CriticalAlerts).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Establish a review schedule to maintain relevance as infrastructure evolves.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintain comprehensive documentation for governance and clarity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-317900505"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The UI and API Bridge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alert Rule Sets represent a convergence of REST API automation and a user-friendly UI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;API automation remains available for DevOps and infrastructure-as-code automation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both approaches can be combined for hybrid workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-121387000"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alert Rule Sets signify a critical advancement in SAP HANA Cloud’s alert management, enabling scalable, efficient, and consistent alert configuration across multiple instances. This feature supports enterprises as they grow their HANA Cloud deployments by simplifying alert management complexities and providing both powerful automation and ease of use.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this tool, administrators gain enhanced operational efficiency and consistency, supporting hundreds of instances if needed, making monitoring more flexible and user-friendly.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introduction-to-alert-rule-sets-in-sap-hana-cloud-central/ba-p/14223552"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:57:50.208000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/429-too-many-requests-error-on-sap-commerce-clouds/qaq-p/14224690</id>
    <title>429 Too many requests error on SAP Commerce CLouds</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T01:05:10.353000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the scope on commerce integration with S4, via CPI, when performing the full material load, we are getting 429 too many requests. Which is the rate limit which is setup in Commerce? can it be increased?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/429-too-many-requests-error-on-sap-commerce-clouds/qaq-p/14224690"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T01:05:10.353000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/429-too-many-requests-error-on-sap-commerce-clouds/qaa-p/14224691#M457864</id>
    <title>Re: 429 Too many requests error on SAP Commerce CLouds</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T01:05:17.569000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The rate limit feature is available on the endpoint level and can be configured in four level:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;No limit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;there is no limit to active open connections. This was the default configuration before the implementation of WAF in&amp;nbsp;SAP Commerce Cloud.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Small:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;threshold of 50 requests, five-second cooldown.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Medium:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;threshold of 500 requests, five-second cooldown.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Large:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;threshold of 5000 requests, five-second cooldown.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can know more about this using KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003403719" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3403719&lt;/A&gt; - HTTP 429 Too Many Requests - SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/429-too-many-requests-error-on-sap-commerce-clouds/qaa-p/14224691#M457864"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T01:05:17.569000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/browser-content-area-in-enable-now-is-capturing-entire-browser/qaa-p/14224692#M48152</id>
    <title>Re: Browser Content Area in Enable Now is capturing entir...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T01:14:31.320000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>salisbury54</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/804935</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Adding a little more to the scenario, I run producer on my PC and have this issue but if I use the same PC to logon to a virtual desktop, everything works fine in both Chrome and Edge. Very strange. Same PC but different settings based on VDI settings changing something.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/browser-content-area-in-enable-now-is-capturing-entire-browser/qaa-p/14224692#M48152"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T01:14:31.320000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/error-in-smq2-for-inbound-delivery-quot-the-assert-condition-was-violated/qaa-p/14224693#M207225</id>
    <title>Re: Error in SMQ2 for inbound Delivery"The ASSERT conditi...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T01:26:56.666000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaghavanKathamuthu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17050</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;On my case batch number of process order and component was not there in EWM as its decentralized. Since created it manually in EWM via MSC2n to solve the issue.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/error-in-smq2-for-inbound-delivery-quot-the-assert-condition-was-violated/qaa-p/14224693#M207225"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T01:26:56.666000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/error-in-smq2-for-inbound-delivery-quot-the-assert-condition-was-violated/qaa-p/14224694#M207226</id>
    <title>Re: Error in SMQ2 for inbound Delivery"The ASSERT conditi...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T01:27:41.593000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaghavanKathamuthu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17050</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;On my case batch number of process order and component was not there in EWM as its decentralized. Since created it manually in EWM via MSC1n to solve the issue.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/error-in-smq2-for-inbound-delivery-quot-the-assert-condition-was-violated/qaa-p/14224694#M207226"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T01:27:41.593000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/rework-process-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-process-manufacturing/qaa-p/14224695#M207227</id>
    <title>Re: Rework Process in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition (P...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T01:29:24.015000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1961193"&gt;@MohamedKharbouch&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consider consulting &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/84dbf30eedb4450983dc3d1c81b71996/f6ff965653691e5ee10000000a4450e5.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manufacturing&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/2508/SolP/BJN?region=DE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Rework Processing – Stock-Manufactured Material (BJN)&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F5323')/S23OP" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Process Order Operations&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/2bba750d1e124e1ea2a039bb1cd9b6c5/39bd6d57284f346ae10000000a4450e5.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Process Order Confirmation Object Page&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarise, based on the details you provided, a reworks scenario like you described can be done with a dedicated rework recipe and process order.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First is to model a rework recipe in the manage recipes app, where the nonconforming FG is the input and the conforming FG, co-products and scrap are the outputs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Then you should create a rework process order in the manage process order app, making sure you reference the rework recipe.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;During the order confirmation, ensure you issue the nonconforming FG as input and record receipts of conforming FG as input and record receipts of conforming FG, co-products and scrap.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please note that costs will then be collected on the rework order and can be settled accordingly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This approach I mentioned above will ensure transparency of materials flows; it will help you correct cost allocation and traceability in line with process industry best practices.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Should you often carry out rework, consider maintaining a dedicated order type for rework to distinguish it from standard production.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. Happy to answer any further questions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/rework-process-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-process-manufacturing/qaa-p/14224695#M207227"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T01:29:24.015000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/sap-public-cloud-outbound-del-and-inspection-lot-in-different-plants-to/qaa-p/14224701#M84348</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud: Outbound Del. and Inspection Lot in...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T01:44:05.376000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1485573"&gt;@AM1987&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Have a look at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/2805020" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KBA 2805020&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d1e58be39d884a0dbf75a7526a9acbf4/dc733e09815e41d3b0591bfd7640f1b9.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Quality Certificates&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F2378')/S14OP" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Certifications&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/quality-certificate-for-delivery/qaq-p/5613580" target="_blank"&gt;Quality certificate for Delivery&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, the summary is, the quality certificate generation is plant-dependent in public cloud. The inspection lot and the outbound delivery must belong to the same plant for the system to pull the results and generate the certificate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you inspection lot exists in a different plant, the certificate cannot be automatically retrieved in the delivery process, therefore aligning with the systems standard behaviour in public cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You have the options to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure that the inspection lot is created in the shipping plant&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alternatively, you can generate the quality certificate directly from the inspection lot plant and then attach it manually to the outbound delivery document.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/sap-public-cloud-outbound-del-and-inspection-lot-in-different-plants-to/qaa-p/14224701#M84348"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T01:44:05.376000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/5-things-you-didn-t-know-about-sap-joule-for-developers-plus-an-exciting/ba-p/14224703</id>
    <title>5 Things You Didn’t Know About SAP Joule for Developers — Plus an Exciting Update</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T01:53:30.531000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HaHoang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1673814</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Artificial intelligence is reshaping how we work, and developers are among the first to feel the impact. SAP Joule for Developers is&amp;nbsp;a collection of AI capabilities in SAP Build and ABAP Environment designed to help developers build smarter, faster, and more intuitively — whether you’re streamlining repetitive coding tasks or creating complex integrations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And here’s the big news:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The free promotion for SAP Joule for Developers has been extended.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That means you now have even more time to explore Joule, experiment with projects, and see firsthand how it can transform your workflows — &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;all at no cost&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are hosting an engaging &lt;STRONG&gt;webinar&lt;/STRONG&gt; with demos, use cases and best practices on how to maximize value with Joule in SAP Build. Read till the end to find the registration link!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Without further ado, here are five things you might not know about SAP Joule for Developers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890040104"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. It’s More Than Just an AI Assistant&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HaHoang_0-1758584515204.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318220i883D09392294E961/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="HaHoang_0-1758584515204.png" alt="HaHoang_0-1758584515204.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Many developers see Joule as just a chatbot. But it’s far more powerful. Joule for Developers goes beyond simple answers — it integrates into your workflow, generates context-aware code suggestions, and automates repetitive tasks. Whether you’re building in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, working in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, or connecting with third-party services, Joule is designed to keep your productivity high.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Learn more about capabilities via our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-for-developers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;webpage&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693526599"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It Speaks “Developer” Fluently&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HaHoang_1-1758584515206.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318221iA41684708356D4FF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="HaHoang_1-1758584515206.png" alt="HaHoang_1-1758584515206.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule understands technical prompts and adapts its recommendations to your specific context. Describe what you want to create, and Joule can generate API calls, reusable code snippets, or even integration patterns tailored to your environment.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Explore a tutorial in ABAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/abap-platform-rap120" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497013094"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Built-In Security and Compliance Awareness&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build—with SAP Joule for Developers embedded—is built on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;enterprise-grade security&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. It adheres to SAP’s compliance standards, so your code and data are always protected. You can confidently experiment with AI in your workflows, backed by privacy, governance, and regulatory safeguards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Read more about SAP’s approach to security and compliance in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-service/build-service-guide/security" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/06/e0f9895d-c47e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1429582308"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. It Helps You Learn as You Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HaHoang_2-1758584515206.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318222i12E602C33728DA19/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="HaHoang_2-1758584515206.png" alt="HaHoang_2-1758584515206.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule isn’t just about solutions — it’s about learning. As you code, Joule explains the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;why&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; behind its suggestions. This helps developers discover new frameworks, understand best practices, and ramp up on unfamiliar technologies faster.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Think of it as a mentor who’s always available, providing guidance while letting you stay in the driver’s seat.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Try a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/protected/index.html#/missiondetail/4441/4727/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;tutorial&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on how to create CAP application in SAP Build.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1103986084"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. It Works Across Your Development Stack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HaHoang_3-1758584515207.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318223i82A8779797D32182/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="HaHoang_3-1758584515207.png" alt="HaHoang_3-1758584515207.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule isn’t limited to a single tool or environment. Whether you’re generating processes or building applications, SAP Joule for Developers can support you. This flexibility means you can bring AI assistance into the environments you already know — without having to change how you work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Free Access to SAP Joule for Developers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now is the best time&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to explore, innovate, and see how Joule can transform the way you build — without worrying about cost.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Get started &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-sap-joule-for-developers-claim-your-free-access-today/ba-p/14183158" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;today&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mark your calendar&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Join our upcoming &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build with Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; webinar on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;September 24th&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to see live demos, best practices, and how to maximize the value of Joule in your projects. Register &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=5051265&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=A7AEB5FB1B797BB3D0785EA75BABB9C0&amp;amp;groupId=6301406&amp;amp;partnerref=multiregpage&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/5-things-you-didn-t-know-about-sap-joule-for-developers-plus-an-exciting/ba-p/14224703"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T01:53:30.531000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-create-stories-in-sap-public-cloud-3sl/qaa-p/14224704#M4927100</id>
    <title>Re: unable to create Stories in sap public cloud(3SL)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T01:58:12.826000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235643"&gt;@Thanushree1999&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Have a looked at &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a630d57fc5004c6383e7a81efee7a8bb/c00cbf7fe8464663aee830fb6e7eec13.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage KPIs and Reports&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a630d57fc5004c6383e7a81efee7a8bb/dd28bf545e91ee05e10000000a4450e5.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Analytics in Cloud&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarise based on the details and the screenshot provided, the error you are experiencing indicates a missing role or inactive analytics account. There are a few things to evaluate:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ensure your user has the analytics specialist role assigned.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Verify that the business role includes catalogs such as &lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP_CORE_BC_EXT_KPI which helps Manage KPIs and Reports or SAP_CORE_BC_EXT_STORY which focuses on Story Design&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confirm that your business user is active and linked correctly in the manage workforce.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If your roles are correct but the issue persists, reach out to your administrator to check your embedded SAC provisioning because if you design stories, you must also have an active SAC account.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-create-stories-in-sap-public-cloud-3sl/qaa-p/14224704#M4927100"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T01:58:12.826000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/error-edocument-cockpit/qaa-p/14224705#M255350</id>
    <title>Re: Error eDocument Cockpit</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T02:19:01.826000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1833438"&gt;@JordanoJ&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Have a looked at &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/9d078d90fbbb4a298fbfc0a35047ec23/70a21788ed5d4036b66bf83a798e6726.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Submitting Electronic Documents&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/4603118feda9495892abadbe8f8c3d14/695d9ff12b3849b98c8b267f4cecbb99.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;eDocument Cockpit&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarise, the situation you described is common when you integrate eDocument cockpit with external e-invoicing provider through the integration suite. From your description the iFlow is executed successfully. The error you are experiencing indicates a destination configuration issue on the cloud side.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First thing to check is to ensue the outbound service is assigned and points correctly to your integration suite endpoint.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your communication system linked to &lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP_COM_0521 has the correct host, authentication method and user.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If your iFlow process and finishes but does not map back the response to S4, the cockpit will flag it as an error. You may need to adapt iFlow to send back a proper status in the expected format.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If everything is configured, then make sure you clear and retry the document in eDocument cockpit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/error-edocument-cockpit/qaa-p/14224705#M255350"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T02:19:01.826000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crystaldecisions-shared-crystalreportsexception-is-not-marked-as/qaa-p/14224706#M4927101</id>
    <title>Re: CrystalDecisions.Shared.CrystalReportsException is no...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T02:38:53.244000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DonWilliams</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121895</uri>
    </author>
    <content>check your web.config files and check out MS's info I posted on the error, it's a IIS config error likely...</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/crystaldecisions-shared-crystalreportsexception-is-not-marked-as/qaa-p/14224706#M4927101"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T02:38:53.244000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/sap-public-cloud-quality-certificate-doesn-t-print-the-mean-value-results/qaa-p/14224707#M84349</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Public Cloud: Quality Certificate doesn't print t...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T02:40:27.972000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1485573"&gt;@AM1987&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Have a look at &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d1e58be39d884a0dbf75a7526a9acbf4/dc733e09815e41d3b0591bfd7640f1b9.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Quality Certificates&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d1e58be39d884a0dbf75a7526a9acbf4/95bed3bd2c9d4c39ac02c615629dc3ae.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Quality Certificates for Inspection Lots&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/2805020" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KBA 2805020&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d1e58be39d884a0dbf75a7526a9acbf4/d010ce7fa4fc40b48bf4eeccc2002c3a.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Record Inspection Results&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To summarise, your set up in CBS by creating a new result origin (Y1) and assigning it in the certificate profile is the correct approach. However, for your certificate to print the mean value of all inspection points you must ensure you meet the public cloud requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You must define the master inspection characteristic for summarised recording.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Second, in the record inspection results, you must ensure that a summarised result is calculated and saved for the inspection lot.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Final step as you have already done is to is to assign in the certificate profile the result selection level to summarised result origin= Y1.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If these settings are correct, the system will pull the mean value across all inspection points into the quality certificate. However, if only the last value is printed, then that usually mans that the MIC or the inspection is still set to single result recording or summarised values were not maintained in the inspection lot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/quality-certificate-for-delivery/qaq-p/5613580" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/quality-certificate-for-delivery/qaq-p/5613580&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/sap-public-cloud-quality-certificate-doesn-t-print-the-mean-value-results/qaa-p/14224707#M84349"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T02:40:27.972000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/india-tds-recipient-type-in-business-partner-master-data/qaq-p/14224708</id>
    <title>India TDS Recipient type in Business partner master data</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T02:41:27.557000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to make &amp;nbsp;TDS Recipient type PERSON_NAME in business partner master data in public cloud?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BR,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vaishnavi&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/india-tds-recipient-type-in-business-partner-master-data/qaq-p/14224708"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T02:41:27.557000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/india-tds-recipient-type-in-business-partner-master-data/qaa-p/14224709#M4227781</id>
    <title>Re: India TDS Recipient type in Business partner master data</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T02:41:35.078000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;--Cause--&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Standard behavior: We can use SSCUI 103127 - Define Account Groups with Screen Layout (Supplier) to make the field "TDS Recipient Type" mandatory.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;--Solution--&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The path:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open SSCUI 103127 - Define Account Groups with Screen Layout (Supplier).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the Supplier.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the Company Code Data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the Withholding Tax Data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select "Withholding tax category, w/h tax 2" and change it to "required" for the second one.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/india-tds-recipient-type-in-business-partner-master-data/qaa-p/14224709#M4227781"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T02:41:35.078000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/service-entry-sheet-by-value/qaa-p/14224710#M4227782</id>
    <title>Re: Service Entry Sheet by value</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T02:53:10.605000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2098305"&gt;@lmarellano&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Have a look at &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0e602d466b99490187fcbb30d1dc897c/2a0d6dbbe16e4e3281c3ce1d9bd994cf.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Service Procurement&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/bb9f1469daf04bd894ab2167f8132a1a/57010c45171e48f1b75a47bb1064bdf4.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create Service Entry Sheet&lt;/A&gt; for more details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarise, the standard service entry receipts in public cloud are quantity driven. When you create a PO with a fixed quantity and price, the system expects you to post receipts as percentages or partial quantities. The system then calculates the corresponding amounts which explains the rounding issues you are seeing. If your requirement is to post service receipts directly by amount, then you should use a limit-based service PO.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When you create PO, ensure you maintain an overall limit in the limits section instead of specifying a fixed quantity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When you create a service entry sheet against this PO, you can then enter the exact amount for each service point.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The system consumes against the limit amount rather than distributing based on quantities or percentages.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/service-entry-sheet-by-value/qaa-p/14224710#M4227782"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T02:53:10.605000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-filter-rsusr200-report-by-company-country-to-monitor-user-master/qaq-p/14224711</id>
    <title>How to filter RSUSR200 report by company/country to monitor user master data</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T02:56:04.006000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>snowdrop44</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2172260</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am a fresher new in a SAP world :). I need to organize user master data on a monthly basis to check if there are any new users created or deleted. Currently, I run the RSUSR200 report, but it shows all users across multiple countries in my workplace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My requirement is to filter the output so that only users belonging to my company/country are displayed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a way to restrict RSUSR200 by company code or country?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Or is there another standard report or method to achieve this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ideally, I want to easily compare month by month to identify new and removed users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Appreciate your guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-filter-rsusr200-report-by-company-country-to-monitor-user-master/qaq-p/14224711"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T02:56:04.006000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/c4c-is-there-a-new-solution-for-image-intelligence/qaa-p/14224712#M457865</id>
    <title>Re: C4C Is there a new solution for Image Intelligence?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T02:59:19.860000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>abreuleandro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I was wondering that too, I haven't found any info on that.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/c4c-is-there-a-new-solution-for-image-intelligence/qaa-p/14224712#M457865"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T02:59:19.860000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mass-download-of-pdf-s-and-emails-generated-in-production-which-have-been/qaq-p/14224713</id>
    <title>Mass download of pdf's and emails generated in Production which have been issued to customers</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T03:01:40.557000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you please let me know how to mass download all the generated pdf's and emails in Production system for customers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We want to be able to mass extract/ download all the created invoices, dunning notices or other business process output documents sent to the customer from Production system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. We can see the pdf's and emails generated in Display Dunning Notice within Display Dunning History App.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We want to mass download all the generated Dunning notices including pdf's and emails. Can you please let me know how to do this is production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. In Display Billing Documents App we can view the Billing Invoices generated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We want to be able to mass download all the processed Billing Invoices from here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Similarly for other business processes which generated documents issued to customer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mass-download-of-pdf-s-and-emails-generated-in-production-which-have-been/qaq-p/14224713"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T03:01:40.557000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mass-download-of-pdf-s-and-emails-generated-in-production-which-have-been/qaa-p/14224714#M4227785</id>
    <title>Re: Mass download of pdf's and emails generated in Produc...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T03:01:48.995000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear customer,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The questions should be addressed one by one per application.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For sales billing document, it's possible to extract PDFs via the following API:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/03c04db2a7434731b7fe21dca77440da/fe6f3eda2f914d81b512493fd79e9769.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Billing Document - Read, Cancel, GetPDF | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the rest applications, you can please follow this post to gain answers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scarlett&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/mass-download-of-pdf-s-and-emails-generated-in-production-which-have-been/qaa-p/14224714#M4227785"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T03:01:48.995000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-imaging-intelligence-plug-in-for-planograms-c4c/qaa-p/14224715#M457866</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Imaging Intelligence plug-in for PLANOGRAMS - C4C</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T03:03:25.336000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>abreuleandro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46992</uri>
    </author>
    <content>The video link doesn't work</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/sap-imaging-intelligence-plug-in-for-planograms-c4c/qaa-p/14224715#M457866"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T03:03:25.336000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/custom-cds-modification-after-publishing-s4-public-cloud/qaa-p/14224716#M4927102</id>
    <title>Re: Custom CDS - Modification After Publishing - S4 Publi...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T03:05:06.009000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris1973</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2035121</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1883200"&gt;@SamHilton&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your question.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Have a look at &amp;nbsp;SAP Note 2587346,&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/e30de6eae4d24d70b65996ac8ff88848.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Custom CDS Views&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/building-custom-solutions-by-extending-cds-views-on-sap-s-4hana-cloud/ba-p/13435361" target="_blank"&gt;Building Custom Solutions by Extending CDS Views on SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The summary is, CDS views are handled differently in public cloud compared to on-premise or private cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To prevent inconsistencies, you cannot directly change the join conditions of a base CDS view if it is referenced by other CDS views.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You are recommended to create a new CDS view with the modified join conditions and then adjust dependent CDS views to point to this new view.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since direct editing is not possible, CDS extensibility must be done using the custom CDS views app. Eclipse development is on available for on-premise, private cloud systems or on BTP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this provides the desired insight. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Chris&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/custom-cds-modification-after-publishing-s4-public-cloud/qaa-p/14224716#M4927102"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T03:05:06.009000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/can-i-extend-a-certain-app-with-clean-core-how/bc-p/14224717#M184770</id>
    <title>Re: Can I extend a certain app? With Clean Core? How?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T03:11:42.198000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gowthami5</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1856640</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172702" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;BartvdKamp&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157846"&gt;@mlauber&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;I have a similar requirement to extend slow and non moving materials app with some standard fields and calculated fields. Do you think the approach of&amp;nbsp; extending view will work when the consumption view is not released and will this be considered clean core?&amp;nbsp; I do not want to use custom fields and logic as these are some calculated fields needed to be displayed only for reporting purpose&amp;nbsp; in the app and is not needed to be saved in the database table.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Could you please suggest any approach?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/can-i-extend-a-certain-app-with-clean-core-how/bc-p/14224717#M184770"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T03:11:42.198000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-is-the-quot-golden-tax-invoice-number-quot-stored-in-sap-s-standard/qaq-p/14224718</id>
    <title>How is the "Golden Tax Invoice Number" stored in SAP's standard field design?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T03:24:09.062000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Inquiry regarding whether SAP has a standard field in finance documents designed to store the golden tax invoice number (20 digits)?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-is-the-quot-golden-tax-invoice-number-quot-stored-in-sap-s-standard/qaq-p/14224718"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T03:24:09.062000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-is-the-quot-golden-tax-invoice-number-quot-stored-in-sap-s-standard/qaa-p/14224719#M4227787</id>
    <title>Re: How is the "Golden Tax Invoice Number" stored in SAP'...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T03:24:17.088000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;To store Golden Tax invoice numbers in financial documents, the SGTXT field can be utilized through BAdI implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the app&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Create Golden Tax Documents - China&lt;/EM&gt;, use BAdI ID: IDGTCN_OB_OPR_AFT_FETCH_INVC (China: Operations After Fetching VAT Invoices).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the app&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Create Outbound Files - China&lt;/EM&gt;, employ BAdI ID: IDGTCN_WRITEBACK_CLOUD.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3659427" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3659427 - How is the "Golden Tax Invoice Number" stored in SAP's standard field design? - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-is-the-quot-golden-tax-invoice-number-quot-stored-in-sap-s-standard/qaa-p/14224719#M4227787"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T03:24:17.088000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/date-of-last-sales-order/qaa-p/14224721#M4227788</id>
    <title>Re: Date of Last Sales Order</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T03:26:18.335000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Adie</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/180947</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello MarisaF-UPI,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the standard report, i.e. Sales Order Volume report, it is possible to filter by account, and show the sales orders as well as their calendar day (posting date in the order). You are able to set filter on the order, but not able to set formular or condition to show only the last sales order.&amp;nbsp; You can export the report and set sorting based on sales order ID, to get the last sales order and its posing date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alternatively, you may check in the account master data, in Sales tab, it shows you all the sales history created for this account.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set filter as Sales Order in Doc.Type,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set sorting in the Document Item ID&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then you will get the posting date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="order list in account.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318225i80BD027F8A26D44E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="order list in account.png" alt="order list in account.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adie&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/date-of-last-sales-order/qaa-p/14224721#M4227788"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T03:26:18.335000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/contract-and-lease-management-migration-in-sap-public-cloud/qaq-p/14224725</id>
    <title>Contract and Lease Management Migration in SAP Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:00:09.522000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>charlene2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1528680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Expert,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am new to contact and lease management. Can i know what is the best practice approach to migrate CLM contract for Lease In and Lease Out scenario?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/contract-and-lease-management-migration-in-sap-public-cloud/qaq-p/14224725"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:00:09.522000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-address-invoice-transmission-issues-with-baiwang-cloud-integration/qaq-p/14224726</id>
    <title>How to Address Invoice Transmission Issues with Baiwang Cloud Integration?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:02:30.253000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Implementation of Baiwang Cloud for direct issuance of VAT electronic invoices is in place, with an expected transmission of invoice numbers and timestamps to SAP. However, invoices are not being transmitted. Clicking "Invoice" triggers a 500 error, and accessing "Attachment" results in an empty content display.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-address-invoice-transmission-issues-with-baiwang-cloud-integration/qaq-p/14224726"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:02:30.253000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-address-invoice-transmission-issues-with-baiwang-cloud-integration/qaa-p/14224727#M4227791</id>
    <title>Re: How to Address Invoice Transmission Issues with Baiwa...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:02:38.138000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Please verify that the Baiwang URL is configured in the "Maintain Protection Allowlists" app and then test its functionality to ensure it is working correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3659400" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3659400 - How to Address Invoice Transmission Issues with BaiWang Cloud Integration? - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-address-invoice-transmission-issues-with-baiwang-cloud-integration/qaa-p/14224727#M4227791"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:02:38.138000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/date-of-last-sales-order/qaa-p/14224731#M4227792</id>
    <title>Re: Date of Last Sales Order</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:11:25.563000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vincent_Zhu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131883</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;Incoming Sales Orders - Flexible Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; app (ID: F1249)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add customer account, order date, item details, and quantities to your analysis&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Apply filters to show the most recent orders per customer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/date-of-last-sales-order/qaa-p/14224731#M4227792"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:11:25.563000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/specific-changes-in-patch-1400-of-cras-2020-sp4/qaq-p/14224733</id>
    <title>Specific changes in patch 1400 of CRAS 2020 SP4</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:14:00.836000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Federico_Ogalesco</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2228696</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I just need to know the specific changes in patch 1400 of CRAS 2020 SP4&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/specific-changes-in-patch-1400-of-cras-2020-sp4/qaq-p/14224733"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:14:00.836000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/browser-content-area-in-enable-now-is-capturing-entire-browser/qaa-p/14224734#M48153</id>
    <title>Re: Browser Content Area in Enable Now is capturing entir...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:16:34.731000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anton_Mavrin1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109800</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Update: This issue has been resolved with the lates hotfix. It was applied 1-2 weeks ago.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/browser-content-area-in-enable-now-is-capturing-entire-browser/qaa-p/14224734#M48153"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:16:34.731000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/enable-now-data-integration-into-sap-analytics-cloud/qaa-p/14224735#M48154</id>
    <title>Re: Enable Now Data Integration into SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:18:09.537000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anton_Mavrin1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109800</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Nah, I don't like the idea of giving SAC JSON data as files. Will continue using MS Excel or MS Power BI, as they parse JSON data without issues.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/enable-now-data-integration-into-sap-analytics-cloud/qaa-p/14224735#M48154"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:18:09.537000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-it-possible-to-add-custom-fields-in-quot-create-incoming-invoices-quot/qaa-p/14224736#M4227793</id>
    <title>Re: Is it possible to add Custom Fields in "Create Incomi...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:18:22.409000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vincent_Zhu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131883</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As said, custom field is not supported in the "Create Incoming Invoices" application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760957481"&gt;Recommended Alternative Solution&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use the "Create Supplier Invoice" app instead&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;. This app provides the following advantages:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Full custom field support&lt;/STRONG&gt; through the Custom Fields and Logic app&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can create supplier invoices without purchase order reference&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports G/L account items only&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Displays G/L account items in both form mode and table format&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/is-it-possible-to-add-custom-fields-in-quot-create-incoming-invoices-quot/qaa-p/14224736#M4227793"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:18:22.409000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/dive-into-the-future-of-sap-universal-id-and-understand-the-changes/bc-p/14224737#M533</id>
    <title>Re: Dive into the future of SAP Universal ID and understand the changes underway</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:20:11.676000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>keith007</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/744567</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you ask me the Universal ID was confusing and now going back to using "s" or "p" users is worse.&amp;nbsp; Especially because now you can't choose which s-user you actually want to log on as it ends up logging you on as a user you were not expecting.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I don't know if this makes sense as I am really confused - even after contacting support twice.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;UID was a pain to start with but did work once you got used to it and now it has effectively been reversed out.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I resisted UID initially until it became mandatory &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/dive-into-the-future-of-sap-universal-id-and-understand-the-changes/bc-p/14224737#M533"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:20:11.676000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s4h-public-cloud-custom-cdsview-external-api-for-create-update-operations/qaa-p/14224740#M4227794</id>
    <title>Re: S4H public cloud - Custom CDSView External API for cr...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:24:32.863000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vincent_Zhu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131883</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Yes,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;create and update operations are possible for custom External APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but with important distinctions based on the type of custom object you're working with.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760957506"&gt;For Custom Business Objects (CBOs)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Full CRUD operations are supported&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for Custom Business Objects. This includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Add new business object instances&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Query existing data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Modify existing instances&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delete&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Remove instances&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also use&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;batch operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to load datasets in a single API call, which is particularly useful for bulk data operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For updating Custom Business Objects via External API, refer to the SAP Help documentation on "Updating Business Object Instances with an OData Request".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1564444001"&gt;For Custom CDS Views&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom CDS Views created for External API scenarios are read-only&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The External API scenario for Custom CDS Views only supports:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Data retrieval and querying&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;View/Browse functionality&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Displaying data in browsers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create, update, and delete operations are&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;not supported&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for Custom CDS Views exposed as External APIs.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/s4h-public-cloud-custom-cdsview-external-api-for-create-update-operations/qaa-p/14224740#M4227794"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:24:32.863000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/asset-transfer-process-in-s4-hana/qaq-p/14224743</id>
    <title>Asset transfer process in s4 hana</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:31:03.905000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ssaikam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2254325</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Would please tell me what is process of Asset Transfer in S4 Hana (inter company process), What are methods are available in S4 Hana.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/asset-transfer-process-in-s4-hana/qaq-p/14224743"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:31:03.905000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/pgi-delivery-date-to-milestone-actual-date/qaq-p/14224749</id>
    <title>PGI Delivery date to Milestone Actual Date</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:42:00.810000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mlasya85</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/889258</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are working on an Engineering-to-Order (ETO) scenario with milestone billing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our requirement is as follows&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When we do the PGI(Post Goods Issue) confirmation during delivery, the PGI date should automatically default to the milestone actual date.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Currently, users have to manually enter the milestone actual date as the PGI date.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Setup we are considering:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The network will have an activity called “Shipment”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All required milestones will be attached to this activity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Question:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Is there a way to automate this so that the PGI date is derived directly and apply as the milestone actual date (instead of manual entry)? If yes, what would be the best approach (config, BAdI, user exit, etc.)?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/pgi-delivery-date-to-milestone-actual-date/qaq-p/14224749"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:42:00.810000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/prevent-earliest-start-date-from-going-past-today-in-backward-scheduling/qaq-p/14224753</id>
    <title>Prevent Earliest Start Date from Going Past Today in Backward Scheduling (Assembly Process)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:50:33.302000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mlasya85</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/889258</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are working with Assembly Processing using backward scheduling in projects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After backward scheduling based on Delibery date in Sales order ,the Earliest Start Date of the first activity should not go into the past.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If the earliest state date falls in to the past date, the system should use today’s date and continue scheduling forwards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Questions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;is my understanding correct?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are there specific network scheduling settings (e.g., date checks, scheduling) should be done in scheduling parameters needed to achieve this?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/prevent-earliest-start-date-from-going-past-today-in-backward-scheduling/qaq-p/14224753"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:50:33.302000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/jira-to-sap-calm-via-sap-integration-suite/qaq-p/14224754</id>
    <title>JIRA  to SAP CALM via SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T04:52:17.155000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sureshkumar6</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2036136</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are planning to establish an integration between Jira and SAP Cloud ALM using the SAP Integration Suite. Kindly provide the detailed connection setup and configuration guide, including any prerequisites, authentication methods, message mapping, and error handling best practices necessary for a seamless data exchange.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/jira-to-sap-calm-via-sap-integration-suite/qaq-p/14224754"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T04:52:17.155000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/does-quot-updating-subscriptions-quot-update-db-model-schema-of-every/qaq-p/14224756</id>
    <title>Does "updating subscriptions" update db model/schema of every tenant</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T05:06:07.506000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dongdong1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2009525</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As the subject, when we do subscriptions, how about db model/schema ? Will model/schema be updated during the subscription update ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;endpoint:&amp;nbsp;saas-manager/v1/application/subscriptions/batch&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/does-quot-updating-subscriptions-quot-update-db-model-schema-of-every/qaq-p/14224756"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T05:06:07.506000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-to-implement-triangular-trade-intercompany-business-in-sap-s-4hana/qaa-p/14224757#M207228</id>
    <title>Re: How to Implement Triangular Trade Intercompany Busine...</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T05:06:35.610000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ying_Li1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132129</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Below is the business process for this scenarios :&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The German company sells to the customer and the US company delivers (i.e. the US plant is still the delivering plant in SO2), but the German company does this by buying the goods from the French company. This company in turns buys the goods from the US company: a purchase order towards the French company is automatically created when SO2 is saved, leading to a sales order in France (SO4') and an additional purchase order from the French company towards the US (PO3'), which created SO4.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="截屏2025-09-22 17.13.15.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317798iEF09E8B773608FE6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="截屏2025-09-22 17.13.15.png" alt="截屏2025-09-22 17.13.15.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A multi level process using a single SAP S/4HANA system is also planned to be available. One or more intermediate companies can be included in the process, where for example the German company still determines the US plant as the delivering plant but where the ordering is done via the French company (PO3 leading to SO4' in the figure), that in turn orders the goods from the delivering company in the US (PO3' and SO4).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Currently ,only workaround solution could be used .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Single SO+Advanced intercompany&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please wait for the further update.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/how-to-implement-triangular-trade-intercompany-business-in-sap-s-4hana/qaa-p/14224757#M207228"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T05:06:35.610000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
