<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-10-30T17:59:01.687533+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-build-clarity-in-sap-projects-with-jira/ba-p/14257145</id>
    <title>How to build clarity in SAP Projects with Jira</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T13:42:53.879000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Bogdan_Gorka</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157661</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="Is-it-your-day-in-SAP-project-life?" id="toc-hId-1892894400"&gt;Is it your day in SAP project life?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your SAP project is in the middle of Fit-to-Standard analysis, your Requirements Backlog grows quickly, requirements are flowing in from all teams, but it’s impossible to see what matters most or what type of work is hiding behind the summary and description.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If that sounds familiar, your project might be missing the structured requirement classification discipline recommended by SAP Activate. Without this approach, the requirements backlog turns into a flat list, where priorities will be hard to assign and some of the expected outcomes will not be properly documented.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With structured classification, it becomes clear what type of outcomes we’re delivering and what kind of documentation and work is actually required. It enables credible estimation, release wave planning, and test coverage without the need to re-explain the project every week.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="What-is-Requirement-Classification?" id="toc-hId-1696380895"&gt;What is Requirement Classification?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Classification provides a structured way to label requirements so they can be grouped, prioritized, tracked, and reported consistently across both functional and technical workstreams.&lt;BR /&gt;Together with formulation standards, it keeps your requirements backlog clean and actionable for delivery and status reporting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every requirement should be labeled along &lt;STRONG&gt;two dimensions&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1️) Level - hierarchy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; shows where the requirement sits in the project - higher strategic level or lower detailed level.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2️) Type - nature of work:&lt;/STRONG&gt; signals what kind of effort is needed to deliver it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="The-Dual-Classification-Model-—-Levels-&amp;amp;-Types" id="toc-hId-1499867390"&gt;The Dual Classification Model — Levels &amp;amp; Types&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Levels hierarchy &lt;/STRONG&gt;- reflects the “zoom” level:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; L1 – High-Level Business Requirement:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;EM&gt;The “why”&lt;/EM&gt; - what business value or capability must be achieved.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; L2 – Process-Level Requirement:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;EM&gt;The “what”&lt;/EM&gt; - process activities or steps that bring the business outcome to life.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; L3 – Functional Requirement:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;EM&gt;The “how”&lt;/EM&gt; - concrete system behaviors, validations, or interactions that enable the process step. At this level, SAP Activate recommends requirements be formulated so they are traceable and testable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Types - nature of work&lt;/STRONG&gt; - reflects the solution pathway:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; FIT:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Standard SAP functionality meets the need &lt;EM&gt;as is&lt;/EM&gt;; adopt standard SAP.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; GAP:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Missing functionality requiring additional configuration or enhancement.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; EXT (Extension / WRICEF):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Technical work — interfaces, reports, conversions, enhancements, forms.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; NFR (Non-Functional Requirement):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Qualities such as performance, security, compliance, or usability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Combine both dimensions and you’ll see your full solution scope - how much fits standard SAP, which areas need only configuration, and where technical extensions or non-functional demands will influence delivery. This will help later with accurate effort estimation and release governance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="From-Discover-to-Explore:-how-requirements-detail-changes" id="toc-hId-1303353885"&gt;From Discover to Explore: how requirements detail changes&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discover Phase:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Requirements are collected as high-level outcomes or business goals mapped to solution scope. They are articulated as value drivers and not yet detailed as process or system requirements.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prepare Phase:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Refined and agreed high level requirements are turned into scope statements and acceptance criteria. They become part of the project charter, forming the project baseline.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore Phase:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Time to dive in. Now, during the Fit-to-Standard workshops, the team validates which SAP Best Practices satisfy business needs (&lt;STRONG&gt;FIT&lt;/STRONG&gt;), pinpoint deltas (&lt;STRONG&gt;GAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;EXT/WRICEF&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;NFR&lt;/STRONG&gt;), and detail process-level or functional requirements for each business activity. The goal is not to restate strategic goals but to clarify how each is realized in process terms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Requirements Levels and Types table.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334346iFC04FDBE9B1B5E3E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Requirements Levels and Types table.png" alt="Requirements Levels and Types table.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1106840380"&gt;Requirements refinement example&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a quick example to demonstrate how the level of details changes between requirement levels. These changes are the result of iterations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High Level (L1):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;“&lt;EM&gt;Ensure that &lt;STRONG&gt;customer credit&lt;/STRONG&gt; exposure is controlled during the order-to-cash process to minimize financial risk and enforce company credit policy.&lt;/EM&gt;”&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process Level (L2):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“Add a process step to validate &lt;STRONG&gt;customer credit &lt;/STRONG&gt;before order confirmation, ensuring that orders exceeding credit limits are identified and stopped before delivery or invoicing.”&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Functional Level (L3):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“&lt;STRONG&gt;As a&lt;/STRONG&gt; Sales Representative &lt;STRONG&gt;when&lt;/STRONG&gt; a Sales Order is saved for a customer whose credit exposure exceeds their credit limit &lt;STRONG&gt;the system will&lt;/STRONG&gt; automatically block the Sales Order and display a message indicating the credit limit breach &lt;STRONG&gt;so that &lt;/STRONG&gt;financially non-compliant orders are prevented from further processing and company credit policy is enforced.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Depending on SAP coverage, requirement form this example could be a &lt;STRONG&gt;GAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; (needs configuration) or an &lt;STRONG&gt;EXT&lt;/STRONG&gt; (custom validation).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When a Level 3 requirement is formulated using an agreed template and properly classified, it becomes much easier to estimate the required effort and remains traceable from the very beginning all the way through deployment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="What-about-Non-Functional-Requirements?" id="toc-hId-910326875"&gt;What about Non-Functional Requirements?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;It may seem counterintuitive, but SAP methodologies - including Activate and Focused Build - classify most Non-Functional Requirements (NFRs) at the same (functional) level as detailed system requirements. While their name suggests they are “non-functional,” they describe qualities that apply to specific system functions, such as performance, security, or usability. In practice, they sit at the same level of detail as functional requirements, because they can be specified, tested, and verified against system behavior.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“The system shall process 10 000 purchase order lines within 60 seconds under normal load conditions.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“User data shall be stored only within EU-based data centers.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Level 3 Requirements.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334347iE883344AF0E8766E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Level 3 Requirements.png" alt="Level 3 Requirements.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-713813370"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Bringing classification to practice in Jira&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The flexibility of Jira allows you to capture more than just a requirement’s name and description. You can also collect structured metadata for governance and reporting. You are not limited in customizations like in SAP native tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Possible Jira configuration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add custom fields to record key attributes such as Requirement Level (High-Level, Process-Level, Functional) and Requirement Type (FIT, GAP, EXT, NFR, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure these fields as drop-down lists so that users must select a defined value, ensuring consistent classification across all teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Requirement screen - classification metadata.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334348i07E8A0FAF8260699/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Requirement screen - classification metadata.png" alt="Requirement screen - classification metadata.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Standardized metadata enables filtering, reporting, and building reporting dashboards by type, level, or workstream, giving full transparency into project and solution scope composition.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even that simple setup unlocks powerful reporting in Jira: dashboards showing % FIT coverage, distribution of GAPs and WRICEFs, or NFR readiness by release. Your backlog becomes a live dashboard, not a static list in Excel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Requirements dashboard - classification.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334349iDB9AC28AF5BEDC70/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Requirements dashboard - classification.png" alt="Requirements dashboard - classification.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="What’s-in-it-for-you?" id="toc-hId-517299865"&gt;What’s in it for you?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-turn-sap-workshop-notes-into-clear-and-testable-requirements/ba-p/14255076" target="_self"&gt;Just like requirement formulation standard discussed on SAP Community here&lt;/A&gt;, clarity is also about bringing structure and governance to Requirements Management. When every requirement has its place and type, governance stops being a reporting exercise and becomes a shared language. Classification is not overhead or project administration - it is the structure that keeps delivery, design, and testing aligned, supports compliance, and maintains clear documentation from the first workshop to go-live.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;And the question&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If I opened your requirements tracker today (I hope it is Jira) and picked five random requirements, would I instantly see what each one means, what type of work it implies, and where it fits in your process? If not, you know now what to do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If you have found this article informative, please leave me a Kudo on top of this page.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This will encourage me to publish more articles on SAP Community. Thank you!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="About-author" id="toc-hId-320786360"&gt;About author&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Bogdan Górka works as Atlassian Solution Architect and SAP Project Governance Consultant. Creator of R2D ALM for Jira, independent Atlassian consultant, and founder of PMBG.EU.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-build-clarity-in-sap-projects-with-jira/ba-p/14257145"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T13:42:53.879000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/create-credit-memo-via-api-for-a-purchase-order-s4hc/qaa-p/14257146#M4230514</id>
    <title>Re: Create credit memo via API for a purchase order - S4HC</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T13:44:50.554000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PatrickNguyen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1403458</uri>
    </author>
    <content>"to_SuplrInvcItemPurOrdRef" : { "results" : [ { "TaxCode" : "V0", "DocumentCurrency" : "EUR", "SupplierInvoiceItemAmount" : "12.00", "PurchaseOrderQuantityUnit" : "PC", "QuantityInPurchaseOrderUnit" : "1", "FiscalYear" : "2022", "IsNotCashDiscountLiable" : false, "SupplierInvoiceItem" : "1", "PurchaseOrder" : "4500005670", "PurchaseOrderItem" : "10"</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/create-credit-memo-via-api-for-a-purchase-order-s4hc/qaa-p/14257146#M4230514"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T13:44:50.554000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/need-help-with-prd-audit-report-on-icontent-server-use/qaa-p/14257148#M49030</id>
    <title>Re: Need help with PRD Audit report on iContent Server use</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T13:49:15.924000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PL1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/100630"&gt;@barbarapailet7&lt;/a&gt;, alternatively to the custom report, for contents in iContent, the iContent Management tool (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-release-information/8e0d540f96474717bbf18df51e54e522/d444d3e964564090b34e91058fed75a6.html?parentHref=https%3A%2F%2Fhelp.sap.com%2Fwhats-new%2F8fcf4960eea24f78b1d7613da406a885%3FProduct%3DLearning&amp;amp;parentName=SAP+SuccessFactors+What%27s+New&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bulk Delete Unused iContent Files From Learning Administration&lt;/A&gt; | &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-learning/managing-sap-successfactors-learning-for-administrators/deleting-online-content-from-icontent-management-tool?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Deleting iContent Files Using the iContent Management Tool&lt;/A&gt;) can be used once rolled out to your datacenter (KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003664753" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3664753&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/need-help-with-prd-audit-report-on-icontent-server-use/qaa-p/14257148#M49030"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T13:49:15.924000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/adding-the-item-active-field-to-the-learning-history-report/qaa-p/14257152#M49031</id>
    <title>Re: Adding the Item Active field to the Learning History...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T13:51:39.511000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PL1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36915"&gt;@joellesmith_QP34&lt;/a&gt;, it’s worth posting this question here as well: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-successfactors-learning-custom-report-exchange/gh-p/hcm-learning-custom-report" target="_blank"&gt;Learning Custom Report Exchange Forum&lt;/A&gt; (this space in the SAP Community is dedicated to sharing custom reports and tips and tricks related to customizations).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/adding-the-item-active-field-to-the-learning-history-report/qaa-p/14257152#M49031"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T13:51:39.511000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/error-while-exporting-the-local-content-in-build-work-zone-standard-edition/ba-p/14257149</id>
    <title>Error while exporting the local content in Build Work Zone, Standard Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T13:52:03.194000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ROHITGERA1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7607</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Folks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently I have encountered one error when exporting the Local Content in SAP Build Work Zone, Standard Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This issue is there as of 30th October 2025. In future SAP will do the permanent fix for the issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Error Details:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below will be the error when exporting the Local content in BWZ, SE:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Export process was stopped due to an error. Please try again and if the issue persists, open a support ticket with error code 54c8e678-c55f-4a8e-7def-006b439d6253&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;PFA the screen shot for same.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;After so many follow up with SAP Product team, they told that if a role id contain Slash "/" in it then it will give this kind of error. they are working&amp;nbsp; on the solution as permanent fix for same.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Meanwhile as a work around we can remove the slash "/" from the role id which is having and it will resolve the issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is the reply from SAP Team:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;"Thank you for your patience while we investigated the export issue you reported, we've identified the root cause and are actively working on a permanent fix.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;We found that the export function currently works for all roles that do not have a forward slash (/) in their ID. To unblock your workflow, please recreate your local app (as IDs are immutable) and choose an ID that does not contain a forward slash. This will allow you to export content while we finalize the proper fix.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;We are conducting a deeper investigation to implement a robust solution. We will let you know as soon as the fix is deployed."&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have deleted the existing role because once role created we can not change the id. After deletion I have created new role and in id I have not used the slash.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this will solve the problem for many customer which took 1 month for me to fix it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rohit Gera&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/error-while-exporting-the-local-content-in-build-work-zone-standard-edition/ba-p/14257149"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T13:52:03.194000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/seamlessly-expand-from-event-mesh-to-advanced-event-mesh-with-our-new/bc-p/14257153#M185826</id>
    <title>Re: Seamlessly Expand from Event Mesh to Advanced Event Mesh with Our New Export Feature</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T13:52:13.652000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lina_stehle</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/227531</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Christian &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47257"&gt;@chris_75&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;unfortunately, the transport from a dev to prod landscape is not yet supported. The "Export Configuration" button in it's current form is only meant to help the expand use-case to Advanced Event Mesh.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, we are aware of the additional requirement of transporting Event Mesh configuration across landscapes. This feature might come up in the future, so please stay tuned!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Lina&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/seamlessly-expand-from-event-mesh-to-advanced-event-mesh-with-our-new/bc-p/14257153#M185826"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T13:52:13.652000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-data-variants-from-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-test-automation-tool/bc-p/14257155#M185827</id>
    <title>Re: How to use Data Variants from SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Test Automation Tool (TAT) in SAP Cloud A</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T13:54:03.612000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Volodymyr_Bondarenko</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2262684</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Very interesting, I assume regression tests are no longer relevant once TAT is implemented.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-data-variants-from-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-test-automation-tool/bc-p/14257155#M185827"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T13:54:03.612000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/new-plant-code-for-3pl-warehouse-integration-in-s-4hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14257161#M4230515</id>
    <title>Re: New plant code for 3PL Warehouse Integration in S/4HA...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T13:57:23.940000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dawid90</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172309</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1500465"&gt;@Kasirajan&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In S/4HANA Cloud, public edition there isn’t a single “migration plant analyzer” that lists every config and technical object.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ll need a combo of CBC exports, “where-used” apps, and a few admin tools to build a reliable hit-list.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s the practical toolbox that can be use:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1) Central Business Configuration (CBC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set Up Organizational Structure is where you add the new plant and let CBC enforce required relationships (company code, sales org delivery plant, etc.). Use this first to surface mandatory follow-ups.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Download Business Configuration from CBC to get a ZIP of spreadsheets. File containing information on configuration data and selected scope of your project.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details in link how activate in CBC Prepare Download of My Configuration button below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dawid90_0-1761828926299.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334355i1619C8820889AD1E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dawid90_0-1761828926299.png" alt="dawid90_0-1761828926299.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-download-configurations-from-my-cbc-project/qaa-p/13749904#M4190179" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-download-configurations-from-my-cbc-project/qaa-p/13749904#M4190179&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3453205" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3453205&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Change logs in CBC can also show who changed what and when.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003295974" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/0003295974&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dawid90_1-1761828926300.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334356i38D6038B32C45170/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dawid90_1-1761828926300.png" alt="dawid90_1-1761828926300.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2) “Where-Used” apps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Where-Used List – Cost Centers / Activity Types / Profit Centers help you find org-object dependencies (allocations, cycles, service orgs, etc.) that might indirectly hinge on plant assignments or need role restriction updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F3867')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F3867')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F3751')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F3751')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F3549')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F3549')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3) Extensibility &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Extensibility Inventory app and Extensibility Cockpit app show dependencies across custom fields, custom logic, custom CDS views, forms, custom comms scenarios, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F2587')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F2587')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F2866')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F2866')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4) Output &amp;amp; forms&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Output Parameter Determination: scan determination rules (e.g., by plant, shipping point) and assigned form templates that may need duplicates for the new plant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a630d57fc5004c6383e7a81efee7a8bb/fdc3cf565b1b6b15e10000000a441470.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a630d57fc5004c6383e7a81efee7a8bb/fdc3cf565b1b6b15e10000000a441470.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5) Integrations to 3PL&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Communication Arrangements / Systems / Users: inventory all active integrations used by the current plant so you can clone or retarget for the new partner.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F1763')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F1763')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F1762')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F1762')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F1338')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F1338')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure Value Mapping app: search for any value maps that include the plant code (common in EDI/API mappings) and add the new plant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6) Authorizations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maintain Business Roles: many roles restrict by Plant. Add the new plant value to relevant role restrictions so users can actually see/work in it on day one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comments from my side why this is not automatically:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some impacts remain design-time decisions rather than discoverable by a single report in Public Cloud, for example, price/condition records that are plant-specific, shipping-point/route determination, ATP/supply-assignment, MRP areas, production versions/work centers, or valuation/costing settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this helps&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dawid&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/new-plant-code-for-3pl-warehouse-integration-in-s-4hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14257161#M4230515"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T13:57:23.940000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/rap-practice-is-ui-preview-expected/qaa-p/14257162#M4930572</id>
    <title>Re: RAP practice: Is UI preview expected?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T13:59:17.139000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Johnmic</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2086511</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Yes, that’s expected. I actually got a bit confused about this myself when I was going through some &lt;A href="https://www.certboosters.com/exam/sap/c-abapd-2507" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;ABAP Cloud practice questions&lt;/A&gt; during my training. I thought maybe I had accidentally selected a UI template somewhere. But the Fiori Elements preview you see is generated automatically as soon as you expose your RAP BO through an OData V4 service binding in ADT.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s simply a built-in preview UI based on your CDS views and behavior definition. No special project setup required. Just keep in mind it’s mainly for quick testing. For any real application, you’d add proper UI annotations or build a full Fiori Elements app in BAS.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/rap-practice-is-ui-preview-expected/qaa-p/14257162#M4930572"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T13:59:17.139000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/file-extension-docx-not-allowed-for-workstation-application-wrd-for-dms/qaq-p/14257163</id>
    <title>File extension docx not allowed for workstation application WRD for DMS object</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:00:32.117000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>prashanth5577</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2262683</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While loading IDOCs I'm getting Workstation application DOX not defined error. Could you please help me?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have checked in the DC50 also it is maintained in the T-Code I have attached my error screenshot as well as the DC50 T-Code screenshot.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please help me out from this issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prashanth Kumar.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Error Diagnosis Screenshot" style="width: 660px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334354i9EAB9C6C90004292/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-29 202004.png" alt="Error Diagnosis Screenshot" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Error Diagnosis Screenshot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Error after processing IDOCs" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334357iF04EE245282ABDE7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-29 234417.png" alt="Error after processing IDOCs" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Error after processing IDOCs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DC30 Screenshot of *.DOC" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334358i56CFD2B2692F1E28/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-30 182623.png" alt="DC30 Screenshot of *.DOC" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;DC30 Screenshot of *.DOC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/file-extension-docx-not-allowed-for-workstation-application-wrd-for-dms/qaq-p/14257163"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:00:32.117000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-reverse-the-accrued-amount-in-invoice-without-final-settlement-of/qaq-p/14257166</id>
    <title>How to reverse the accrued amount in Invoice without Final Settlement of the Condition Contract?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:06:08.261000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>anwesha08</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/147872</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have a scenario where Business wants to reverse the SD invoice rebate accrual &amp;amp; manual accrual w/o generating any credit note to Customer. The manual accrual can be reversed by WB2R_AB_DOCS by selecting the manual accrual settlement document. At this point if we do Final Settlement, credit memo gets generated which can be reversed by the same process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However,&amp;nbsp; Business doesn't want to generate credit memo &amp;amp; reverse the manual accrual and invoice accrued amount at the end of the period. How to achieve this any suggestion?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#ConditionContractManagement#SettlementManagement#Rebate&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-reverse-the-accrued-amount-in-invoice-without-final-settlement-of/qaq-p/14257166"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:06:08.261000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/designing-an-idempotent-sap-business-one-woocommerce-sync-patterns-pitfalls/ba-p/14249326</id>
    <title>Designing an Idempotent SAP Business One ↔ WooCommerce Sync: Patterns, Pitfalls, and a Minimal Refer</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:10:17.449000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>replanta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2260958</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762949603"&gt;Why idempotency matters&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Commerce APIs and corporate ERPs live in noisy networks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Webhooks can be delivered &lt;STRONG&gt;once, twice, or never&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cron and queues can retry at awkward times.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Human operators re-process orders when in doubt.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Without idempotency, duplicate pushes create ghost invoices, stock drift, and reconciliation nightmares. Your sync layer must guarantee &lt;STRONG&gt;“exactly-once effects”&lt;/STRONG&gt; even if the transport is &lt;STRONG&gt;at-least-once&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;WooCommerce ──(OrderCreated Webhook)──▶ Sync API (Ingress)
        ▲                                   │
        │                              Validate + Normalize
        │                                   │
        └──(Health/Retries)◀── Work Queue ◀─┘
                                         │
                                      Workers
                                         │
                                SAP B1 Service Layer / DI-API
                                         │
                                   Result &amp;amp; Audit Log
                                         │
                                  Callback / Notes on Order&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1695518817"&gt;Core components&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ingress API&lt;/STRONG&gt;: receives Woo events or is called by cron. Adds &lt;STRONG&gt;idempotency key&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the message (e.g., &lt;CODE&gt;wc_order_id&lt;/CODE&gt; + stable salt).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Work queue&lt;/STRONG&gt;: decouples reception from processing; supports backoff and DLQ (dead letter queue).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workers&lt;/STRONG&gt;: implement mapping, pre-checks, SAP calls, and &lt;STRONG&gt;idempotent write&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Audit log + metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt;: every attempt is recorded with correlation IDs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reconciliation jobs&lt;/STRONG&gt;: periodic sanity checks to detect drift (e.g., stock/price mismatches).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1369922593"&gt;Data contract and mapping&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Define a &lt;STRONG&gt;versioned contract&lt;/STRONG&gt; between Woo and SAP. Keep a living spec (&lt;CODE&gt;v1&lt;/CODE&gt;, &lt;CODE&gt;v1.1&lt;/CODE&gt;, …). Typical mappings:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Order header&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;DocDate&lt;/CODE&gt; ← Woo order date (UTC normalized).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;CardCode&lt;/CODE&gt; ← Customer code (derived from email/metadata or a “generic web” account with address lines).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Comments&lt;/CODE&gt; ← Human note + machine hints (payment/ref, applied coupon, shipping method).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;UDFs&lt;/CODE&gt; ← DNI/NIE, marketing source, consent flags.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lines&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;ItemCode&lt;/CODE&gt; ← SKU (strict).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Quantity&lt;/CODE&gt; ← Int/decimal; enforce unit policy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Price&lt;/CODE&gt; ← Decide: pre-VAT vs after-VAT. Keep one source of truth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;DiscountPercent&lt;/CODE&gt; ← Merge order-level and line-level discounts carefully.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Taxes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Align &lt;STRONG&gt;tax groups&lt;/STRONG&gt; (SAP) with &lt;STRONG&gt;Woo tax classes&lt;/STRONG&gt; (name + rate). Don’t hardcode 21% if rates can vary per product/region.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;When Woo shows prices &lt;STRONG&gt;incl. VAT&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensure you send &lt;CODE&gt;PriceAfterVAT&lt;/CODE&gt; (or compute net + tax group consistently).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Shipping &amp;amp; fees&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Model shipping as a non-inventory item with its own tax group.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Payment fees (if used) should be explicit items for auditability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1173409088"&gt;Idempotency strategy&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keying&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Use a stable, deterministic &lt;STRONG&gt;idempotency key&lt;/STRONG&gt; per semantic operation. For order creation, a good default is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;"wc:" + order_id + ":comments:v2"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;edger table&lt;/STRONG&gt; (minimal schema)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;CREATE TABLE sync_ledger (
  id BIGINT AUTO_INCREMENT PRIMARY KEY,
  idem_key VARCHAR(128) UNIQUE NOT NULL,
  source VARCHAR(32) NOT NULL,    -- 'wc'
  target VARCHAR(32) NOT NULL,    -- 'sapb1'
  op VARCHAR(32) NOT NULL,        -- 'create_invoice', 'patch_comments'
  status VARCHAR(16) NOT NULL,    -- 'applied','skipped','failed'
  target_docnum VARCHAR(64) NULL, -- SAP DocNum/DocEntry
  checksum VARCHAR(64) NULL,      -- payload hash (optional)
  created_at TIMESTAMP DEFAULT CURRENT_TIMESTAMP,
  updated_at TIMESTAMP DEFAULT CURRENT_TIMESTAMP ON UPDATE CURRENT_TIMESTAMP
);
​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apply-once guard (PHP example)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;function already_applied($pdo, $key){
  $stmt = $pdo-&amp;gt;prepare("SELECT status, target_docnum FROM sync_ledger WHERE idem_key=?");
  $stmt-&amp;gt;execute([$key]);
  return $stmt-&amp;gt;fetch(PDO::FETCH_ASSOC);
}

function mark_applied($pdo, $key, $op, $docnum){
  $stmt = $pdo-&amp;gt;prepare("
    INSERT INTO sync_ledger (idem_key, source, target, op, status, target_docnum)
    VALUES (?, 'wc','sapb1', ?, 'applied', ?)
    ON DUPLICATE KEY UPDATE status='applied', target_docnum=VALUES(target_docnum)
  ");
  $stmt-&amp;gt;execute([$key, $op, $docnum]);
}

function create_invoice_once($pdo, $payload){
  $key = "wc:".$payload['order_id'];
  if ($row = already_applied($pdo, $key)) {
    // Return the previously created doc (idempotent)
    return ['status'=&amp;gt;'ok','docnum'=&amp;gt;$row['target_docnum'],'idempotent'=&amp;gt;true];
  }
  // ... map Woo → SAP body
  $sap = sap_create_invoice($payload); // call Service Layer/DI-API
  mark_applied($pdo, $key, 'create_invoice', $sap['DocNum']);
  return ['status'=&amp;gt;'ok','docnum'=&amp;gt;$sap['DocNum'],'idempotent'=&amp;gt;false];
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Retry/backoff&lt;BR /&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;exponential backoff&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; with jitter (e.g., 5s, 15s, 45s, 2m… up to a ceiling).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Only retry on &lt;STRONG&gt;transient&lt;/STRONG&gt; failures (timeouts, 5xx).&lt;BR /&gt;Stop on &lt;STRONG&gt;validation&lt;/STRONG&gt; errors and route to DLQ with a clear reason.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-976895583"&gt;Observability and audit&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Minimum viable signals:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Correlation ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;: include &lt;CODE&gt;X-Correlation-ID: wc:&amp;lt;order_id&amp;gt;&lt;/CODE&gt; in all logs and SAP calls when possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt;: processed/min, success rate, median &amp;amp; p95 latency, retries, DLQ size.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Structured logs&lt;/STRONG&gt;: JSON lines with stage, order_id, idempotency_key, op, outcome, docnum, error_code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example (JSON log):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{"ts":"2025-10-21T07:25:00Z","corr":"wc:58291","stage":"worker",
 "op":"create_invoice","idemp":"wc:58291","result":"applied","docnum":"153447"}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-780382078"&gt;ecurity and privacy&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PII minimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: only store what you need for reconciliation. Mask sensitive fields in logs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transport&lt;/STRONG&gt;: TLS everywhere; verify certificates; set sane timeouts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Auth&lt;/STRONG&gt;: never embed long-lived SAP creds in frontend systems. Keep secrets in your sync service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reconciliation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: a periodic job that compares a slice of last N orders between Woo and SAP and emits a report.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-583868573"&gt;Handling prices and stock (the tricky parts)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prices&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Decide if Woo is &lt;STRONG&gt;incl. VAT&lt;/STRONG&gt; and make the mapping deterministic. If SAP holds net prices:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Convert Woo gross → net using the exact tax group.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Or switch to &lt;CODE&gt;PriceAfterVAT&lt;/CODE&gt; in SAP where appropriate (be consistent).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure coupon discounts don’t double-apply (line-level vs order-level).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stock&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you maintain multi-warehouse levels, your queue should:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read current availability from SAP (01, LI, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Apply business rules (which warehouse feeds the web?).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Push the &lt;STRONG&gt;effective&lt;/STRONG&gt; stock back to Woo on a schedule (and after significant changes).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-387355068"&gt;Testing matrix (what to simulate)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Duplicate webhook deliveries (2–5 times).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP API 5xx and slow responses (timeouts).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Price with and without VAT; multiple tax classes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shipping with different tax groups.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Partial failures: header accepted, line rejected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Network partitions (queue builds up).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Schema evolution: add UDF, new field in comments, deprecate a field.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-190841563"&gt;Minimal worker skeleton (Python-ish pseudocode)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def worker_loop(queue, sap_client, db):
    for msg in queue.consume():
        order = msg.payload
        idem = f"wc:{order['id']}"

        prior = db.find_ledger(idem)
        if prior and prior.status == 'applied':
            ack(msg); continue

        try:
            body = map_woo_to_sap(order)      # normalize/mapping
            doc  = sap_client.create_invoice(body)  # call Service Layer
            db.upsert_ledger(idem, op='create_invoice', status='applied', docnum=doc['DocNum'])
            ack(msg)
        except TransientError as e:
            msg.retry(backoff='expo_jitter')
        except ValidationError as e:
            db.upsert_ledger(idem, op='create_invoice', status='failed', docnum=None)
            msg.to_dlq(reason=str(e))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--5671942"&gt;Rollback &amp;amp; human-in-the-loop&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;No blind deletes&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Create compensating actions (credit memo) instead of destructive edits.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide a small &lt;STRONG&gt;ops dashboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;: search by order ID, see ledger status, re-send safe operations with a single click.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-145068910"&gt;What about the checkout side?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you operate in regions that need &lt;STRONG&gt;national ID validation&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., Spain’s DNI/NIE/CIF), implement:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Client-side&lt;/STRONG&gt; hints to reduce friction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Server-side&lt;/STRONG&gt; validation for integrity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blocks &amp;amp; Classic&lt;/STRONG&gt; compatibility (selector names differ).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Store validated ID as a UDF in SAP so finance can reconcile.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This reduces address/accounting errors &lt;STRONG&gt;before&lt;/STRONG&gt; the sync pipeline receives the order.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--51444595"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The best SAP ↔ WooCommerce integrations succeed not because the API calls are clever, but because the &lt;STRONG&gt;system around them&lt;/STRONG&gt;—idempotency, retries, observability, and data discipline—is boringly reliable. Start with a strong contract, a small ledger, and a queue; the rest is iteration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--541361107"&gt;About the author&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Luis Javier Gil&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a WordPress/WooCommerce developer and founder at Replanta LC. He builds production-grade integrations (SAP Business One ↔ WooCommerce), performance tooling, and checkout compliance features.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/designing-an-idempotent-sap-business-one-woocommerce-sync-patterns-pitfalls/ba-p/14249326"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:10:17.449000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/request-for-guidance-on-entering-physical-location-data-for-fixed-assets-in/qaq-p/14257169</id>
    <title>Request for Guidance on Entering ‘Physical Location’ Data for Fixed Assets in SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:12:22.247000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aalmayyahi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2262032</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dear Team,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;We are currently working on updating the Physical Location information for our fixed assets in SAP. We would appreciate your guidance or suggestions on the best way to enter and manage this data.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Here are the details of our situation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; We have approximately 3,000 fixed asset records.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Each fixed asset (FA) card may represent one or more units.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Each unit can be associated with up to 40 different physical locations.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Could you please advise on the following:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What are the recommended options or fields in SAP to capture multiple physical locations for a single FA?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Are there any best practices or configuration settings we should consider to ensure accurate reporting and easy maintenance?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Thank you in advance for your support.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/request-for-guidance-on-entering-physical-location-data-for-fixed-assets-in/qaq-p/14257169"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:12:22.247000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/2h2025-sfcomp-31209-advanced-filters-on-worksheets/qaa-p/14257170#M49032</id>
    <title>Re: 2H2025 - SFCOMP-31209: Advanced Filters on Worksheets</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:16:34.665000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DavidSomelofske</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The filters, when enabled are available on all tabs on all three template types (Comp, VarPay and Total).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I just tested in my demo system on a total comp template using filters on all the tabs and the filters were successful.&amp;nbsp; What I would say is to logoff and then login to retest.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;If you are still having issues, add another comment with screen shots and we will take another look.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks, David&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/2h2025-sfcomp-31209-advanced-filters-on-worksheets/qaa-p/14257170#M49032"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:16:34.665000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/information-missing-when-activating-identity-authentication-integration-in/qaq-p/14257171</id>
    <title>Information missing when activating Identity Authentication Integration in LMS - for externals</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:20:57.760000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>teresa_costa</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2262686</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When activating Identity Authentication Integration in LMS for externals (last step of the process) there's an error referring that the following parameters are not configured on System Administration &amp;gt; Configuration &amp;gt; System Configuration &amp;gt; SAP CLOUD IDENTITY, but I am not able to identify from where in IAS / IPS I get this information. Does anyone faced the same issue?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;IasServiceProviderID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;IpsSourceSystemID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;IpsAPIUrl&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;metadataProviders[IAS].value&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/information-missing-when-activating-identity-authentication-integration-in/qaq-p/14257171"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:20:57.760000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-reverse-rebate-accrued-amount-in-invoice-without-final-settlement-of/qaq-p/14257174</id>
    <title>How to reverse rebate accrued amount in Invoice without Final Settlement of Condition Contract?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:22:59.619000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>anwesha08</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/147872</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have a scenario where Business wants to reverse the SD invoice rebate accrual &amp;amp; manual accrual w/o generating any credit note to Customer. The manual accrual can be reversed by WB2R_AB_DOCS by selecting the manual accrual settlement document. At this point if we do Final Settlement, credit memo gets generated which can be reversed by the same process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However,&amp;nbsp; Business doesn't want to generate credit memo &amp;amp; reverse the manual accrual and invoice accrued amount at the end of the period. How to achieve this any suggestion?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#ConditionContractManagement#SettlementManagement#Rebate&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-reverse-rebate-accrued-amount-in-invoice-without-final-settlement-of/qaq-p/14257174"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:22:59.619000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-mdg-fi-node-xxx-is-not-located-within-the-hierarchy/qaq-p/14257175</id>
    <title>SAP MDG FI: Node XXX is not located within the hierarchy</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:24:10.406000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sandeep_suggu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11644</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;!-- StartFragment  --&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hi SCN Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope you are all doing well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While performing operations on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP MDG Finance Data Loads&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Cost and Profit Center Hierarchy), I encountered an error during &lt;STRONG&gt;File Upload – Step 04 (Check &amp;amp; Execute):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;"Node XXX is not located within hierarchy."&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Interestingly, this cost hierarchy already exists in the system for the given edition, but it is not visible under &lt;STRONG&gt;Display Master Data: Cost Center Group hierarchy&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s what I have already checked:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In &lt;STRONG&gt;Steps 1 to 3&lt;/STRONG&gt; of File Upload, all parameters were evaluated and assigned correctly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The variant settings appear fine.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The hierarchy structure in the system matches the Excel file.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m unsure what might be causing this issue. Could anyone please guide me on:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What parameters I should re-check or adjust?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Possible reasons why the hierarchy is not being recognized at Step 04?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Any best practices or troubleshooting steps for this scenario?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your insights or experiences would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Sandeep Suggu.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;!-- EndFragment  --&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-mdg-fi-node-xxx-is-not-located-within-the-hierarchy/qaq-p/14257175"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:24:10.406000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/test-equipment-management-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-edition/qaq-p/14257178</id>
    <title>Test equipment management in S/4HANA Public Cloud Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:25:05.514000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>9150</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1604373</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi QM Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am looking for a best practice process for test equipment management in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Has anyone already gained experience in this area? I think this process is not available in Public Cloud Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The inspection typ 14 is also not&amp;nbsp; available in Standard Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your feedback!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards Sam.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/test-equipment-management-in-s-4hana-public-cloud-edition/qaq-p/14257178"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:25:05.514000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-can-assigment-details-section-to-have-symbols-in-its-number/qaa-p/14257179#M49034</id>
    <title>Re: Variable Pay - Can Assigment Details section to have...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:27:58.868000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laura_Gyselbrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/29863</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I actually remembered this note after we had already resolved the issue — of course!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the end, we managed to fix it by exporting the configuration from another environment and importing it.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/variable-pay-can-assigment-details-section-to-have-symbols-in-its-number/qaa-p/14257179#M49034"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:27:58.868000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ec-promotion-promote-link-in-worksheet-is-not-available/qaa-p/14257180#M49035</id>
    <title>Re: EC Promotion - Promote link in worksheet is not avail...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:30:41.233000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laura_Gyselbrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/29863</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Issue solved - KBA 3669643 - &lt;A href="https://eur02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fme.sap.com%2Fnotes%2F03669643&amp;amp;data=05%7C02%7Claura.gyselbrecht%40flexso.com%7C7b12f729957542c2833f08de1313f04a%7C49c3d703357947bfa8887c913fbdced9%7C0%7C0%7C638969173625477702%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJFbXB0eU1hcGkiOnRydWUsIlYiOiIwLjAuMDAwMCIsIlAiOiJXaW4zMiIsIkFOIjoiTWFpbCIsIldUIjoyfQ%3D%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=KAnmcHA8Ah2LzSHIjzgmztDUFcuHB8S0zHuNn2ed28Q%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Promotion link is not visible in worksheet when user proxy as another user&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/ec-promotion-promote-link-in-worksheet-is-not-available/qaa-p/14257180#M49035"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:30:41.233000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-fiori-apps/qaa-p/14257181#M62264</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Fiori Apps</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:30:49.369000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>junwu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/126031</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;?? you are missing button or content?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-fiori-apps/qaa-p/14257181#M62264"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:30:49.369000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-use-the-new-grc-ruleset-manager-grac-rule-set-manager-sample-excel/bc-p/14257184#M176165</id>
    <title>Re: How to use the new GRC Ruleset Manager (GRAC_RULE_SET_MANAGER Sample Excel File)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:35:00.444000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>IsmailDincer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1830076</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Super informative and helpful. Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-use-the-new-grc-ruleset-manager-grac-rule-set-manager-sample-excel/bc-p/14257184#M176165"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:35:00.444000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori-forum/sm30-customizing-table-to-fiori-app/td-p/14257186</id>
    <title>SM30 customizing table to Fiori App</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:39:25.654000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>d_schuitemaker62</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/716640</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When using SM30 for custom tables, it is possible to use C as the type, so that the table can only be maintained via TR.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For Cloud Proof technology, we should replace these SM30 by Fiori Apps, to maintain custom tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How to achieve, that the user gets a TR popup for a Customizing request, when saving an entry via such a Fiori App?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori-forum/sm30-customizing-table-to-fiori-app/td-p/14257186"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:39:25.654000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/calling-an-external-web-service-via-https-using-the-system-certificate/qaa-p/14257187#M4930575</id>
    <title>Re: Calling an external web service via https using the system certificate store</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:40:46.052000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VolkerBarth</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/352</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hm, the error message seems to mix up SQLCODEs and ODBC 3 states? (HY000 would be "Database server already running")... - That being said, have you tried to use web client logging (via sa_server_option('WebClientLoggingusing'...) and/or used the procedure's HTTP(EXCEPTIONS=OFF) option to get more diagnostics?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If you are able to call the web service via other web clients, are you not able to find out how they accept the web server's certificate? Do they use SNI (which you could make SQL Anywhere use via the CERTIFICATE clause....)?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Otherwise, I'm out of my wits.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/calling-an-external-web-service-via-https-using-the-system-certificate/qaa-p/14257187#M4930575"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:40:46.052000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-api-management-with-s4hana-via-sap-po/qaa-p/14257188#M4930576</id>
    <title>Re: SAP API Management with S4HANA via SAP PO</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:44:17.144000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>germinico</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2262689</uri>
    </author>
    <content>it is possible to connect API Management on BTP with SAP PO ?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-api-management-with-s4hana-via-sap-po/qaa-p/14257188#M4930576"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:44:17.144000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/why-sap-crystal-reports-viewer-doesn-t-support-windows-11-print-preview/qaa-p/14257189#M4930577</id>
    <title>Re: Why SAP Crystal Reports Viewer doesn't support Window...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:44:50.286000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DonWilliams</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121895</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;So what you are saying is it doesn't work using Windows applications, correct?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;quick test, create a test app that doesn't use CR runtime, just open any document and use Windows Print dialogs, does that work?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nothing CR can do, post your question to Windows Forums...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here's what I see using SP 38 and POC and the Snagit Print Preview, note, P2P doesn't show me a dialog box using my test app:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DonWilliams_0-1761831517709.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334364i90FDC2B1918C525B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DonWilliams_0-1761831517709.png" alt="DonWilliams_0-1761831517709.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also note: CR .NET uses Windows default dialog boxes, there are 2 different ones as you've seen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;System.Drawing.Printing.PrintDocument pDoc = new System.Drawing.Printing.PrintDocument();&lt;BR /&gt;System.Drawing.Printing.PageSettings pPage = new PageSettings();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you try my printer test app, and it will need to be updated according to my Blog:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2021977247"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upgrading-a-visual-studio-2008-gt-2022-net-project-with-the-latest-cr-net/ba-p/13469215" target="_blank"&gt;Upgrading a Visual Studio 2008-&amp;amp;gt;2022 .NET project with the latest CR .NET SDK packages&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you don't get what you want using that test app it's not a CR issue...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use a report with saved data and set the default printer to Snagit.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/why-sap-crystal-reports-viewer-doesn-t-support-windows-11-print-preview/qaa-p/14257189#M4930577"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:44:50.286000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-note-for-create-xml-transformation-logbr-nf-to-xml-download/qaa-p/14257190#M4230519</id>
    <title>Re: SAP NOTE FOR CREATE XML TRANSFORMATION LOGBR_NF_TO_XM...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:45:24.453000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hce</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1614005</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear colleagues,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to inform you about an issue we have identified regarding the implementation of a manual step for the tax reform in Brazil.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Although we are operating with an &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA 1709&lt;/STRONG&gt; system, and &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3642384" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 3642384 - Brazil Tax Reform Troubleshooting Guide - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;indicates that the &lt;CODE&gt;LOGBR_NF_TO_XML_DOWNLOAD&lt;/CODE&gt; transformation exists in S/4HANA releases (as per point E4 of the note, which states it "only exists in the S4 system release"), &lt;STRONG&gt;we have found that this transformation is not available in our environment&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consequently, we are unable to perform the manual step described in &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3618181" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 3618181 - Prerequisite tax invoice fields for CBS and IBS tax situation&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;using the &lt;CODE&gt;STRANS&lt;/CODE&gt; transaction code, as the expected transformation is not found.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need to investigate this discrepancy, as the absence of this structure prevents the correct application of the steps recommended by SAP for the tax reform scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Already opened incident with Sap support, but still without answer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hélio Paixão&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-note-for-create-xml-transformation-logbr-nf-to-xml-download/qaa-p/14257190#M4230519"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:45:24.453000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/creating-a-successfactors-learning-story-report-a-comprehensive-guide/bc-p/14257191#M7303</id>
    <title>Re: Creating a SuccessFactors Learning Story Report: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:46:13.039000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MADHUPAN</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2567</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Really Helpful ! Thanks a lot &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I have one question: once I save the report, can I edit it later? I want to test the same scenario as in your example, but I'm unable to do so.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/creating-a-successfactors-learning-story-report-a-comprehensive-guide/bc-p/14257191#M7303"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:46:13.039000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/exceptional-aggregation/qaa-p/14257192#M4930578</id>
    <title>Re: Exceptional Aggregation</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:52:07.612000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Martin_Kuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/275733</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi, you need to use the Gross Amount, not the Header gross Amount as base for your exception (not expeptional) aggregation.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/exceptional-aggregation/qaa-p/14257192#M4930578"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:52:07.612000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unable-to-find-mapping-for-linktoobj-field-in-owor-production-orders-via/qaq-p/14257193</id>
    <title>Unable to find mapping for “LinkToObj” field in OWOR (Production Orders) via SAP Service Layer</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T14:53:56.629000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>IRONTECH</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1803896</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m trying to update the field &lt;STRONG&gt;“LinkToObj”&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the &lt;STRONG&gt;OWOR (Production Orders)&lt;/STRONG&gt; table from &lt;STRONG&gt;“Sales Order”&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;STRONG&gt;“Production Order”&lt;/STRONG&gt; using the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Service Layer&lt;/STRONG&gt; with a &lt;STRONG&gt;PUT&lt;/STRONG&gt; request.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, I can’t find any corresponding property or mapping attribute for &lt;STRONG&gt;LinkToObj&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the Service Layer metadata or documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone managed to modify this field through the Service Layer, or know the correct field name or approach to do so?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance for your help!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unable-to-find-mapping-for-linktoobj-field-in-owor-production-orders-via/qaq-p/14257193"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T14:53:56.629000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/calling-an-external-web-service-via-https-using-the-system-certificate/qaa-p/14257198#M4930579</id>
    <title>Re: Calling an external web service via https using the system certificate store</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:01:00.623000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stalker4</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1750830</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The server is running with the “-zoc” option. Here is the result of the server log for this Web service call.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[connid = 8, [30/10/2025:15:59:01.796 0200]]
[connid = 8, [30/10/2025:15:59:01.796 0200], REQUEST]
POST /realms/dnipro/protocol/openid-connect/token HTTP/1.1
Content-Type: application/x-www-form-urlencoded; charset=windows-1251
Connection: close
ASA-Id: bcb757c755f4420581a02a295a32ae91
Content-Length: 99
Accept-Charset: windows-1251, UTF-8, *
Date: Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:59:01 GMT
Host: sbx-id-service.globalpoll.com.ua
User-Agent: SQLAnywhere/17.0.10.5866

[connid = 8, Error: socket closed]
[connid = 8, socket closed]
[connid = 8, Error: socket closed by peer]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;If necessary, I can show you the log of this web service call from "Postman". Would you like to see it ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I made a small change to the procedure itself:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;set 'HTTP(VERSION=1.1;EXCEPTIONS=OFF)'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is “SNI” ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/calling-an-external-web-service-via-https-using-the-system-certificate/qaa-p/14257198#M4930579"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:01:00.623000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-story-new-table-switch-formatting-after-new-table-switch-table/qaq-p/14257199</id>
    <title>SAC story New table switch formatting - After New table switch table formatting is not getting saved</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:04:43.316000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lpb0417</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/824881</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does anyone tried the new table experience,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we have switched our existing story tables to new table, After New table switch table formatting is not getting saved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone pl suggest the solution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;LakshmiPrasanna&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-story-new-table-switch-formatting-after-new-table-switch-table/qaq-p/14257199"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:04:43.316000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/capacity-scheduling-tables-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-limitation-with-date/qaq-p/14257200</id>
    <title>Capacity Scheduling Tables in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public - limitation with date range</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:08:23.253000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nicolasduches</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/106500</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;BR /&gt;We use this app "Capacity Scheduling Table" to schedule our production orders.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we click in orders and the windows for dispatch open. the date range have always 4 days. But when we click date range to choose the date, it's impossible to chose the date of the day?? Why?&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;APP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nicolasduches_0-1761832785741.png" style="width: 185px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334365i72C96F4E657A780D/image-dimensions/185x61/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="185" height="61" role="button" title="nicolasduches_0-1761832785741.png" alt="nicolasduches_0-1761832785741.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You can see the date range, by default it's today until november 2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nicolasduches_1-1761832797786.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334366i1C15496F8697E9A3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nicolasduches_1-1761832797786.png" alt="nicolasduches_1-1761832797786.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nicolasduches_2-1761832807019.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334367i478981EFA675CCF5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nicolasduches_2-1761832807019.png" alt="nicolasduches_2-1761832807019.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we like to chose date range, it's impossible to chose today... why? see error message&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nicolasduches_3-1761832819040.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334368iEE93E6C26902975D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="nicolasduches_3-1761832819040.png" alt="nicolasduches_3-1761832819040.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can i do something to be able to chose the date of the day?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/capacity-scheduling-tables-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-limitation-with-date/qaq-p/14257200"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:08:23.253000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sales-oder-created-with-wrong-time-slot/qaq-p/14257202</id>
    <title>Sales oder created with wrong time slot</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:11:49.271000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ricardo_ASP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1989524</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello dear colleagues,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The process implemented with one of our customers is based on an EDI connection.&lt;BR /&gt;Sales orders are created based on the message sent by the customer, and in that message, the customer specifies different delivery time slot within the same day.&lt;BR /&gt;When creating the sales order, system always uses the first time and assigns that same time when creating the second sales order.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone experienced a similar problem?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sales-oder-created-with-wrong-time-slot/qaq-p/14257202"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:11:49.271000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori-forum/sm30-customizing-table-to-fiori-app/m-p/14257203#M34</id>
    <title>Re: SM30 customizing table to Fiori App</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:13:38.877000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>junwu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/126031</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;that's default, you don't have to do anything if I am not wrong.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori-forum/sm30-customizing-table-to-fiori-app/m-p/14257203#M34"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:13:38.877000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/difference-in-business-partner-tabs-between-prd-and-test-system/qaq-p/14257204</id>
    <title>Difference in Business Partner Tabs Between PRD and TEST  system</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:15:07.258000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>archana_raut38</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1794365</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are facing a inconsistency between our PRD and TEST environments related to the display of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Partner (BP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In &lt;STRONG&gt;PRD&lt;/STRONG&gt;, when displaying the Business Partner. We can see the tabs &lt;STRONG&gt;Company Codes&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Purchasing Organizations&lt;/STRONG&gt; under the Business Partner role.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, in &lt;STRONG&gt;TEST&lt;/STRONG&gt;, for the same BP grouping and category, these tabs are tabs are not visible. We only &amp;nbsp;see the &lt;STRONG&gt;Basic Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Address&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Roles&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Bank Accounts&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Attachments&lt;/STRONG&gt; are visible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could anyone please suggest why there is a difference in the BP tabs display between the PRD and TEST systems?&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/difference-in-business-partner-tabs-between-prd-and-test-system/qaq-p/14257204"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:15:07.258000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/data-is-not-populating-in-sap-fiori-app-and-in-tile-count-is-not-showing/qaa-p/14257205#M4930581</id>
    <title>Re: Data is not populating in sap Fiori app and in tile count is not showing.</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:16:31.649000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joel_John</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172000</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Is this a standard app or custom? Is there an error message? If so, what does it say? Have you tried any debugging steps?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/data-is-not-populating-in-sap-fiori-app-and-in-tile-count-is-not-showing/qaa-p/14257205#M4930581"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:16:31.649000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/you-are-not-authorized-to-use-transaction-fbw3/qaa-p/14257206#M256118</id>
    <title>Re: You are not authorized to use transaction FBW3</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:19:31.300000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dawid90</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172309</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1465584"&gt;@Sabrina89&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Maintain Business Role app, search for the role appropriate for your country, e.g., SAP_BR_AR_ACCOUNTANT_IT (IT = Italy), and add it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then, inside the role, go to the business catalog tab, edit, and add business catalogs SAP_FIN_BC_AR_BOE_PC and SAP_FIN_BC_AR_PDC_PC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Refresh SAP and give a feedback it's working.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More details below in implementation information tab for which countries the role I wrote about works.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('FBW3')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('FBW3')/S35&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dawid&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/you-are-not-authorized-to-use-transaction-fbw3/qaa-p/14257206#M256118"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:19:31.300000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori-forum/fiori-elements-object-page-l%C3%A4dt-ui-ger%C3%BCst-und-buttons-nicht/td-p/14257207</id>
    <title>Fiori Elements Object Page lädt UI-Gerüst und Buttons nicht</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:23:37.643000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nelson_dev</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2262698</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hallo Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ich stehe vor einem schwerwiegenden Problem mit einer Fiori Elements Object Page, die zwar über das Fiori Launchpad gestartet wird, aber &lt;STRONG&gt;kein vollständiges UI-Gerüst&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Header-Fakten, Aktions-Buttons, Facet-Tabs/Unterabschnitte) rendert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Das Problem liegt nicht in der Anzeige von Daten, sondern in der &lt;STRONG&gt;Ladephase der Seite selbst&lt;/STRONG&gt;, was auf einen Fehler in der Metadaten-Verarbeitung oder der Laufzeitumgebung hindeutet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892895239"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Kontext und Setup&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;App-Typ:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Fiori Elements (basierend auf einer Consumption/Analytical CDS View).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Haupt-Entität:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;CODE&gt;ZC_LabelDeviceConfiguration&lt;/CODE&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Metadaten-Generierung:&lt;/STRONG&gt; CDS-basiert (ABAP Programming Model for SAP Fiori/RAP).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696381734"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fehlerbild in der Object Page&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Die Fiori Launchpad &lt;STRONG&gt;Kachel&lt;/STRONG&gt; wird korrekt angezeigt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Die &lt;STRONG&gt;URL&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;CODE&gt;.../ZC_LabelDeviceConfiguration('TXL-123')&lt;/CODE&gt;) wird korrekt aufgerufen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Die Seite zeigt &lt;STRONG&gt;nur den Anwendungsnamen&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;CODE&gt;IBC printer management&lt;/CODE&gt;) und eventuell den &lt;STRONG&gt;Titel/Beschreibung&lt;/STRONG&gt; des Objekts, aber &lt;STRONG&gt;keine Buttons, keine Struktur, keine Tabs&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Das UI-Gerüst bleibt leer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499868229"&gt;Technisches Problem: Kritischer OData-Fehlschlag&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Beim Laden der Object Page schlägt der initiale OData-Request zur Datenbeschaffung und &lt;STRONG&gt;Metadaten-Verarbeitung&lt;/STRONG&gt; fehl:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Getestet:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Der kritische OData-Aufruf zur Abfrage der Hauptdaten und der assoziierten Untertabellen (&lt;CODE&gt;$expand&lt;/CODE&gt;) wurde im Gateway Client (&lt;CODE&gt;/IWFND/GW_CLIENT&lt;/CODE&gt;) direkt getestet und schlägt mit einem generischen OData-Fehler fehl.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Request URI:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;CODE&gt;/sap/opu/odata/sap/ZPP_IBC_LABELING_SRV/ZC_LabelDeviceConfigurationSet('TXL-123')?$expand=to_zlabeldevsync&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Response:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Generischer OData-Fehler (&lt;CODE&gt;&amp;lt;error xmlns...&amp;gt;&lt;/CODE&gt;, Code: &lt;CODE&gt;00505692409C1ED99...&lt;/CODE&gt;), der auf einen &lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP-Laufzeitfehler (Dump)&lt;/STRONG&gt; im Backend hindeutet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Da dieser initiale Request fehlschlägt, kann das Fiori Elements Framework die notwendigen Informationen (Action-Buttons, Facet-Definitionen) nicht abrufen und bricht die UI-Generierung ab.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303354724"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Frage an die Community&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Welcher &lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP-Laufzeitfehler (Dump-Titel in ST22)&lt;/STRONG&gt; ist typisch, wenn ein &lt;CODE&gt;$expand&lt;/CODE&gt; auf einer CDS-Assoziation zu einem Abbruch der OData-Verarbeitung führt, bevor Daten zurückgegeben werden können?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Können &lt;STRONG&gt;fehlende Annotationen&lt;/STRONG&gt; in der CDS View (wie z.B. &lt;CODE&gt;@Consumption.semanticKey&lt;/CODE&gt;) dazu führen, dass die &lt;STRONG&gt;UI-Generierung&lt;/STRONG&gt; komplett fehlschlägt, obwohl die &lt;CODE&gt;UI.HeaderInfo&lt;/CODE&gt; vorhanden ist?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Gibt es bekannte Probleme mit &lt;STRONG&gt;inkonsistenten Schlüsseln&lt;/STRONG&gt; zwischen dem Hauptobjekt und dem Kind-Objekt, die zu einem Dump während des &lt;CODE&gt;$expand&lt;/CODE&gt;-Prozesses führen?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Habt ihr noch andere Ideen?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vielen Dank für jeden Hinweis, der uns hilft, den zugrundeliegenden ABAP-Fehler zu lokalisieren, der die gesamte UI-Generierung blockiert.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori-forum/fiori-elements-object-page-l%C3%A4dt-ui-ger%C3%BCst-und-buttons-nicht/td-p/14257207"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:23:37.643000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-fiori-apps/qaa-p/14257208#M62265</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Fiori  Apps</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:26:30.812000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>The screenshots seem to say that the button "create" is displayed for one system but not displayed for the other, but your text is saying something else. Please clarify.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-fiori-apps/qaa-p/14257208#M62265"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:26:30.812000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/se78-logo/qaa-p/14257211#M4930582</id>
    <title>Re: se78 - logo</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:32:55.473000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>width 25, what is that? What about "sizing"? Screenshot is better. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-place-an-se78-image-on-an-adobe-form/bc-p/13270652" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-place-an-se78-image-on-an-adobe-form/bc-p/13270652&lt;/A&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/se78-logo/qaa-p/14257211#M4930582"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:32:55.473000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/production-scheduling-considering-limited-setup-times/qaq-p/14257212</id>
    <title>Production Scheduling considering limited setup times</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:33:14.077000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SimonB4</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2129342</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear all,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have the following challenge to set up either in S/4 HANA ERP or in PP/DS:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On a work center e.g. CNC milling machine, the setup (1h) must be scheduled within the day times (07:00 - 16:30), while the machine itself can work 24h.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I tried so far with&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;2 capacities&amp;nbsp; in the work center setup time in both capacities and both relevant for capacity scheduling&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Suboperation with a setup work center (Works not 100% reliable in PP/DS scheduling)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward for some hints.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/production-scheduling-considering-limited-setup-times/qaq-p/14257212"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:33:14.077000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-fiori-apps/qaa-p/14257217#M62266</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Fiori Apps</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:36:35.403000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S0027278946</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2231701</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I found the solution</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/sap-fiori-apps/qaa-p/14257217#M62266"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:36:35.403000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/wien-events/sap-stammtisch-wien-13-11-2025-ganserl-essen-amp-post-sap-teched-spezial/ec-p/14257218#M41</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Stammtisch Wien - 13.11.2025 - Ganserl Essen &amp; Post-SAP-TechEd Spezial</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:36:38.608000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mmuttenthaler</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8390</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;spitzen Idee, mein Lieblings(-Frühstücks)lokal.&lt;BR /&gt;Bitte für mich das Gansl (kein Menü) bestellen&lt;BR /&gt;Danke&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/wien-events/sap-stammtisch-wien-13-11-2025-ganserl-essen-amp-post-sap-teched-spezial/ec-p/14257218#M41"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:36:38.608000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-your-transition-paths-to-sap-business-data-cloud-data-architecture/ba-p/14257176</id>
    <title>Planning your transition paths to SAP Business Data Cloud (data architecture miniseries)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:45:00.537000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JoseBastidas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3227</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Planning your transition paths to SAP Business Data Cloud.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334360i3D94D25DD6617A99/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Planning your transition paths to SAP Business Data Cloud.png" alt="Planning your transition paths to SAP Business Data Cloud.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modernizing your data landscape starts with a clear path to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join this &lt;STRONG&gt;exclusive session for SAP Partners&lt;/STRONG&gt;, part of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Architecture Miniseries&lt;/STRONG&gt;, to explore proven architecture options and transition strategies that enable unified data operations, faster innovation, and insight-driven decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ll cover how &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; integrates with SAP BDC to power hybrid innovation, connect data products across &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and support both greenfield and phased modernization scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ll also gain access to &lt;STRONG&gt;complimentary SAP assessments&lt;/STRONG&gt; that help you plan and execute a confident transition to SAP BDC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Register here &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jul/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010869.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jul/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010869.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPBusinessDataCloud #SAPPartners #DataArchitecture #SAPBTP #SAPAnalytics&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-your-transition-paths-to-sap-business-data-cloud-data-architecture/ba-p/14257176"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:45:00.537000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/bc-p/14257235#M185829</id>
    <title>Re: BTP Trial Update: CF Runtime Availability</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:46:03.715000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CarolinBoeke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44516</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Christian (&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10851"&gt;@ceedee666&lt;/a&gt;),&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for reaching out. Integration Suite ist still available on Trial and can be leveraged. You can reach out to our BTP Trial Support Inbox (&lt;A href="mailto:sapbtptrialsupport@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;sapbtptrialsupport@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;) so we can have a closer look at your curriculum and connect you with SAP University Alliances to find a solution.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I understand you frustration and hope we can find a solution together.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Carolin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/bc-p/14257235#M185829"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:46:03.715000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/third-party-meeting-app-integration-with-successfactors-interview/ba-p/14257234</id>
    <title>Third-Party Meeting App Integration with SuccessFactors Interview Scheduling Solution</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:49:31.329000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Berg_Song</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44306</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This blog presents a practical solution for integrating third-party meeting platforms with SuccessFactors Interview Scheduling in scenarios where a standard integration with Microsoft Teams already exists. Due to current system limitations—specifically, the absence of supported meeting type fields in SuccessFactors Recruiting—this workaround provides a feasible approach until native enhancements become available. It is hoped that future releases, particularly with SmartRecruiters joining the SAP product family, will address these gaps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="background" id="toc-hId-1763812610"&gt;Background&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A multinational customer uses multiple online meeting tools, with Microsoft Teams being the primary platform. The goal was to automate interview meeting invitations across all supported meeting tools besides Teams. Once the interview time is confirmed, SAP Cloud Platform Integration (CPI) or another middleware should retrieve the necessary details—meeting time, participants (interviewer, candidate, and organizer)—then call the corresponding third-party meeting API to create the meeting and calendar event, followed by triggering a standalone email notification with the meeting link.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Community-Flow-Copy of Interview Integration.drawio.png" style="width: 791px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334386iB0FEE1C6312B294C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Community-Flow-Copy of Interview Integration.drawio.png" alt="SAP Community-Flow-Copy of Interview Integration.drawio.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="limitations" id="toc-hId-1567299105"&gt;Limitations&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Interview Type&lt;/STRONG&gt; field is not available in the &lt;CODE&gt;JobApplicationInterview&lt;/CODE&gt; API, and no alternative standard field exists to differentiate meeting tools. &lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="254DE1BB-A108-44CC-8808-2320D29D4387.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334377iF2798038CDF30735/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="254DE1BB-A108-44CC-8808-2320D29D4387.png" alt="254DE1BB-A108-44CC-8808-2320D29D4387.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Custom fields cannot be added to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Interview Schedule&lt;/STRONG&gt; user interface.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;There is no &lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Services Center (ISC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; trigger to monitor interview events and invoke the &lt;CODE&gt;JobApplicationInterview&lt;/CODE&gt; API in real time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once &lt;STRONG&gt;Interview Scheduling&lt;/STRONG&gt; is enabled, "Interview Scheduling" cannot be initiated via API unlike the old feature, as documented in the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-platform/sap-successfactors-api-reference-guide-odata-v2/jobapplicationinterview?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors API Reference Guide&lt;/A&gt;. These constraints not only prevent clear differentiation between interviews conducted via third-party meeting platforms and those hosted on Microsoft Teams, but also make it impossible to initiate interview scheduling from external platforms and synchronize the confirmed interview times back into SuccessFactors for subsequent assessment and evaluation processes. &lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4BA7E5E5-FA25-4D01-9DE8-5E315D5AC425.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334379i6F173C7800048232/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4BA7E5E5-FA25-4D01-9DE8-5E315D5AC425.png" alt="4BA7E5E5-FA25-4D01-9DE8-5E315D5AC425.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="workaround" id="toc-hId-1370785600"&gt;Workaround&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disable Interview Scheduling&lt;/STRONG&gt; and use the legacy interview setup approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Microsoft Teams meeting integration cannot be used.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This feature will eventually be deprecated.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use a free-text &lt;STRONG&gt;Notes&lt;/STRONG&gt; field, where HR can specify the meeting tool for middleware reference.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add a custom field&lt;/STRONG&gt; — &lt;EM&gt;Meeting Tool&lt;/EM&gt; — in the job application template and grant recruiters edit access during the meeting stage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Middleware can query this field to identify the meeting platform and call the appropriate API to create the meeting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The drawback is that the organizer must perform operations in separate page—Interview Schedule and application profile(Meeting Tool)—reducing usability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Multiple custom fields are required if multiple interview rounds use different third-party tools, to avoid duplicate meeting creation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="technical-solution-details" id="toc-hId-1174272095"&gt;Technical Solution Details&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create a Custom Field: Meeting Tool&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="5C92F778-4622-469C-9F9A-6AC88587D7AD.jpg" style="width: 870px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334382i3F5FF1CDE9F7887F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5C92F778-4622-469C-9F9A-6AC88587D7AD.jpg" alt="5C92F778-4622-469C-9F9A-6AC88587D7AD.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recruiter initiates interview scheduling&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and the candidate confirms the time slot.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Middleware queries&lt;/STRONG&gt; interview scheduling, meeting tool, candidate, organizer, and interviewer information.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;API Endpoint:&lt;/STRONG&gt; {{SF API Endpoint}}/odata/v2/JobApplicationInterview?$format=json&amp;amp;$expand=jobApplication/cust_MeetingTool,interviewer&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sample Response:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;{
  "d": {
    "results": [
      {
        "__metadata": {
          "uri": "https://api15.sapsf.cn/odata/v2/JobApplicationInterview(599L)",
          "type": "SFOData.JobApplicationInterview"
        },
        "applicationInterviewId": "599",
        "templateType": "JOB_REQ",
        "notes": null,
        "endDate": "/Date(1696950000000+0000)/",
        "candSlotMapId": "599",
        "isTimeSet": 1,
        "source": "INTERNAL",
        "recruitEventStaffId": null,
        "applicationId": "632",
        "startDate": "/Date(1696946400000+0000)/",
        "status": "RATED",
        "interviewer": {
          "__metadata": {
            "uri": "https://api15.sapsf.cn/odata/v2/User('000010')",
            "type": "SFOData.User"
          },
          "userId": "SFADMIN",
          "email": "sf@demo.com"
        },
        "jobApplication": {
          "__metadata": {
            "uri": "https://api15.sapsf.cn/odata/v2/JobApplication(632L)",
            "type": "SFOData.JobApplication"
          },
          "cust_MeetingTool": {
            "results": []
          }
        }
      },
      {
        "__metadata": {
          "uri": "https://api15.sapsf.cn/odata/v2/JobApplicationInterview(601L)",
          "type": "SFOData.JobApplicationInterview"
        },
        "applicationInterviewId": "601",
        "templateType": "JOB_REQ",
        "notes": null,
        "endDate": "/Date(1696662000000+0000)/",
        "candSlotMapId": "603",
        "isTimeSet": 1,
        "source": "INTERNAL",
        "recruitEventStaffId": null,
        "applicationId": "651",
        "startDate": "/Date(1696660200000+0000)/",
        "status": "NOT_RATED",
        "interviewer": {
          "__metadata": {
            "uri": "https://api15.sapsf.cn/odata/v2/User('000011')",
            "type": "SFOData.User"
          },
          "userId": "64002294",
          "email": "sf@demo.com"
        },
        "jobApplication": {
          "__metadata": {
            "uri": "https://api15.sapsf.cn/odata/v2/JobApplication(651L)",
            "type": "SFOData.JobApplication"
          },
          "cust_MeetingTool": {
            "results": []
          }
        }
      }
    ]
  }
}&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;H2 id="conclusion" id="toc-hId-977758590"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;While this workaround enables integration with third-party meeting software, it highlights the need for SAP SuccessFactors to enhance the Interview Scheduling feature. Ideally, the platform should support native integration options for external meeting platforms. As SmartRecruiters becomes part of the SuccessFactors product family, we look forward to seeing these improvements that make SAP Recruiting more versatile and competitive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Besides, &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-recruiting/setting-up-and-maintaining-sap-successfactors-recruiting/rest-api-for-third-party-integration-with-interview-scheduling?q=sm-mapping&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;in the recent 2025 2H release&lt;/A&gt;, I noticed the introduction of a new feature titled “REST API for Third-Party Integration with Interview Scheduling.” However, no corresponding details or implementation guidelines are currently available in the OData API documentation, RCM implementation guide, or the SAP SuccessFactors Business Accelerator Hub. &lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334383i29CE9259A69E221B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image.png" alt="image.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/third-party-meeting-app-integration-with-successfactors-interview/ba-p/14257234"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:49:31.329000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/service-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-2025-release/ba-p/14233333</id>
    <title>Service Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2025 Release</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:57:02.994000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DequanXu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/166429</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog shares highlights on Service Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2025 Release, showcasing how these innovations address critical business challenges in service delivery, operational efficiency, and customer satisfaction.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The innovations in this blog are a part of SAP features released on October 8, 2025.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can find an overview of selected innovation highlights across all lines of business in the blog posts below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-erp-private-2025-product-release-highlights/ba-p/14237649" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 Product Release Highlights by Bert Schulze&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" href="http:/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-innovations-in-sap-cloud-erp-private-2025/ba-p/14249159" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AI-innovations in SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 by Yannick Peterschmitt&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-erp-private-2025-fps0-release-highlights-part-1/ba-p/14236762" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 FPS0 Release Highlights by Harish Mangtani&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890930083"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1694416578"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Core Service Management Enhancements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Plant and storage location in service transactions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Service team determination based on custom attributes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tool items in service transactions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Copying additional contract items from service contract templates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Service with advanced execution: navigation link from maintenance order to service order&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Fiori apps for maintenance management in Service with Advanced Execution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Resource-related cost items in Service Order for Advanced Execution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497903073"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-Powered Service Intelligence with Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule: Provide summary of service delivered for a given equipment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule: Enhancements to service orders&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule: Enhancements to Service Confirmations – Complete &amp;amp; Cancel&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule: Search and create follow-ups for in-house service objects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Searching, navigating to, and managing service contracts with Joule&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301389568"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Operational Excellence Features&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ad hoc billing plan enhancements&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consistent settlement of hierarchies, including settlement to cost-based CO-PA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced shipping of in-house service objects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intracompany logistics for in-house service objects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Additional supports for products in quantity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extensibility Fiori app F7695 "Manage In-House Services"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Changing service contracts in mass&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;OData v4 APIs for Service Order, Service Confirmation, and Service Quotation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simplifying transition to service contract management via migration object in migration cockpit&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104876063"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-908362558"&gt;Plant and Storage Location in Service Transactions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This feature introduces dedicated, editable fields for Plant and Storage Location at the item level of service transactions. Planners and coordinators can specify where service work is performed or staged for each line item, ensuring that follow-on logistics and financial processes use the correct plant and storage location. This makes multi-plant and multi-location scenarios easier to model and manage across quotes, orders, and confirmations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This increases flexibility in service execution, reduces manual corrections, and aligns downstream logistics and accounting, helping teams accelerate fulfillment and improve data quality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Plant and storage location in service transactions" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334369i98CAD416C5D6B7AF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Plant and storage location in service transactions.png" alt="Screenshot: Plant and storage location in service transactions" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Plant and storage location in service transactions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-711849053"&gt;Service Team Determination Based on Custom Attributes&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Service team determination now supports custom attributes in assignment rules. Administrators can include factors such as product line, region, priority, customer tier, or organization-specific attributes to drive automated routing. The rules reflect how your service organization operates, ensuring service orders and requests are assigned to the best-fit team from the start.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This offers more flexibility to model determination rules based on customer requirements, enabling more-precise routing, fewer reassignments, and stronger SLA adherence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Service Team determination based on custom attributes" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334372i3EF635704C4E87F7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Service Team determination based on custom attributes.png" alt="Screenshot: Service Team determination based on custom attributes" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Service Team determination based on custom attributes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-515335548"&gt;Tool Items in Service Transactions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Service transactions can include tool items to capture specialized tools required to deliver a service. Tool usage is represented as dedicated line items, enabling both external billing (where relevant) and internal cost allocation. This ensures tools are planned, accounted for, and settled alongside labor and materials in a standardized way.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This extends service process coverage by supporting tool items, creating clearer cost tracking and standardized planning for engagements that rely on specialized equipment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Tool Items in Service Transactions" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334373i1E96B039628541B4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tool items in service transactions.png" alt="Screenshot: Tool Items in Service Transactions" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Tool Items in Service Transactions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-318822043"&gt;Copying Additional Contract Items from Service Contract Templates&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Users can enrich existing service contracts by searching and selecting items from approved service contract templates during extensions or changes. A guided copy capability lets teams add reusable building blocks to contracts quickly and consistently, reducing the need to create items from scratch.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This streamlines contract changes, saves time, lowers error rates, speeds responses to customer requests, reduces administrative effort, and enables scaling without a proportional increase in workload.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Copying Additional Contract Items from Service Contract Templates" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334374i3C66D68D36C0FEFA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Copying additional contract items from service contract templates.png" alt="Screenshot: Copying Additional Contract Items from Service Contract Templates" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Copying Additional Contract Items from Service Contract Templates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-122308538"&gt;Service with Advanced Execution: Navigation Link from Maintenance Order to Service Order&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Advanced Execution harmonizes asset and service management by enabling the asset management phase model for billable maintenance orders and providing direct navigation to related service quotes or service orders. Approval workflows are supported within the phase model for both scenarios, creating a controlled, end-to-end flow for billable work across maintenance and service.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This creates functional alignment between asset management and service management, supporting smoother handovers, improved visibility, and more-governed execution for billable work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--149436336"&gt;SAP Fiori Apps for Maintenance Management in Service with Advanced Execution&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Modern SAP Fiori apps can be used to handle billable maintenance processes within the Advanced Execution scenario. Enabled capabilities include displaying, status changes, and scheduling of billable maintenance orders (where applicable) using apps such as Manage Maintenance Orders, Find Maintenance Order, Find Maintenance Order and Operation, Manage Components and Services, Maintenance Backlog Overview, Manage Maintenance Planning Buckets (including the new version), Manage Maintenance Backlog, and Manage Maintenance Notifications and Orders (for phase-enabled orders). This brings an aligned user experience between maintenance and service.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This makes it easier to adopt service-relevant innovations from maintenance management, reduces training complexity, and increases efficiency through a consistent user experience across maintenance and service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: SAP Fiori Apps for Maintenance Management in Service with Advanced Execution" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334376i84B4340515804804/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Fiori apps for maintenance management in the Service with Advanced Execution.png" alt="Screenshot: SAP Fiori Apps for Maintenance Management in Service with Advanced Execution" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: SAP Fiori Apps for Maintenance Management in Service with Advanced Execution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--345949841"&gt;Resource-Related Cost Items in Service Orders for Advanced Execution&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Service Orders display resource-related cost items (RRCIs) based on planned data. When the process starts with a Service Quotation, RRCIs can be copied to the Service Order (per copy control) and refreshed or redetermined from the latest planning data in the corresponding billable maintenance order using the Refresh Planning action. If starting directly with a Service Order, RRCIs can be generated and later refreshed from maintenance order planning; Refresh Planning is available until the first release of the Service Order.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This supports accurate cost estimation and pricing by carrying planned costs and markups forward from quotation to order and keeping them current with the latest maintenance planning data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Resource-Related Cost Items in Service Orders for Advanced Execution" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334395i2791D521C34FDD45/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ressource related Cost Items in Service Order for Advance Execution.png" alt="Screenshot: Resource-Related Cost Items in Service Orders for Advanced Execution" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Resource-Related Cost Items in Service Orders for Advanced Execution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--249060339"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule AI-Powered Service Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--738976851"&gt;Joule: Provide Summary of Service Delivered for a Given Equipment&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule provides a conversational, consolidated view of equipment-related service information, including Equipment Service Report, Service History, Basic Details, and Warranty Information. Users can retrieve these insights without navigating multiple apps, streamlining planning, execution, and customer interactions from a single entry point. Available only with SAP S/4HANA Cloud, private edition.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This speeds up information access and decision-making at the point of service, helping technicians and managers reduce app switching and resolve issues more quickly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--935490356"&gt;Joule: Enhancements to Service Orders&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule now supports richer interactions with service orders via natural language: search using additional criteria, jump directly to an order’s item overview, and perform status actions such as complete, business complete, reopen business, reject, or set in process. Users can also complete or set individual items to in process and display item list information—all through conversational prompts. Available only with SAP S/4HANA Cloud, private edition.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This enables faster, centralized handling of service orders and items, reducing clicks and cycle time while improving throughput and control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1132003861"&gt;Joule: Enhancements to Service Confirmations – Complete &amp;amp; Cancel&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule adds conversational capabilities for service confirmations: search confirmations, display transaction history at header and item levels, and complete or cancel confirmations directly. Available only with SAP S/4HANA Cloud, private edition.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This centralizes confirmation processing and history, speeding administrative steps, reducing errors, and helping ensure timely, accurate handling.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1328517366"&gt;Joule: Search and create follow-ups for in-house service objects&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This innovation transforms service object management through conversational AI. Service managers can now use natural language to search for in-house service objects across the system, eliminating the need to navigate through multiple screens or remember specific transaction codes. The AI understands context and intent, allowing queries like "show me all service objects for customer ABC" or "find repair items pending approval." Beyond search, Joule can automatically create follow-up documents such as service orders, quotations, or delivery documents based on conversational prompts. This reduces manual data entry, minimizes errors, and accelerates service processing workflows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This human-centric approach optimizes the daily workflow of service managers. It boosts efficiency by streamlining object discovery and follow-up creation, reducing clicks and time-to-action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Graphic: Joule: Search and create follow-ups for in-house service objects" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334378iCD01438B7C2FB194/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joule- search and create follow-ups for in-house service objects.png" alt="Graphic: Joule: Search and create follow-ups for in-house service objects" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Graphic: Joule: Search and create follow-ups for in-house service objects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1525030871"&gt;Searching, navigating to, and managing service contracts with Joule&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule extends its AI capabilities to service contract management, enabling users to perform complex contract operations through natural language requests. Users can ask Joule to "create a service contract for equipment maintenance" or "cancel contract SC12345 due to customer request," and the system guides them directly to the appropriate functionality. This eliminates the learning curve for new users and reduces the time experienced users spend navigating the system. The AI provides contextual guidance throughout the process, ensuring compliance with business rules and reducing processing errors.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The benefit is faster navigation and task execution for contract-related processes. Teams get specific answers and direct access to actions, lowering the effort needed to manage contracts and improving user satisfaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1428141369"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1624654874"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Operational Excellence Features&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1946387695"&gt;Ad hoc billing plan enhancements&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The system now performs comprehensive validity checks on ad hoc service contract items, automatically verifying that billing values align with net values. When discrepancies are detected, users receive immediate notifications with detailed explanations of the variance. Additionally, organizations can now create reusable ad hoc billing plan templates that can be copied into new billing plans, standardizing billing processes across similar service contracts. This enhancement significantly reduces billing errors, improves financial accuracy, and enables faster contract setup through template reuse.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These safeguards improve billing accuracy, reduce discrepancies, and minimize manual oversight. The result is more reliable financial records, greater customer trust through consistent billing, and time savings that allow teams to focus on strategic tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Graphic: Ad hoc billing plan enhancements" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334381iDD0926EF129FE296/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ad hoc billing plan enhancements.png" alt="Graphic: Ad hoc billing plan enhancements" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Graphic: Ad hoc billing plan enhancements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--2142901200"&gt;Consistent settlement of hierarchies, including settlement to cost-based CO-PA&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Service orders and contracts can now be automatically settled to both margin analysis and costing-based Profitability Analysis (CO-PA), providing comprehensive financial visibility. This dual settlement approach enables organizations to analyze service profitability from multiple perspectives - understanding both direct margins and comprehensive cost structures. The integration supports hierarchical service structures, ensuring that complex service arrangements with multiple levels are properly reflected in financial reporting. This enhancement enables more informed pricing decisions and better portfolio management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The ability to leverage either margin analysis or cost-based CO-PA provides deeper insights into service transaction profitability. It centralizes reporting, supports nuanced analysis, and informs pricing and portfolio decisions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--2046011698"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1759039086"&gt;Enhanced shipping of in-house service objects&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Organizations can now assign specific ship-to parties to in-house service objects and configure alternative shipping addresses at both service and object levels. New shipping attributes are automatically transferred to outbound deliveries, ensuring seamless logistics coordination. This flexibility is particularly valuable for multi-location service operations where objects may need to be returned to different customer sites or service centers. The enhancement streamlines post-service logistics and reduces exceptions in delivery processing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Service managers gain more flexibility when returning in-house service objects to customers and better control over outbound deliveries. These enhancements streamline logistics and reduce exceptions in post-service handoffs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Enhanced shipping of in-house service objects" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334387i8D2F726D4DB89257/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Enhanced shipping of in-house service objects.png" alt="Screenshot: Enhanced shipping of in-house service objects" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Enhanced shipping of in-house service objects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1562525581"&gt;Intracompany logistics for in-house service objects&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This innovation enables seamless transfer of service objects between plants and storage locations within the same company code. Objects can be received via standard delivery processes and displayed with clearly defined location information. The system provides full visibility into logistics-related documents and supports flexible stock management by allowing selection between customer stock B and returns order stock E. This capability improves asset utilization, reduces manual coordination efforts, and strengthens traceability throughout the service lifecycle.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This innovation enables smooth transfers across locations, improves visibility of current object location, and integrates inbound and outbound logistics steps. It reduces manual coordination and strengthens traceability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1659415083"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Intracompany logistics for in-house service objects" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334388iCEACA55F273836A7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Intracompany logistics for in-house service objects.png" alt="Screenshot: Intracompany logistics for in-house service objects" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Intracompany logistics for in-house service objects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1169498571"&gt;Additional supports for products in quantity&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The system now maintains synchronized quantities between returns order items and in-house service objects, ensuring data consistency across all related documents. When returns order item quantities change, corresponding in-house object quantities update automatically. Subservice objects are now displayed directly below main objects in relevant applications and can be sorted by item number for improved usability. This synchronization eliminates quantity discrepancies and provides service managers with accurate, real-time information for decision-making.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result is consistent returns processing and enhanced usability. Service managers can rely on accurate quantities and clearer lists, reducing errors and speeding up operational tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Additional supports for products in quantity" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334389iCF931C77595A86EA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Additional supports for products in quantity.png" alt="Screenshot: Additional supports for products in quantity" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Additional supports for products in quantity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-972985066"&gt;Changing service contracts in mass&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A new application supports bulk updates to service contracts, including mass repricing, party changes, and automated processing through background jobs. Multiple contracts can be processed simultaneously, with the system handling complex business logic and validation rules. This automation significantly reduces administrative overhead for large-scale contract modifications, ensures consistency across contract portfolios, and enables rapid response to market changes or organizational restructuring.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By automating bulk changes, companies reduce manual maintenance effort and administrative cost. It ensures consistency across contracts and speeds up large-scale updates with minimal user intervention.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Changing service contracts in mass" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334390i76725975A061C517/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Changing service contracts in mass.png" alt="Screenshot: Changing service contracts in mass" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Changing service contracts in mass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-776471561"&gt;Extensibility Fiori app F7695 Manage In-House Services&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Organizations can now define custom fields and add them to the user interface while maintaining adherence to SAP S/4HANA standards. Custom logic can be created and maintained to enhance application behavior without compromising system integrity. This extensibility enables customer-specific solutions while preserving upgrade compatibility, reducing the need for separate custom developments and accelerating tailored enhancements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organizations gain flexibility to deliver customer-specific solutions without diverging from standard. This reduces the need for bespoke developments elsewhere and accelerates tailored enhancements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Extensibility Fiori app F7695 Manage In-House Services" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334391i63CD3B58AD8D4802/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Extensibility Fiori app F7695 Manage In-House Services.png" alt="Screenshot: Extensibility Fiori app F7695 Manage In-House Services" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Extensibility Fiori app F7695 Manage In-House Services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-579958056"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OData v4 APIs for Service Order, Service Confirmation, and Service Quotation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New OData v4 A2X APIs replace deprecated v2 versions, offering improved performance and expanded functionality. The v4 APIs include additional properties and entities, such as follow-up service order items and partner functions at the quotation item level. These modern APIs provide better processing efficiency, reduced resource consumption, and enhanced integration capabilities for external applications. The upgrade future-proofs connectivity and enables richer integration scenarios.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modernizing integrations with OData v4 improves processing time and resource consumption on both client and server. Expanded properties enable richer scenarios and future-proof connectivity for external applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-551628242"&gt;Simplifying transition to service contract management via migration object in migration cockpit&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A dedicated migration object in the SAP S/4HANA migration cockpit supports standardized data migration from legacy contract management solutions through staging tables. This reduces transformation complexity, minimizes migration risks, and accelerates time-to-value for organizations transitioning to SAP S/4HANA Service Management. The standardized approach improves data quality and shortens the path to operational readiness.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This reduces transformation risk and cost by streamlining migration projects. A standardized object accelerates data onboarding, improves quality, and shortens the path to operational readiness in service contract management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot: Simplifying transition to service contract management via migration object in migration cockpit" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334392i991CBA7FCD2284CF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Simplifying the transition to service contract management through a migration object in the migration cockpit.png" alt="Screenshot: Simplifying transition to service contract management via migration object in migration cockpit" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Screenshot: Simplifying transition to service contract management via migration object in migration cockpit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1424569926" id="toc-hId-61711730"&gt;More information&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks for reading this blog post.&amp;nbsp;Stay ahead by following the latest updates with the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/PSCC_Enablement/tg-p/board-id/erp-blog-sap" target="_blank"&gt;PSCC_Enablement&lt;/A&gt; tag in SAP Community.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/service-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-2025-release/ba-p/14233333"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:57:02.994000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/bc-p/14257250#M185830</id>
    <title>Re: BTP Trial Update: CF Runtime Availability</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:58:45.181000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ceedee666</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10851</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Carolin,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;the&amp;nbsp;Integration Suite is only part of my lecture. I use it to access a small "erp" system i developed using CAP and deploy to the BTP. With not being able to deploy the erp system the whole lecture setup is not possible anymore.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And one thing is for sure. If I have to move my whole lecture to a new stack now, I'll definitely not going back to the SAP BTP anymore.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Christian&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/btp-trial-update-cf-runtime-availability/bc-p/14257250#M185830"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:58:45.181000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/unexpected-generali-logo-in-background-during-manager-enrollment/qaa-p/14257251#M49036</id>
    <title>Re: Unexpected Generali Logo in Background During Manager...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T15:59:55.264000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PL1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1984680"&gt;@JeffKELLERHALS&lt;/a&gt;, this doesn’t look like an expected behavior and I’m not aware of any configuration for it. If this is still happening, I’d recommend creating a case with SAP Support, under the “LOD-SF-LMS-USR” component (KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0002748769" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2748769&lt;/A&gt;), granting support access through a user who can replicate it (KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2088892" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2088892&lt;/A&gt;) - this will assist with the analysis.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/unexpected-generali-logo-in-background-during-manager-enrollment/qaa-p/14257251#M49036"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:59:55.264000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-call-a-remote-odata-api-from-your-local-cap-java-project/bc-p/14257254#M185831</id>
    <title>Re: How to Call a Remote OData API from Your Local CAP Java Project</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:01:50.276000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KaushikSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2109690</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/841332"&gt;@Umezuki&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Getting this error -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;Failed to get destination with name 'API_BUSINESS_PARTNER'&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Mentioned exactly all properties of &lt;STRONG&gt;5.3&lt;/STRONG&gt; in applicatoin.yaml including name: &lt;STRONG&gt;S4Sandbox&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="KaushikSAP_0-1761836462498.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334401iF08D68D361676703/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KaushikSAP_0-1761836462498.png" alt="KaushikSAP_0-1761836462498.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my case, generated CQN looks little different from your example&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;package cds.gen.businesspartnerservice;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;import com.sap.cds.ql.CdsName;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;import com.sap.cds.services.cds.ApplicationService;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;import com.sap.cds.services.cds.CqnService;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;import com.sap.cds.services.cds.RemoteService;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;import javax.annotation.processing.Generated;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;@Generated("cds-maven-plugin")&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;@CdsName(BusinessPartnerService_.CDS_NAME)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;public interface BusinessPartnerService extends CqnService {&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;interface Application extends ApplicationService, BusinessPartnerService {&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;}&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;interface Remote extends RemoteService, BusinessPartnerService {&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;}&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier" color="#333399"&gt;}&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-call-a-remote-odata-api-from-your-local-cap-java-project/bc-p/14257254#M185831"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:01:50.276000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/testing-group/test-blog-post-page-edit-test/ba-p/14257260</id>
    <title>Test Blog post page edit test+</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:04:53.794000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PC825</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2254442</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Test Blog post page refresh&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;edit test&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/testing-group/test-blog-post-page-edit-test/ba-p/14257260"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:04:53.794000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/replication-steps-for-bp-cusgen-entity-custom-fields-in-mdg-codeployment/qaq-p/14257262</id>
    <title>Replication steps for BP_CUSGEN entity  custom fields in MDG codeployment</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:05:59.536000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SeshaKaturu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1561247</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In MDG Codeployment&amp;nbsp; replication scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have added 2 custom fields in data model BP----&amp;gt;BP_CUSGEN entity. Added two custom fields on Customer UI screen(Control data ).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now I need to replicate the data entered in 2 custom fields on UI screen&amp;nbsp; to the backend ECC system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Appreciate your&amp;nbsp; inputs&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/replication-steps-for-bp-cusgen-entity-custom-fields-in-mdg-codeployment/qaq-p/14257262"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:05:59.536000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/you-are-not-authorized-to-use-transaction-fbw3/qaa-p/14257265#M256119</id>
    <title>Re: You are not authorized to use transaction FBW3</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:09:06.670000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaymondGiuseppi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/185148</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Did you already look at the SAP Fiori Apps Reference site for&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('FBW3')/S35" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;App ID FBW3 - Post Bills of Exchange Receivables Usage&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Implementation information, Configuration&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":down_arrow:"&gt;⬇️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Business Role(s)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/you-are-not-authorized-to-use-transaction-fbw3/qaa-p/14257265#M256119"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:09:06.670000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-bw-bex-report-i-have-issue-with-japan-currency-divding-by-100-kigfigure/qaa-p/14257267#M4930584</id>
    <title>Re: SAP bw bex report I have issue with japan currency di...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:10:21.513000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>akshay_ghai1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/854794</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This issue is due to how SAP stores currency KF at DB level. SAP stores Currency KF with 2 decimal places by default and if there is no value after decimal , it shifts 2 KF digits after decimal due to which issue. Compare the data between ADSO&amp;nbsp; active table /BIC/AXXX2 and&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;sql view /BIC/AXXX8.&amp;nbsp;/BIC/AXXX8 it will have two KF with suffix INTERNAL&amp;nbsp; and EXTERNAL.&amp;nbsp; External will match the data to source ERP. Please check and let me know if it solves your issue.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-bw-bex-report-i-have-issue-with-japan-currency-divding-by-100-kigfigure/qaa-p/14257267#M4930584"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:10:21.513000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-gui-latest-patch/bc-p/14257269#M176167</id>
    <title>Re: SAP GUI latest patch</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:12:30.742000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sapreinhart77</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/471755</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For your information:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;PL15 has solved the problem with text entry.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's see what errors GUI has now.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":face_with_rolling_eyes:"&gt;🙄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/179796"&gt;@ILIAN_Grigorov&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1405677"&gt;@Krtkbrn13&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;: thank your very much for your support.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-gui-latest-patch/bc-p/14257269#M176167"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:12:30.742000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/copenhagen-events/copenhagen-sap-teched-meet-up-november-2025/ec-p/14257271#M2</id>
    <title>Re: Copenhagen SAP Teched Meet up - November 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:13:29.585000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnePetteroe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I will be waving to you from Berlin&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hugging_face:"&gt;🤗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/copenhagen-events/copenhagen-sap-teched-meet-up-november-2025/ec-p/14257271#M2"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:13:29.585000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/unexpected-generali-logo-in-background-during-manager-enrollment/qaa-p/14257273#M49037</id>
    <title>Re: Unexpected Generali Logo in Background During Manager...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:17:11.269000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JeffKELLERHALS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1984680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/unexpected-generali-logo-in-background-during-manager-enrollment/qaa-p/14257273#M49037"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:17:11.269000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/unexpected-generali-logo-in-background-during-manager-enrollment/qaa-p/14257274#M49038</id>
    <title>Re: Unexpected Generali Logo in Background During Manager...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:17:56.779000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JeffKELLERHALS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1984680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, Thanks for your investigation, I already cretated a case to the SAP Support, Have a nice day, Jeff</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/unexpected-generali-logo-in-background-during-manager-enrollment/qaa-p/14257274#M49038"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:17:56.779000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/debugging-abap-on-bw4hana-does-not-work/qaa-p/14257276#M4930585</id>
    <title>Re: Debugging ABAP on BW4Hana does not work</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:21:39.488000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>akshay_ghai1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/854794</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi ,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Most probably the condition is not being satisfied due to which the debugger is not opening at breakpoint. Just try one workaround to debug in GUI. Open the DTP request from manage request and click on the transformation&amp;nbsp; in header and once it opens the transformation in GUI , Display generated program from Extras and add your breakpoint and and Open the new GUI screen and open the manage request and open the DTP request and now click on DTP and simulate the DTP and the debugger will open in GUI so you can debug in old fashioned way.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/debugging-abap-on-bw4hana-does-not-work/qaa-p/14257276#M4930585"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:21:39.488000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-rap-managed-scenario-deletion-of-associated-entity-foreign-keys-etc/qaq-p/14257280</id>
    <title>abap rap managed scenario - deletion of associated entity - foreign keys etc.</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:26:33.887000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>raada</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/451889</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can you explain me, how the foreign keys in db are expected to work in abap rap?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use case: I am creating simple managed rap scenario for job application management. To each application can be associated company and contact person. Respective foreign keys are defined in the application db table as well. Records for company table are managed from separate rap/fiori application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I create a job application record with associated company I would expect the hana will prevent deletion of the company (because of the foreign key usage in application table). But I can delete the respective company ...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Am I missing anything?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance for your insight ...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Radim&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-rap-managed-scenario-deletion-of-associated-entity-foreign-keys-etc/qaq-p/14257280"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:26:33.887000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/story-report-responsive-pages/qaq-p/14257281</id>
    <title>Story report responsive pages</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:28:55.393000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jen_Cooper</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/55368</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is anyone using the Story report responsive pages in their dashboards? We are finding them difficult to use. Any page filters seems to disappear and the reordering of elements doesn't seem that flexible it's hard to design a page that looks good on a desktop monitor and phone size screen area.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyone have tips or tricks on using the responsive pages with Story reports?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/story-report-responsive-pages/qaq-p/14257281"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:28:55.393000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-do-you-handle-terms-amp-conditions-confirmation-when-external-users/qaa-p/14257283#M49040</id>
    <title>Re: How do you handle Terms &amp; Conditions confirmation whe...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:29:23.840000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PL1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17973</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/167278"&gt;@julia_geze&lt;/a&gt;, you could review the item prerequisite feature (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-learning/managing-sap-successfactors-learning-for-administrators/adding-prerequisites-to-learning-items?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Adding Prerequisites to Learning Items&lt;/A&gt;). This way, before purchasing the desired course, users need to complete the prerequisite, which could be a simple file containing the terms and conditions, using an AICC wrapper (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-learning/implementing-structured-content/when-and-how-to-use-aicc-document-wrapper?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;When and How to Use the AICC Document Wrapper&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-do-you-handle-terms-amp-conditions-confirmation-when-external-users/qaa-p/14257283#M49040"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:29:23.840000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/calling-an-external-web-service-via-https-using-the-system-certificate/qaa-p/14257284#M4930587</id>
    <title>Re: Calling an external web service via https using the system certificate store</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:30:38.460000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VolkerBarth</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/352</uri>
    </author>
    <content>SNI is Server Name Indication. As to your POST request, is it expected that is has no body? (At least, that's quite unusual IMHO.) Generally, I would compare the logged requests and responses of your SA web client with that of other working clients and try to find relevant differences. Aside: I'm just another SAP customer so you might ask the official SAP support for more.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/calling-an-external-web-service-via-https-using-the-system-certificate/qaa-p/14257284#M4930587"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:30:38.460000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-migrate-data-from-s4hana-cloud-private-to-s4hana-cloud-public/qaq-p/14257289</id>
    <title>How to migrate data from S4HANA Cloud Private to S4HANA Cloud Public?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:34:52.476000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gleglise</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45383</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;According to the guide&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP S/4HANA Migration Cockpit SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition,&lt;BR /&gt;The&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Migration Cockpit, is&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Not designed for:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Migrating data directly from SAP S/4HANA system to other SAP S/4HANA systems&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;independent of deployment option is currently not supported"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Therefore, what alternatives do we have if a client is in S4HANA Cloud Private and wants to migrate their data to a new S4HANA Cloud Public system? This isn't a greenfield deployment, but rather a conversion. Is there a plan to provide an SAP application that can facilitate this type of migration?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;I would appreciate any suggestions or links that might help.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-migrate-data-from-s4hana-cloud-private-to-s4hana-cloud-public/qaq-p/14257289"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:34:52.476000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/job-profile-url-on-latest-people-profile-user-card/qaq-p/14257295</id>
    <title>Job Profile URL on Latest People Profile User Card</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:38:01.445000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tbrown</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/107814</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Latest People profile, I was able to enable the Job Profile hyperlink&amp;nbsp; in the team member's profile card for Employee View of Others role. However, when I add the same permissions to Employee View of Self role, the hyperlink is not present. I've followed KBAs to enable and compared the permissions of the two roles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is it normal behavior of the system that an employee cannot view their own job profile in their own user card?&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/job-profile-url-on-latest-people-profile-user-card/qaq-p/14257295"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:38:01.445000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/plm-tech-uncovered-sap-integrated-product-development-update-10-2025/ba-p/14257154</id>
    <title>PLM Tech Uncovered: SAP Integrated Product Development Update 10/2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:47:43.493000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sina_Goetz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/828883</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Banner IPD Update Blog Oct 2025.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334345i0AFB9E9E8445F946/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Banner IPD Update Blog Oct 2025.png" alt="Banner IPD Update Blog Oct 2025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PLM Tech Uncovered: SAP Integrated Product Development Update 10/2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hello and welcome to the October 2025 blog in this series! I’m excited to walk you through the latest SAP Integrated Product Development features - let’s dive in:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Change Management&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/4382ac66b18b4699b75b2ce904a2da44/bc991abd55c24ac7b458e6e2cf542328.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Linking Change Validities Within Change Processes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In the Manage Change Processes app, you can link change validities to change processes.&lt;BR /&gt;The product structure uses these validities to determine the “valid from” date, indicating when a change should take effect. They can also be referenced to track and document the implementation of changes to specific business objects.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Product Structure&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/4382ac66b18b4699b75b2ce904a2da44/cc3b624df0564747a8f951607a7f799c.html?version=Cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Date validity available for product structure editing&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You can edit a product structure by specifying when the edits become effective. In the Configure Product Structure app, administrators can specify whether a structure type is edited by date validity or as a versioned structure, and whether a change ID is required for an editing profile. If a change ID is mandatory, users must select one when editing a product structure with that profile. Users can view a component’s header change ID and its validity in the Header Data section of the Structure Editor screen.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product Data Integration&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73555000100800004516&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#;INNO=A710F8E3EB331EEF879EE0809B233366" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Synchronize attributes from authoring tool to EPS product&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Design engineers can synchronize attributes and properties from a CAD authoring tool to an EPS product linked to a PDI Design Item, making the authoring-system information available for downstream business processes.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Specification Management&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PLM_EPD/b183c303b8fc4254a08e565cdee4e163/48df6f0f34854a1dbd39f290a77b2ef0.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Add specifications to collaborations from the Find Specifications app&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You can add specifications to existing collaborations directly from the search results in the Find Specifications app.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To stay informed until the next update you can:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pencil:"&gt;✏️&lt;/span&gt;Subscribe to the &lt;A href="https://url.sap/5nbm4a" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/A&gt; on SAP Integrated Product Development Help Portal&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;Join our LinkedIn group &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/groups/9257139/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Solutions for PLM&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;Visit us at &lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/IPD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;www.sap.com/IPD&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":loudspeaker:"&gt;📢&lt;/span&gt;Want to &lt;STRONG&gt;give feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt; on SAP Integrated Product Development?&lt;BR /&gt;Watch this short&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":television:"&gt;📺&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/activity-7336337958846754816-Qn1o?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;amp;rcm=ACoAAD7NYvwBVArctOHTzpn1Xnqc70RiGDie4SI" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;video&lt;/A&gt; to see how, then send your feedback directly from the app - we’d love to hear from you.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/plm-tech-uncovered-sap-integrated-product-development-update-10-2025/ba-p/14257154"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:47:43.493000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/upgrade-xi-to-2020/qaq-p/14257313</id>
    <title>Upgrade XI to 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:51:14.649000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>wiggan74</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2262713</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have CR XI and need to upgrade to CR 2020. Can I buy the Upgrade 2020 package or do I need to but a Full 2020 package?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;/Jessica&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/upgrade-xi-to-2020/qaq-p/14257313"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:51:14.649000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unable-to-create-new-entries-for-define-change-documents-collective/qaq-p/14257315</id>
    <title>Unable to create New Entries for “Define Change Documents, Collective Purchase Requisition.</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T16:54:10.097000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sandeep_shankarampet</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2210470</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The user has access to the &lt;EM&gt;Application Implementation Activities&lt;/EM&gt;, but in the IMG activity&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“Define Change Documents, Collective Purchase Requisition, MRP relevance”&lt;/STRONG&gt; (under menu -edit), the user is unable to add new entries – the &lt;STRONG&gt;New Entries&lt;/STRONG&gt; button is greyed out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The user performing this change has &lt;STRONG&gt;unrestricted access&lt;/STRONG&gt;, for the role &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_BR_BPC_EXPERT&lt;/STRONG&gt;, yet the button remains disabled.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could someone help explain:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Why would the &lt;STRONG&gt;New Entries&lt;/STRONG&gt; button be unavailable in this customizing node?&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Are there additional authorizations (catalogs/roles) or system settings required besides the role?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Please find the screenshots for your reference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image (25).png" style="width: 539px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334415i3364A8869134212C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image (25).png" alt="image (25).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image (26).png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334417i7799A041C3F33B5C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image (26).png" alt="image (26).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image (27).png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334419iB5026D650AE1CB63/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image (27).png" alt="image (27).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sandeep&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/unable-to-create-new-entries-for-define-change-documents-collective/qaq-p/14257315"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T16:54:10.097000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/enhancing-sap-s-4hana-business-partner-with-a-custom-tab/ba-p/14256857</id>
    <title>Enhancing SAP S/4HANA Business Partner with a Custom Tab</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:00:00.039000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mickaelquesnot</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150004</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":blue_book:"&gt;📘&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Comprehensive Guide: Enhancing SAP S/4HANA Business Partner with a Custom Tab&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This guide provides a complete, end-to-end process for consultants, key users, and end-users on how to enhance the SAP S/4HANA Business Partner (BP) master data screen. We will walk through the technical steps to add a new, custom tabulation (tab) that displays and saves custom fields, based on the specific "FID" bank details example from your document.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Goal:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The standard SAP Business Partner screen needs to capture additional, company-specific bank information that is not available in the standard fields. In this case, we need to add a new tab called "Bank details (FID)" to store indicators for "Customer Account Type" and "Vendor Account Type".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This guide is broken into three parts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The End-User Experience:&lt;/STRONG&gt; What the final result looks like.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The "How-To" Build Guide:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A detailed, step-by-step tutorial for consultants and key users on how to implement this enhancement.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Test Plan:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A practical, real-world business case to validate the solution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The End-User Experience (The "What") &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;🧑‍&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an end-user (such as a Master Data Steward or Finance Clerk), your interaction with the system is simple. When you open the Maintain Business Partner app (or BP transaction), you will see the enhancement directly on the screen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Process: Maintaining FID Bank Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access Business Partner:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You open the Manage Business Partner Master Data Fiori app or run transaction BP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find BP:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You search for and open a Business Partner, for example, 1009 (F-LYON).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;View Custom Tab:&lt;/STRONG&gt; In the "General Data" for the BP, you will see a new tab labeled &lt;STRONG&gt;"Bank details (FID)"&lt;/STRONG&gt; alongside the standard tabs like "Address" and "Payment Transactions".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;View Data:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Clicking this tab displays the custom bank information, including the standard bank details and the new custom fields, such as "Indicator: Customer Account Type" and "Indicator: Vendor Account Type".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Edit Data:&lt;/STRONG&gt; In change mode, you can edit these fields (e.g., check a box) just like any standard field. When you save the Business Partner, this custom information is saved with it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The "How-To" Build Guide (The "How") &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section is for &lt;STRONG&gt;Consultants and Key Users&lt;/STRONG&gt;. We will build the enhancement shown in your documents from start to finish.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.1 Concepts: How BP Enhancement Works (The BDT)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To add new tabs or fields to the BP transaction, SAP provides a standard framework called the &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Data Toolset (BDT)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Think of the BP screen not as one single program, but as a collection of building blocks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Set:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A logical grouping of data (e.g., "Bank Details").&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;View:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A single subscreen (dynpro) that displays data. This is what you create in the Screen Painter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Section:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A container that holds one or more "Views."&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Screen:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A container that holds one or more "Sections." This is what appears as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Tab&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Screen Sequence:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Defines the order of all "Screens" (Tabs) for a specific BP role or view (like "General Data").&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our goal is to create our own custom &lt;STRONG&gt;View&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Section&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Screen&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and then add our new &lt;STRONG&gt;Screen (Tab)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the standard &lt;STRONG&gt;Screen Sequence&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.2 The Build Process: Step-by-Step&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is the complete process to replicate the "Bank details (FID)" enhancement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Create the Data Model (The Foundation)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, we need a place to store our new custom data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Go to Transaction SE11 (ABAP Dictionary).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create a Custom Table:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Create a transparent table named ZBUT0BK.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description:&lt;/STRONG&gt; "BP: Bank Details (FID)"&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fields:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;MANDT (Key)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PARTNER (Key) (Type BU_PARTNER)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BUKRS (Key) (Type BUKRS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BKVID (Key) (Type BU_BKVID)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ZZXDEBI: "Indicator: Customer Account Type" (Type XFELD)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ZZXKRED: "Indicator: Vendor Account Type" (Type XFELD)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This table will hold our custom indicators, linked to the BP's main bank data key. Your document also shows these fields appended to BUT0BK, which is necessary so the standard bank data structure (used by the screen) is aware of them.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Create the Screen (The User Interface)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, we create the actual screen (dynpro) that the user will see.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Go to SE80 or SE38&lt;/STRONG&gt; to create a new Function Group (e.g., ZUD0). SAPLZUD0 is the program name for this function group.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Go to SE51 (Screen Painter).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create Screen:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Program:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAPLZUD0&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Screen number:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1500&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Design the Layout:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the graphical editor to design the layout. You will likely add a &lt;STRONG&gt;Table Control&lt;/STRONG&gt; (like GT_BUT0BK in the doc) to display multiple bank entries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add fields from your program's global data (see Step 3) for your custom fields (e.g., GT_BUT0BK-ZZXDEBI, GT_BUT0BK-ZZXKRED).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Write the Flow Logic:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The flow logic connects the screen to your ABAP code. Your document shows the following logic:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;ABAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;* MODULE PBO_1500.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; LOOP AT GT_BUT0BK WITH CONTROL TCTRL_BUT0BK CURSOR GV_BK_LINACT.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; MODULE GT_BUT0BK_INIT.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; ENDLOOP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; MODULE TCTRL_PBO.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; MODULE SEPA_MANADATE_PBO.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;PROCESS AFTER INPUT.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;* MODULE PAI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; LOOP AT GT_BUT0BK.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; MODULE GT_BUT0BK_MODIFY.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; ENDLOOP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; MODULE BANK_DETAILS_CURSOR_GET.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; MODULE GT_BUT0BK_LINACT_DETERMINE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; MODULE GT_BUT0BK_MARK_SINGLE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Create the Logic (The "Engine")&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This ABAP code defines what happens during BDT events (e.g., loading or saving data).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Go to SE37 (Function Builder).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create BDT Event Function Modules:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ZUP_BUPA_PBC_MISC (Before screen callup): Loads data from the database.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ZUP_BUPA_PBO_MISC (Before Output): Prepares data for display.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ZUP_BUPA_PAI_MISC (After Entry): Saves data from the screen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add Code to ZUP_BUPA_PBC_MISC:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This FM calls a FORM routine (e.g., BUP500_PBC) inside your function group LZUD0F00 (an include in SAPLZUD0).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Logic (from your doc):&lt;/STRONG&gt; This code reads &lt;EM&gt;both&lt;/EM&gt; the standard bank data and your custom Z-table data, combining them into a single internal table (GT_BUT0BK) for the screen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;ABAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*... (Inside FORM BUP500_PBC) ...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;* Get the current BP number&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CHECK CVI_BDT_ADAPTER=&amp;gt;IS_DIRECT_INPUT_ACTIVE( ) = ABAP_FALSE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CHECK CVI_BDT_ADAPTER=&amp;gt;GET_CURRENT_BP( ) IS NOT INITIAL.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CLEAR GV_PARTNER.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CALL METHOD CVI_BDT_ADAPTER=&amp;gt;GET_CURRENT_BP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; RECEIVING&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; R_PARTNER = GV_PARTNER. [cite: 105, 106]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;* Fill table control table GT_BUT0BK from standard table&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SELECT * FROM BUT0BK INTO CORRESPONDING FIELDS OF TABLE XBUT0BK&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; WHERE PARTNER = GV_PARTNER. [cite: 106]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*... (Logic to move XBUT0BK to GT_BUT0BK) ...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;REFRESH GT_BUT0BK.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;LOOP AT XBUT0BK.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; CLEAR GT_BUT0BK.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; MOVE-CORRESPONDING XBUT0BK TO GT_BUT0BK. [cite: 108]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; * Now read custom Z-table data for this entry&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; READ TABLE GT_ZBUT0BK INTO GS_ZBUT0BK&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; WITH KEY PARTNER = XBUT0BK-PARTNER.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; *... (add BKVID and BUKRS to key if needed) ... [cite: 109]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; IF SY-SUBRC = 0.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; GT_BUT0BK-ZZBUKRS = GS_ZBUT0BK-BUKRS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; GT_BUT0BK-ZZXDEBI = GS_ZBUT0BK-ZZXDEBI. [cite: 110]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; GT_BUT0BK-ZZXKRED = GS_ZBUT0BK-ZZXKRED. [cite: 111]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; ENDIF.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; APPEND GT_BUT0BK.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ENDLOOP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You must also create the ZUP_BUPA_PAI_MISC logic to update/modify/insert entries in your ZBUT0BK table when the user saves.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Configure BDT (The "Wiring")&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now we use the BDT BUS* transactions (via SM30 or directly) to connect all our objects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUS23 (Data Sets):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create Data Set ZUF020 ("Bank Details (FID)").&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUS2 (Field Groups):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create Field Group 6009 ("Bank Details (FID)").&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign your fields (e.g., BUT0BK-BKVID, GT_BUT0BK-ZZXDEBI, GT_BUT0BK-ZZXKRED) to this group. This links the fields to the field group for screen control.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUS3 (Views):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This is the most critical step. Create View ZUF500 ("Bank Details").&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Application:&lt;/STRONG&gt; BUP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Set:&lt;/STRONG&gt; ZUF020&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subscreen:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Program SAPLZUD0, Screen 1500&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Function Modules:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Before screen callup: ZUP_BUPA_PBC_MISC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Before Output: ZUP_BUPA_PBO_MISC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After Entry: ZUP_BUPA_PAI_MISC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUS4 (Sections):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create Section ZUF500 ("BP Bank Details").&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign your View ZUF500 to this section.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUS5 (Screens):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create Screen ZUF500 ("Bank details (FID)").&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set Screen Type to "Data Screen" and Screen origin to "BDT".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign your Section ZUF500 to this screen.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUS6 (Screen Sequences):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Find the standard Screen Sequence BUP001 ("General Data").&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to "Screen Sequence -&amp;gt; Screens".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add a new entry: your Screen ZUF500 ("Bank details (FID)"). This adds your custom screen as a new tab to the "General Data" view.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUSD (BP Views):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select BP View 000000 ("Business Partner (General)").&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to "BP View -&amp;gt; Data Sets".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add a new entry: your Data Set ZUF020 ("Bank Details (FID)"). This links your data to the main BP application.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5: Configure Field Control (The "Permissions")&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, we must make our new fields visible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Go to SPRO:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cross-Application Components -&amp;gt; SAP Business Partner -&amp;gt; Business Partner -&amp;gt; Basic Settings -&amp;gt; Field Groupings -&amp;gt; Configure Field Attributes per Client.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure Attributes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the activity "Configure Field Attributes for Each Client".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Find your new Field Group 6009 ("Bank Details (FID)").&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set its status to &lt;STRONG&gt;"Opt. entry" (Optional entry)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Also, ensure the standard "Bank Details" field group (e.g., 9) is set to "Opt. entry" or "Display" so the standard bank data is visible.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt; your changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Test Plan (The "Verification") &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;🧪&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, let's test the complete solution with a practical business case.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.1 Business Case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A Finance Clerk needs to maintain special "FID" bank indicators for Business Partner &lt;STRONG&gt;1009 (F-LYON)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This BP already has standard bank details. The clerk must verify the new tab, confirm it loads the correct data, and ensure that changes are saved correctly to the custom table ZBUT0BK.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.2 Master Data &amp;amp; Test Data Preparation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Partner:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ensure BP 1009 exists in the system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Standard Bank Data:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ensure BP 1009 has at least one bank detail entry in table BUT0BK. (Example: IBAN FR2714508... ).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Bank Data:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to transaction SM30.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter table/view ZBUT0BK and click "Maintain".&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new entry matching the BP's bank data:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 1009&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CoCd:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 0001 (or the relevant Company Code from BUT0BK)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer:&lt;/STRONG&gt; X (Set this indicator)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vendor:&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Leave blank)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save the entry.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.3 Test Procedure&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Test Step #&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Test Step Name&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instruction&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expected Result&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pass/Fail&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log On &amp;amp; Access BP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log on as a Master Data Steward. Open the Maintain Business Partner app (or BP transaction).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Maintain Business Partner screen appears.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find Business Partner&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find and open BP 1009.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;BP 1009 (F-LYON) is displayed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Verify Custom Tab&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ensure you are in the "General Data" role (e.g., 000000). Look at the row of tabs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A new tab "Bank details (FID)" is visible&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;4&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Verify Data Load (PBC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click the "Bank details (FID)" tab.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The screen displays the bank data for BP 1009. The custom checkbox "Indicator: Customer Account Type" &lt;STRONG&gt;is checked&lt;/STRONG&gt; (from our SM30 data). The "Vendor" checkbox is unchecked.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;5&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Verify Field Control (SPRO)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click the "Change" button to enter edit mode.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The custom fields ("Customer," "Vendor") are &lt;STRONG&gt;ready for input&lt;/STRONG&gt; (not grayed out), confirming the "Opt. entry" setting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;6&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Verify Data Change (PAI)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the "Indicator: Vendor Account Type" box. Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Business Partner is saved without errors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;7&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Verify Data Persistence&lt;/STRONG&gt; (UI)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Re-open BP 1009 in display mode and navigate back to the "Bank details (FID)" tab.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Both checkboxes ("Customer" and "Vendor") are now checked.&lt;/STRONG&gt; The change was saved.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;8&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Verify Data Persistence&lt;/STRONG&gt; (DB)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to SE16N. Open table ZBUT0BK. Enter PARTNER = 1009. Execute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;The record for BP 1009 is displayed. The fields ZZXDEBI and ZZXKRED &lt;STRONG&gt;are both set to 'X'&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Export to Sheets&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You have successfully enhanced the SAP S/4HANA Business Partner master data. By following the standard &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Data Toolset (BDT)&lt;/STRONG&gt; framework, you have created an upgrade-safe custom tab. This process involved:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Creating the &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Model&lt;/STRONG&gt; (ZBUT0BK).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Building the &lt;STRONG&gt;UI&lt;/STRONG&gt; (SE51) and &lt;STRONG&gt;Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt; (SE37).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Wiring everything together using the &lt;STRONG&gt;BDT&lt;/STRONG&gt; (BUS* transactions).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Setting field permissions (SPRO).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This enhancement provides a flexible way to meet specific business requirements directly within the standard master data transaction, ensuring a seamless experience for your end-users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA BP screen enhancement with custom tabulation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I will add some custom fields to an additional tabulation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[Custom fields attached on table BUT0BK and ZBUT0BK tables needs to place on Business Partner custom tab for updates]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Steps –&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BUS23&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BUS4&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BUS5&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BUS6&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Screen is attached to BUP001&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; General Data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BUS3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Program Name SAPLZUD0&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Screen number 1500&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before screen callup&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ZUP_BUPA_PBC_MISC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before Output&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ZUP_BUPA_PBO_MISC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After Entry&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ZUP_BUPA_PAI_MISC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BUS2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BUSD – Data Set attached to standard Business Role&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1634705931"&gt;Screen Painter Concepts&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Screen Painter is a ABAP Workbench tool that allows you to create screens for your transactions. You use it both to create the screen itself, with fields and other graphical elements, and to write the flow logic behind the screen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In older documentation, screens are sometimes referred to as dynpros. This is short for "Dynamic Program", and means the combination of the screen and its accompanying flow logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567275145"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Screen Painter Architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You use the Screen Painter to create and maintain all elements of a screen. These are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Screen Attributes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Describe a screen object in the R/3 System. Screen attributes include the program the screen belongs to and the screen type.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Screen layout&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Screen elements are the parts of a screen with which the user interacts. Screen elements include checkboxes and radio buttons.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Elements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Correspond to screen elements. Fields are defined in the ABAP Dictionary or in your program.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flow logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Controls the flow of your program.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370761640"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Two Screen Painter Modes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Screen Painter has a&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;layout editor&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;that you use to design your screen layout. It works in two modes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_NETWEAVER_702/ff59ad5d6c55101492f7f1c64dee0529/d1801b77454211d189710000e8322d00.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Graphical mode&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_NETWEAVER_702/ff59ad5d6c55101492f7f1c64dee0529/d180231e454211d189710000e8322d00.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Alphanumeric mode&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Both modes offer the same functions but use different interfaces. In graphical mode, you use a drag and drop interface similar to a drawing tool. In alphanumeric mode, you use your keyboard and menus.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Graphical mode is available only on MS Windows 95, MS Windows NT, and Unix/Motif platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To activate the graphical mode, choose&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Utilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the Screen Painter, then select the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Graphical layout editor&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;option.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174248135"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Creating a Screen: Basics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a screen in an existing program and define its attributes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Design the screen layout and define the attributes of the elements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Write the flow logic.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977734630"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Basic Principles&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uses predefined elements with links to the ABAP Dictionary or program.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports forwards navigation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Supports complex elements: Table Control and Tabstrip Control, and Custom Container.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cut/ Copy/ Paste (&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Graph. fullscreen)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Undo/ Redo (&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Graph. fullscreen)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before screen callup&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ZUP_BUPA_PBC_MISC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;CHECK&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;CVI_BDT_ADAPTER&lt;SPAN&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;IS_DIRECT_INPUT_ACTIVE&lt;SPAN&gt;(&amp;nbsp;)&amp;nbsp;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;ABAP_FALSE&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;CHECK&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;CVI_BDT_ADAPTER&lt;SPAN&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GET_CURRENT_BP&lt;SPAN&gt;(&amp;nbsp;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;IS&amp;nbsp;NOT&amp;nbsp;INITIAL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;CLEAR&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GV_PARTNER&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;CALL&amp;nbsp;METHOD&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;CVI_BDT_ADAPTER&lt;SPAN&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GET_CURRENT_BP&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;RECEIVING&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;R_PARTNER&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GV_PARTNER&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;*------&amp;nbsp;fill&amp;nbsp;table&amp;nbsp;control&amp;nbsp;table&amp;nbsp;GT_BUT0BK&amp;nbsp;from&amp;nbsp;table&amp;nbsp;-------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SELECT&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;*&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;FROM&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;BUT0BK&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;INTO&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;CORRESPONDING&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;FIELDS&amp;nbsp;OF&amp;nbsp;TABLE&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;XBUT0BK&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;WHERE&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;PARTNER&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GV_PARTNER&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;REFRESH&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GT_ZBUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SELECT&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;*&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;FROM&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;ZBUT0BK&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;INTO&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;CORRESPONDING&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;FIELDS&amp;nbsp;OF&amp;nbsp;TABLE&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GT_ZBUT0BK&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;WHERE&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;PARTNER&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GV_PARTNER&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;*------&amp;nbsp;fill&amp;nbsp;table&amp;nbsp;control&amp;nbsp;table&amp;nbsp;GT_BUT0BK&amp;nbsp;from&amp;nbsp;table&amp;nbsp;-------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;*------&amp;nbsp;XBUT0BK&amp;nbsp;--------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;REFRESH&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GT_BUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;LOOP&amp;nbsp;AT&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;XBUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;CLEAR&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GT_BUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;MOVE-CORRESPONDING&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;XBUT0BK&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;TO&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GT_BUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;READ&amp;nbsp;TABLE&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GT_ZBUT0BK&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;INTO&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GS_ZBUT0BK&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;WITH&amp;nbsp;KEY&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;PARTNER&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;XBUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;PARTNER&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;IF&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;SY&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;SUBRC&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;GT_BUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;ZZBUKRS&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GS_ZBUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;BUKRS&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;GT_BUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;ZZXDEBI&amp;nbsp;=G&amp;nbsp;S_ZBUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;ZZXDEBI&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;GT_BUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;ZZXKRED&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;=&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;GS_ZBUT0BK&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;ZZXKRED&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;ENDIF&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before Output&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ZUP_BUPA_PBO_MISC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After Entry&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ZUP_BUPA_PAI_MISC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BP Screen–&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-910303844"&gt;Configure Field Attributes per Client&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this activity you define which fields at field group level in master record maintenance (for example&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUPA&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;for SAP Business Partner and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUPR&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;for Business Partner Relationships)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Require an entry (required entry)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are ready for input (optional entry)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are displayed (display)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are hidden (hide),&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;depending on the application object.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This definition is linked with the field status of the other criteria. The status of the field in the input screen for master data is derived from this link.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the attributes delivered, and change if necessary.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/enhancing-sap-s-4hana-business-partner-with-a-custom-tab/ba-p/14256857"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:00:00.039000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/cancellation-of-a-reversal-in-transaction-rerapprv-for-a-saf-t-pt-certified/qaq-p/14257325</id>
    <title>Cancellation of a reversal in transaction RERAPPRV, for a SAF-T PT certified document</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:06:14.592000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Andrejmnunes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/175107</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&lt;STRONG&gt;,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A reversal of an &lt;STRONG&gt;RE document&lt;/STRONG&gt; (using transaction RERAPPRV) was carried out for a previous month, which had already been certified and reported to the Portuguese tax authority through the SAF-T PT file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this reversal, the reversed &lt;STRONG&gt;RE document&lt;/STRONG&gt; is no longer consistent with the communication made through the SAF-T PT file, as it is canceled in our system but invoiced in the Portuguese tax authority’s system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there any way to undo/cancel the reversal so that the &lt;STRONG&gt;RE document&lt;/STRONG&gt; is no longer reversed?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/cancellation-of-a-reversal-in-transaction-rerapprv-for-a-saf-t-pt-certified/qaq-p/14257325"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:06:14.592000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/ie02-text-tab-not-saving-entries-when-editing-equipment/qaq-p/14257327</id>
    <title>IE02 text tab not saving entries when editing Equipment</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:08:39.748000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>krzem30</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/883830</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For some users when they go to IE02 to add internal note to Equipment in text tab system is not saving the data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="krzem30_1-1761840164053.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334433iB996B1D4AE1480D8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="krzem30_1-1761840164053.png" alt="krzem30_1-1761840164053.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="krzem30_0-1761839725182.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334429i504F317F89DFE397/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="krzem30_0-1761839725182.png" alt="krzem30_0-1761839725182.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a workaround they have to click on the pen and only when they type text in here it is saving:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="krzem30_2-1761840240823.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334434i127A138432FD2973/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="krzem30_2-1761840240823.png" alt="krzem30_2-1761840240823.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="krzem30_3-1761840280153.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334435i1B87819CA26F0119/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="krzem30_3-1761840280153.png" alt="krzem30_3-1761840280153.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Co you know why it is happening?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/ie02-text-tab-not-saving-entries-when-editing-equipment/qaq-p/14257327"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:08:39.748000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/check-xml-format-of-belgium-invoice/qaq-p/14257328</id>
    <title>check xml format of Belgium invoice</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:10:34.593000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>massimoaurora</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/684914</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I generated XML file for country BE in the ECC . (transaction EDOC_COCKPIT)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;i need to check the format xml of the invoice for PEPPOL Belgium.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;there is a way before to open the channel to PEPPOL for check the formal content ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thanks for an help&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/check-xml-format-of-belgium-invoice/qaq-p/14257328"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:10:34.593000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-silicon-partners-wins-the-2025-partner-innovation-showdown/bc-p/14257329#M9396</id>
    <title>Re: The Silicon Partners Wins the 2025 Partner Innovation Showdown</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:12:24.279000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bbutler</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/120447</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you for the recognition!&amp;nbsp; We want to work more with SAP SuccessFactors going forward to co-innovate.&amp;nbsp; Next up SmartRecruiters. We are proud to be a trusted partner with SAP SuccessFactors.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-silicon-partners-wins-the-2025-partner-innovation-showdown/bc-p/14257329#M9396"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:12:24.279000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/restrict-only-unblock-for-payment-in-manage-supplier-line-items-app/qaq-p/14257334</id>
    <title>Restrict only “Unblock for Payment” in Manage Supplier Line Items app.</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:19:53.448000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sandeep_shankarampet</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2210470</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the app &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Supplier Line Items&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Public Cloud) our business requirement is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Allow the “Block for Payment” tab for users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Restrict&lt;/STRONG&gt; the “Unblock for Payment” tab so users cannot unblock line items.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;What we have done:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;We set the “Authorization Group for Journal Entry Document Type” to &lt;EM&gt;Not Maintained&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Result: Both “Block for Payment” and “Unblock for Payment” tabs got restricted (i.e., inaccessible).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our question:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is it possible to allow &lt;EM&gt;only&lt;/EM&gt; “Block for Payment” and restrict &lt;EM&gt;only&lt;/EM&gt; “Unblock for Payment”?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are there additional authorisations or configuration settings (catalogues/roles) in Public Cloud which support this level of segregation?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any SAP Notes or documentation for this scenario in Public Cloud?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance for your guidance!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="manage supplier line item.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334436iEA10A0B7B13DE0BB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="manage supplier line item.png" alt="manage supplier line item.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks &amp;amp; Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sandeep&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/restrict-only-unblock-for-payment-in-manage-supplier-line-items-app/qaq-p/14257334"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:19:53.448000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/perform-crud-operation-from-sap-btp-bas-on-datasphere/qaq-p/14257348</id>
    <title>Perform CRUD operation from SAP BTP BAS on Datasphere.</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:30:16.598000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Prayas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1908805</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’re working on a BAS (CAPM) application and aiming to perform full CRUD operations using data from &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While we’ve successfully implemented the &lt;STRONG&gt;read (fetch)&lt;/STRONG&gt; functionality using the architecture shown below, we’re currently facing challenges with enabling &lt;STRONG&gt;create, update, and delete&lt;/STRONG&gt; operations directly on Datasphere tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="solution-diagram.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334443i05A3026275E356E6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="solution-diagram.png" alt="solution-diagram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’d really appreciate any guidance, resources, or architectural suggestions that could help us achieve this. If anyone has experience or insights on enabling write operations with Datasphere from BAS, your support would be invaluable!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Datasphere/pd-p/73555000100800002141" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="16-1"&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Cloud+Application+Programming+Model/pd-p/9f13aee1-834c-4105-8e43-ee442775e5ce" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="100-1"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Fiori+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800000375" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="20-1"&gt;SAP Fiori Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/perform-crud-operation-from-sap-btp-bas-on-datasphere/qaq-p/14257348"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:30:16.598000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-system-refresh-through-lama-3-0-sp-34-is-failing-at-post-copy/qaq-p/14257349</id>
    <title>SAP System Refresh through LAMA 3.0 SP 34 is failing at Post copy automation import</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:30:20.753000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sharanabasappa</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/137909</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are currently performing System refresh through the LAMA using the restore based refresh procedure in lama and we are stuck at the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Post copy automation import step.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;LAMA executed PCA export and while import step post restore is failing with the error &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;id 10:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Invalid XML format [Error: 00/001]&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;id 11:Execution of RFC 'STC_TM_SESSION_IMPORT' failed!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;id 12:Error occured: com.sap.nw.lm.aci.engine.base.api.util.exception.EngineBaseException: Execution of RFC 'STC_TM_SESSION_IMPORT' failed!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;and the logs:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exception thrown by Operation handler when executing process step with ID 'process-aed400dc-b5a4-11f0-ca06-000006784226-step-32'&lt;BR /&gt;[EXCEPTION]&lt;BR /&gt;com.sap.nw.lm.aci.engine.base.exception.EngineException: com.sap.nw.lm.aci.engine.base.api.util.exception.EngineBaseException: Execution of RFC 'STC_TM_SESSION_IMPORT' failed!&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.engine.operation.handler.provisioning.PSCAHandler.execute(PSCAHandler.java:162)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.process.framework.process.ProcessStepExecutionListener.executeOperationHandlerPhase(ProcessStepExecutionListener.java:305)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.process.framework.process.ProcessStepExecutionListener.onExecute(ProcessStepExecutionListener.java:276)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.process.framework.process.ProcessStepExecutionListener.dispatchWorkTask(ProcessStepExecutionListener.java:214)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.process.framework.process.ProcessStepExecutionListener.onMessage(ProcessStepExecutionListener.java:192)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.nw.lm.aci.engine.base.msgbus.MessageBus$MessageSender.sendInternal(MessageBus.java:918)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.nw.lm.aci.engine.base.msgbus.MessageBus$MessageSender.lambda$send$0(MessageBus.java:864)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.base.metric.types.AbstractMetric.meteredExecution(AbstractMetric.java:30)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.base.metric.types.impl.RuntimeMetric.meteredExecution(RuntimeMetric.java:32)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.base.metric.types.HistogramMetric.meteredExecution(HistogramMetric.java:66)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.nw.lm.aci.engine.base.msgbus.MessageBus$MessageSender.send(MessageBus.java:863)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.nw.lm.aci.engine.base.msgbus.MessageBus$MessageAsyncSender.run(MessageBus.java:1013)&lt;BR /&gt;at java.util.concurrent.ThreadPoolExecutor.runWorker(ThreadPoolExecutor.java:1149)&lt;BR /&gt;at java.util.concurrent.ThreadPoolExecutor$Worker.run(ThreadPoolExecutor.java:624)&lt;BR /&gt;at java.lang.Thread.run(Thread.java:838)&lt;BR /&gt;Caused by: com.sap.nw.lm.aci.engine.base.api.util.exception.EngineBaseException: Execution of RFC 'STC_TM_SESSION_IMPORT' failed!&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.engine.operation.handler.util.RFCHandlerUtility.checkBapiOperationResult(RFCHandlerUtility.java:120)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.engine.operation.handler.util.RFCHandlerUtility.checkBapiOperationResult(RFCHandlerUtility.java:96)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.engine.operation.handler.provisioning.PSCAHandler.exImPortTaskListRun(PSCAHandler.java:903)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.engine.operation.handler.provisioning.PSCAHandler.startOperation(PSCAHandler.java:681)&lt;BR /&gt;at com.sap.tc.vcm.engine.operation.handler.provisioning.PSCAHandler.execute(PSCAHandler.java:155)&lt;BR /&gt;... 14 more&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The xml file is fine at the mentioned and tried maintaining at the ctc_data path too, but no luck.&amp;lt;path to file&amp;gt;/vcm_exp_I10_2025_10_29_08_08/ctc_data/sessions/STCTM.SAP_BASIS_COPY_REFRESH_20251029081024313.XML&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;RFC connection to the target works fine.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fencing is allowed from the LAMA to Target system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please let me know if anyone faced same issue or any resolution steps would be appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sharan&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-system-refresh-through-lama-3-0-sp-34-is-failing-at-post-copy/qaq-p/14257349"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:30:20.753000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/influence-the-next-wave-of-sap-btp-innovation-join-the-sap-customer/ba-p/14257344</id>
    <title>Influence the Next Wave of SAP BTP Innovation: Join the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative 2025-3</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:31:53.418000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nadine_p</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/762608</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BTP.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334440i5E6F1D6551ABBFF3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BTP.png" alt="BTP.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transforming Enterprise Innovation with SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BTP is revolutionizing how businesses innovate. This integrated platform combines application development, automation, data and analytics, integration, and AI, empowering enterprises to achieve new levels of efficiency and intelligence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, you can be a part of this transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The third cycle of the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative for 2025 is here, offering you the opportunity to shape the future of SAP BTP. As a customer or partner, you’re invited to collaborate directly with SAP developers and product teams to influence upcoming features, tools, and innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is not just about early access; it’s a chance to steer the direction of enterprise technology.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Don’t wait - registration is open only until November 14, 2025.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check out the full list&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/880" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;or follow the links below to discover the exciting opportunities:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4036" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Adoption of the SAP Job Scheduling service and it's new capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4066" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted message monitoring agent for SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4020" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Attachment handling made easy with SAP Document Management service CAP Plugin&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4032" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CAP Apps and SAP BTP Kyma Runtime Environment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4028" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Effortlessly manage you documents using SAP Document Management service mobile application&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4027" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Improving the Admin's and Solution Architect's Experience on SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4062" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center: Long-Term User Research Initiative&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4022" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Shape the future of job orchestration capabilities in SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4041" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The impact of AI on SAP BTP users&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s build the future together!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation thrives through collaboration. By participating in the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative projects, you help SAP develop more effective and relevant solutions for businesses like yours. This is your chance to impact the future of enterprise technology.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t miss out - sign up today at&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://influence.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;influence.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and be a part of the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Cycle 3 in 2025!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warm regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Team&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Follow-up after registration: When you register for a project, you will be invited to an introductory call with the SAP project lead. Participation beyond this point is optional and typically governed by the &lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/MvteHxp/Public%20Info%20on%20FBA_09_2024.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Feedback Agreement with SAP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/influence-the-next-wave-of-sap-btp-innovation-join-the-sap-customer/ba-p/14257344"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:31:53.418000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/difference-in-business-partner-tabs-between-prd-and-test-system/qaa-p/14257351#M256123</id>
    <title>Re: Difference in Business Partner Tabs Between PRD and TEST  system</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:32:13.958000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan-Crosby</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13126</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Likely a difference between assigned authorizations or some type of in-flight configuration/development that exists in the lower environment.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/difference-in-business-partner-tabs-between-prd-and-test-system/qaa-p/14257351#M256123"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:32:13.958000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/bc-p/14257355#M185834</id>
    <title>Re: Unlocking the Next Chapter of Seamless Planning in SAP Business Data Cloud with Live Versions</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:37:14.513000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Max_Gander</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14553</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/794282"&gt;@thomaselit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please, send me an example. Properties should be visible.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/bc-p/14257355#M185834"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:37:14.513000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/has-anyone-extended-calm/qaa-p/14257362#M4930592</id>
    <title>Re: Has anyone extended CALM?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:40:27.019000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>XavierPicquart</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/164863</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me try to answer your questions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;1. How can custom logic be integrated into CALM?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you please give me more details on what you would like to achieve?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;2. How can custom apps be integrated into CALM?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud ALM provides public API for integration with custom apps or 3rd party tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPCloudALM/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/package/SAPCloudALM/overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;3. Can CALM be integrated into Workzone?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm not a Workzone expert but you can create tiles in Workzone and link them to SAP Cloud ALM applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;4. Is it possible to access Hana behind CALM? I know that there are many APIs.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No. SAP Cloud ALM APIs are available to push or pull data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;5. Can standard apps from CALM be extended?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, using APIs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;6. Is there a way to display logs from CALM in the Cloud Logging Service? In particular, SLG1 from SAP.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is a way to integrate SAP Cloud ALM with Cloud Logging Service.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/alm/sap-cloud-alm/operations/expert-portal/setup-managed-services/calm-setup-cl.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://support.sap.com/en/alm/sap-cloud-alm/operations/expert-portal/setup-managed-services/calm-setup-cl.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Xavier&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/has-anyone-extended-calm/qaa-p/14257362#M4930592"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:40:27.019000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-create-active-x-component/qaq-p/14257368</id>
    <title>Cannot Create Active X Component</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:49:40.664000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MihirSuman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1599288</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Members,&lt;BR /&gt;We have a .NET VB application which uses SAP Function (SAP.FUNCTION.UNICODE) which was working fine in 32 bit SAP GUI, however post upgrade of SAP GUI to 64 bit, the function is throwing the exception :&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cannot Create Active X Component&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We found that Unicode folder has been moved from ProgramFiles(x86) to ProgramFiles, which we assume is causing this error.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Following is the code snippet&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MihirSuman_0-1761842496890.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334460i8B063A9AD4B4060D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MihirSuman_0-1761842496890.png" alt="MihirSuman_0-1761842496890.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Kindly Suggest code changes.&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cannot-create-active-x-component/qaq-p/14257368"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:49:40.664000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/entendiendo-la-extensibilidad-en-sap-cloud-erp-parte-2/bc-p/14257372#M185835</id>
    <title>Re: Entendiendo la Extensibilidad en SAP Cloud ERP: Parte 2</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:51:33.395000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>erickgomez-tech</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9329</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hola &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/127584"&gt;@monicapimiento&lt;/a&gt;, encantado de saludarte y de comentarte la publicación.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) Valoro muchísimo que esté escrito en español, esto tiene un valor incalculable&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) Aunque no trabajo directamente con SAP Cloud ERP, con tu publicación no solo he aprendido cosas nuevas que debo conocer, sino que me da un panorama que puedo adaptar para la conversación relacionada con SAP Business One&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3) Soy fan total y full de BTP y Build, me encanta&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4) Eres un crack, decía en mi live que eres una bendición, porque tener a alguien como tú en SAP es realmente un gran éxito&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Abrazo, mil gracias por la publicación y quedamos a la espera de las siguientes partes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Atentamente,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Erick Gómez&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/entendiendo-la-extensibilidad-en-sap-cloud-erp-parte-2/bc-p/14257372#M185835"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:51:33.395000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E5%AE%9E%E9%99%85%E6%88%90%E6%9C%AC%E6%A0%B8%E7%AE%97%E6%8A%A5%E9%94%9933q/qaa-p/14257373#M4230525</id>
    <title>Re: 实际成本核算报错33Q</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:53:28.669000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOSOBHI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1953210</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E5%AE%9E%E9%99%85%E6%88%90%E6%9C%AC%E6%A0%B8%E7%AE%97%E6%8A%A5%E9%94%9933q/qaa-p/14257373#M4230525"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:53:28.669000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E5%AE%9E%E9%99%85%E6%88%90%E6%9C%AC%E6%A0%B8%E7%AE%97%E6%8A%A5%E9%94%9933q/qaa-p/14257374#M4230526</id>
    <title>Re: 实际成本核算报错33Q</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:54:17.155000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOSOBHI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1953210</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I got the same error i cant fix it can u help me</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/%E5%AE%9E%E9%99%85%E6%88%90%E6%9C%AC%E6%A0%B8%E7%AE%97%E6%8A%A5%E9%94%9933q/qaa-p/14257374#M4230526"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:54:17.155000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-s-4-public-cloud-historical-balances-migration-opening-balances/qaa-p/14257377#M4230527</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S/4 Public Cloud - Historical Balances Migration...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:59:40.497000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SaadFeroz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1539129</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135235"&gt;@Luis_Amaral_Rib43&lt;/a&gt; Try loading historical balance for all periods previous year, including period 16 in your case to populate ending balance in the row highlighted.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-s-4-public-cloud-historical-balances-migration-opening-balances/qaa-p/14257377#M4230527"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:59:40.497000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/quot-money-quot-and-quot-date-quot-format-display-according-to-quot-locale/qaa-p/14257378#M49042</id>
    <title>Re: "Money" and "Date" format display according to "Local...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T17:59:42.708000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>xavierlegarrec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20879</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2081280"&gt;@MariamDia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We don't have access to these tables you are asking about at the end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If it's working fine for most employees in most countries where the right money and dates formats are showing based on the country they are in BUT it's not working only for these 2 countries then I would advise creating a support ticket for this and then letting us know here what they think.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you can't get anyone to show in their regional money and date format then let us know.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Xavier&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/quot-money-quot-and-quot-date-quot-format-display-according-to-quot-locale/qaa-p/14257378#M49042"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T17:59:42.708000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/run-the-material-ledger-to-report-errors-33q/qaa-p/14257379#M4230528</id>
    <title>Re: Run the material ledger to report errors（33Q）</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:01:20.837000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOSOBHI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1953210</uri>
    </author>
    <content>How u solve it?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/run-the-material-ledger-to-report-errors-33q/qaa-p/14257379#M4230528"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:01:20.837000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/run-the-material-ledger-to-report-errors-33q/qaa-p/14257380#M4230529</id>
    <title>Re: Run the material ledger to report errors（33Q）</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:02:40.214000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOSOBHI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1953210</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Some help how to do it</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/run-the-material-ledger-to-report-errors-33q/qaa-p/14257380#M4230529"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:02:40.214000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/document-generation-in-ec/qaq-p/14257385</id>
    <title>Document Generation in EC</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:06:59.234000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Melissa_S</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1392039</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello all,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am wondering how others are using document generation in EC?&amp;nbsp; We are considering using it for promotion/transfer offer letters.&amp;nbsp; Is anyone using document generation for these types of offer letters?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/document-generation-in-ec/qaq-p/14257385"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:06:59.234000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/entendiendo-la-extensibilidad-en-sap-cloud-erp-parte-1/bc-p/14257384#M185836</id>
    <title>Re: Entendiendo la Extensibilidad en SAP Cloud ERP: Parte 1</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:07:05.335000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>erickgomez-tech</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/9329</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hola&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/127584"&gt;@monicapimiento&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Antes de leer en profundidad esta primera entrega de la serie de publicaciones que estás entregando, yo no sabía tanto del mundo de la extensibilidad en SAP Cloud ERP, ¿me interesa este conocimiento? Sí, porque algunos clientes y partners que me buscan para asesorarlos con BTP y Build para SAP Business One, siempre terminan preguntándome por lo mismo, pero de cara a S4HC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Resumido: no solo que ahora tengo una comprensión ampliada de las opciones de extensibilidad para SAP Cloud ERP, sino que este mismo enfoque me sirve para confirmar y aterrizar los mismos requerimientos para SAP Business One, es decir, tus publicaciones me ayudarán a ganar dinero.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mil gracias, tus publicaciones son de muy alto valor y estoy seguro de que ayudarán a millones de personas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Un abrazo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Atentamente,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Erick Gomez&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/entendiendo-la-extensibilidad-en-sap-cloud-erp-parte-1/bc-p/14257384#M185836"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:07:05.335000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/regarding-exam/qaa-p/14257390#M4930594</id>
    <title>Re: Regarding exam</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:18:16.607000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RibeiroE</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39289</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2261060"&gt;@shivasai_adigoppula&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To assist you, as per KBA &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2404504" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2404504 - How to get help with the SAP Learning Hub or SAP Training Center&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To get help for the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Training Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/learninghub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning Hub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, use the "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Contact Us&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;" button (preferred). Or, at the bottom of the page, click on "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Visit the Help Center"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;where you can find a ticketing system to request support with the Training/Learning Hub. You can also&amp;nbsp;contact the SAP Training Center or SAP Learning Hub teams via the Contact details at the bottom of the page.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If the above links are not available, with a logged in session go to&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.learning.sap.com/#/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://support.learning.sap.com/#/home&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to search for an option to 'Create a new ticket' with SAP Learning Hub team.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;BR&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/regarding-exam/qaa-p/14257390#M4930594"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:18:16.607000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/ias-activation-email-resend-after-expired/qaa-p/14257392#M4930595</id>
    <title>Re: IAS activation email resend after expired</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:21:27.815000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Luvv_LK</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1418383</uri>
    </author>
    <content>how to setup the window for expiry for the activation link.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/ias-activation-email-resend-after-expired/qaa-p/14257392#M4930595"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:21:27.815000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-your-transformation-journey-with-the-sap-customer-evolution-kit/ba-p/14257393</id>
    <title>Accelerate Your Transformation journey with the SAP Customer Evolution Kit</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:26:58.385000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gisela_Picaro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53523</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Is the SAP Customer Evolution Kit?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Customer Evolution Kit is a personalized, high-touch engagement lasting just 3–5 days. &lt;SPAN&gt;1:1 virtual sessions with dedicated SAP experts&lt;/SPAN&gt;, your team receives tailored insights, real-time simulations, and practical guidance to plan your cloud or hybrid transition. The objective is to help business owners, IT leaders, and key users make informed decisions about modernization, digital transformation, and the evolution of your SAP landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Gisela_Picaro_0-1761843492380.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334469i9B05CECB13066B5D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Gisela_Picaro_0-1761843492380.png" alt="Gisela_Picaro_0-1761843492380.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who can benefit?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The program is designed for SAP ERP/ECC, S/4HANA On-Premise, and a broad array of LoB solutions (finance, supply chain, procurement, HR, CX, and more). If your organization is considering the future – migration, process innovation, or simply staying ahead – this engagement gives you the clarity and support needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Consider Moving to SAP Business Suite?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Migrating to SAP Business Suite (S/4HANA – cloud or hybrid editions) unlocks the power of in-memory computing, AI-driven automation, and real-time analytics. It ensures compliance with the latest security and regulatory standards, seamless upgrades, and access to the newest ERP features. Data moves more freely, processes are optimized, and your business is prepared for tomorrow’s opportunities, among many others today's and future Business&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maintenance Strategy: Key Dates to Know&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has announced important changes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mainstream maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; for SAP ECC EhP 0-5&amp;nbsp;ends in Dec 31,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2025 &lt;/STRONG&gt;and for EhP&amp;nbsp;6-8 &amp;amp; Business Suite 7 ends in &lt;STRONG&gt;2027&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extended maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt; is available (with additional fees) through &lt;STRONG&gt;2030&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moving to S/4HANA or SAP Business Suite is not just a technical migration—it’s a strategic imperative to stay secure, and remain competitive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;information about SAP software releases:&amp;nbsp;release types, maintenance durations, planned availability, and upgrade paths at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/pam" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Product Availability Matrix (PAM).&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/release-upgrade-maintenance/maintenance-information/maintenance-strategy.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learn more about the SAP Release and Maintenance Strategy&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your organization has an active SAP support agreement, you can sign up for the SAP Customer Evolution Kit free of charge here: &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/sap-customer-evolution-kit/en_us/home.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register today and don’t miss this opportunity to accelerate your journey with confident planning and expert support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-your-transformation-journey-with-the-sap-customer-evolution-kit/ba-p/14257393"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:26:58.385000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-mdk-filter-list-picker-using-the-value-selected-in-the-previous-list/qaa-p/14257395#M4930596</id>
    <title>Re: SAP MDK - Filter List picker using the value selected...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:28:48.725000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohammedSaleem_Bani</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1424267</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Jitendra,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-mdk-filter-list-picker-using-the-value-selected-in-the-previous-list/qaa-p/14257395#M4930596"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:28:48.725000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-mdk-filter-list-picker-using-the-value-selected-in-the-previous-list/qaa-p/14257397#M4930597</id>
    <title>Re: SAP MDK - Filter List picker using the value selected...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:29:11.256000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohammedSaleem_Bani</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1424267</uri>
    </author>
    <content>asdf</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-mdk-filter-list-picker-using-the-value-selected-in-the-previous-list/qaa-p/14257397#M4930597"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:29:11.256000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/quot-money-quot-and-quot-date-quot-format-display-according-to-quot-locale/qaa-p/14257401#M49044</id>
    <title>Re: "Money" and "Date" format display according to "Local...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:33:55.544000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DavidSomelofske</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721</uri>
    </author>
    <content>In addition, If you use a toDate function, the format of the result will be in the format defined, in this case, mm/dd/yyyy. You could try conditional logic. For example, if country is Hungary then use the toDate dd/mm/yyyy else us mm/dd/yyyy, and so on</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/quot-money-quot-and-quot-date-quot-format-display-according-to-quot-locale/qaa-p/14257401#M49044"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:33:55.544000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-check-consumption-for-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-and-its-components/ba-p/14257413</id>
    <title>How to check consumption for SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) and its components?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:37:48.747000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FernandaFroelich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1410810</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Symptom&lt;/STRONG&gt;: You don't know how to check&amp;nbsp;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) usage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Requirements&lt;/STRONG&gt;: You need to have an S-user and the role of Super Administrator assigned in SAP for Me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you don't have an S-User, please check&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/my-support/users/welcome.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;this page&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you are unsure which role you have, please check&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/1282821" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;this note&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resolution&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) Open&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and log in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) Navigate to the "&lt;EM&gt;Dashboards&lt;/EM&gt;" section and click "&lt;EM&gt;Finance &amp;amp; Legal&lt;/EM&gt;".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3) Select "&lt;EM&gt;Consumption&lt;/EM&gt;".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4) Filter for "&lt;EM&gt;Business Data Cloud&lt;/EM&gt;".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5) Click on the measured number to open a card; it explains the consumption by each metric.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Image 01&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="FernandaFroelich_0-1761845531617.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334479iD0F371C3EF721D18/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FernandaFroelich_0-1761845531617.png" alt="FernandaFroelich_0-1761845531617.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Image 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="FernandaFroelich_1-1761845660774.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334481iF80B9112937B79F9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FernandaFroelich_1-1761845660774.png" alt="FernandaFroelich_1-1761845660774.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important reminder:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP Databricks usage is based on actual consumption instead of what is in the quota assignment. For SAP Analytics Cloud, it is considered the number of users assigned for each SAC license according to the quota assignment. For more information on the components usage (SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Datasphere), please refer to this &lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/support/en_us/library/ssp/my-support/systems-installations/system-measurement/cloud-saas-application-usage/sap-business-data-cloud.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt;. If you want to know more about how the metric itself works, check this &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center/agreements/cloud/cloud-services.html?search=Business%20Data%20Cloud&amp;amp;sort=latest_desc&amp;amp;pdf-asset=aaa18b5a-267f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b&amp;amp;page=4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;pdf&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-check-consumption-for-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-and-its-components/ba-p/14257413"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:37:48.747000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/sap-community-how-to-search-for-and-post-sap-cpq-questions/qaa-p/14257419#M84497</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Community: How to search for and post SAP CPQ que...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:46:00.275000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>eric_silva</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/887906</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/666005"&gt;@Sergey_L&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;1. When you're searching you can filter by the tag SAP CPQ or just type SAP CPQ as search and the content that appears will have at least CPQ mentioned.&lt;BR /&gt;2. You can use &lt;SPAN&gt;Financial Management Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Regarding the bonus, I'm unsure, it seems some kind of bug in the community platform itself.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Hope this helps, let me know if there are follow up questions &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;All the best,&lt;BR /&gt;Eric Silva&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/sap-community-how-to-search-for-and-post-sap-cpq-questions/qaa-p/14257419#M84497"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:46:00.275000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/transparent-menu-icon/qaa-p/14257428#M4230530</id>
    <title>Re: Transparent Menu Icon</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:57:31.446000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>paolo_fornari3</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/206226</uri>
    </author>
    <content>how to build an icon menu with transparency on v. 10 ?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/transparent-menu-icon/qaa-p/14257428#M4230530"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:57:31.446000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
