<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-07-21T12:29:01.495821+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/character-limit/qaa-p/14157738#M45060</id>
    <title>Re: Character Limit</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T11:38:20.162000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Punita</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35074</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Yilin, The template XML does not have meta-enforce-rte-limit or meta-enforce-plain-text-length-limit configured. For the Section comment, we have set a maximum limit of 8000 characters, and since Section comment is a required field, we also need to set the Item comment limit to 8000 characters, but without making it required.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/character-limit/qaa-p/14157738#M45060"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T11:38:20.162000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-blogs/be-the-u-in-sap-4-u-sap-for-utilities-in-september/ba-p/14157671</id>
    <title>Be the U in SAP 4 U  - SAP for Utilities in September</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T11:48:24.075000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TammyPowlas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/82</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am looking forward to &lt;A target="_self"&gt;SAP for Utilities, produced by ASUG&lt;/A&gt;, in September in Denver, Colorado.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="TammyPowlas_0-1753088097141.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289138i7E00134B11463943/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="TammyPowlas_0-1753088097141.png" alt="TammyPowlas_0-1753088097141.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Source: ASUG&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Top reasons to attend:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Community meetups&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Last year we held meetups for Water utilities, Canadian utilities, electric – here’s a look back at what as discussed for Water utilities:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="TammyPowlas_1-1753088218244.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289141i15AA10077583D37A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="TammyPowlas_1-1753088218244.png" alt="TammyPowlas_1-1753088218244.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will discuss what you want to discuss.&amp;nbsp; Take this opportunity to share and learn best practices from your peers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hear from other utilities, just like yours&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how leading utilities are embracing cutting-edge technologies to transform and streamline their operations. Learn how SAP innovations are driving business simplification&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp; showcase of SAP solutions tailored for utilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Head to the exhibition hall to experience live demos, engage in expert-led discussions, and connect with exhibitors offering cutting-edge technologies, support services, software innovations and hosting options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gather Insights from Customer Stories:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hear from &lt;STRONG&gt;Consumers Energy&lt;/STRONG&gt; explore their SAP S/4HANA launch playbook—covering everything from internal buy-in and scope alignment to financial and regulatory approvals, team mobilization, and organizational change—based on their journey since May 2024.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Join &lt;STRONG&gt;Dominion Energy&lt;/STRONG&gt; to explore their SAP S/4HANA EAM journey, highlighting how innovation, metrics, and a growth mindset have fostered organizational change, employee empowerment, and increased solution adoption.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learn from &lt;STRONG&gt;Eversource&lt;/STRONG&gt; to hear their CIS transformation enhanced address validation—improving billing accuracy, reducing fraud and safety risks, and ensuring regulatory compliance and efficient service delivery.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Join the &lt;STRONG&gt;OGE (Oklahoma Gas and Electric)&lt;/STRONG&gt; session “Through the Breach – Security and Compliance in the Shared Responsibility Model” to explore how RISE with SAP delivers transformative technological and procedural advancements that strengthen organizational security and compliance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Attend PG&amp;amp;E (&lt;STRONG&gt;Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to explore their Clean Core transformation with RISE with SAP—highlighting their shift from a complex legacy ERP to a modern, agile system through fit-to-standard principles, stakeholder alignment, and enterprise design that supports decarbonization, regulatory compliance, and customer-focused innovation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Southern California Edison&lt;/STRONG&gt; presents its Next Gen ERP, showcasing how SAP S/4HANA is fueling innovation, advancing sustainability goals, and driving operational excellence—raising business unit maturity to the top quartile of the industry.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Southwest Gas &lt;/STRONG&gt;features real-world insights as utilities and partners—building on their SAP CX 1.0 successes—collaborate to shape SAP CX 2.0 with forward-looking architecture, increased extensibility, and modern development strategies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DTE Energy&lt;/STRONG&gt; shares how integrating SAP CDP with SAP Emarsys is transforming customer engagement by unifying fragmented data, automating processes, and eliminating silos to enhance operational efficiency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PG&amp;amp;E&lt;/STRONG&gt; and SAP address the growing complexity of New Load Connections and Electric Generation Interconnections, spotlighting how utilities are streamlining these critical processes amid California’s rapid energy transition and rising customer electrification. (note: first time I recall an important topic like this is discussed at a conference).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OG&amp;amp;E&lt;/STRONG&gt; (along with fellow SAP Mentor Diego Dora) showcases how generative AI-powered tools helped overcome delivery challenges in their SAP S/4HANA transformation—automating and governing critical lifecycle processes to accelerate results without compromising quality.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Eugene Water &amp;amp; Electric Board&lt;/STRONG&gt; showcases how their cloud-based SAP S/4HANA implementation is unlocking the Clean Core strategy—enhancing resiliency, automating operations, and optimizing processes across finance, customer service, and meter-to-cash.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discover how &lt;STRONG&gt;Loudoun Water&lt;/STRONG&gt;’s Jeff Smith leveraged his experience at Fairfax Water to implement reporting enhancements that increase visibility and improve EAM Master Data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UGI Utilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; shares how a decade of technology modernization revealed integration challenges that ultimately led to a strategic shift toward a unified financial platform using SAP solutions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Chesapeake Utilities Corporation&lt;/STRONG&gt; highlights its transformation of Customer and Field Services by modernizing its Customer Information platform, integrating Florida City Gas, and leveraging RISE with SAP and SAP BTP Enterprise Asset Management to enhance customer experiences and application hosting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discover how SAP C4C V2 enhancements are tailored for &lt;STRONG&gt;SoCalGas&lt;/STRONG&gt;—integrating industry-specific use cases to elevate end-user experience, operational efficiency, and customer engagement.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;London Hydro&lt;/STRONG&gt; shares its end-to-end Greenfield CIS transformation with SAP S/4HANA—focused on modernizing billing through dual contract conversion, streamlining customer communications, and advancing its vision as a digital-first utility in partnership with TCS.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Southwest Gas&lt;/STRONG&gt; showcases its digital transformation in field operations using SAP BTP, SuccessFactors, and Concur to optimize operational efficiency through automated expense reporting and streamlined training management with QR code-enabled access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not a customer session but an important session from SAP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explore SAP's future-ready service management, where the planned sunset of legacy CS features by 2030 prompts utilities to understand evolving capabilities, retained functions, and new innovations within SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register today: &lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/SAP-For-Utilities-2025/agenda" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://events.asug.com/event/SAP-For-Utilities-2025/agenda&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope to see you in Denver in September.&amp;nbsp; Do you have any must-see sessions?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-blogs/be-the-u-in-sap-4-u-sap-for-utilities-in-september/ba-p/14157671"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T11:48:24.075000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-activate-travel-management-node-in-spro/qaa-p/14157751#M4220602</id>
    <title>Re: How to activate Travel Management node in SPRO</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T11:49:35.083000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>leela_Maya</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1397345</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Travel Management path will be shown&amp;nbsp;in SPRO&amp;nbsp; only after&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;activating&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; business function&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; EA-TRV&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Enterprise Extension for Travel Management), &lt;/STRONG&gt;however, travel requests under Financial Accounting will be shown only after activating the business function&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;FIN_TRAVEL_1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-activate-travel-management-node-in-spro/qaa-p/14157751#M4220602"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T11:49:35.083000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-complete-guide-to-calling-actions-in-ui5-with-custom-code/bc-p/14157758#M174530</id>
    <title>Re: The Complete Guide to Calling Actions in UI5 with Custom Code</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T11:55:05.456000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hschaefer123</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11479</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Marian,&lt;BR /&gt;very useful.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;My problem in the past was always RAP (not CAP) where i had to use unofficial workarounds like the annotation:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1434188"&gt;@CDS&lt;/a&gt;.odata.bindingparameter.collection&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;that was replaced by the simplified binding syntax:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/releases/archive/2023/jan23#simplified-syntax-for-binding-parameters" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/releases/archive/2023/jan23#simplified-syntax-for-binding-parameters&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;RAP only allow bound actions, but you had also to distinguish between:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;bound actions or functions&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;without context&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;with context&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;unbound actions or funtions&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards Holger&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-complete-guide-to-calling-actions-in-ui5-with-custom-code/bc-p/14157758#M174530"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T11:55:05.456000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/completion-trigger-email-notification-and-home-page-card-for-custom-task/bc-p/14157759#M6957</id>
    <title>Re: Completion Trigger Email Notification and Home Page Card for Custom Task (Exit Questionnaire)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T11:55:18.765000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Giuseppe3</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1418275</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1681795"&gt;@alperendiktas&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I implemented (for Custom Task ONB 2.0) following the steps you explained but I don't get any cards on the Home Page, where could I have gone wrong?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you very much!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/completion-trigger-email-notification-and-home-page-card-for-custom-task/bc-p/14157759#M6957"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T11:55:18.765000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/resource-purchase-amp-consumption-ifp-product-costing/qaa-p/14157766#M4920485</id>
    <title>Re: Resource Purchase &amp; Consumption IFP Product Costing</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T11:57:37.161000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SANA11</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1696282</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/181359"&gt;@gunesbt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46410" target="_blank"&gt;@Susanne_Helbig&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; please assist in given logic Purchase = (Consumption + Target Closing Inventory) – Opening Inventory,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/resource-purchase-amp-consumption-ifp-product-costing/qaa-p/14157766#M4920485"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T11:57:37.161000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-rap-date-field-value-help-with-future-dates-disabled/qaq-p/14157781</id>
    <title>ABAP RAP - Date field value help with future dates disabled?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:02:12.452000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mohit_dev</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16137</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP ABAP RAP Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is it possible to disable the future dates in the value help of a date field in SAP RAP application?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, if today is 15th July 2025, the value help should show the future dates, i.e. 16th July onwards as greyed out/disabled.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Just FYI. We are currently handling this requirement based on a validation on save. Is there any other efficient way of handling this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/abap-rap-date-field-value-help-with-future-dates-disabled/qaq-p/14157781"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:02:12.452000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/ke30-revenue-not-appear-for-customer/qaq-p/14157783</id>
    <title>KE30 revenue not appear for customer</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:03:11.613000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Senara</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1609333</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please could you let me know as to why there is no revenue recorded for cooperate customer 2009577 for company code 1400 in KE30 when the billing type is ZDOM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Senara_1-1753092112045.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289220i6248F632F2F7761F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Senara_1-1753092112045.png" alt="Senara_1-1753092112045.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/ke30-revenue-not-appear-for-customer/qaq-p/14157783"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:03:11.613000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-develop-a-mobile-banking-app/bc-p/14157785#M174531</id>
    <title>Re: How to Develop A Mobile Banking App</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:04:30.139000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ShaneCorn</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2011771</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Mobile banking app development is revolutionizing how users manage their finances. By integrating secure features like biometric authentication, real-time transaction tracking, and push notifications, these apps offer convenience and enhanced security. Mobile banking apps allow users to perform transactions, check balances, pay bills, and even apply for loans right from their smartphones. For financial institutions, these apps provide opportunities for increased customer engagement and improved operational efficiency. With advancements in AI, blockchain, and data encryption, mobile banking continues to evolve, offering more personalized and secure banking experiences, ultimately fostering trust and satisfaction within the community.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-develop-a-mobile-banking-app/bc-p/14157785#M174531"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:04:30.139000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/loading-a-business-partner-customer-with-idoc-debmas06/qaa-p/14157786#M4220603</id>
    <title>Re: Loading a Business Partner (Customer) with IDOC DEBMAS06</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:04:38.481000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Hadjolian16</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139179</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/198425"&gt;@paul_gendreau&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;do I understand correctly (ref. to the below) that a BP cannot be transferred and created with an IDoc in S4Hana (e.g. scenario when transferring master data from one client to another client, BP Internal numbering and Customer/Supplier External numbering with same number) if there is CVI already in place? Is there a way how to proceed, or bullet two is the way?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;IDOCs integration in S/4 for creation of Customer/Supplier with same number as BP (Customizing configured as BP Internal numbering and Customer/Supplier External numbering with same number) will not be supported.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Creating a BP per Customer and a BP per Vendor is the simple case. Merging related Customer and Vendor into a single BP is more complex and constrained (e.g. SAP Note 2617002 - Legal Entity Check).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/loading-a-business-partner-customer-with-idoc-debmas06/qaa-p/14157786#M4220603"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:04:38.481000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/c-act-2403-sap-certified-associate-project-manager-sap-activate/qaq-p/14157788</id>
    <title>C_ACT_2403 – SAP Certified Associate Project Manager – SAP Activate</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:08:27.072000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cecil1191</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2191567</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've just started preparing for the &lt;STRONG&gt;C_ACT_2403 – SAP Certified Associate Project Manager – SAP Activate&lt;/STRONG&gt; exam. I have over 10 years of experience in SAP and project management, and I’m also PMP certified .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’d really appreciate any &lt;STRONG&gt;study tips , recommended resources , or sample study plans &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;from those who have already taken the exam.&lt;BR /&gt;How much time did you spend preparing? What did your preparation routine look like? Were there any specific topics or tools you found particularly challenging?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance for sharing your insights &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":folded_hands:"&gt;🙏&lt;/span&gt; — looking forward to learning from this great community!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Cecil&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/questions-about-sap-websites/c-act-2403-sap-certified-associate-project-manager-sap-activate/qaq-p/14157788"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:08:27.072000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/create-deep-entity-using-rap-unmanaged/bc-p/14157796#M174532</id>
    <title>Re: CREATE_DEEP_ENTITY using RAP ( Unmanaged )</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:12:25.656000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>baizonghua38</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/130071</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/178735"&gt;@Mahmoud_Wael&lt;/a&gt; :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have implemented deep_created according to your code,&lt;BR /&gt;but the items returned are still empty.&lt;BR /&gt;Can you provide the complete code?&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="baizonghua38_0-1753092736256.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289230i2DD6600F1E2B7B12/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="baizonghua38_0-1753092736256.png" alt="baizonghua38_0-1753092736256.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/create-deep-entity-using-rap-unmanaged/bc-p/14157796#M174532"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:12:25.656000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/best-practice-approach-for-automation-of-pay-components-salary/qaq-p/14157804</id>
    <title>Best practice approach for Automation of pay components(Salary)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:17:04.412000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RahulTiwari</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1440321</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyone know regarding best practice approach for Automation of pay components( salary structure) instead of rule how we can do ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/best-practice-approach-for-automation-of-pay-components-salary/qaq-p/14157804"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:17:04.412000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/invoice-date-control-while-creating-customer-invoice/qaa-p/14157814#M205637</id>
    <title>Re: Invoice Date Control While Creating Customer Invoice</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:23:02.834000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mehmetozen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1584456</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello all, issue is resolved with the latest release. SAP keeps this information on BIL_DOC-DEFAULTBILLINGDOCUMENTDATE field from now on. So the control can be done at&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SD_BIL_DATA_TRANSFER BADI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/invoice-date-control-while-creating-customer-invoice/qaa-p/14157814#M205637"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:23:02.834000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/what-features-from-pp-ds-and-what-differences-between-preactor-siemens/qaa-p/14157819#M205638</id>
    <title>Re: What features from PP-DS and what differences between...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:26:13.692000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>miguelcastrosan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5413</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP PP-DS (Production Planning and Detailed Scheduling) is a native module within SAP S/4HANA that offers integrated planning and scheduling based on material availability and finite capacity constraints. It’s well-suited for companies already operating within the SAP ecosystem, offering strong alignment with master data (BOMs, routings), MRP, and execution systems. The system provides tools like heuristics, interactive planning boards, and real-time alerts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Siemens Opcenter APS (formerly Preactor) is a standalone, highly flexible scheduling solution that supports both finite and infinite capacity planning, with the ability to define complex sequencing rules and simulate “what-if” scenarios. It integrates with any ERP, not just SAP, making it ideal for mixed environments or industries with custom workflows, such as job shops or batch production.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[ES]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP PP-DS (Planificación de la Producción y Programación Detallada) es un módulo nativo de SAP S/4HANA que permite planificar considerando restricciones de capacidad y disponibilidad de materiales. Está pensado para empresas que ya utilizan SAP, ofreciendo una integración directa con los datos maestros, el MRP y la ejecución en planta. Incluye herramientas como heurísticas, tableros gráficos y alertas en tiempo real.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Siemens Opcenter APS (anteriormente Preactor) es una solución de planificación avanzada independiente, muy configurable, que permite tanto planificación finita como infinita, reglas de secuenciación personalizadas y simulaciones tipo “what-if”. Es ideal para entornos de fabricación complejos o mixtos, y puede integrarse con cualquier ERP, no solo SAP.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Hope this helps as an introductory point of view.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/what-features-from-pp-ds-and-what-differences-between-preactor-siemens/qaa-p/14157819#M205638"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:26:13.692000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-secure-login-service-for-sap-gui-now-supports-custom-certificate/bc-p/14157824#M183027</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Secure Login Service for SAP GUI Now Supports Custom Certificate Authorities on AWS</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:28:00.646000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Martina_Kirschenmann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5013</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Shaun,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We do not plan to add certificate lifecycle management to SAP Secure Login Service. This capability is now available as part of the RISE operations services.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Martina&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-secure-login-service-for-sap-gui-now-supports-custom-certificate/bc-p/14157824#M183027"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:28:00.646000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/opentext-vim-basic-configuration-for-document-processing-dp-document-types/bc-p/14157832#M71745</id>
    <title>Re: OpenText VIM: Basic configuration for Document Processing (DP) document types</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:33:28.905000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Fjoralba</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1499588</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/162467"&gt;@PankajPareek&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Can you please help me? I need to have also in vim Analytic also not vim Documents. Is it possible? How i can implement it in order to be shown also not VIM documents ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/opentext-vim-basic-configuration-for-document-processing-dp-document-types/bc-p/14157832#M71745"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:33:28.905000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/supplementary-units-of-measure-on-ecrs-rp-edit-receipts-report/qaq-p/14157833</id>
    <title>Supplementary Units of Measure on /ECRS/RP_EDIT receipts report</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:33:46.423000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sprog</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1852880</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Please can anyone advise me on Supplementary units of measure?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We receipt a material in KG’s wet and the supplementary unit needs to be its dry weight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have been told that the dry weight should be 50% the value of the wet weight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have actioned the following however the Receipts Intrastat declaration created via MEIS and then /ECRS/RP_EDIT is not converting the value correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configuration as per KBA 2782253&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Map Customs unit of measure to internal unit of measure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;IMG Governance, Risk and Compliance -&amp;gt; International Trade -&amp;gt; Classification -&amp;gt; Define Unit of Measure System &amp;gt; UOM_EU&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Mapping for Customs Unit to internal unit of Measure KGM to KG&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sprog_0-1753093783554.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289259i0B9166A453DC6C72/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sprog_0-1753093783554.png" alt="Sprog_0-1753093783554.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign Unit of measure system to Numbering Scheme&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;IMG Governance, Risk and Compliance -&amp;gt; International Trade -&amp;gt; Classification -&amp;gt; Commodity Codes -&amp;gt; Define Numbering Scheme Content for commodity code&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sprog_1-1753093783556.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289258i73F65F20EAC93C39/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sprog_1-1753093783556.png" alt="Sprog_1-1753093783556.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Master data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Commodity code – customs unit assign KGM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Material code assigned to commodity code&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Material maser – additional data units of measure 1 KGM = 2KG&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sap Notes Implemented&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3228475&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3197861 prerequisite for 3228475&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3203417 prerequisite for 3197861&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The receipts report shows the same quantity of 200 KG’s for both the supplementary net weight and the net weight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system is not using the KG to KGM conversion, have I configured step 1 correctly?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/supplementary-units-of-measure-on-ecrs-rp-edit-receipts-report/qaq-p/14157833"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:33:46.423000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4-hana-tm-determine-additional-agreement-party-tg-in-fo/bc-p/14157836#M7526</id>
    <title>Re: SAP S/4 Hana - TM determine additional agreement party (TG) in FO</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:35:25.612000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Isu1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1724891</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, I've the requirement to fill different parties, for example: party for surveillance, and Insurrance, and I need to have this 2 partner functions to determine price conditions for each service, how can we map this 2 parties automatically to Additional Ag. Party (function Tg) ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4-hana-tm-determine-additional-agreement-party-tg-in-fo/bc-p/14157836#M7526"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:35:25.612000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/document-generation-mapping/qaa-p/14157837#M45063</id>
    <title>Re: Document Generation mapping</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:35:43.354000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GouthamVarma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/861870</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To get the next month record value in that field you can map future direct option and select that field which will always trigger the future value, but it also has disadvantages:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For Example&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Current date is July 21&lt;BR /&gt;There is a future record created for July 22 then in that case it triggers the July 22 value instead of next month so instead of this the best you can do is create a document generation mapping business rule with conditions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank You&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/document-generation-mapping/qaa-p/14157837#M45063"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:35:43.354000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/new-role-and-role-based-permission-for-expanded-goal-visibility-in-sap/ba-p/14157803</id>
    <title>New Role and Role-Based Permission for Expanded Goal Visibility in SAP SuccessFactors PMGM</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:36:55.046000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Haridha_Ponnusamy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/118171</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In evolving performance management landscape, &lt;STRONG&gt;visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;flexibility&lt;/STRONG&gt; are crucial for HR and talent professionals to drive employee success effectively. SAP SuccessFactors has introduced an exciting new enhancement in the Goal Management module: the &lt;STRONG&gt;Extended EH role&lt;/STRONG&gt;, paired with a dedicated &lt;STRONG&gt;Role-Based Permission (RBP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This upgrade broadens access to performance goals, empowering HR leaders and administrators like never before.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1993354569"&gt;What is the Extended EH Role?&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditionally, access to employee performance goals in SuccessFactors was limited to direct managers and their reporting lines in the organization. The Extended EH role changes this by allowing designated HR users and talent administrators to access performance goals based on flexible target population relationships defined in the RBP framework.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means access is no longer confined to direct reports but can include broader employee groups based on organizational requirement&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;EH&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;Employee's HR representative&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The&amp;nbsp;Extended EH&amp;nbsp;role defines designated HR representatives, not confined to direct reporting relationships but determined by any target population relationship defined in the RBP&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extended EH for Performance Goals&lt;/STRONG&gt;, in addition to existing employee-HR relationships.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1796841064"&gt;Benefits of the Extended EH Role&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Broader Access Across the Organization:&lt;/STRONG&gt; HR leaders gain visibility into employee goals beyond their immediate hierarchy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexible Role Assignments:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Permission can be assigned per goal plan template, enabling customized access tailored to organizational needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved Talent Management:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Greater access supports proactive coaching, better performance reviews, and stronger goal alignment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1600327559"&gt;How to Configure the Extended EH Role&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;To enable this feature, ensure your system meets the following prerequisites:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The latest Goal Management is enabled.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The EH role is configured in your goal plan templates for respective &lt;STRONG&gt;Action permission in each goal plan state&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;based on organizational requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Haridha_Ponnusamy_3-1753093377288.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289245iDAF441FC01D75C9F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Haridha_Ponnusamy_3-1753093377288.png" alt="Haridha_Ponnusamy_3-1753093377288.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can assign the Extended EH for Performance Goals permission through &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Permission Roles&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; under &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administrator Permissions &amp;gt; Manage Goals &amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;Extended EH for Performance Goals.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Haridha_Ponnusamy_2-1753093208531.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289243i6B80C1455133F7F5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Haridha_Ponnusamy_2-1753093208531.png" alt="Haridha_Ponnusamy_2-1753093208531.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assign it separately for each goal plan template to control access finely.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1403814054"&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;By expanding performance goal visibility beyond direct reports, organizations empower HR and talent administrators with the insights needed to foster employee development at scale. This enhancement helps HR leaders support goal tracking, alignment, and performance management more effectively across diverse teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1207300549"&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The introduction of the Extended EH role marks a strategic advancement in SAP SuccessFactors Goal Management, giving HR professionals greater flexibility and control over performance goal visibility. Organizations adopting this feature can expect improved goal oversight, enhanced employee development, and stronger alignment with business objectives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further information, refer:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3606219" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3606219 - Understanding and Managing Extended EH Permissions in Latest Goal Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-release-information/8e0d540f96474717bbf18df51e54e522/0d97fbc2c1e94b2eaa7151a8a424457b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;New Role and Role-Based Permission for Expanded Performance Goal Visibility | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/successfactors-performance-and-goals/implementing-and-managing-goal-management/roles-in-goal-plans" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Roles in Goal Plans | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore more blogs on SAP SuccessFactors authored by me:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/understanding-the-current-goal-management-landscape/ba-p/13804541" target="_blank"&gt;Understanding the Current Goal Management Landscap... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/system-email-notification-status-report/ba-p/13573334" target="_blank"&gt;System Email Notification Status Report - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/integration-between-sap-successfactors-and-microsoft-365-with-cpm-features/ba-p/13562736" target="_blank"&gt;Integration Between SAP SuccessFactors and Microso... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/configuring-custom-fields-to-the-country-specific-corporate-data-models/ba-p/13566794" target="_blank"&gt;Configuring Custom Fields to the Country Specific ... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/visibility-of-calculated-overall-section-competency-goals-ratings-in/ba-p/13564180" target="_blank"&gt;Visibility of calculated overall section (Competen... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/configuration-for-named-vs-anonymous-visibility-of-rater-s-name-on-360/ba-p/13548750" target="_blank"&gt;Configuration for Named vs Anonymous visibility of... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Stay tuned for more SuccessFactors tips, updates, and real-world use cases coming soon!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/new-role-and-role-based-permission-for-expanded-goal-visibility-in-sap/ba-p/14157803"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:36:55.046000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/custom-mdf-analysis-dimension-problem-neuroinclusion/qaa-p/14157844#M45064</id>
    <title>Re: Custom MDF Analysis Dimension problem - Neuroinclusion</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:41:45.514000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DariusSoreata</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1596737</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17486"&gt;@YSE-1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I think I made a breakthrough on this, but the SQL is not validating.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, in Tables and Column, I have selected EXTERNAL CODE from Cust_Neuroinclusion as the Primary Person ID. (In custom object definitions, external code is linked to user, so I believe this is correct). Next, in the Cust_Neuroinclusiondetails, I have selected EXTERNAL CODE and CUST_STATUS (this is the picklist, where the neuroinclusion values are stored)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I build the below lookup and then I tried to make a custom dimension.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DariusSoreata_0-1753094722739.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289272iCCCF6F372E1EE321/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DariusSoreata_0-1753094722739.png" alt="DariusSoreata_0-1753094722739.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I first tried with a table dimension, like this, which gave me a successful initial load, but then in Edit Hiearchies it came with some other fields/nodes that don't have any values. In fact, it seems that it is coming with the Challenged status, but we are not using that in our system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DariusSoreata_1-1753094943038.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289276i5B14A84449D068FE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DariusSoreata_1-1753094943038.png" alt="DariusSoreata_1-1753094943038.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DariusSoreata_3-1753095231544.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289282i903C6EAB89B2ACC5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DariusSoreata_3-1753095231544.png" alt="DariusSoreata_3-1753095231544.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DariusSoreata_4-1753095296430.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289284i9A26E048C40821AA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DariusSoreata_4-1753095296430.png" alt="DariusSoreata_4-1753095296430.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then I tried making it as a SQL, but I get this error. The 14 rows is perfect, those are the values that we have in the system, I did a canvas report on that and it returned the same, but I can't seem to make the SQL valid. Any tips on this? It says that the Syntax is incorrect for the Dimension, I've never seen this before.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DariusSoreata_2-1753095024865.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289279i8C370A50B3367B1E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DariusSoreata_2-1753095024865.png" alt="DariusSoreata_2-1753095024865.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SELECT neuro."EXTERNAL_CODE" AS "USER_SYS_ID", details."SF_FIELD1" AS "Neuroinclusion Status" FROM "[%ODS_DATABASE%]"."MDF_SPLIT_GENERIC_OBJECT_T_cust_neuroinclusion" neuro LEFT JOIN "[%ODS_DATABASE%]"."MDF_SPLIT_GENERIC_OBJECT_T_cust_neuroinclusiondetails" details ON neuro."EXTERNAL_CODE" = details."EXTERNAL_CODE"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is the SQL^^&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/custom-mdf-analysis-dimension-problem-neuroinclusion/qaa-p/14157844#M45064"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:41:45.514000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/personnel-number-must-be-hidden-from-partner-functions-bp/qaa-p/14157847#M4220604</id>
    <title>Re: Personnel number must be hidden from Partner Function...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:42:10.500000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Have a look at this&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/UI_DATA_PROTECTION_MASKING_FOR_S4HANA/a884fc9a091748c9a1f2a8c376dcd5bf/b419581035944dd4ba849370a29778ac.html?form=MG0AV3&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Help documentation&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/personnel-number-must-be-hidden-from-partner-functions-bp/qaa-p/14157847#M4220604"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:42:10.500000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-remove-the-deletion-status-x-from-ikpf-lstat/qaa-p/14157850#M4220605</id>
    <title>Re: how to remove the deletion status X from ikpf-lstat</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:43:27.596000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>antonio27</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1732735</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;There is no solution. It is an intended SAP behavior.&amp;nbsp; Go to OSS note&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1606106564"&gt;3249733 - Cancel/reverse Physical Inventory document in Inventory Management&lt;/H1&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-remove-the-deletion-status-x-from-ikpf-lstat/qaa-p/14157850#M4220605"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:43:27.596000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cpq-sap-sales-cloud-version-2-seamless-mashup-integration-for-smarter/ba-p/14157852</id>
    <title>🛒 SAP CPQ + SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 = Seamless Mashup Integration 🧩 for Smarter Selling</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:46:48.516000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP has taken a significant step forward by enabling a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;mashup integration between SAP CPQ (Configure, Price, Quote)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;, delivering a unified quoting experience directly within the Sales Cloud interface.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735189285"&gt;What Is Mashup Integration?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mashup integration refers to embedding one application’s functionality into another, creating a seamless user experience without switching tabs or logging into multiple systems. In this case, SAP CPQ is embedded directly into SAP Sales Cloud V2, allowing sales professionals to create and manage quotes without leaving the CRM environment.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-07-21_12-37-08.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289267iA2D4B39D76A0C8BE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-07-21_12-37-08.png" alt="2025-07-21_12-37-08.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1538675780"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":glowing_star:"&gt;🌟&lt;/span&gt; Key Benefits of the Integration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1471244994"&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;Unified Experience&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sales reps can now access SAP CPQ directly within the Sales Quote section of SAP Sales Cloud V2. No more toggling between tabs or applications—everything happens in one place.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1274731489"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;Seamless Authentication&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks to integration with your identity provider (IdP), users enjoy&amp;nbsp;single sign-on (SSO)&amp;nbsp;capabilities. This means secure, frictionless access to both systems with one login, enhancing security and user convenience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1078217984"&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;Real-Time Data Sync&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Quotes created in SAP CPQ are instantly reflected in SAP Sales Cloud V2 with provided SAP Standard Integrations are enabled in your tenant. This ensures that all stakeholders—from sales to finance—are working with the most up-to-date information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-881704479"&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;Improved Productivity&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;By reducing context switching and streamlining workflows, sales teams can focus more on selling and less on navigating systems. This leads to faster quote generation and improved customer responsiveness.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-685190974"&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;Customization and Flexibility&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The mashup can be tailored to meet specific business needs, including custom UI elements, workflows, and approval processes—all within the familiar Sales Cloud interface.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-359594750"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ How It Works&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded UI:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP CPQ is embedded as a mashup component in the Sales Quote view.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SSO via Identity Provider&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Authentication is handled via your existing IdP, ensuring secure and seamless access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Standard Integrations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Quotes, pricing, and configurations flow between systems in real time, powered by SAP’s robust integration framework.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cpq-sap-sales-cloud-version-2-seamless-mashup-integration-for-smarter/ba-p/14157852"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:46:48.516000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/vendor-blocked-in-s4-but-external-procurement-rel-is-still-active-in-pp-ds/qaa-p/14157859#M4220606</id>
    <title>Re: Vendor blocked in S4 but External procurement Rel. is...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:50:08.109000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="3"&gt;For information, Core Interface (CIF) transfers PIRs and Source Lists, but it will &lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;not&lt;/FONT&gt; automatically deactivate or delete external procurement relationships in PPDS when a vendor is blocked in S/4&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="3"&gt;If you want to automate this process, explore the below workarounds:-&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="3"&gt;CIF can be scheduled as a delta transfer job to regularly push the changes. However, Vendor block status is not always part of the standard delta logic. You can enhance the CIF integration model to include vendor status checks and trigger deletion of external procurement relationships.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="3"&gt;The other option can be developing a custom ABAP report that reads the blocked vendors from S/4 (LFA1-SPERR), Identifies associated external procurement relationships in PPDS and deletes them for removal. Schedule this as a background job to run daily or weekly depending upon Business critical&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/vendor-blocked-in-s4-but-external-procurement-rel-is-still-active-in-pp-ds/qaa-p/14157859#M4220606"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:50:08.109000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/create-own-signavio-reports-in-process-manager/qaa-p/14157860#M4920487</id>
    <title>Re: create own signavio reports in process manager</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:50:24.788000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>merlezapf</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1168605</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks for the information! Is there any possibility to create an excel report? Because the filter function in word or PDF documents is not really working.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/create-own-signavio-reports-in-process-manager/qaa-p/14157860#M4920487"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:50:24.788000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/last-movement-in-wh-monitor/qaa-p/14157863#M205639</id>
    <title>Re: Last movement in WH Monitor</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:51:58.656000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hannes_mack</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/290169</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we have the same topic here. In WM / SRM this functionality is existing by SAP standard but in EWM this is missing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So how can it be acchieved to add a new column in the EWM Warehouse Monitor considering the latest putaway warehouse task for the specific product and display the number of days since this date?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/last-movement-in-wh-monitor/qaa-p/14157863#M205639"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:51:58.656000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/issue-with-cost-from-child-wbs-element-not-settled-to-profitability-segment/qaa-p/14157865#M4220607</id>
    <title>Re: Issue with cost from child WBS element not settled to...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:52:38.874000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sanjeev_Jetty</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2010009</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you Marcio&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I tried without maintaining the RA key for lower-level WBS and run the result analysis for higher-level WBS. Then settled cost from lower to higher-level WBS and then to PSG.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/issue-with-cost-from-child-wbs-element-not-settled-to-profitability-segment/qaa-p/14157865#M4220607"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:52:38.874000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/xslt-transformation-error/qaa-p/14157868#M4920488</id>
    <title>Re: XSLT transformation error</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:54:33.182000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bidhanjena13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/156099</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I was having similar issue in my end tag but with the system expected end of element xmlns value issue. The &amp;lt;tt:skip/&amp;gt; worked like a charm, Thanks a lot.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/xslt-transformation-error/qaa-p/14157868#M4920488"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:54:33.182000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-complete-guide-to-calling-actions-in-ui5-with-custom-code/bc-p/14157873#M174534</id>
    <title>Re: The Complete Guide to Calling Actions in UI5 with Custom Code</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T12:58:31.605000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marian_Zeis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/61</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11479"&gt;@hschaefer123&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/890406"&gt;@ismet_toksoy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;with RAP there are some more challenges which was out of scope for this one, but it is still planned to do here&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-complete-guide-to-calling-actions-in-ui5-with-custom-code/bc-p/14157873#M174534"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T12:58:31.605000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/bupa-inbound-main-save-m09-confirmation-back-to-ci/qaa-p/14157877#M4220608</id>
    <title>Re: BUPA_INBOUND_MAIN_SAVE_M09 confirmation back to CI</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:00:38.326000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;As you know, IDOC type BUPA_INBOUND_MAIN_SAVE_M09 is designed for Inbound BP creation and not outbound confirmation. It will not automatically generate a response or acknowledgement IDoc as like ALEAUD01 does. So, it cannot be configured to send a confirmation message on its own.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Couple of options are there which you can explore:-&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Use ALEAUD01 which is the standard way to confirm IDoc processing status. You can configure ALEAUD01 to be triggered automatically via Partner Profile settings via we20.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;You can create a custom outbound IDoc that sends confirmation back to CI. Trigger it after successful BP creation using BADI_BUPA_CREATE or a workflow event tied to BP creation&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/bupa-inbound-main-save-m09-confirmation-back-to-ci/qaa-p/14157877#M4220608"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:00:38.326000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sales-org-specific-number-range-for-settlement-document-in-condition/qaa-p/14157882#M205640</id>
    <title>Re: Sales org specific number range for Settlement Docume...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:02:12.953000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kadudas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/756687</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello Victor, is it possible to give Alphanumeric number range for Company code specific settlement document numbe rranges ? I dont see that option, unlike in SD billing documents.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sales-org-specific-number-range-for-settlement-document-in-condition/qaa-p/14157882#M205640"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:02:12.953000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/enhancement-for-cor6n/qaq-p/14157883</id>
    <title>Enhancement for COR6N</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:03:00.360000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mahil</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1735104</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;kindly provide BADI or user exit for COR6N (NTER CONFIRMAION FOR PRODUCITON ORDER: GOODS MOVEMENT). my requirement is disable the quantity, plant, storage Location field( that is user cannot the the these fields).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Advance Thanks.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/enhancement-for-cor6n/qaq-p/14157883"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:03:00.360000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/bc-p/14157884#M14352</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Certification Transformation: How You Can Get and Stay Certified</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:03:28.491000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Margit_Wagner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/138893"&gt;@WaldemarFal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;I would like to encourage you to post your blog in our&amp;nbsp;Learner Stories board. There our learners can discover inspiring stories from learners around the globe, where they share their experiences how upskilling with SAP impacted their life. Get inspired by how building SAP skills can help propel careers to new heights and how you can start your own learning journey.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is the link to start a blog &lt;A title="start a blog in our&amp;nbsp;Learner Stories board" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/forums/postpage/board-id/learner-stories" target="_blank"&gt;start a blog in our&amp;nbsp;Learner Stories board&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Kind regards&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Margit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/bc-p/14157884#M14352"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:03:28.491000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-refer-to-the-quantity-of-another-bom-component-in-a-dependency/qaq-p/14157887</id>
    <title>How to refer to the quantity of another BOM component in a dependency?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:04:44.639000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>floydaus</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/715602</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Good afternoon,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am setting up the variant configurator including the BOM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I need to calculate the quantity of component 1000014930 based on the quantity of component 1000014929.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BOM 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289275i568DDFA7F762B706/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BOM 1.png" alt="BOM 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I understand that this should be done with a characteristic, that retrieves the quantity of a component. I have setup this characteristic, but I don't know how I can make it retrieve the quantity of component&amp;nbsp;1000014929 and how this should be setup in the dependency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BOM 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289289iC956A4041EEBDCDF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BOM 2.png" alt="BOM 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any help is appreciated!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-refer-to-the-quantity-of-another-bom-component-in-a-dependency/qaq-p/14157887"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:04:44.639000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/bc-p/14157888#M14353</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Certification Transformation: How You Can Get and Stay Certified</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:05:17.997000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KarthikKalaimani</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1994579</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Suzanne,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you so much for your prompt and helpful response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I truly appreciate the clarity you've provided regarding the certification eligibility and the steps outlined for opening a support ticket. I’ll refer to the “Staying Certified – FAQ” and follow the suggested approach should we face any subscription-related issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, thank you for pointing me to the SAP Partner Portal for further details on the certification criteria. I will review the information there and, if needed, reach out to the partner competency team for any specific clarifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once again, thank you for your support and guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warm regards,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Karthik Kalaimani&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/bc-p/14157888#M14353"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:05:17.997000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-complete-guide-to-calling-actions-in-ui5-with-custom-code/bc-p/14157889#M174535</id>
    <title>Re: The Complete Guide to Calling Actions in UI5 with Custom Code</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:05:19.261000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>qmacro</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great post Marian, thanks for sharing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(The following is a rather minor subject, I don't want to detract from the great details you share!)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I noticed the examples you gave for actions and functions; the topic is always interesting to me and I would like to use this opportunity to ask the readers for their additional examples. I do this because I am of the mind that "&lt;SPAN&gt;Post an order" (quoted above as an example of an action) is something I would personally prefer or expect to see as a regular OData "create" operation (via HTTP POST), and "Generate report" (quoted above as another example of an action) feels more like it should be a (side-effect-free) function, that could then be called via HTTP GET (and enjoy cacheing if appropriate) rather than the semantically heavy HTTP POST (which is required for any action).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I'd love to hear from folks - what are your fav examples?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks&lt;BR /&gt;DJ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-complete-guide-to-calling-actions-in-ui5-with-custom-code/bc-p/14157889#M174535"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:05:19.261000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/issue-with-cost-from-child-wbs-element-not-settled-to-profitability-segment/qaa-p/14157891#M4220611</id>
    <title>Re: Issue with cost from child WBS element not settled to...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:05:44.643000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sanjeev_Jetty</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2010009</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Ken,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I removed the RA key for WBS elements used only for posting cost. Then run the result analysis for higher-level WBS and tried to settle cost from lower to higher-WBS then to PSG. It worked.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you&lt;BR /&gt;Sanjeev&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/issue-with-cost-from-child-wbs-element-not-settled-to-profitability-segment/qaa-p/14157891#M4220611"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:05:44.643000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/returning-an-sfc-in-done-status-back-to-its-original-routing-in-sap-dm/bc-p/14157892#M6029</id>
    <title>Re: Returning an SFC in 'Done' Status Back to Its Original Routing in SAP DM</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:06:11.656000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManoelCosta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/175657</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2797822" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2797822 - Corrections for SAP Digital Manufacturing, Release&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for latest updates, where it reads:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;20/Jul/2025: SAP Digital Manufacturing for execution:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;SFC&amp;nbsp;Change Production&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;You can't use production change to move SFCs to or from Special, Nonconformance, or Disposition routings. If user tries to perform Change production to or from special, nonconformance, or disposition routings, user will receive error message "You cannot perform production change for the SFCs having Special, Nonconformance, or Disposition routings."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Br, Manoel&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-members/returning-an-sfc-in-done-status-back-to-its-original-routing-in-sap-dm/bc-p/14157892#M6029"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:06:11.656000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/business-partner-contact-person-adress-data-issue-err-am054/qaa-p/14157894#M4920489</id>
    <title>Re: Business Partner Contact Person Adress Data Issue (Er...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:07:58.518000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;I presume, in German language, the system may defaulted to a different screen variant that expects a Personnel number (PERNR).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Check with the below options&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Go to BUPT to check screen sequences and field groups for BP role and person type. &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Compare the config for German vs English to see if the field is marked as required in one but optional in the other&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/business-partner-contact-person-adress-data-issue-err-am054/qaa-p/14157894#M4920489"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:07:58.518000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/create-multiple-freight-orders-fo-for-a-single-freight-unit-w-o-fu-split/qaa-p/14157896#M205641</id>
    <title>Re: Create multiple freight orders (FO) for a single frei...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:09:38.501000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Wolfgang_Mayer1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132403</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Rohit, I've just tested this in our demo system. Even when passing a partial quantity (tag "PiecesTransportationQuantity") during FO creation using service "transportationordergen", the system creates the FO with the full FU quantity. Kind regards Wolfgang</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/create-multiple-freight-orders-fo-for-a-single-freight-unit-w-o-fu-split/qaa-p/14157896#M205641"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:09:38.501000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/gurugram-blog-posts/get-ready-for-sap-aidevcon-2025-in-gurugram-india/bc-p/14157897#M81</id>
    <title>Re: 🚀 Get Ready for SAP AIDevCon 2025 in Gurugram, India! 🚀</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:10:39.962000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vaibhavkansal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125148</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great work&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/123700"&gt;@ChandraBhushanSingh&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, it's a very good opportunity to learn and know more about AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assuming it's not only limited to&amp;nbsp;college students and lecturers, professionals can also be participate ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/gurugram-blog-posts/get-ready-for-sap-aidevcon-2025-in-gurugram-india/bc-p/14157897#M81"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:10:39.962000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-blog-posts/welcome-all-sap-community-members-start-here/bc-p/14157898#M37359</id>
    <title>Re: Welcome all SAP Community members, start here!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:10:44.930000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>UjjawalSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2057358</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone tell me the steps to get SERVICE KEY credentials in HCI server.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank You!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ujjawal&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-blog-posts/welcome-all-sap-community-members-start-here/bc-p/14157898#M37359"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:10:44.930000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/sap-certification-c-act-and-e-actai-study-content/qaa-p/14157900#M19669</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Certification C_ACT and E_ACTAI - Study Content</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:12:37.161000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Margit_Wagner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1431826"&gt;@Jayesh65&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please access our &lt;A title="sAP CERTIFICATION C_ACT SAP Certified Associate - Project Manager - SAP Activate" href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-project-manager-sap-activate" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CERTIFICATION C_ACT SAP Certified Associate - Project Manager - SAP Activate&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;site.&lt;BR /&gt;There you the l&lt;/SPAN&gt;earning Journey to prepare for this certification and also sample question for self evaluation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please access our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="SAP CERTIFICATION E_ACTAI SAP Certified Specialist - Project Manager - SAP Activate for Agile Implementation Management" href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-specialist-project-manager-sap-activate-for-agile-implementation-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CERTIFICATION E_ACTAI SAP Certified Specialist - Project Manager - SAP Activate for Agile Implementation Management&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;.There you the learning Journey to prepare for this certification and also sample question for self evaluation.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Kind regards&lt;BR /&gt;Margit&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/sap-certification-c-act-and-e-actai-study-content/qaa-p/14157900#M19669"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:12:37.161000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-complete-guide-to-calling-actions-in-ui5-with-custom-code/bc-p/14157901#M174536</id>
    <title>Re: The Complete Guide to Calling Actions in UI5 with Custom Code</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:16:11.901000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marian_Zeis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/61</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53"&gt;@qmacro&lt;/a&gt;You're right, the name of the function and its actual application don't always fit here, and they don't work as the name suggests. My goal was simply to implement the action in the frontend because that alone was very time-consuming.&lt;BR /&gt;Where and how the action/function can be used is also an important discussion.&lt;BR /&gt;I personally had a use case where an entity was created via an action, but it was more of a niche case.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;btw: love this feedback on my post, that what i am here for &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😄&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-complete-guide-to-calling-actions-in-ui5-with-custom-code/bc-p/14157901#M174536"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:16:11.901000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/sap-certified-associate-sap-s-4hana-for-management-accounting-associates/qaa-p/14157902#M19670</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Certified Associate – SAP S/4HANA for Management...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:16:16.051000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Margit_Wagner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/935"&gt;@REHANC&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please access our &lt;A title="C_TS4CO SAP Certified Associate - SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition for Management Accounting" href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-s-4hana-for-management-accounting-associates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;C_TS4CO&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="C_TS4CO SAP Certified Associate - SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition for Management Accounting" href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-s-4hana-for-management-accounting-associates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SA&lt;/SPAN&gt;P Certified Associate -&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition for Management Accounting&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;site.&lt;BR /&gt;There you find the recommended steps to prepare for the exam and also sample question for self-evaluation.&lt;BR /&gt;Kind&amp;nbsp; regards&lt;BR /&gt;Margit&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/sap-certified-associate-sap-s-4hana-for-management-accounting-associates/qaa-p/14157902#M19670"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:16:16.051000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/build-ai-services-using-the-sap-cloud-application-programming-model-and/ev-p/14157903</id>
    <title>🇩🇪 Build AI services using the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model and Generative AI Hub</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:17:56.650000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>noravonthenen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7343</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/codejam-cap-llm/tree/main" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CodeJam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;event is on the topic of&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build AI services using the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model, SAP AI Core and Generative AI Hub.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;It is beneficial if you have some basic knowledge about JavaScript as we're using the SAP Cloud SDK for AI with the JavaScript variant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This CodeJam introduces attendees to aspects of exposing generative artificial intelligence (genAI) capabilities to execute tasks using a given business context.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During this event, you'll become acquainted with the theory behind genAI, SAP AI Core, SAP AI Launchpad, and learn how to use the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model to expose AI capabilities through your own OData service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While working through the exercises, you'll become comfortable creating CDS-based service definitions and integrating them into the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) and SAP AI Core Foundation Models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is an&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;in-person event only&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;(not virtual) and is planned for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Friday September 26th, 2025 in Hamburg, Germany&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":germany:"&gt;🇩🇪&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;from 09:30 am - 03:30 pm. The workshop site will be the SAP office in Hamburg.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The event will be held in english.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The instructor is the Developer Advocate&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/898"&gt;@nicoschoenteich&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prerequisites: Any Chromium-based web browser, such as Google Chrome.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that seating is limited -&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;we can only accomodate 25 attendees&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Register here in the Community Event using the RSVP functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;For more information on SAP CodeJam events, to ask questions, and to chat with your fellow attendees, head over to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CodeJam group&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/build-ai-services-using-the-sap-cloud-application-programming-model-and/ev-p/14157903"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:17:56.650000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/comparison-between-sap-cpi-and-mulesoft/ba-p/14157376</id>
    <title>Comparison between SAP CPI and Mulesoft</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:19:29.990000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stephen_xue</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/214851</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1606101827"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mulesoft Anypoint Platform is a middleware platfom acquired by Salesforce. It has been widely used in many industries. On the other hand, SAP has its Integration Suite Platform based on the BTP and it's purely on premise middleware product SAP PI/PO. What are the advantages and disadvantages of SAP middleware products? How do these characteristics impact the project implementation? Which middleware should we choose for a certain project solution? I'd like to make a comparison between them from the following aspects as a developer. The content can be a reference to the architects, or presales. and If you have any other opionions or coents, happy to leave behind. These are the aspects to be compared:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Middleware Product Architecture, on cloud or on premise&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Centra ERP System&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Suitable Implementation Methodology&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;API Management Coupling&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Design and Development&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Debug tool for Development&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Logging and Alert&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unit Test Tool&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mapping technique Complexity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Connector Diversity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;DevOps Supporting Tool&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Authentication and Authorization&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1409588322"&gt;Comparison&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1342157536"&gt;Middleware Product Architecture, on cloud or on premise&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The middleware Mulesoft consists of The Mulesoft Anypoint Studio and Mulesoft Anypoint Platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_1-1753074889983.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289024iDA62E7AD88B8C4DE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_1-1753074889983.png" alt="stephen_xue_1-1753074889983.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Mulewoft Anypoint Studio is a local app installed on the local machine. It is the main development tool of Mulesoft.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_2-1753075185987.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289025iB8DB142C08D3A626/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_2-1753075185987.png" alt="stephen_xue_2-1753075185987.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Mulesoft Anypoint Platform is a cloud based product on the internet. It is the main design tool and runtime tool of Mulesoft.&amp;nbsp; The development UI is purely browser based.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Integration Suite is a service within the BTP which is purely on the cloud and web browser based. SAP CPI is the main development tool and SAP API Management is the main design tool. They are different subcomponents inside the integration suite. SAP Integration Suite is on the internet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP PI/PO is a on premise product, which is now, after version 7.31(if my memory is correct) a purely java-based software. It is a server installed locally in the client's intronet. According to current SAP office&amp;nbsp;announcements, it will stop provide support to SAP PI/PO by the end of year 2027. If you are still using the product in your landscape, it is time to look for its substitution now.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1145644031"&gt;Centra ERP System&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mulesoft is a product of Salesforce and it has&amp;nbsp;sophisticated connectors for Salesforce operations. Therefore, if your centra ERP system is salesforce, Mulesoft should be the best option of the middleware. While SAP CPI is a SAP product of course, if your centra ERP system is S4HANA or its previous versin ECC, SAP CPI should be the most convenient middleware to be chosen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since Salesforce is a cloud product on the internet, I would say that, SAP CPI still provide a good support to Salesforce as well as long as the relevant service or interface can be easily exposed by means of restful API or SOAP based API. On the other hand, it should be the same convenient for the Mulesoft to integrate with S4HANA on cloud. Whereas if it is S4HANA on premise or on RISE, things become another story. Without the SAP Cloud Connector, all of the interfaces( proxy, idoc, odata) of S4HANA on premise can only be connected once the firewall has been opened up. You probably needs to setup a DMZ(Demilitarized zone) in your network. Anyway it will largely increase the effort of cyber team or basis. This is normally used if the middleware if SAP PI/PO however. Good thing is , it will become a history soon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_3-1753076639148.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289027iA8F379BAA0B05E21/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_3-1753076639148.png" alt="stephen_xue_3-1753076639148.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud Connector is a very powerful tool for any SAP on-premise product integration. It is a big advantage to the SAP integration Suite or SAP CPI.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What if the centra ERP system is something other than a SAP product or Salesforce? Please go though the following comparison.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-949130526"&gt;Suitable Implementation Methodology&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to Mulesoft API lifecycle, we can see that the Mule implementation is highly compatible with the Agile Development Process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_1-1753077226677.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289028i0D9849A62EC50CAD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_1-1753077226677.png" alt="stephen_xue_1-1753077226677.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Both SAP Integration Suite and SAP PI/PO is more suitable for waterflow development process, according to my experience. In some of projects I participated, they used Agile mode for SAP CPI or SAP PI/PO development as well. It has a scrum master, a product owner, a tester and an integration developer in a group and has daily morning standup etc. Whereas I cannot see any benifits of this approach to be honest.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-752617021"&gt;API Management Coupling&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the modern age, a middleware product should provide a platform for API Management, including authentication, quota controlling, XML/JSON threat protection etc. This is a limitation of SAP PI/PO, which has no such function.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mulesoft Anypoint Platform has a component called API Manager, which provides policy based API management mechnism.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_2-1753078331714.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289030i87C48BE0B672B696/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_2-1753078331714.png" alt="stephen_xue_2-1753078331714.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However the process to expose an interface as an API is not very straightforward, it needs some extra configurations in the global configuration of anypoint studio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_3-1753078451288.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289031iD446736F01E0F77C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_3-1753078451288.png" alt="stephen_xue_3-1753078451288.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For SAP Integration suite, it has an component called API Management.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_4-1753078577179.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289033iE120CB9032D0F65C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_4-1753078577179.png" alt="stephen_xue_4-1753078577179.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It doesn't need any extra steps in the SAP CPI to connect the API proxy. On the other hand, the SAP API Management can retrieve OData v2 metadata from S4 backend directly via the catelog service. The SAP API management is based on APIGee and it is policy based as well. It provides OAuth v2 token generating service which is better than Mulesoft API Management from my feeling.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-556103516"&gt;Design and Development&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;In Mulesoft development, you can design the API by using YAML in the 'design center' of the Anypoint Platform.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_5-1753078912698.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289035i9A35362481ECD197/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_5-1753078912698.png" alt="stephen_xue_5-1753078912698.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The API document is generated automatically. More intesting is, once the designed content has been uploaded to 'Exchange', the Anypoint Platform can generate the process flow automatically for the Anypoint Studio. The means the development in Mulesoft is closely linked to its design content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP Integration Suite, the design tool inside the API Management provides a sort of swagger view by using OpenAPI script as below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_0-1753087280569.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289128i776E0510623535E6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_0-1753087280569.png" alt="stephen_xue_0-1753087280569.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once configured with relevant target URL and proxy URL, it can be connected with any services including any SAP CPI services exposed, or even the OData services from S4 HANA on premise. However the designed API proxy has no direct connection to the CPI iflows developed. In other words, the development of SAP CPI and design of API in the SAP API Management are two separated steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-359590011"&gt;Debug tool for Development&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Mulesoft Anypoint Studio, you can setup breakpoint inside any steps of a flow. The flow will stop at breakpoint once the endpoint has been triggered. Almost all veriables, message body, headers can be viewed in the debug mode just like debugging a program.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_1-1753087892553.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289135i2CDE592E9FE33087/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_1-1753087892553.png" alt="stephen_xue_1-1753087892553.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP CPI,&amp;nbsp; you can set an iflow into 'Trace' mode.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_5-1753088131409.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289139i8871498F0ECB9DE6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_5-1753088131409.png" alt="stephen_xue_5-1753088131409.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once done and the iflow has been triggered, the framework stored all message header/body information of each step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_6-1753088333882.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289143i1B4998315010B7D9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_6-1753088333882.png" alt="stephen_xue_6-1753088333882.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, SAP CPI provides a simulation tool by which you can test maximum 10 steps of an iflow, excluding any external calls.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, you cannot stop the process in form of breakpoint in the SAP CPI.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-163076506"&gt;Logging and Alert&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mulesoft provides standard 'Logger' Step for writing any logs to the console. The statement inside Logger is DataWeave-compatible. DataWeave is the Mulesoft embeded script language.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_0-1753090554684.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289188i22E351B2B830F0FD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_0-1753090554684.png" alt="stephen_xue_0-1753090554684.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Runtime Manager of the Mulesoft Anypoint Platform, it has the alert repository tool in which the alert can be configured.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_1-1753090816257.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289192i763BBC8162F6BACB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_1-1753090816257.png" alt="stephen_xue_1-1753090816257.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once configured, it can be linked to any application inside the Exchange.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For SAP CPI, there is no native alert step. People normally use the combination of the exception handling process and SMTP receiver adapter to imitate the alert notification. Meanwhile, the SAP BTP provides an alert notification service, which is not straightforward and a bit hard to use in the SAP CPI so far as I know.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_2-1753091107970.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289195i80AA7B4C77BDB9B1/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="stephen_xue_2-1753091107970.png" alt="stephen_xue_2-1753091107970.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BTP alert notification service is not quite convenient to be used for SAP CPI iFlows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My feeling is the the alert of SAP PI/PO is even better than SAP CPI with regard to the configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--33436999"&gt;Unit Test Tool&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Mulesoft Anypoint Studio provides MUnit and Munit Tools on the flow level. The component can be used to setup different unit test cases which is suitable for the Agile Development Standard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_3-1753091523937.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289200iB274E1D1BF77C98C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_3-1753091523937.png" alt="stephen_xue_3-1753091523937.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP CPI has no native unit test tool. The embeded simulation tool can be used to test steps inside and external API test tools like POSTMAN can be used to conduct system integration test. Whereas this is different from the concept of Unit Test and there is no step to check if the outcome is correct or not.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP CPI does provide a connectivity test tool which is very handy. It provides a tool to check connection over HTTPS, SMTP, SFTP etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_4-1753091937495.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289211i86193D8ED61DBE86/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_4-1753091937495.png" alt="stephen_xue_4-1753091937495.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-117303853"&gt;Mapping Technique Complexity&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Mulesoft Anypoint Studio has two main mapping methods:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--372612659"&gt;Graphic Mapping&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_5-1753092160629.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289221i4CC1C3B467545CC0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_5-1753092160629.png" alt="stephen_xue_5-1753092160629.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--569126164"&gt;DataWeave&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_6-1753092245659.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289222iE9D10CEE6E327BE1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_6-1753092245659.png" alt="stephen_xue_6-1753092245659.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It has a specific 'Transform Message' step which is for mapping and almost all of the native steps do contain a mapping step inside as well. All of these embedded mapping steps are compatible with DataWeave script. Since DataWeave is the Mulesoft build-in script, it has a relative good performance and provides a powerful functionalily for any different message format including XML, JSON, CSV etc. and the script is similar to the natual language which is not hard to master.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For SAP CPI, it normally supports three different types of Mapping:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--765639669"&gt;Graphical Mapping&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_7-1753092505226.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289223iE7C9E92DAB3E6E54/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_7-1753092505226.png" alt="stephen_xue_7-1753092505226.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--962153174"&gt;XSLT Mapping&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_8-1753092588618.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289224iD912DF17800EDE9C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_8-1753092588618.png" alt="stephen_xue_8-1753092588618.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1158666679"&gt;Groovy Script Mapping&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_9-1753092648826.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289226iF9BE9DEA557E53AA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_9-1753092648826.png" alt="stephen_xue_9-1753092648826.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP CPI iflow supports javascript as well. whereas i just do not know that very few cases are using the Javascript as the mapping script.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For SAP PI/PO, it supports graphical mapping, xslt mapping and java mapping.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The graphical mapping is normally to beginner which is easy to understand and suitable for relative simple mapping logic. However it is a bit hard to deal with context change. One of the limitation is that it only supports XML message.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The XSLT mapping is the industry standard for XML transformation. For sophisticated developer, it can be used to transform messages into JSON or CSV. However since it is a sort of recursion and&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;declarative language, bad programming skill may impact the overall performance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The groovy script is the recommended mapping method in SAP CPI. However since it is a open standard programming language, which is lack of any system native performance tuning, any bad programming habit may impact the process performance as well.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1061777177"&gt;Connector Diversity&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Mulesoft Anypoint Studio, there are hundreds of connectors available, including ones for popular SaaS applications like SAP and Salesforce, cloud services in AWS and Azure, and databases using open protocols like ODBC and JDBC. Furthermore, MuleSoft Exchange offers over 250 out-of-the-box connectors.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_10-1753093755619.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289255i88450F80ADE3EF2A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_10-1753093755619.png" alt="stephen_xue_10-1753093755619.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please be aware that , Mulesoft connector for third party systems, like SAP, still needs dll or jar library. like for SAP, it needs jco library. unless the SAP service can be exposed in form of API or SOAP web service.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For SAP CPI, it is said that there are over 60 pre-built adapters for systems based on different protocols, including SFTP, AMQP, HTTPS, SMTP etc. The integration suite provides a service called Open Connector, which is more flexible for connectivity. However, this service is not free of charge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_11-1753094121626.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289262i5DB53A646EE27972/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_11-1753094121626.png" alt="stephen_xue_11-1753094121626.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1258290682"&gt;DevOps Supporting Tool&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Mulesoft Anypoint Platform supports Maven for library updates. It supports GITHUB for content backup and versioning. It can be integrated with Jenkins for CICD.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_1-1753094508343.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289268iE309E80AF9C72470/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_1-1753094508343.png" alt="stephen_xue_1-1753094508343.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For SAP CPI, it has its native versioning control mechnism for iflow and API proxies. Almost all contents are transportable by using a separated BTP service called Cloud Transportation Management. Since it is purely a cloud based development enviroment, the server maintanance is done by SAP and&amp;nbsp; is nothing to do with the integration developer. It is said that the CICD can be managed by Jenkins in some tutorials, whereas I have never seen it in any real cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1454804187"&gt;Authentication and Authorization&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Mulesoft Anypoint Platform, you can define your own business group and its sub group for different landscapes like dev, test, UAT, Production. You provide access to different group by using the roles, which is clear and does make sense.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_2-1753095089615.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289280i9443CDF2C2799CE0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_2-1753095089615.png" alt="stephen_xue_2-1753095089615.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For SAP Integration Suite, the user access consists of nature user access and system user access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For nature user access, it is controlled by means of role collections. The role connection is a combination of roles in the level of BTP sub account. The BTP sub account is the collection of services or applications, like SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_3-1753095329727.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289285iD778AE9FB91A17CD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_3-1753095329727.png" alt="stephen_xue_3-1753095329727.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It means, the nature user access control of SAP Integration Suite is NOT inside the service SAP Integration Suite, but the entity one level above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For system user access, it is controlled by means of Service Key configuration, which is in the BTP subaccount as well. Different from the nature user access, it is not using the role collection mechanism.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="stephen_xue_4-1753095809385.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289295i3EC9A21E48D6C576/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="stephen_xue_4-1753095809385.png" alt="stephen_xue_4-1753095809385.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Integration Suite access control is a bit complex and tedious. Good thing is, normally this piece of work is not the task of the integration team, but the security team or basis team.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For SAP PI/PO, both the system user and nature user are maintained by using the same tool, called SAP Netweaver Admin. At least for me, it is easier to understand compared with SAP CPI.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1357914685"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP PI/PO is out of date product. Though its last version call SAP Process Orchestration, it is not convenient for the integration orchestration, since it is on premise within the corprorate network, which is a bit hard to connect with any services on the internet. and SAP will stop support it in year 2027. So it is time to plan to get rid of it now if you are still using.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP CPI is suitable for most of integration requirement and it is purely cloud based. If any SAP system is your centra ERP system, please do not hasitate to choose it, though it is still suitable for any non-system integration, orchestration or work as Enterprise Servie Bus.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mulesoft is generically suitable for any system integration, especially the project is using the Agile Standard Development Process. It can also be used as the middleware if the centra ERP is a SAP product. However without the BTP Cloud Connector, you might need extra work on firewall configuration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have&amp;nbsp;experience in either platforms, you are most welcome to leave the comment below for the benifit of readers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/comparison-between-sap-cpi-and-mulesoft/ba-p/14157376"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:19:29.990000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/data-services-manager-change-db-server-name-cannot-add-in-repository-bodi/qaq-p/14157907</id>
    <title>Data Services Manager, change DB server name, cannot add in repository, BODI-310079 Already exists</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:21:46.416000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LDay75</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2202787</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Our SQL servers are being refreshed and the DBAs have created new aliases to connect to the existing servers to make it easier when they switch over to the new ones.&amp;nbsp; In SAP Data Services Server Manager under the Job Server Properties the server name field is grayed out for editing so I removed the base LREPO_DEV repository and tried to re-add it in using the server alias in the DB Server Name and I am now getting an error stating that the repo already exists, BODI-310079.&amp;nbsp; The repo no longer shows in the list of existing repositories and I have also removed the section in the DSConfig file located in the&amp;nbsp;D:\SAP BusinessObjects\Data Services\conf\migrated directory.&amp;nbsp; The DSConfig file in the&amp;nbsp;D:\SAP BusinessObjects\Data Services\conf directory does not contain any repo specific entries.&amp;nbsp; I was also able to update the server name in the CMC without issue, I just have not deleted the repo from there due to the possible loss of existing DEV work that our dev team has been working on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any help on this would be greatly appreciated, I have tried everything I could that I found on this KB and other searches for this error and nothing has helped so far.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="LDay75_0-1753096842937.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289302iF88F6ACDDBCF18DD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="LDay75_0-1753096842937.png" alt="LDay75_0-1753096842937.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/data-services-manager-change-db-server-name-cannot-add-in-repository-bodi/qaq-p/14157907"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:21:46.416000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core/ev-p/14157908</id>
    <title>🇩🇪 Getting started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:22:18.163000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>noravonthenen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7343</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CodeJam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;event is on the topic of&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Getting started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and Python&lt;/SPAN&gt;. You do not need to have any background in the topic, but a lot of curiosity!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this CodeJam you will learn how to use Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core to implement a retrieval augmented generation (RAG) use case to improve the responses of large language models (LLMs) and reduce hallucinations. You will learn how to deploy an LLM and the orchestration service on SAP AI Core and query it via SAP AI Launchpad and the Python SDK. Furthermore, you will learn about the most important genAI concepts and create and use embeddings to improve your RAG response and build your own chatbot with memory.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is an&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;in-person event&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;only&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(not virtual) and is planned for&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Friday September 26th, 2025 at the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;office in Hamburg&lt;/SPAN&gt;, Germany&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":germany:"&gt;🇩🇪&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;from 09:30 - 15:30 local time. The language of the event and the content will be English.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The instructor will be Developer Advocate&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7343" target="_blank"&gt;@noravonthenen&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prerequisites:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Any Chromium-based web browser, such as Google Chrome, Microsoft Edge, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that spaces are limited - we can only accommodate&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;18&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;attendees&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Register here in the Community Event using the RSVP functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;For more information on SAP CodeJam events, to ask questions, and to chat with your fellow attendees, head over to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CodeJam group&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core/ev-p/14157908"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:22:18.163000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-events/sap-inside-track-fortaleza-2025/ec-p/14157909#M29</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Inside Track Fortaleza 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:23:26.577000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vaibhavkansal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125148</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140615"&gt;@MRobalinho&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;waiting to get this publish, I have register for the online lecture similar to last year&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face:"&gt;😀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-events/sap-inside-track-fortaleza-2025/ec-p/14157909#M29"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:23:26.577000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/hello-please-help-when-using-the-mf-in-a-bom-the-values-are-erased-when/qaa-p/14157912#M4220612</id>
    <title>Re: Hello, please help.When using the MF in a BOM, the va...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:26:14.722000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;When you switch components in a configurable BOM, SAP re-evaluates the object dependencies and reinitializes the screen context. If the characteristics or values are not persistently stored or linked to the new component, system clears them. This is common when using MFs that span multiple components, SAP does not automatically carry over the configuration&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Some workarounds are&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Define object dependencies (example preconditions or procedures) that retain characteristic values across component switches. This ensures that when a component is changed, the sytem re-applies the correct values.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Ensure all components share the same class assignment so that characteristics are consistently available. If a component lacks the class, SAP may not know how to apply the values&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/hello-please-help-when-using-the-mf-in-a-bom-the-values-are-erased-when/qaa-p/14157912#M4220612"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:26:14.722000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/conditional-suppression-of-group-footer/qaq-p/14157913</id>
    <title>Conditional Suppression of Group Footer</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:26:22.942000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>carmine1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/729647</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Group 1 is Customer ID&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Group 2 is one of two possible product categories; let's call them A and B.&amp;nbsp; So,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Customer Header
    Group A Header
      Detail
      Detail
    Group A Footer
    Group B Header
      Detail
      Detail
    Group B Footer
  Customer Footer

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some customers will have both product categories, some may have product group A detail but not B, while some may have Product B detail but not A.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;In the case where there are no detail records for either product group A or group B, I want to suppress the printing of the product group footer and print only the customer group footer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this possible?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/conditional-suppression-of-group-footer/qaq-p/14157913"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:26:22.942000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/gl-balance-discrepancy/qaa-p/14157915#M4220613</id>
    <title>Re: GL Balance Discrepancy</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:30:31.343000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jitin_chawla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/187914</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cancellation of the Payment will happen on a different date if the user selects the date as "Current System Date" in the system message which appears when cancelling a payment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the system message, there are 2 options which appear:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Original Document Date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Current System Date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the user selects the Original Document Date, then the Payment and its cancellation will be posted on the same date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For fixing your issue, you need to check if you create a manual JE and it helps or not. The issue with manual JE is that the Payment and its cancellation will be linked to each other so there is just the adjustment which you are going to be making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kr,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Jitin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/gl-balance-discrepancy/qaa-p/14157915#M4220613"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:30:31.343000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/workflow/qaa-p/14157917#M45065</id>
    <title>Re: Workflow</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:31:02.641000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ka12</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1650244</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, I don't quite understand. To enable the option to remove the flow in the participant step, what should I configure?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/workflow/qaa-p/14157917#M45065"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:31:02.641000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/business-roles-required-to-release-unlock-condition-contract-for-sales/qaa-p/14157918#M4220614</id>
    <title>Re: Business roles required to release/unlock Condition C...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:31:22.954000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/850056"&gt;@yasuyo_goto&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sorry for the delay in replying to your message, and thank you for your remark on the scope item no.5F2 (Perhaps it's hidden due to role restrictions)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The process you confirmed under 1B6 (Sales Rebate Processing) is correct.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, you are correct that SAP_BR_INTERNAL_SALES_REP can create and release condition contracts, while SAP_BR_SALES_MANAGER handles approvals. However, sometimes both roles are not necessary if the user has full access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/business-roles-required-to-release-unlock-condition-contract-for-sales/qaa-p/14157918#M4220614"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:31:22.954000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-define-possible-bom-usage-composition-for-material-master/qaa-p/14157920#M4220615</id>
    <title>Re: How to define possible BOM usage/composition for mate...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:32:54.492000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Usage type U is flexible and often used as Configurable BOMs, but it does not automatically replicate to usage type M. When a new material is created from a configuration, the system does not copy the BOM to usage M, unless explicitly instructed. As a result CS03 with usage M shows no components, even though they exist under usage U&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;What you can do is go to cs01 to create a BOM for the newly generated material. Set BOM usage = M. Copy components from the U-BOM or use reference BOM if applicable&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" color="#000000"&gt;Create a reference BOM that links multiple material variants to a single BOM structure. This allows consistent component usage across variants and supports multiple usage types&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-define-possible-bom-usage-composition-for-material-master/qaa-p/14157920#M4220615"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:32:54.492000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-use-al11-in-sap-fiori-ui5-app/qaq-p/14157921</id>
    <title>How do use AL11 in SAP Fiori/UI5 App?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:33:17.856000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>walkerist79</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/798835</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have created a custom UI5 application which have an input field for an input file. It should have a functionality to upload from local file or upload to AL11.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="walkerist79_0-1753097459843.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289306iC86F77A1FB4AFB4C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="walkerist79_0-1753097459843.png" alt="walkerist79_0-1753097459843.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assuming that I will be using an OData for service for this, is it possible to upload the file in AL11 via front end?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-do-use-al11-in-sap-fiori-ui5-app/qaq-p/14157921"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:33:17.856000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/when-we-moved-to-s-4-hana-from-r-3-many-issues-on-alv-especially-context/qaq-p/14157922</id>
    <title>when we moved to S/4 HANA from R/3 many issues on ALV especially context menu how to overcome?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:33:42.247000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ramesh_J22</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2163329</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prior to S/4 HANA Transformation, we are using CL_SALV_TABLE for ALV. After S/4 HANA Transformation, we could not be able to get required context menu especially like below,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ramesh_J22_0-1753097396127.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289305i6C1AF3D3CAFEEFE0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ramesh_J22_0-1753097396127.png" alt="ramesh_J22_0-1753097396127.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Whereas we are getting like below,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ramesh_J22_0-1753097754420.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289307iCAD1866A46B6F33D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ramesh_J22_0-1753097754420.png" alt="ramesh_J22_0-1753097754420.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Missing few of the options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thank you very much.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Kind Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Ramesh.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/when-we-moved-to-s-4-hana-from-r-3-many-issues-on-alv-especially-context/qaq-p/14157922"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:33:42.247000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/completion-trigger-email-notification-and-home-page-card-for-custom-task/bc-p/14157923#M6958</id>
    <title>Re: Completion Trigger Email Notification and Home Page Card for Custom Task (Exit Questionnaire)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:34:38.362000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alperendiktas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1681795</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1418275"&gt;@Giuseppe3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;It is working for OFB, unfortunately workflows are not working for ONB.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/completion-trigger-email-notification-and-home-page-card-for-custom-task/bc-p/14157923#M6958"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:34:38.362000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-blog-posts/welcome-all-sap-community-members-start-here/bc-p/14157924#M37360</id>
    <title>Re: Welcome all SAP Community members, start here!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:34:43.053000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KatherineKenneally</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/328</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2057358"&gt;@UjjawalSAP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- can you please ask your question in the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/qa-p/technology-questions" target="_blank"&gt;Q&amp;amp;A section&lt;/A&gt;?&lt;BR /&gt;You can also subscribe to &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/all-sap-managed-tags/ct-p/managed-tags" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Managed tags&lt;/A&gt; of topics of interest to you - and find out more information this way.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-blog-posts/welcome-all-sap-community-members-start-here/bc-p/14157924#M37360"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:34:43.053000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/se80-embedded-view/qaq-p/14157928</id>
    <title>SE80 - embedded view</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:37:04.709000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In SE80, within a Web Dynpro component under the &lt;EM&gt;Windows section, when attempting to embed another view, the selection popup opens but does not allow any interaction.&lt;BR /&gt;There is no matchcode help (F4), and manual input is disabled — making it impossible to select another component view&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;We discovered the issue after HRSP semestrial update, but not sure when it started.&lt;BR /&gt;SAP_BASIS 750 DIGITS SAPK-75029INSAPBASIS SAP Basis Component&lt;BR /&gt;SAP_ABA 750 DIGITS SAPK-75029INSAPABA Cross-Application Component&lt;BR /&gt;SAP_UI 754 DIGITS SAPK-75415INSAPUI User Interface Technology&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To&lt;BR /&gt;SAP_BASIS 750 DIGITS SAPK-75031INSAPBASIS SAP Basis Component&lt;BR /&gt;SAP_ABA 750 DIGITS SAPK-75031INSAPABA Cross-Application Component...(truncated) &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/se80-embedded-view/qaq-p/14157928"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:37:04.709000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/se80-embedded-view/qaa-p/14157929#M4920494</id>
    <title>Re: SE80 - embedded view</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:37:11.613000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Anyone is aware, how to activate this feature?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/se80-embedded-view/qaa-p/14157929#M4920494"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:37:11.613000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/controlling-and-scheduling-the-production-using-the-work-center-formula/ba-p/14157931</id>
    <title>Controlling and Scheduling the Production Using the Work Center Formula Parameter</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:37:46.351000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>I351081</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/27760</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735190183"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Requirement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Company X wants to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;determine&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;the duration or cost of operation required to produce a given product depending on factors like work center or tool. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Company X uses a multiplier called the efficiency factor to the standard execution time, which varies depending on the age of the tools used or weather conditions, etc. They want to execute the process in their SAP Cloud ERP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1538676678"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Solution at H&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;igh Level&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This solution focuses on calculating the execution time of an operation based on the efficiency factor&lt;BR /&gt;defined during the creation/updation of production routing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The multiplier that Company X uses is created as a custom field (called &lt;STRONG&gt;YY1_EFF_FACTOR&lt;/STRONG&gt;) in Production Routing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Steps to follow:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Access the &lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Fields&lt;/STRONG&gt; app from the SAP Fiori launchpad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2. Choose&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add Fields&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;to create a custom field. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;3. In the &lt;STRONG&gt;New Field&lt;/STRONG&gt; popup, set the Business Context to &lt;STRONG&gt;Manufacturing: Bill of Operations&amp;nbsp; Operation (PP_BILLOFOPERATIONS_OPERATION)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;4. Set the field type to &lt;STRONG&gt;Quantity with Unit,&lt;/STRONG&gt; as no other Business context or field t&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ypes are supported for Work Centre Formula Parameters. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;5. Once the required&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;data is entered, c&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;hoose&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Create and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Edit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="1_CustomFields.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289119i5EA926631A9F2BC3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1_CustomFields.png" alt="1_CustomFields.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;6.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;On the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;General Information&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; tab, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;take &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;note&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; of&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Field Component Name&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; ending with the suffix &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;‘&lt;STRONG&gt;_PPO&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. This suffix is&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;used to map the custom field to a parameter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="2suffix_ppo.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289121i797E19563BA7FF1A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2suffix_ppo.png" alt="2suffix_ppo.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;7.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;On the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Interfaces&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;tab, enable the custom field’s usage for the relevant SAP GUI screens, CDS Views, and Services.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="3UserInterface.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289125i9A99366E3CE133F2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3UserInterface.png" alt="3UserInterface.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;8.&amp;nbsp;Enable the custom field’s usage for the relevant business scenario. Enable &lt;STRONG&gt;Routing to Production Order on Operation Level&lt;/STRONG&gt; for Discrete Manufacturing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="4EnableBS.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289127i35500522E4B1D0A4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4EnableBS.png" alt="4EnableBS.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;9. Navigate back to &lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Field&lt;/STRONG&gt; work list page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;10. Search for EFF_FACTOR. Select EFF_FACTOR for business context &lt;STRONG&gt;Manufacturing: Order Operation (PP_ORDER_OPERATION)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;11. On the &lt;STRONG&gt;User Interfaces&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab, enable the custom field’s usage for the relevant SAP GUI screens, CDS Views, and Services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_0-1753090127703.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289180iC1738E9F3776CF72/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_0-1753090127703.png" alt="I351081_0-1753090127703.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;12.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;workcenter&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;formula &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;parameter &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ZPP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Define Parameters&lt;/STRONG&gt; activity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (&lt;STRONG&gt;ID: 102242&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In your configuration environment, use the search function to open the configuration activities. For more information, see also &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/e5ec5859d8e54df98492d80564a734c0/0b3f87579f345c08e10000000a441470.html?state=DRAFT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configuration Environment of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_1-1753090229601.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289182iEAF09941ED43809C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_1-1753090229601.png" alt="I351081_1-1753090229601.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;13.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;parameter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;with&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;origin 8 (Custom Field from Operation)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Fill in all the necessary data, leaving the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;‘Field Name’&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;field blank.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_2-1753090330449.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289185i5DF30C4416FF1BA4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_2-1753090330449.png" alt="I351081_2-1753090330449.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;14.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Once the parameter is created, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;create&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; a WKC formula where the SAP standard parameter &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP_01&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; is multiplied by &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ZPP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to calculate costs in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Define Formulas for Work Centers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; activity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; (&lt;STRONG&gt;ID: 102002&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. In your configuration environment, use the search function to open the configuration activities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_3-1753094219096.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289263i532DE0D0D231288D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_3-1753094219096.png" alt="I351081_3-1753094219096.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;15.&amp;nbsp;Once the parameter is created and formula defined, map the newly created custom field to Workcenter formula parameter. Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;Mapping Custom Tasklist Operation Fields to Work Center Formula Parameters&lt;/STRONG&gt; configuration activity (&lt;STRONG&gt;ID: 106627&lt;/STRONG&gt;) to map the fields. In your configuration environment, use the search function to open the configuration activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_4-1753094338954.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289264i1A11FCBA68BCBD90/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_4-1753094338954.png" alt="I351081_4-1753094338954.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;16. Therefore, the creation of the work center formula parameter, definition of the formula, and mapping of the work center parameter to the routing operation custom field are complete.&lt;BR /&gt;The next step will be to either create a new work center according to the business scenario or update the existing work center with the newly created work center formula.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_5-1753094514053.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289269iAAEADB8C79E5AAF3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_5-1753094514053.png" alt="I351081_5-1753094514053.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;17.&amp;nbsp;In the work center, use the newly created work center formula parameter under capacities, scheduling, and costing as per the business need.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Capacity:&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_6-1753094565844.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289270iE816435DED243816/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_6-1753094565844.png" alt="I351081_6-1753094565844.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Scheduling:&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_7-1753094875741.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289273i3F944353C56A259A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_7-1753094875741.png" alt="I351081_7-1753094875741.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Costing:&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_8-1753094907658.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289274iD628125C168843AC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_8-1753094907658.png" alt="I351081_8-1753094907658.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;18.&amp;nbsp;For production routing, you can add new operations or update the same operation with a new work center having the newly created work center formula.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_9-1753094989874.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289277i91664B80CE71C441/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_9-1753094989874.png" alt="I351081_9-1753094989874.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Change shown for routing operation 0060:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="I351081_10-1753095132551.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289281i16205F5E4B6C681A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_10-1753095132551.png" alt="I351081_10-1753095132551.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;19.&amp;nbsp;In the custom fields, &lt;STRONG&gt;EFF_FACTOR&lt;/STRONG&gt; is visible, and we can enter some efficiency factor into it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_11-1753095236516.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289283i20C7015F01E43711/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_11-1753095236516.png" alt="I351081_11-1753095236516.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;20.&amp;nbsp;Create Production Order for same material.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="text-align: center; padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_12-1753095343944.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289286i4B2078A15716049A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_12-1753095343944.png" alt="I351081_12-1753095343944.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;21.&amp;nbsp;Navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;Operation Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_13-1753095460457.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289287iCA4813B7CC10075E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_13-1753095460457.png" alt="I351081_13-1753095460457.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;22.&amp;nbsp;Note the set-up duration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="text-align: center; padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_14-1753095637798.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289291iB82F529DBE64B805/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_14-1753095637798.png" alt="I351081_14-1753095637798.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;23.&amp;nbsp;Come back to Routing and change &lt;STRONG&gt;EFF_FACTOR&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;STRONG&gt;20&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_15-1753095707414.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289294i8F5E682491382620/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_15-1753095707414.png" alt="I351081_15-1753095707414.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;24.&amp;nbsp;Schedule the created PO for the same operation. You will&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;notice a change in setup duration due to a change in&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;EFF_FACTOR&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;routing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_16-1753095859890.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289296i0328DA7FDCCBDC6D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_16-1753095859890.png" alt="I351081_16-1753095859890.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;25.&amp;nbsp;Similarly, in Production Order, change the &lt;STRONG&gt;EFF_FACTOR&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;STRONG&gt;30&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_17-1753095943184.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289297i131C40618EA25A40/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_17-1753095943184.png" alt="I351081_17-1753095943184.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;26.&amp;nbsp;Before rescheduling, note the set-up duration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="text-align : left; padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="I351081_18-1753096003802.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289298i50C6E1A0DC19C7B5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_18-1753096003802.png" alt="I351081_18-1753096003802.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After reschedule, the duration changes based on the change in &lt;STRONG&gt;EFF_FACTOR&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="I351081_19-1753097056969.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289303i268E87171C5C4CE9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="I351081_19-1753097056969.png" alt="I351081_19-1753097056969.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By following these steps, Company X can effectively streamline its production processes, ensuring efficiency and cost-effectiveness. Embracing SAP Cloud ERP not only enhances operational accuracy but also empowers the company to adapt swiftly to changing conditions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/controlling-and-scheduling-the-production-using-the-work-center-formula/ba-p/14157931"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:37:46.351000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/exploring-the-benefits-of-multiple-specifications-in-inspection-lot/bc-p/14157932#M71746</id>
    <title>Re: Exploring the Benefits of Multiple Specifications in Inspection Lot Creation</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:38:44.551000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AhmedHesham1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2141734</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Nice blog Mahmoud its very helpful, keep going.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/exploring-the-benefits-of-multiple-specifications-in-inspection-lot/bc-p/14157932#M71746"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:38:44.551000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/character-limit/qaa-p/14157933#M45066</id>
    <title>Re: Character Limit</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:38:54.769000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yilin_Z</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/141760</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Punita, in your scenario, there's no limit on the item comment currently. You need to use require field to set the 8000 character limit on the item comment.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/character-limit/qaa-p/14157933#M45066"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:38:54.769000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/bc-p/14157935#M14354</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Certification Transformation: How You Can Get and Stay Certified</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:40:08.806000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Madhukar_Sanmane</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1811262</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have recently completed&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;C_STC&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP Certified Associate - Solution Transformation Consultant with SAP Cloud ALM. It was a good experience learning from the scratch and clearing certification. Demo tenant was a great help. Creating your own project, scope, task, test case, defect etc in the demo tenant really helped in understanding the concepts. Having some understanding of Activate methodology, Signavio process navigator also helped.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Certification exam experience was really smooth and trouble free. Able to select timeslot of my choice and complete the exam without any issues. Getting ready for the next certification exam!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/bc-p/14157935#M14354"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:40:08.806000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/variant-matching-doesn-t-scrap-material-flagged-for-deletion/qaa-p/14157936#M83160</id>
    <title>Re: Variant Matching doesn't scrap material flagged for d...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:40:20.344000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;Variant matching checks for characteristic value matches but does not evaluate material status or deletion flags by default. Fields like MSTAE (Cross-Plant Material Status) and LVORM (Deletion Flag) are not part of the standard filtering logic in CU50 or VA01. This means obsolete or flagged materials can still be matched and proposed—even if they’re blocked for sales or marked for deletion.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;What you can do is set MSTAE to a status that blocks sales (e.g., status that prevents order entry). This won’t stop variant matching but will prevent selection in VA01, helping in case 2.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;In the configuration profile, you can define variant matching strategy to complete configuration only and combine with a custom filter via enhancement to exclude obsolete variants&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;For any reasons, if enhancement is not feasible, create a custom characteristic like ZOBSOLETE_FLAG, assign value X to obsolete variants, use a precondition or procedure to prevent selection or explode an error when matched. This avoids tampering with valid characteristics and keeps your logic clean.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-q-a/variant-matching-doesn-t-scrap-material-flagged-for-deletion/qaa-p/14157936#M83160"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:40:20.344000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/create-deep-entity-using-rap-unmanaged/bc-p/14157959#M174538</id>
    <title>Re: CREATE_DEEP_ENTITY using RAP ( Unmanaged )</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:43:55.819000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tisha_Haria</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/736602</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/130071"&gt;@baizonghua38&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;: Please implement the read method of the particular entity&amp;nbsp; for which data is being posted&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/create-deep-entity-using-rap-unmanaged/bc-p/14157959#M174538"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:43:55.819000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/multiple-component/qaq-p/14157962</id>
    <title>multiple component</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:45:28.899000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nazim94</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1715658</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I try to make a delivery issue challan, the system shows multiple materials. system cannot accept multiple components&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nazim94_1-1753098269304.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289330i5FAAF3CB4FCD5087/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Nazim94_1-1753098269304.png" alt="Nazim94_1-1753098269304.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/multiple-component/qaq-p/14157962"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:45:28.899000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-validation-rules/qaa-p/14157963#M4920495</id>
    <title>Re: SAC validation rules</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:45:36.761000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TahaKocyigit</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1390300</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Nikhil,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If I need to use more than one costcenter for an account, how can I match this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sac-validation-rules/qaa-p/14157963#M4920495"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:45:36.761000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/api-for-bank-integration/qaa-p/14157964#M4220618</id>
    <title>Re: API for Bank Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:46:21.130000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PoojaTest91</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2082803</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I cannot open the link. Is this API deprecated?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/api-for-bank-integration/qaa-p/14157964#M4220618"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:46:21.130000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-integrate-sap-datasphere-to-sap-cpq-and-extract-data-from-datasphere/qaa-p/14157967#M4920496</id>
    <title>Re: how to integrate SAP Datasphere to SAP CPQ and extrac...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:49:06.234000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stevica</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121029</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP CPQ provides API calls for custom tables, which you can potentially leverage to populate a CPQ custom table from&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Datasphere.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CPQ/08a7929ad06d4680b4f18cb57bc1a1d3/4d3db31e3c71467a8701a0e68f7a84db.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CPQ/08a7929ad06d4680b4f18cb57bc1a1d3/4d3db31e3c71467a8701a0e68f7a84db.html?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://default-us1-prd-01.cpq.cloud.sap/api/custom-table/index.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://default-us1-prd-01.cpq.cloud.sap/api/custom-table/index.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stevica&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-integrate-sap-datasphere-to-sap-cpq-and-extract-data-from-datasphere/qaa-p/14157967#M4920496"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:49:06.234000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/refresh-development-system/qaa-p/14157969#M4920497</id>
    <title>Re: Refresh Development System</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:52:44.352000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aukasz_SaBek</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2024353</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, Said_Asar_SA&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you would like to refresh your development systems by copying from another system, be extremely careful. In general SAP does not recommend&amp;nbsp;the copy of development systems, because many system specific attributes will be overwritten during the copy and that will lead to inconsistencies after copy. It is possible that your system and ChaRM/QGM&amp;nbsp;project cannot be used after the copy.&amp;nbsp;Consider this before you really perform&amp;nbsp;the system copy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nevertheless, if you still would like to make the system copy and take the above risks,&amp;nbsp;you must still&amp;nbsp;close all project cycles where the development system is involved before the system copy takes place. For detail information, please take a look at KBA 2259615.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please check note :&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/885343/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/885343/E&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards, Łukasz&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/refresh-development-system/qaa-p/14157969#M4920497"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:52:44.352000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/package-and-transport-assignment-after-datasource-replication-bw-4hana/qaq-p/14157971</id>
    <title>Package and transport assignment after DataSource replication (BW/4HANA)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:55:02.215000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anni5</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1860255</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;when I replicate and activate a datasource in my BW-system there ist no package and no transport assignment. At the moment I do the assignment manually. Is there a way to get an automatic pop-up for the assignment like we have for all the other objects in BW-system?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am using a BW/4HANA 2021 system and working in the SAP HANA Studio (Eclipse).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/package-and-transport-assignment-after-datasource-replication-bw-4hana/qaq-p/14157971"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:55:02.215000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/session-1-recap-amp-highlights-data-inspired-successful-concepts-for-data/bc-p/14157972#M845</id>
    <title>Re: Session 1 Recap &amp; Highlights– Data Inspired – Successful concepts for data-driven organizati</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:55:09.179000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexanderroan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/561103</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1608450"&gt;@Gaurish-Dessai&lt;/a&gt;, I think it's important to take a step back from technology and data detail and think about the broader context. I really like that you started the series from this perspective.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The instincts or bias that leaders bring to an organisation is a big topic for me. This goes beyond technology and into their broader approach to strategy and transformation. CEOs and CFOs that come from organisations or industries that make a lot of acquisitions tend to want to bring that with them, alternatively leaders from industries like manufacturing tend to bring a strong focus on cost management and P&amp;amp;L optimisation.&amp;nbsp; Leaders from Financial Services tend to want to optimise the balance sheet. As you said, it can be good and bad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I often think the cases where it works 'very well' are pure coincidence. I've noted that leaders tend to 'backwards rationalise' their success, this is very common in management books. They try create a 'recipe' after the fact. Which may or may not be the reason for their success or failure. There's often more factors at play than people are aware of.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When it comes to CIOs, the ones that come from organisations that had solid well designed global SAP implementations tend to want to bring that strategy of leveraging well designed ERP for comparability, consistency etc. On the other hands CEOs who come from the organisations that grew quickly through acquisitions tend to be unaware of the real benefits that come with that kind of work. The profile of IT people and leaders in general is quite interesting. It's rarely balanced. Some tend to focus on data, others on solutions, others on skilling up their people, others on micro managing cost, others on interesting innnovation topics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;None of these things are really problems in themselves, the issues come from 'unaware bias' or 'unaware instincts', I think it's important for leaders to understand their motivations and make sure they consider all options / all possibilities when developing strategy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I think this is quite relevant for enterprise architects too. They are one of the key positions in IT that can bring together the 'right way to do process', 'the right way to do systems', 'the right way to do data', many other roles are stuck in silos.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So yes, this kind of dicussion can open up a lot of interesting dialogue!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/session-1-recap-amp-highlights-data-inspired-successful-concepts-for-data/bc-p/14157972#M845"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:55:09.179000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sneak-peek-in-to-sap-analytics-cloud-release-for-q3-2025/bc-p/14157973#M183028</id>
    <title>Re: Sneak Peek in to SAP Analytics Cloud release for Q3 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T13:55:11.721000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>christian1963</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1697314</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;There are a lot of generative AI features here...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Will these also be available in the Neo environment?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Will there be similar limitations as with "Just Ask," e.g., live connections only work via Datasphere?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Is data import into SAC a key prerequisite?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sneak-peek-in-to-sap-analytics-cloud-release-for-q3-2025/bc-p/14157973#M183028"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:55:11.721000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/conditional-suppression-of-group-footer/qaa-p/14157976#M4920499</id>
    <title>Re: Conditional Suppression of Group Footer</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:03:36.561000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ido_millet</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/210105</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;A group cannot exist if it has no records.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The easiest way to ensure a customer without products has a record, is to use an &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Outer Join&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/conditional-suppression-of-group-footer/qaa-p/14157976#M4920499"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:03:36.561000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/about-myself/td-p/14157977</id>
    <title>About Myself.</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:04:04.179000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vinitakasliwal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45314</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Everyone,&lt;BR /&gt;My name is Vinita kasliwal and I’m excited to be part of the SAP Community&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;I&lt;/U&gt; work with SAP and Microsoft Product, and I use tools like Microsoft Excel and Power BI with SAP for reporting and analytics.&lt;BR /&gt;I'm looking forward to learning and connecting with others here.&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/about-myself/td-p/14157977"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:04:04.179000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/wien-discussions/sapfluencer-award/td-p/14157978</id>
    <title>SAPFluencer Award</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:04:28.256000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>foessleitner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/80</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hi,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;vielleicht habt ihr es schon gelesen. Es gibt da im Herbst die Verleihung eines SAPFluencer Award. Alle Details hier:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ankerkopf.de/sapfluencer-award/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://ankerkopf.de/sapfluencer-award/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vielleicht wollt ihr ja auch jemanden nominieren?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;lg Föß&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/wien-discussions/sapfluencer-award/td-p/14157978"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:04:28.256000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/deletion-flag-update-in-pricing-records-while-creation-is-not-show-in-the/qaa-p/14157979#M4220619</id>
    <title>Re: Deletion Flag update in Pricing Records while creatio...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:07:18.854000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmipathi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If you want to have a track on this, use program RV16ACHD where you can include Condition type, Key combination and date range.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;If that is not showing, go to v/06, select that condition type and tick the Change Document settings. If the deletion flag is not marked for change logging, update the config to include it&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/deletion-flag-update-in-pricing-records-while-creation-is-not-show-in-the/qaa-p/14157979#M4220619"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:07:18.854000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/conditional-suppression-of-group-footer/qaa-p/14157980#M4920500</id>
    <title>Re: Conditional Suppression of Group Footer</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:09:22.164000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>carmine1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/729647</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I think you misunderstand.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/conditional-suppression-of-group-footer/qaa-p/14157980#M4920500"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:09:22.164000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-delete-null-entries-values-during-calculation-in-data-action-in-sac/qaa-p/14157981#M4920501</id>
    <title>Re: How to delete null entries/values during calculation...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:09:45.285000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>zee_siddique15</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/843175</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370"&gt;@N1kh1l&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, yes for some reason the Delete () statement is not deleting the completing record (or not doing anything), if my one of 3 measures in a record is Null.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Zeenat S&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-delete-null-entries-values-during-calculation-in-data-action-in-sac/qaa-p/14157981#M4920501"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:09:45.285000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/bc-p/14157982#M14355</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Certification Transformation: How You Can Get and Stay Certified</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:10:24.340000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KarthikKalaimani</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1994579</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/138893"&gt;@WaldemarFal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;I would like to understand if a consultant who is proficient to take a certification - let's assume&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Financial Accounting | C_S4CFI in this case. He has lost his certification validity due to not "Staying Current". Can this consultant purchase only the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CER001 SAP Certification Exam, One Attempt&lt;/STRONG&gt; and attempt to clear the certification or should he have a valid Learning Hub access to achieve his certification? Any insights on this would be greatly appreciated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Thank you.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Karthik&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/bc-p/14157982#M14355"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:10:24.340000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/facing-issues-with-shown-data-in-sac/qaa-p/14157991#M4920502</id>
    <title>Re: Facing issues with shown data in SAC</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:11:15.327000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/711428"&gt;@hoernst&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Better way to debug this would be to either assign the same roles and teams to this users both in BW and SAC which is working for other users. Or Assign yourself the roles and teams currently assigned to this user and see if you face the same problem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps !!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nikhil&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/facing-issues-with-shown-data-in-sac/qaa-p/14157991#M4920502"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:11:15.327000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/conditional-suppression-of-group-footer/qaa-p/14157993#M4920503</id>
    <title>Re: Conditional Suppression of Group Footer</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:12:53.290000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>carmine1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/729647</uri>
    </author>
    <content>I think you misunderstand. The Customer (Group 1) exists and *some* detail exists, whether it be product category A or B or both (Group 2). In the case where there is *only* product category A *or* B detail records, then the Group 2 footer is superfluous and I would like to suppress it.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/conditional-suppression-of-group-footer/qaa-p/14157993#M4920503"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:12:53.290000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/creating-additional-operation-during-new-order-creation-through/qaq-p/14157994</id>
    <title>Creating Additional operation during new order creation through notification</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:13:13.043000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jagadeeshpt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1383688</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Business requirement is to have an additional operation during new order creation through notification.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;We have checked BAPI and BADI on same , but its not working as expected.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Please suggest possibilities to achieve this requirement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks and Regards&lt;BR /&gt;Jagadeesh&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/creating-additional-operation-during-new-order-creation-through/qaq-p/14157994"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:13:13.043000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/sap-ariba-sourcing/m-p/14157996#M10228</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Ariba Sourcing</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:15:03.123000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vinitakasliwal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45314</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome to SAP Community&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/sap-ariba-sourcing/m-p/14157996#M10228"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:15:03.123000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/remove-1st-rehire-verification-check-and-only-use-the-2nd-rehire/qaa-p/14157997#M45067</id>
    <title>Re: Remove 1st rehire verification check and only use the 2nd rehire verification?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:15:05.107000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kristi_Thomas</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/51782</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13248"&gt;@Nishant&lt;/a&gt;_Varshney - I never received an official response but from what I know there isn't a way to disable the first rehire verification check. Which is dissapointing.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/remove-1st-rehire-verification-check-and-only-use-the-2nd-rehire/qaa-p/14157997#M45067"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:15:05.107000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/renaming-custom-tab-created-by-custom-fields-and-logic-application/qaa-p/14157998#M4920504</id>
    <title>Re: Renaming custom tab created by Custom Fields and Logic application?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:17:32.926000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S0025326646</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1474773</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Are there any update? Where you able to do it?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/renaming-custom-tab-created-by-custom-fields-and-logic-application/qaa-p/14157998#M4920504"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:17:32.926000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-sustainability-control-tower-q2-2025-updates-amp-highlights/ba-p/14157995</id>
    <title>SAP Sustainability Control Tower: Q2 2025 Updates &amp; Highlights</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:18:52.051000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>amandamasuku</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/867717</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the first half of 2025, global sustainability governance has entered a new phase of scrutiny and recalibration. The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;EU Omnibus amendments&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to the CSRD have postponed timelines and reduced the scope of immediate obligations for thousands of companies, temporarily easing the pressure of compliance. However, this regulatory pause has only sharpened the spotlight on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;data integrity, preparedness, and strategic ESG integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At the same time, investors, regulators, and civil society are intensifying their expectations. Public disclosures are no longer judged on completeness alone—they must be audit-ready, aligned with recognized frameworks like &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ESRS and EU Taxonomy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Companies are expected to move beyond box-ticking compliance into continuous ESG performance management, proactively steering their sustainability journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sustainability Control Tower (SCT) is designed precisely for this challenge. It enables organizations to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Record ESG factors&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; with out-of-the-box integration to SAP systems and trusted third-party sources&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analyze performance across financial, operational, and sustainability dimensions to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;support informed decisions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerate the transition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; through auditable, framework-aligned reporting—covering both regulatory and voluntary disclosures, powered by AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Building on our momentum from Q1, this quarter's updates focus on strengthening &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ESRS-aligned metric coverage,&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;deeper analytical flexibility, improved auditability, and tighter alignment with financial structures.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Expansion of SAP-provided metric coverage&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To support organizations on their ESRS compliance journey, SAP Sustainability Control Tower (SCT) continues to expand its library of SAP-provided metrics aligned with the European Sustainability Reporting Standards. These include both qualitative and quantitative definitions based on EFRAG's implementation guidance. Current metric coverage is available in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_SUS_SCT/21ecfb83f8d14e5982b7af315da5889a/3904fa967d1f4c3d928d2e719141b016.html#overview-of-available-quantitative-metrics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and detailed in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sustainability-control-tower-update-on-sap-provided-metrics-on-esrs/ba-p/14066241" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Community blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, offering transparency and reuse for accelerated implementation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="amandamasuku_0-1753099835434.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289334i3C27CCE536A97C2B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="amandamasuku_0-1753099835434.png" alt="amandamasuku_0-1753099835434.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking ahead, we plan to reach approximately 80% coverage of ESRS data points by the end of 2025, including metrics from ESRS 2, S2–S4, G1, and additional quantitative metrics from ESRS Topical Standards. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73555000100800003523&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#;INNO=B9314318771A1FD083C58B214E869B7A" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This roadmap&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; aims to enable our customers to progressively adopt SCT content for structured, auditable, and regulation-ready ESG disclosures while maintaining flexibility to extend for sector-specific or company-specific needs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analyze ESG Data App Enhancements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Analyze ESG Data application now offers a significantly improved analytics experience with the introduction of the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analytics &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;tab. Users can explore all standard custom quantitative metrics in greater depth by applying drill-down dimensions, choosing between chart or table formats, and configuring default views tailored to reporting needs. This new flexibility allows up to three charts to be displayed simultaneously, each with independent metric, period, and structure settings.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="amandamasuku_1-1753099835435.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289335i98326E671E0F1C07/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="amandamasuku_1-1753099835435.png" alt="amandamasuku_1-1753099835435.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In parallel, users can manage and switch between saved configurations of grouped metric tiles (“Overviews”), enabling different perspectives for different stakeholders or strategic priorities. Together, these enhancements empower users to personalize and streamline how ESG data is analyzed, viewed, and shared – supporting more informed decision-making and stronger alignment with sustainability goals. F&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ind full details here: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_SUS_SCT/0ec96e5804244b40b2adab7bbe20fcff/abdc311f68744331a6af6f6e55e83158.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using the Analyze ESG Data Application&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="amandamasuku_2-1753099835436.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289333i7F1DB2E996792F74/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="amandamasuku_2-1753099835436.png" alt="amandamasuku_2-1753099835436.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom Templates for “Generate ESG Reports with AI” App&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Generate ESG Reports with AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; app now offers greater flexibility and control through the introduction of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;custom templates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Users can create or edit templates to tailor the structure and content of ESG reports using available SAP-provided quantitative metrics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Within the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Templates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; section, you can now select “Create” to build a new template or modify an existing one by adding sections and subsections, defining narrative text, and selecting from a predefined list of charts and tables. For each component, a content preview is available to ensure alignment with the selected reporting period. Once finalized, templates can be saved and reused, enabling consistent and structured ESG reporting across time periods.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="amandamasuku_3-1753099835437.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289336i9B481D7C3E718CA8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="amandamasuku_3-1753099835437.png" alt="amandamasuku_3-1753099835437.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When generating a report, you can preview or download the result as a PDF—and for added customization, you can edit any section manually. SAP's built-in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-assistance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; now supports dynamic revisions: simply select a passage and use the “Revise” option to receive suggestions to shorten or lengthen the text, helping refine your final ESG narrative with ease and speed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="amandamasuku_4-1753099835438.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289337iEFEFC62B1880A8D4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="amandamasuku_4-1753099835438.png" alt="amandamasuku_4-1753099835438.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiscal Period Support&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The new &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage Fiscal Year Variants &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;app brings flexible fiscal period support to SAP Sustainability Control Tower, allowing customers to define and activate custom fiscal year variants that align with their internal planning cycles. Whether using standard calendar months or granular date-based periods (like semi-monthly ranges), organizations can now tailor their ESG data analysis and reporting across key apps such as &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analyze ESG Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage GHG Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;View Emission Dashboard&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Built-in validation checks help ensure data compatibility, with options to consolidate or reimport data when switching to a new variant. This enables more accurate reporting, tighter alignment with financial periods, and greater control over how sustainability data is structured and interpreted across the organization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change log updates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In Q2, we've significantly improved transparency and traceability across SAP Sustainability Control Tower (SCT). Users can now track create, update, and delete changes to public overview configurations in the Analyze ESG Data app using the View Change Logs app. This functionality extends further, providing detailed logs for changes in business activity data, clearly showing the number of updated or imported records and distinguishing between actual and target data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New Languages Supported&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To better serve global enterprises, SAP SCT now supports Turkish and Italian languages. This update enables local teams to work in their native languages and enhances cross-regional collaboration on sustainability data collection and reporting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="amandamasuku_5-1753099835439.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289338i5D383DA4EFA5B80C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="amandamasuku_5-1753099835439.png" alt="amandamasuku_5-1753099835439.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;H2 2025 Roadmap Updates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking ahead, we’re focused on simplifying and harmonizing ESG data consumption and reporting. A key milestone will be the delivery of a unified &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Read API&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for metric values – supporting both quantitative and qualitative data – to&amp;nbsp; make calculated ESG metrics easily accessible to external tools like disclosure management platforms. This API will also expose key metadata (including ESG standard references) and allow for both bulk and individual metric retrieval based on reporting scopes. We’re also working on improving flexibility in data modeling by enabling &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;custom account groups&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, account-to-group mappings, and supporting activity data input through multiple channels. Additionally, we’ll continue expanding &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;metric-level analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;measure drilldowns&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and export formats in the Analyze ESG data application. To enhance data quality and reporting alignment, we’re introducing tools for guiding data requirements based on double materiality, setting up reporting hierarchies and data sources, and improving transparency on data completeness. In parallel, we aim to deliver ESRS-aligned metric definitions that cover up to 70% of EFRAG's guidance, along with clear documentation and community updates to keep you informed as mentioned above. Stay tuned: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73555000100800003523&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SCT Roadmap Explorer.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additional Information&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For in-depth details on SAP Sustainability Control Tower, we recommend browsing the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_SUS_SCT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. For an overview of all new features and functions, check the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/d70085db59f0412e9bb1ddfa8157c507?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s New&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; section, which is updated with every new software release.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-sustainability-control-tower-q2-2025-updates-amp-highlights/ba-p/14157995"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:18:52.051000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-secure-login-service-for-sap-gui-now-supports-custom-certificate/bc-p/14158000#M183030</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Secure Login Service for SAP GUI Now Supports Custom Certificate Authorities on AWS</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:19:04.790000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shaun_Wimpory</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/208232</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the prompt reply, Martina.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there a proposed solution for customers running S/4HANA on-premises or self-managed in a hyper scaler? (eg not in RISE)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shaun&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-secure-login-service-for-sap-gui-now-supports-custom-certificate/bc-p/14158000#M183030"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:19:04.790000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/customer-wants-to-export-ias-audit-logs/qaa-p/14158002#M4920505</id>
    <title>Re: Customer wants to export IAS Audit logs.</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:20:26.136000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PhillipButts38</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6209</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks Matthias! We will dig through this and see how to enable this through the subaccount.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/customer-wants-to-export-ias-audit-logs/qaa-p/14158002#M4920505"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:20:26.136000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/is-there-a-standard-query-to-get-the-conversion-rates-from-bw/qaa-p/14158003#M4920506</id>
    <title>Re: Is there a standard query to get the conversion rates...</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:21:55.448000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1841790"&gt;@mousumi2&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I do not think there is a standard query for Exchange rates in BW. As far I&amp;nbsp; know BW stores Exchange rates in tables &lt;SPAN&gt;TCURR and then there is a RSCUR transaction which runs the translation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_BW4HANA/107a6e8a38b74ede94c833ca3b7b6f51/4a27a96a81661d10e10000000a42189b.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_BW4HANA/107a6e8a38b74ede94c833ca3b7b6f51/4a27a96a81661d10e10000000a42189b.html?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hope this helps !!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Nikhil&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/is-there-a-standard-query-to-get-the-conversion-rates-from-bw/qaa-p/14158003#M4920506"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:21:55.448000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-dm-subsequent-assignment-of-routing-to-order/qaq-p/14158005</id>
    <title>SAP DM - Subsequent assignment of Routing to Order</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:23:35.795000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>IsabelTh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1635811</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we are currently designing a workaround for a specific use case. To do this, we copy an order-specific routing without marking it directly as the current version. Now we can't find an option to subsequently assign this task list as the current version for an order. We can assign it to the SFC via the Production Change Service. However, as the old version remains for the order, we cannot track the progress in Manage Orders App after the new version has been created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does anyone know if this is somehow possible?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-dm-subsequent-assignment-of-routing-to-order/qaq-p/14158005"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:23:35.795000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/error-in-updating-custom-field-of-prps-table-using-bapi-bus2054-change/td-p/14158007</id>
    <title>Error in updating custom field of PRPS table using BAPI_BUS2054_CHANGE_MULTI</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:25:00.546000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yashi2002</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/880234</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hi All,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Can anyone help me -&amp;gt; I'm trying to update custom fields using FM &lt;STRONG&gt;(&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BAPI_BUS2054_CHANGE_MULTI)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But, it's giving me and error message that is code&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;CNIF_PI&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;error no. &lt;STRONG&gt;081.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;My code is:-&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;LOOP AT gt_prps_update ASSIGNING FIELD-SYMBOL(&amp;lt;gs_prps_update&amp;gt;).&lt;BR /&gt;CALL FUNCTION 'BAPI_PS_INITIALIZATION'.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;READ TABLE gt_pspid ASSIGNING FIELD-SYMBOL(&amp;lt;gs_pspid&amp;gt;)&lt;BR /&gt;WITH KEY pspnr = &amp;lt;gs_prps_update&amp;gt;-psphi BINARY SEARCH.&lt;BR /&gt;IF sy-subrc = 0.&lt;BR /&gt;DATA(gv_pspid) = &amp;lt;gs_pspid&amp;gt;-pspid.&lt;BR /&gt;ENDIF.&lt;BR /&gt;CLEAR: gt_wbs_elem, gt_wbs_detail, gt_return.&lt;BR /&gt;CALL FUNCTION 'BAPI_BUS2054_GETDATA'&lt;BR /&gt;EXPORTING&lt;BR /&gt;i_project_definition = gv_pspid&lt;BR /&gt;TABLES&lt;BR /&gt;et_wbs_element = gt_wbs_detail&lt;BR /&gt;et_return = gt_return.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CALL FUNCTION 'CONVERSION_EXIT_ABPSN_OUTPUT'&lt;BR /&gt;EXPORTING&lt;BR /&gt;input = &amp;lt;gs_prps_update&amp;gt;-posid&lt;BR /&gt;IMPORTING&lt;BR /&gt;output = gv_posid.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;DELETE gt_wbs_detail WHERE wbs_element &amp;lt;&amp;gt; gv_posid.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;APPEND VALUE bapiparex(&lt;BR /&gt;structure = gc_structure&lt;BR /&gt;valuepart1 = |{ gv_posid WIDTH = 24 }{ &amp;lt;gs_prps_update&amp;gt;-zzielanln1 WIDTH = 12 }|&lt;BR /&gt;valuepart2 = |{ gv_posid WIDTH = 24 }{ &amp;lt;gs_prps_update&amp;gt;-zzielanln2 WIDTH = 12 }|&lt;BR /&gt;) TO gt_extension.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;gt_wbs_elem = VALUE #(&lt;BR /&gt;FOR &amp;lt;gs_wbs_detail&amp;gt; IN gt_wbs_detail&lt;BR /&gt;( wbs_element = &amp;lt;gs_wbs_detail&amp;gt;-wbs_element ) ).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;gt_wbs_upd = VALUE #(&lt;BR /&gt;FOR &amp;lt;gs_wbs_detail&amp;gt; IN gt_wbs_detail&lt;BR /&gt;( wbs_element = &amp;lt;gs_wbs_detail&amp;gt;-wbs_element ) ).&lt;BR /&gt;ENDLOOP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IF gt_extension IS NOT INITIAL.&lt;BR /&gt;CALL FUNCTION 'BAPI_BUS2054_CHANGE_MULTI'&lt;BR /&gt;EXPORTING&lt;BR /&gt;i_project_definition = gv_pspid&lt;BR /&gt;TABLES&lt;BR /&gt;it_wbs_element = gt_wbs_elem&lt;BR /&gt;it_update_wbs_element = gt_wbs_upd&lt;BR /&gt;et_return = gt_return&lt;BR /&gt;extensionin = gt_extension&lt;BR /&gt;extensionout = gt_extension1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CALL FUNCTION 'BAPI_PS_PRECOMMIT'&lt;BR /&gt;TABLES&lt;BR /&gt;et_return = gt_return.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IF gt_return[ 1 ]-type = gc_succ.&lt;BR /&gt;CALL FUNCTION 'BAPI_TRANSACTION_COMMIT'&lt;BR /&gt;EXPORTING&lt;BR /&gt;wait = '1'.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Someone please help me with this.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;It'll be highly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/error-in-updating-custom-field-of-prps-table-using-bapi-bus2054-change/td-p/14158007"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:25:00.546000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/workflow/qaa-p/14158008#M45068</id>
    <title>Re: Workflow</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:28:21.307000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aboooood86</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/804139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>would you first let us know how the participant got the Workflow in the first place? and do you want that the participant never get the Workflow again ?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/workflow/qaa-p/14158008#M45068"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:28:21.307000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/which-certification-is-beneficial-along-with-sap-ibp/qaq-p/14158009</id>
    <title>Which Certification is beneficial along with SAP IBP?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:28:23.182000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mukesh_Bhutekar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1799689</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Which Certification is beneficial along with SAP IBP? SAP BTP or&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;P Certified Associate - Positioning&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;P Business AI Solutions as part of&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;P Business Suite or&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SA&lt;/SPAN&gt;P Certified Associate - Positioning&amp;nbsp;SAP Business Suite via&amp;nbsp;SAP Supply Chain Management Solutions?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please suggest if you have any new recommendations?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/which-certification-is-beneficial-along-with-sap-ibp/qaq-p/14158009"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:28:23.182000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/hci-server-credentials/qaq-p/14158010</id>
    <title>HCI Server Credentials</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T14:28:28.295000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>UjjawalSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2057358</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone tell me how to get &lt;STRONG&gt;HCI Service Keys (Client id and Client Secret)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please share the steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank You!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ujjawal&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/hci-server-credentials/qaq-p/14158010"/>
    <published>2025-07-21T14:28:28.295000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
