<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/all_replies.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - All Replies</title>
  <updated>2025-10-13T13:59:01.457700+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Replies in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/calling-sap-ai-core-orchestration-v2-api-from-sap-build-a-quick-fix-guide/bc-p/14242269#M185333</id>
    <title>Re: Calling SAP AI Core Orchestration v2 API from SAP Build: A Quick Fix Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:17:08.199000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>franciscogubb72</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/116758</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/205468"&gt;@martin_donadio&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my case, I was facing the same issue, and yes, in my case the problem was I did not add the v2 before the /completion. So I changed from:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.ai.prod.eu-central-1.aws.ml.hana.ondemand.com/v2/inference/deployments/df381315fb2383f6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.ai.prod.eu-central-1.aws.ml.hana.ondemand.com/v2/inference/deployments/df381315fb2383f6&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.ai.prod.eu-central-1.aws.ml.hana.ondemand.com/v2/inference/deployments/df381315fb2383f6/v2" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.ai.prod.eu-central-1.aws.ml.hana.ondemand.com/v2/inference/deployments/df381315fb2383f6/v2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My confusion raised because I imported the openAPI specification into SAP Build according:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/ORCHESTRATION_API_v2/path/orchestration.v2.endpoints.create" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/ORCHESTRATION_API_v2/path/orchestration.v2.endpoints.create&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That specification for v2 is not including in the path the /v2/orchestration. Hence, I had to force to include this v2 in the destinations of btp.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If there are two versions in the api.sap.com specification:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/ORCHESTRATION_API_v2/path/orchestration.v2.endpoints.create" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/ORCHESTRATION_API_v2/path/orchestration.v2.endpoints.create&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/ORCHESTRATION_API/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/ORCHESTRATION_API/overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Then, I would expect the correct /v2/orchestration path in the v2 documentation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Nata.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/calling-sap-ai-core-orchestration-v2-api-from-sap-build-a-quick-fix-guide/bc-p/14242269#M185333"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:17:08.199000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/adaptation-editor-for-sapui5-adaptation-project-with-vs-code-on-prem/qaa-p/14242270#M4929092</id>
    <title>Re: Adaptation editor for SAPUI5 adaptation project with VS Code - On Prem</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:17:08.531000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gergana_Marcheva</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2170866</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Looks like a problem with the ui5 version. Please change it to 1.108.47 in the ui5.yaml file (on the very bottom of the file).</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/adaptation-editor-for-sapui5-adaptation-project-with-vs-code-on-prem/qaa-p/14242270#M4929092"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:17:08.531000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sii-tip-for-spain-5-sii-adjustments-for-canary-islands-october-2025/bc-p/14242271#M185334</id>
    <title>Re: SII tip for Spain #5: SII Adjustments for Canary Islands October 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:20:48.629000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Carmen1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1449997</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170459"&gt;@FranciscoHurtado&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the quick reply!&amp;nbsp;I'll keep an eye out for the release of the note on this subject.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An additional question, although all the documentation refers to version 1.1, the XML tag remains in version 1.0, right?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Carmen&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sii-tip-for-spain-5-sii-adjustments-for-canary-islands-october-2025/bc-p/14242271#M185334"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:20:48.629000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-erp-private-2025-fps0-release-highlights-part-1/ba-p/14236762</id>
    <title>SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 FPS0 Release Highlights Part 1</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:23:02.170000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Harish_Mangtani</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131964</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Hello and Welcome to the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 FPS0 Product Release Highlights!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;I’m Harish Mangtani from Product Experience at SAP SE. As a Product Manager working closely with our customers and engineering teams, I’m excited to share a hands-on view of the innovations delivered in this release—designed to help organizations run smarter, faster, and more connected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;*NOTE: This blog is the first edition of my personal highlights from the SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 FPS0 release—focusing on innovations I believe bring meaningful business impact across key Lines of Business. A follow-up update is planned by the end of October, where I’ll expand the scope to include additional areas such as Human Capital Management (HCM) and a broader set of innovations delivered across each LoB. A dedicated Part 2 of the blog will follow, highlighting industry-specific capabilities and localization features.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;This release is built on SAP’s AI-First, Suite-First strategy and continues our vision of unifying &lt;STRONG&gt;Applications, Data, and AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;. What stands out is how intelligence and automation are now deeply embedded into business processes, powered by SAP Business Data Cloud and a modular, configurable ERP suite. AI and agents drive productivity, automation, and real-time analytics across the enterprise, empowering business users to make better decisions and execute with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="intr.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326666i61919E3495C72BEA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="intr.png" alt="intr.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;This release also delivers industry-specific capabilities, global coverage, extensibility, and a clean core foundation for ongoing innovation. Whether you’re in Finance, Procurement, Supply Chain, Manufacturing, Sales, Service, or Asset Management, you’ll find new capabilities designed to help teams work smarter and more efficiently. This blog focuses on how these principles translate into tangible innovations—ranging from intelligent agents and harmonized data products to process enhancements across key business areas—that bring meaningful improvements to the ERP experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 refers to the latest release of our cloud ERP offering, encompassing both &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;. While both products share a common foundation, the innovation scope differs: &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered capabilities and intelligent agents are available exclusively in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;, while SAP S/4HANA 2025 includes core functional enhancements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the heart of this release is a layered architecture:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI at the top&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling intuitive user experiences and intelligent agents that automate and optimize business processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud at the core&lt;/STRONG&gt;, providing a unified, governed data foundation that connects SAP and third-party data sources.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Applications at the foundation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, delivering deep industry capabilities and end-to-end process integration across every line of business.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761940673"&gt;Release Planning&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here is a quick recap of the release strategy for 2023–2025, along with a definition of deliveries. This strategy is designed to help customers maximize their potential while keeping them informed about the latest innovations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ReleaseS.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326608i8D84CA9A609608A7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ReleaseS.png" alt="ReleaseS.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the sections that follow, I’ll walk through highlights across Lines of Business—starting with Finance, and continuing through Sales, Supply Chain, Service Management, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565427168"&gt;Finance&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Powered Innovations (AI capabilities available in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition only)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1627079101"&gt;Joule Agent for Accounts Receivables*&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;The Joule Agent for Accounts Receivables empowers accountants to streamline the management of overdue receivables. It enables users to analyze open receivables, identify overdue payments, and receive a summary of the analysis along with recommended next steps. The agent can fetch outstanding balances, retrieve open invoices and credit memos, and provide a history of dunning activities. It also helps identify open disputes that may be impacting overdue amounts and suggests appropriate actions for managing these cases.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/manage-accounts-receivables" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Read more on SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;*Beta Shipment, GA planned&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Finance1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326611i6B29308ED75C54B6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Finance1.png" alt="Finance1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1430565596"&gt;Joule Agent for Cash Manager*&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Cash and Liquidity Management, the Joule Agent provides treasury professionals with conversational access to key financial data. Users can ask questions about current cash positions, liquidity forecasts, and bank balances. Joule responds with contextual insights and enables direct navigation to relevant apps for further action.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/cash-and-liquidity-management-76e87ba4a34d40a1aa7b860c465a9a5b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Read more on SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;*Beta Shipment, GA planned&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1234052091"&gt;Dispute Manager – Incorrect Invoice (FI-CA)*&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Dispute Manager in Contract Accounting (FI-CA) integrates with Joule to guide users through the resolution of incorrect invoice disputes. Based on the dispute type—such as missing credit, incorrect credit, or missing payment—Joule presents verification options and resolution steps, including reviewing contract accounts, creating or assigning credit memos, and reassigning payments.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/JOULE/82a14f108cfa4d4788244d81371e072b/9efcd97a276949cfbc027d4da13ff33d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Read more on SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;*Beta Shipment, GA planned&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="fin2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326616iEF42EF513E2A5231/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="fin2.png" alt="fin2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1037538586"&gt;AI-Assisted Trade Classification Proposals&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This innovation introduces a simulation app that helps teams assess how effectively the fuzzy search algorithm classifies products based on existing data. By comparing proposed trade classification numbers with those already assigned, users can evaluate the accuracy of AI-driven suggestions. Combined with the creation of product description attributes, this supports a more automated and reliable approach to global trade compliance.&lt;BR /&gt;Read more here&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;URL:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/f71f71283d8c4bce92aff58392a4bbad.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/f71f71283d8c4bce92aff58392a4bbad.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="trade.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326617iD736984DA3D9E21A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="trade.png" alt="trade.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-841025081"&gt;BRIM: Joule for Subscription Order Management&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule for Subscription Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; streamlines the process of creating and managing subscription orders. Using AI, this intelligent agent automates the creation of subscription-based orders, reducing the time and effort typically needed to set up and maintain subscription models. It ensures that the correct terms, pricing, and billing cycles are applied by automatically analyzing customer preferences and historical data. This not only simplifies subscription management but also enhances accuracy and compliance, making it easier for businesses to scale subscription-based services. By automating these tasks, teams can focus on higher-value activities like customer engagement and strategic planning, while Joule handles the routine administrative work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/create-subscription-order?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule for Subscription Order Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core functional innovations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-644511576"&gt;Optimize cash and improve supply chain resilience with SAP Taulia integration&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Receivables Financing with SAP Taulia&lt;/STRONG&gt; provides businesses with a streamlined way to unlock working capital by financing receivables. The integration of SAP S/4HANA with SAP Taulia automates the process of securing financing for outstanding invoices, giving businesses faster access to cash without the need for complex negotiations or third-party intermediaries. This solution simplifies cash flow management by enabling organizations to sell their receivables and receive early payment, while also providing suppliers with the option to get paid sooner. By reducing the need for traditional lines of credit, businesses can improve liquidity, mitigate financial risk, and enhance supplier relationships—all while maintaining control over their receivables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/d7f20c7f332b432a9a7f395bf59dc7b0.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Receivables Financing with SAP Taulia&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Taulia.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326618iD810DCDD00C90708/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Taulia.png" alt="Taulia.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-189832633"&gt;Sales&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Powered Innovations (AI capabilities available in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition only)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-251484566"&gt;Faster Insights into Sales Order Fulfillment Process Using Joule&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt; integrated into the sales order fulfillment process, businesses gain faster insights into potential issues, helping resolve fulfillment challenges quickly. The AI-powered agent proactively analyzes sales order data, identifying potential bottlenecks and inconsistencies in real-time. It automatically provides recommendations for field changes and suggests actions to resolve fulfillment issues, ensuring that orders are processed without unnecessary delays. By using &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;, sales teams can respond to order fulfillment challenges faster, reducing manual intervention and enhancing customer satisfaction with timely deliveries. This intelligent automation improves the overall efficiency of the order-to-cash cycle and ensures a smoother experience for both customers and internal teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/perform-sales-order-fields-changes-and-resolve-fulfillment-issues?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Faster Insights into Sales Order Fulfillment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="sales1.png" style="width: 923px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326619iAEAF3B6766329A7A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sales1.png" alt="sales1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--442746034"&gt;Streamlining Solution Quotations Process Using Joule&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the process of managing and releasing solution quotations becomes faster and more efficient. The AI-powered agent automates key steps such as fetching solution quotation details, releasing and accepting quotations, and ensuring that all necessary information is up to date. By analyzing historical data and customer preferences, Joule makes intelligent recommendations to streamline the approval and modification processes, reducing manual effort and minimizing delays. This leads to quicker turnaround times for your sales teams, ensuring that customers receive accurate and timely quotations, which in turn can accelerate the sales cycle. Whether it's fetching information or managing approval workflows, Joule helps businesses handle solution quotations seamlessly, driving efficiency and improving overall sales performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/perform-release-and-acceptance-of-solution-quotations?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Streamlining Solution Quotations Process Using Joule&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/fetch-solution-quotation-information?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Fetch Solution Quotation Information&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="sales2.png" style="width: 855px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326623iB683813C2540443C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sales2.png" alt="sales2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core functional innovations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--639259539"&gt;Navigation to NAST Output Control in the SAP Fiori Apps for Sales Order and Billing&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new feature in SAP Fiori apps &lt;STRONG&gt;“Manage Sales Orders (Version 2)”&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;“Manage Billing Documents”&lt;/STRONG&gt; enables seamless navigation to &lt;STRONG&gt;NAST output control&lt;/STRONG&gt;, allowing users to quickly access output documents for sales orders and billing. This integration makes it easier for users to view the &lt;STRONG&gt;PDV version&lt;/STRONG&gt; of documents like order confirmations and invoices directly within the apps, improving visibility and accessibility. By providing a single-point access to critical output documents, businesses can streamline their processes, saving time and reducing manual effort. This enhances operational efficiency by simplifying document management and accelerating processing times, ultimately improving the overall sales and billing workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/7b24a64d9d0941bda1afa753263d9e39/e7f14402cf5846b4b3d0d677c15414b1.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Navigation to NAST Output Control in SAP Fiori Apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="sales3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326626i145E3A287D76588F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="sales3.png" alt="sales3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--835773044"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;One-Step Payment Before Sales Order or Delivery is Created&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;One-Step Payment&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature allows businesses to collect payments before the sales order or delivery is created, improving cash flow and simplifying the sales process. With the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Digital Payments add-on&lt;/STRONG&gt;, payments are initiated directly through the payment service provider (PSP), such as in a web shop, and payment details are transferred directly into the sales and finance applications. This streamlines the settlement process, ensuring a smooth match between the payment and the liability. It also allows businesses to handle refunds through credit memos when necessary, accelerating digital payments and reducing the time it takes for customers to pay before goods are shipped.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/5a2a2f7738534c0b84f4b2444f7133b9.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;One-Step Payment Before Sales Order or Delivery&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1032286549"&gt;The New Business Role: Solution Business Specialist&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Solution Business Specialist&lt;/STRONG&gt; role provides users with the tools to manage solution-based selling processes, spanning the entire sales lifecycle. This role includes access to SAP Fiori apps that help in the creation, processing, and monitoring of solution orders, which is especially valuable for handling complex sales scenarios such as bundled offerings or project-based solutions. By linking the role to specific workflows and tasks, it streamlines the sales process, improves collaboration between sales, delivery, and billing teams, and ensures that users can manage solution orders more efficiently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/16a851c2515c47d9bd1b80c9015903a0.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The New Business Role: Solution Business Specialist&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--641994040"&gt;Supply Chain&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Powered Innovations (AI capabilities available in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition only)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1425313559"&gt;AI-Assisted Predictive Labor Demand Planning in Extended Warehouse Management (EWM)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-assisted predictive labor demand planning&lt;/STRONG&gt; helps warehouse managers address labor shortages and increasing delivery demands by providing intelligent insights into workforce needs. By leveraging historical and real-time data, this feature calculates the planned duration of workload records and the required workload for outbound delivery orders. With short-term (next few days) and mid-term (next week) forecasts, managers can anticipate workload changes and adjust staffing accordingly. Interactive charts and key performance indicators (KPIs) allow users to monitor, analyze, and forecast labor demand, enabling better resource planning and more efficient warehouse operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/9832125c23154a179bfa1784cdc9577a/b244f6ba2bfc4f68b654187b1c7ce0df.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-Assisted Predictive Labor Demand Planning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="supply1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326628iD869165AC2A0B5B5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="supply1.png" alt="supply1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core functional innovations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1621827064"&gt;Alternative-Based Confirmation with Stock Transport Document Creation (aATP)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Alternative-Based Confirmation&lt;/STRONG&gt; in &lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced Available-to-Promise (aATP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; enhances the order fulfillment process by providing alternative solutions when stock is unavailable at the original source. When an item cannot be fulfilled from the requested location, the system identifies alternative sources and confirms availability from those locations. The process also involves the creation of a &lt;STRONG&gt;Stock Transport Document&lt;/STRONG&gt; to ensure smooth transfer of stock between locations. This feature helps ensure that customers' orders are fulfilled on time, even when original stock is unavailable, thereby improving customer satisfaction and reducing delays.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/f3fb109337f7411c880a0989a44dbe33.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Alternative-Based Confirmation with Stock Transport Document Creation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="supply2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326630i504013405949E4B7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="supply2.png" alt="supply2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1818340569"&gt;Cross-Delivery Handling Unit in the Advanced Shipping and Receiving Process (Transportation Management)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Cross-Delivery Handling Unit&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature improves the advanced shipping and receiving process by allowing the grouping of multiple deliveries into a single handling unit. This streamlines logistics and enhances transportation efficiency by simplifying the management of goods. Users can track and manage multiple deliveries as a single unit, reducing the complexity of handling individual items separately. This functionality improves the visibility of shipments, simplifies the shipping process, and enables better control over logistics, even when managing complex scenarios across different locations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/006bfa3e3ade4651bf3fbaed22a8fbc7.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cross-Delivery Handling Unit in the Advanced Shipping and Receiving Process&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="tra1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326632i73DC64072312E2F0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="tra1.png" alt="tra1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--2014854074"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The integration of &lt;STRONG&gt;Extended Warehouse Management (EWM)&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt; enables the connection of on-premise warehouse management with cloud-based capabilities. This integration streamlines data synchronization between systems, ensuring real-time inventory updates, enhancing visibility, and improving operational efficiency. By leveraging this integration, businesses can optimize their warehouse processes, improve decision-making, and increase agility in responding to demand and supply fluctuations. This seamless data flow helps improve supply chain management and supports more effective scaling of warehouse operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/c215ff82856248778fdb1120063460a0.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="supply4.png" style="width: 700px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326634i0037D5E219137232/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="supply4.png" alt="supply4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2083599717"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Production Planning-based Availability Check with Supply Creation-Based Confirmation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Production Planning-based Availability Check&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Creation-Based Confirmation&lt;/STRONG&gt; in &lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced Available-to-Promise (aATP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; improves order fulfillment by aligning available production resources with customer demand. This feature leverages real-time production plans to perform availability checks, ensuring that if the required stock is not available, the system automatically generates supply to meet the demand. It then confirms the order based on the updated production plan, offering customers accurate delivery promises and improving overall production planning efficiency. By integrating availability checks with supply creation, this functionality helps businesses manage customer orders more effectively, even in complex production scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/fa10029c613c415eb472b97c84c25705.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Production Planning-based Availability Check with Supply Creation-Based Confirmation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="supp6.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326635i666D6E7ADFBAA7F4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="supp6.png" alt="supp6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1652891379"&gt;Service Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Powered Innovations (AI capabilities available in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition only)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1858756398"&gt;Joule for Equipment Details, Summary, History, and Warranty Data&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule helps service managers by providing a &lt;STRONG&gt;360° view&lt;/STRONG&gt; of services performed on equipment. It displays &lt;STRONG&gt;basic equipment details&lt;/STRONG&gt;, such as its description and attached warranties for both customer and vendor. Users can also view the &lt;STRONG&gt;count of active and completed service transactions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, including requests, contracts, orders, and confirmations. Additionally, Joule offers an &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-generated summary&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the services performed on the equipment, highlighting &lt;STRONG&gt;completed, current, and planned services&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;parts replaced&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;recurring issues&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Based on this data, the system also provides &lt;STRONG&gt;recommendations&lt;/STRONG&gt; to optimize service processes and ensure timely maintenance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/service" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#002a86"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Joule for Service&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#002a86"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ser1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326650iB0DCB28EE0AE969B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ser1.png" alt="ser1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1662242893"&gt;Joule for Fetch, Complete, or Cancel Service Confirmation&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule streamlines the service confirmation process by enabling users to &lt;STRONG&gt;fetch service confirmation details&lt;/STRONG&gt; directly from the system. This feature helps service managers easily retrieve confirmation information for any service activities, ensuring accurate tracking of service progress. Additionally, Joule allows users to &lt;STRONG&gt;complete or cancel service confirmations&lt;/STRONG&gt; with ease, helping ensure that service tasks are either marked as finished or appropriately canceled when needed. This capability helps businesses maintain accurate service records, improve efficiency, and enhance overall service management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/fetch-service-confirmation-information?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule for Fetch, Complete or Cancel Service Confirmation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/complete-or-cancel-service-confirmations?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Complete or Cancel Service Confirmations&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1465729388"&gt;Joule for Service Orders&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule enhances service management by allowing users to &lt;STRONG&gt;search and display service orders&lt;/STRONG&gt; efficiently. Service managers can quickly find relevant service orders based on various criteria, enabling faster decision-making and streamlined operations. Additionally, Joule supports the &lt;STRONG&gt;release of service orders and service order items&lt;/STRONG&gt;, simplifying the process of making service orders active and ready for execution. By enabling seamless navigation and control over service orders, Joule helps businesses enhance service delivery and improve operational efficiency, ensuring that service requests are processed on time and accurately.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/search-and-display-service-orders?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule for Service Orders – Search and Display Service Orders&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/release-service-orders-and-service-order-items?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Release Service Orders and Service Order Items&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1269215883"&gt;Managing Service Contracts with Joule&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule simplifies the management of service contracts by providing a copilot that enhances service contract workflows. With Joule, users can &lt;STRONG&gt;create, change, search, and cancel service contracts&lt;/STRONG&gt; efficiently, reducing the time and effort spent on routine tasks. The copilot interface allows service managers to quickly navigate between functionalities and get specific answers on how to use service contracts within SAP S/4HANA. By utilizing natural language requests, users can manage service contract-related tasks seamlessly, making the process more intuitive and improving overall service delivery.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ser2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326656iF92F3047AB1B3AA2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ser2.png" alt="ser2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core functional innovations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1072702378"&gt;Intracompany Logistics for In-House Service Objects&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Intracompany logistics for in-house service objects&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature streamlines the movement and management of service objects across different plants or storage locations within the same company code. It allows users to &lt;STRONG&gt;transfer service objects&lt;/STRONG&gt; seamlessly between plants, making it easier to manage stock and service resources. Customers' stock can also be utilized for in-house service objects, providing flexibility in inventory management. With this feature, service objects can be received with a delivery, and users can define and display plant and storage locations for effective tracking. The process is simplified with a graphical flow, providing better visibility and control over logistics-related documents. Users can also easily choose between customer stock and returns order stock, receiving service objects from customers directly through inbound deliveries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/a0d81b83c82740e2972c41c0213eb8c7.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Intracompany logistics for in-house service objects&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-876188873"&gt;Plant and Storage Location in Service Transactions&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Plant and Storage Location&lt;/STRONG&gt; functionality in service transactions allows users to efficiently manage service operations by specifying the plant and storage location for service objects. It helps ensure that the relevant materials, spare parts, or equipment are properly assigned to service transactions, ensuring smooth service execution. By defining the appropriate plant and storage location, businesses can streamline the process of allocating service resources, ensuring that the right materials are available when needed. This feature provides greater flexibility and control in managing service logistics and optimizes the overall service management process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/6f1d450517cc4c5da542f4f376334dc6.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Plant and Storage Location in Service Transactions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1266481382"&gt;Asset Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Powered Innovations (AI capabilities available in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition only)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-483161863"&gt;Joule for Maintenance Planner and Maintenance Order Management*&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Joule, maintenance planners gain a powerful tool to optimize asset management and maintenance scheduling. By analyzing real-time data, Joule continuously suggests maintenance schedule adjustments, allowing for task reprioritization and improving overall asset health. It uses details from technical objects to automatically create maintenance planning buckets and align them with maintenance events. Planners can easily view upcoming maintenance events, which are already tied to relevant maintenance orders and notifications. Additionally, Joule allows for the assignment of maintenance orders and notifications directly to these events. The system also checks available slots in production planning, ensuring that work center capacities are blocked for any new operations suggested, optimizing the scheduling process and preventing any scheduling conflicts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/perform-maintenance-jobs" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;perform-maintenance-jobs&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;, &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/display-maintenance-orders-and-maintenance-notifications" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Display Maintenance Orders and Maintenance Notifications&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/create-and-view-maintenance-events" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Maintenance Events&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;*Beta Shipment, GA planned&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-286648358"&gt;Enabling Navigation to Scheduling Apps through Joule&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule enhances the user experience by enabling maintenance planners to seamlessly navigate to SAP S/4HANA Asset Management scheduling apps without having to search through the catalog. This integration simplifies access to relevant apps, allowing planners to directly launch resource scheduling (RSH) apps from a natural language request. For example, a simple query like “How to visualize maintenance work” will immediately direct the user to the relevant scheduling app. Additionally, Joule can provide SAP Help documentation within the conversation, offering guidance and support on how to use the scheduling apps effectively, ensuring a more efficient and streamlined workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core functional innovations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-258318544"&gt;Additional Features for the Manage Maintenance Order App&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Maintenance Order&lt;/STRONG&gt; app in SAP S/4HANA has been enhanced with additional features to improve the efficiency of maintenance planning and execution. These features provide maintenance teams with better visibility and control over the order lifecycle. Users can now easily track maintenance orders and their status, ensuring that all relevant details are updated and accessible. The app enables the management of service notifications, the assignment of maintenance tasks to specific work centers, and the ability to adjust scheduling as needed. It also allows users to monitor the progress of maintenance orders, improving decision-making and ensuring timely completion of tasks. These updates streamline maintenance processes and improve asset reliability, ultimately enhancing operational efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/8fd911422730445e9bc337c824554ccc.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Additional Features for the Manage Maintenance Order App&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-61805039"&gt;Spatial Data Explorer: Creating Geo-Objects for Notifications and Orders Based on Phases and Subphases&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The feature allows users to create geo-objects based on the processing context, phase, and sub-phases of business objects such as Maintenance Notifications and Maintenance Orders. This functionality enables the visualization of these notifications and orders on a map according to the new phase model, enhancing the spatial representation of maintenance activities and improving overall operational planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--134708466"&gt;Assigning Person Responsible from the Maintenance Scheduling Board&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature allows maintenance planners to create and manage the assignment of the person responsible directly from the maintenance scheduling board. It enables users to maintain or change personnel assignments within a single app, eliminating the need to navigate to different apps or screens, streamlining the process and improving efficiency in scheduling and task management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-255584043"&gt;Procurement&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Powered Innovations (AI capabilities available in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition only)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--527735476"&gt;AI-Assisted Creation of Purchase Requisitions&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI-assisted creation of purchase requisitions enables procurement teams to streamline their requisition processes by leveraging AI to predict and automate the creation of purchase requisitions. The system analyzes historical data, inventory levels, and demand patterns to generate requisitions for the required materials. By automating this task, businesses can save time, reduce manual errors, and improve procurement efficiency, ensuring that materials are ordered at the right time and in the right quantities. This also supports better inventory management and timely procurement to meet business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/create-purchase-requisitions?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-Assisted Creation of Purchase Requisitions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--724248981"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purchase Order Changes with Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Purchase Order Changes feature in Procurement, powered by Joule, enables users to efficiently manage and modify existing purchase orders. Leveraging the power of AI, Joule assists users in making changes to key details such as delivery dates, quantities, and prices directly from within the purchase order. Joule’s intelligent suggestions help streamline the change process by automatically adjusting related documents and data across the system, ensuring real-time consistency. This functionality helps procurement teams quickly adapt to changes, ensuring smoother operations and improved responsiveness to evolving business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/change-purchase-orders?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Purchase Order Changes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--920762486"&gt;Transfer to Lean Services from MM-SRV&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Transfer to Lean Services from MM-SRV&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature enables the smooth migration of documents from classic MM-SRV (Materials Management for Services) to Lean Services in SAP S/4HANA. This process allows businesses to transition from the traditional service procurement model to the streamlined Lean Services approach. It facilitates the automated conversion of Purchase Orders (PO) and Contracts by mapping them to the corresponding Lean Service document types. If no mapping exists, the system logs an error and skips the affected document, which requires manual follow-up. This functionality supports the migration process, ensuring that the transition from MM-SRV to Lean Services is as efficient and error-free as possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/f52bdc8e66f14c1ab183a88b7bf8d3a2.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Transfer to Lean Services from MM-SRV&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1117275991"&gt;Custom Split Criteria for Central Purchase Contracts&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Split Criteria for Central Purchase Contracts&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature allows businesses to customize central purchase contracts based on document types, either within a specific connected system or across all connected systems. This functionality enables users to activate or deactivate configuration settings as needed. There are two primary options for configuring custom split criteria for central contracts: first, splitting items into single outline agreements (contract or scheduling agreement), and second, splitting central contracts based on custom criteria such as plant or storage location. Additionally, custom fields can be used as criteria to further refine how central contracts are split. This flexibility allows businesses to streamline the distribution process, facilitating easy call-offs by splitting central contracts based on plant and storage location. Furthermore, the use of custom fields to define splitting criteria enhances efficiency and scalability by aligning with specific business requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A target="_new" rel="noopener"&gt;Custom Split Criteria for Central Purchase Contracts&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--726983482"&gt;Manufacturing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core functional innovations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1510303001"&gt;Using the New Accept MRP Result Button&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The "Accept MRP Result" button allows material planners to flag individual segments as processed in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Material Coverage&lt;/STRONG&gt; app when a problem cannot be resolved or when the production planner decides not to address the issue. This functionality includes a new filter field in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Monitor Material Coverage&lt;/STRONG&gt; app for easier tracking, and also provides the option to "Revoke MRP result" if the planner wants to reconsider a previous decision. By implementing this feature, MRP controllers can work more efficiently, particularly when managing material coverage issues for around 3,000 materials between two MRP runs per day, streamlining decision-making and improving overall productivity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/3720a102615c4e409d545c039c60837d.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using the new Accept MRP Result button&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1538632815"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Transaction Events (BTE) During an MRP Live Run&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Transaction Events (BTE) in MRP Live&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature enables materials relevant for SAP Integrated Business Planning (SAP IBP) or Production Planning and Detailed Scheduling (PP/DS) integration to be planned using MRP live, followed by triggering BTEs for documents created during post-processing. Previously, BTEs were not supported in MRP live for such materials, meaning even when MRP Live was used, the planning was handled in classic ABAP mode. With this update, BTE events are now triggered during the MRP Live run, improving performance by avoiding unnecessary data transfers between the database and application server. A new field, &lt;STRONG&gt;Planning for IBP/PPDS Material&lt;/STRONG&gt;, has been introduced in the transaction &lt;STRONG&gt;PPHMRPSET&lt;/STRONG&gt;, allowing users to select the planning mode for materials in IBP/PPDS integration. This provides two options: &lt;STRONG&gt;In HANA Live&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where material planning is executed using SQL-script procedures, and &lt;STRONG&gt;In MRP Classic&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where planning and BTE triggering are done using ABAP logic. By default, the value is set to "In MRP Classic," but selecting "In HANA Live" enables this feature. Notably, materials with &lt;STRONG&gt;MRP Type X0&lt;/STRONG&gt; will still use classic MRP and remain unaffected by this setting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/2278cd20aacc4fa99aa4dcefc5be0a82.html?version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Transaction Events in MRP Live&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1735146320"&gt;New App: Adjust Fill Levels&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Adjust Fill Levels&lt;/STRONG&gt; app allows warehouse managers to maintain the correct stock levels by adjusting the fill level of containers based on real-time data. This ensures optimal inventory control and avoids issues related to under- or overstocking. The app enables users to update the fill levels for packaging materials or transport containers, ensuring accurate stock information is available for efficient operations. By providing an easy-to-use interface for adjusting these levels, it helps businesses maintain efficient warehouse operations and avoid unnecessary stock discrepancies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/d2d0c92b8b8b45b3b9221541e1b9b685.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;New App: Adjust Fill Levels&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1931659825"&gt;Ability to Create Shop Floor Order for Repair &amp;amp; Parallel Sequences in Routing&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The ability to create a shop floor order for repairs based on rework BOM and shop floor routing allows businesses to manage product repairs or rework activities efficiently. It enables the creation of BOMs and shop floor routings tailored for part repairs, facilitating the creation of shop floor orders for these repair activities. These orders can be adjusted to modify operational activities or components as needed. By enabling repairs for parts that may need rework due to damage, maintenance, or upgrades, businesses can streamline the process for managing completed production orders that require engineering changes or replacement of defective parts. Additionally, the ability to create parallel sequences in shop floor routing empowers production engineers to plan and execute operations simultaneously within the same routing. This flexibility reduces production time, optimizes resource utilization, and supports varied manufacturing scenarios, improving both efficiency and adaptability in production planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/4bd03a9eb3484f629265efda502f02b0.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Ability to Create Shop Floor Order for Repair Based on Rework BOM and Shop Floor Routing&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/c3093dba0d794722b79ac5569fb2eadc.html?version=LATEST&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating Parallel Sequences in Shop Floor Routing&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--2128173330"&gt;Managing Master Manufacturing BOM &amp;amp; Shop Floor Routing for Unitized Material&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The "Manage Production Model-Materials" app enables users to create or edit production models for unitized materials, incorporating both the manufacturing bill of materials (MBOM) and shop floor routing in a single workflow. This approach simplifies the management of both MBOM and shop floor routing, providing a unified view for handling unitized products. By consolidating these elements into one app, businesses reduce the risk of errors and enhance the overall oversight of production processes, improving efficiency and accuracy in managing unitized material production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/c29d5abc6fab4a61910464e1276fbd50.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Production Model-Materials&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1737880821"&gt;R &amp;amp; D and Engineering&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1773766956"&gt;EPPM: Intelligent Project Assistant Capabilities with Joule&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The intelligent project assistant capabilities in Joule enhance user experience by enabling users to retrieve project-related information through natural language processing, eliminating the need to manually open applications. This feature supports a range of tasks, including informational, navigational, and transactional capabilities, such as easily finding and opening apps to display project data. Users can get real-time updates on project changes, missing parts, or overdue activities directly within Joule, and open projects, WBS elements, or networks for viewing or editing through the Project Builder or dedicated object pages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/read-due-or-overdue-activities-in-project-wbs-element-network?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Project Assistant Capabilities for the Joule Copilot&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1577253451"&gt;Joule Support for Bill of Materials&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule, powered by natural language AI, enhances user interaction by supporting both navigational and transactional scenarios for Bill of Materials (BoM). Users can easily access header information for BoMs and query specific BoMs based on material-plant combinations. Additionally, Joule simplifies the process of selecting and opening relevant BoMs directly in the appropriate application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/fetch-bill-of-material-information?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Support for Bill of Materials&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1380739946"&gt;Joule Support for Change Record&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule, the natural language AI assistant, enhances the change record process by supporting both navigational and transactional scenarios. It simplifies the user experience by enabling access to general information about specific change records or groups of change records, at both the header and item levels. Joule also allows users to summarize change records, including descriptions, texts, and included entities, while facilitating the identification of overdue change records and enabling status changes. By offering a streamlined way to find similar records based on criteria like product, description, relevance, and reason for change, Joule accelerates the change process and ensures compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A target="_new" rel="noopener"&gt;Joule Support for Change Record&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1184226441"&gt;Links Between Change Records in SAP PLM&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature in SAP PLM provides enhanced transparency on changes by allowing users to link change records. It enables the definition of possible relationships between different change records, helping to document dependencies or relations for each record. For example, if change record types like problem reports and change requests are configured in the system, users can create a "resolved by" link between a problem report and the engineering change request that resolves it. This functionality ensures compliance with change management processes, while improving traceability and transparency through clear documentation of relationships and dependencies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A target="_new" rel="noopener"&gt;Links Between Change Records&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-987712936"&gt;EPPM: Simplified Object-Based Authorizations for Project System&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new feature for simplified object-based authorizations in the Project System helps to streamline and optimize authorization management for projects and related objects such as WBS elements and networks. It simplifies the maintenance process of object-based authorizations and enhances system performance during the evaluation of these authorizations. This ensures faster and more efficient authorization checks for project-related activities, enabling project managers and users to focus on their tasks without delays in access control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/open-project-wbs-element-and-networks-in-object-pages-or-project-builder-application?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Simplified Object-Based Authorizations for Project System&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1546189136"&gt;Product Compliance&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-762869617"&gt;Compliance Assessment Using Documents for Evaluation of Articles&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature supports compliance for discrete industries by leveraging up-to-date content, such as substance lists and assessments, to evaluate the marketability of products based on regulations like the Restriction of Hazardous Substances (RoHS) directive. Manufacturers can use this capability to ensure that their products comply with regulatory requirements, which is crucial for maintaining marketability in regulated markets. The key benefits include the ability to use embedded regulatory content for decision-making, view the aggregated compliance status of purchased components, collect and consolidate compliance documents, and access market assessments from logistics processes. Additionally, this feature ensures auditable storage of compliance information for product marketability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more info here: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/d85f1e60b89143e3967dd20dd7a6924d.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Compliance Assessment Using Documents for Evaluation of Articles&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-566356112"&gt;Supporting Multi-Component Products for Safety Data Sheet Process&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature enables the ability to send safety data sheets (SDS) for multiple components of a product simultaneously, streamlining the compliance process. By supporting multi-component products, businesses can ensure that all relevant components are covered under safety data sheet regulations at once, enhancing the overall efficiency of regulatory compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-369842607"&gt;Automated Enclosure Variant Suggestions for Packaged Dangerous Goods&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature automatically suggests the appropriate enclosure variants for packaged dangerous goods based on the selected UN-certified packaging, such as Intermediate Bulk Containers (IBC), Large Packaging (LP), UN Bulk Containers, or UN Portable Tanks. It also improves the configuration table for "Specify Descriptions of Dangerous Goods Packages," enhancing how enclosure variants and intermediate packaging are determined. This streamlined process simplifies the data maintenance for dangerous goods regulatory information, ensuring greater accuracy and compliance with packaging regulations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-173329102"&gt;Business Add-In to Complete Safety Data Sheet Generation&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature allows businesses to upload base Safety Data Sheets (SDS), such as raw reports generated by the classic SAP Product Safety application, into the SDS management solution using the Safety Data Sheet Assessment public API. It offers the flexibility to choose the method for final SDS generation, such as utilizing the classic functionality with a business add-in. By integrating these capabilities with SAP S/4HANA for product compliance, the process enhances efficiency and ensures seamless integration with legacy systems, while improving the overall SDS management workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration of Dangerous Goods Mixed Loading Checks in Sales, Delivery, and Transportation Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This feature integrates dangerous goods mixed loading checks throughout the value chain, including sales orders, outbound deliveries, and freight units, orders, and bookings. By enforcing these checks, businesses can ensure that dangerous goods are loaded and transported in compliance with safety regulations. This prevents the execution of noncompliant transports, helping organizations avoid costly penalties and potential safety risks associated with improper handling of dangerous goods.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-563621611"&gt;Business-Ready Data for Smarter Decisions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A key enabler in this release is the integration with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which provides a governed and harmonized data layer across SAP and third-party systems. This unified foundation supports planning, analytics, and AI use cases—ensuring that business teams can work with trusted, real-time data across processes. Check here: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/b83121ecbc49454d80abcd36e55d6e60.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;integration with SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The release also delivers a growing portfolio of &lt;STRONG&gt;data products&lt;/STRONG&gt; tailored to specific business domains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Billing and Invoicing&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Data products for billing requests and documents support near-real-time dashboards and analytics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Financial Operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Contract accounting data products enable deeper insights into provider contracts and accounting documents.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subscription Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Subscription-related data products help track orders, contracts, and agreements for recurring revenue scenarios.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manufacturing Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Unified data for production orders, confirmations, and work centers helps optimize shop floor operations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consult our&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/4d82c97578ab4e33be28f60a2163a4c6.html?advPhr=data+products" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product Lifecycle&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Enhanced data products for BOMs and engineering changes support better product and change management.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information, click&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/c4aa65d50a7342f0a7b5d5a8b0ebbb5d.html?advPhr=data+products" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For a full overview of available data products, visit the &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/dataproducts" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Thank you for engaging with this blog post—your attention is truly appreciated!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1252814904" id="toc-hId-73705099"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register for the SAP Business Suite Product Expert Training 2025!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Business Suite Product Expert Training&amp;nbsp;is a biannual multi-day event designed to empower partners with in-depth knowledge of the latest features and AI-driven innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Join this event to maximize customer success and stay ahead of the rapidly evolving digital landscape.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;From&amp;nbsp;October 6-17, we cover&amp;nbsp;SAP Cloud ERP, Cloud LoB, and SAP SCM&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;From&amp;nbsp;October 27-31, we cover&amp;nbsp;SAP Cloud ERP Private, Cloud LoB, and SAP SCM&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Check out the detailed agenda on this&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/sap-s-4hana-product-expert-training" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;landing page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and register now. Please take into consideration that the registration is available for partners and internal SAP employees only.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For more information on SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition, check out the following links:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/s4hana-private-edition.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition release info&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/5fc51e30e2744f168642e26e0c1d9be1?Product_Line=SAP+S/4HANA;SAP+S/4HANA+and+SAP+S/4HANA+Cloud+Private+Edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What`s New Viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/what-s-new-for-joule-capabilities?version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What`s New for Joule Capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73554900100800000266&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73555000100800004663" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Roadmap Explorer for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://chart-bdmaicr0au.dispatcher.eu2.hana.ondemand.com/index.html?hc_reset" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA PSCC Digital Enablement Wheel&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-055/2022?region=DE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Best practices for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feel free to drop a kudo if you liked this blog post. Don’t hesitate to leave a comment and check out our&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/s4hana" target="_blank"&gt;new community page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to ask your questions and engage with the experts. Follow the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/PSCC_Enablement/tg-p/board-id/erp-blog-sap" target="_blank"&gt;PSCC_Enablement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tag to stay up to date with our latest blog posts. Looking forward to the next release!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow us on&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://twitter.com/sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@SAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and #S4HANA, and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stay connected with me on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/harishmangtani/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@LinkedinHarish&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://twitter.com/HarryMangtani" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@twitterHarryMangtani&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-erp-private-2025-fps0-release-highlights-part-1/ba-p/14236762"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:23:02.170000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/story-reports-combine-holiday-and-timesheet-data-without-a-direct-query/qaq-p/14242272</id>
    <title>Story Reports – Combine Holiday and Timesheet data without a direct query relationship</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:23:10.270000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>skusulja</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/176283</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am building a monthly Timesheet Story Report in SAP SuccessFactors Report Center, based on the Recorded Time Data (V2) query.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Goal:&lt;BR /&gt;Generate a monthly timesheet per employee, showing all attendance and absence types — with columns such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Date&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start Time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;End Time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quantity in hours&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Time Type (working time, vacation, sick leave, holiday, etc.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Problem:&lt;BR /&gt;The Recorded Time Data (V2) table does not contain entries for public holidays.&lt;BR /&gt;The Holiday data exists separately and can only be reached through the User → Employee Information → Job Information path.&lt;BR /&gt;However, when trying to connect those datasets in Story Reports, the query expands uncontrollably — generating huge amounts of redundant data, to the point where nothing meaningful can be displayed or analyzed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have checked all other available query tables and possible combinations — there are no tables that can directly connect or combine both employee timesheet (Recorded Time Data) and holiday information in a way that provides usable, consistent data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additional context:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No Time Tracking license → cannot use Time Valuations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Absence Counting Configuration is not useful for this case.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;I only need this for reporting (not payroll integration).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Questions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is there any supported way to bring Recorded Time Data (V2) and Holiday data together into the same Story Report?&lt;BR /&gt;For example, can this be achieved if I add both tables as two separate data sources, where the only common field between them is the Date column (without any direct relationship through Employee or Job Information)?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can I use any formula or calculated column in Recorded Time Data to identify or return Holiday dates?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any ideas, workarounds, or model design suggestions would be highly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/story-reports-combine-holiday-and-timesheet-data-without-a-direct-query/qaq-p/14242272"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:23:10.270000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/need-guidance-on-bank-reconciliation/qaa-p/14242273#M4229292</id>
    <title>Re: Need guidance on Bank reconciliation</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:23:32.237000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMMED_BASER</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253375</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Nithin,&lt;BR /&gt;Yes, you are correct. Please find the steps for Bank Reconciliation in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud (Simplified Flow).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Set Up House Bank and Bank Accounts&lt;BR /&gt;Use the Manage Bank Accounts Fiori app.&lt;BR /&gt;Define House Bank &amp;amp; Bank Account (linked to a G/L account of type Cash Account with subtype B – Bank Reconciliation Account)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Create G/L Accounts&lt;BR /&gt;Create main bank reconciliation account (Subtype B) and Bank Subaccounts (Subtype S) for incoming/outgoing payments.&lt;BR /&gt;These are defined using the Manage G/L Account Master Data app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Configure Bank Statement Processing&lt;BR /&gt;Use the Manage Automatic Bank Statement Rules app.&lt;BR /&gt;Define external transaction codes (e.g., NTRF, NCHK) and Posting rules that map to G/L accounts&lt;BR /&gt;(It is the replacement of OT83/OT52 from on-premises.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Import Bank Statements&lt;BR /&gt;Use Import Bank Statements app to upload MT940 or CAMT.053 files. You can alternatively, set up Bank Communication Management for automatic uploads.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5. Monitor and Process Statements&lt;BR /&gt;Use Reprocess Bank Statement Items or Postprocess Bank Statement Items apps.&lt;BR /&gt;System auto-clears matched items.&lt;BR /&gt;Unmatched items can be manually assigned or posted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;6. Clear Open Items&lt;BR /&gt;Use Clear Bank Subaccounts or Manage Journal Entries to manually clear if needed.&lt;BR /&gt;Ensure all subaccounts are reconciled with the main bank account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;7. Review Reconciliation Reports&lt;BR /&gt;Use Cash Flow Analyzer or Bank Statement Monitor for visibility.&lt;BR /&gt;Confirm balances match between SAP and actual bank.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope it will help you&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/need-guidance-on-bank-reconciliation/qaa-p/14242273#M4229292"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:23:32.237000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/user-status-profiles-the-key-to-effective-maintenance-order-management/bc-p/14242275#M72127</id>
    <title>Re: User Status Profiles: The Key to Effective Maintenance Order Management</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:23:54.765000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yunuskhaji</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2164289</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2971"&gt;@RAHEEL_BABAR&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;@Thank you&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have some requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Can we use user status to prevent to add material in maintenance order.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. After doing TECO of order, it is still allowing to change the user status. Can we set greyed out the field.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/user-status-profiles-the-key-to-effective-maintenance-order-management/bc-p/14242275#M72127"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:23:54.765000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/stay-current-with-sap-successfactors-performance-and-goal-management-2h/bc-p/14242277#M7216</id>
    <title>Re: Stay Current with SAP SuccessFactors Performance and Goal Management: 2H 2025 Updates</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:25:39.853000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rama3</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1451421</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you for the detail explanation on the 2H 2025 update&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/stay-current-with-sap-successfactors-performance-and-goal-management-2h/bc-p/14242277#M7216"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:25:39.853000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sending-emails-from-sac/qaa-p/14242282#M4929093</id>
    <title>Re: Sending emails from SAC</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:27:42.326000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ilsevg1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1876069</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thnaks, the problem is that the server is not setup’</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sending-emails-from-sac/qaa-p/14242282#M4929093"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:27:42.326000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sending-emails-from-sac/qaa-p/14242287#M4929094</id>
    <title>Re: Sending emails from SAC</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:28:29.063000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ilsevg1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1876069</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks a lot, the issue was the server was not set up properly.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sending-emails-from-sac/qaa-p/14242287#M4929094"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:28:29.063000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/configuration-of-fiori-app-state-for-sharing/ba-p/14240470</id>
    <title>Configuration of Fiori app state for sharing</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:29:01.636000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hironobu_nakayama</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/781777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1633599875"&gt;1. Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;When using Fiori apps in business settings, users often enter search conditions such as specific date ranges or company codes, adjust the order of lists, and then share the app URL with other users via the “Share” button—either by email or chat. However, when the recipient opens the shared URL, the filters may be reset or the sorting order may revert, so the sender’s screen cannot be reproduced. This behavior occurs when accessing from different browsers (e.g., Chrome to Edge), different devices (PC to smartphone), or different sessions. As a result, the recipient may have to ask for the filter conditions again or manually restore the conditions by comparing with screenshots, which can slow down reviews, approvals, or troubleshooting. The cause of this issue lies in the default settings of Fiori Launchpad. By default, the application state (such as filters, sorting, and pagination) is stored in the browser’s temporary storage, so simply sharing the URL will not reflect the filter conditions and other settings. Therefore, even if you open the URL in a different environment, the information saved in the sender’s browser is not referenced, and even if the “sap-iapp-state” parameter is included in the URL, the screen cannot be reproduced. This blog introduces how to configure the system so that information such as filter conditions and table column order can be shared across different browsers or devices.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_0-1760099721811.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325599i8A78D03E4EE9394F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_0-1760099721811.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_0-1760099721811.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1437086370"&gt;2. Mechanism for Sharing App State&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The state of the app is managed by Application State data. Application State data is the "app appearance and filtering state" in Fiori Launchpad.This is the data that handles the data. When a user sets filter conditions or adjusts the order and display columns of the table, the state is recorded as a collective "snapshot" and restored later. For apps that use Fiori elements and SmartFilterBar, the app state is stored and loaded through this Application State data. The Fiori app uses the reference key ("sap-iapp-state" parameter) given to the URL to reproduce the state of the app. The handling method of Application State data in Fiori Launchpad is defined in the Launchpad configuration parameter: APPSTATE_TRANSIENT, and the following two types of parameters are provided.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;true (default)&lt;P&gt;It is a method of maintaining state in a temporary area in the browser (transient). Only the same browser and the same session are maintained, so they cannot be reproduced in different browsers or devices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;false&lt;P&gt;Save the state of the app on the front-end server. Therefore, it is possible to refer to the data stored on the front-end server, allowing the app to be reproduced across different browsers and devices.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1240572865"&gt;3. How to set it up&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In one of the following transactions, set the Launchpad configuration parameter: APPSTATE_TRANSIENT (value: true / false).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;T-cd: /UI2/FLP_CUS_CONF(For client-dependent settings)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;T-cd: /UI2/FLP_SYS_CONF(For client-independent settings)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_1-1760100174572.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325602i970BBAE86C2B35AF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_1-1760100174572.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_1-1760100174572.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1044059360"&gt;4. Notes&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Launchpad configuration parameters: If the APPSTATE_TRANSIENT is set to false, the Application State data is stored on the server, so regular cleanup is required in terms of server load and performance. Data cleanup can be performed from Cleanup Layered Repository Files (T-cd: /UIF/CLEAN_LREP). The cleanup run requires the following parameter settings: (You can't access the cleaned up Application State data.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maximum number of times read：The maximum number of accesses to the Application State data to be deleted (If set to 0, data that has never been accessed is included.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Minimum number of days not accessed：The minimum number of days since the last access (if set to 30, data that has not been accessed in 30 days is eligible.)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_4-1760100765266.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325606iCB2CC919D7D0AD22/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_4-1760100765266.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_4-1760100765266.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information:&amp;nbsp;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/a7b390faab1140c087b8926571e942b7/ffb437e68f464478bbd723ca144a22d7.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cleanup of Expired Application State&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-847545855"&gt;5. Summary&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Launchpad configuration parameters: You can set the APPSTATE_TRANSIENT to false to share the state of the app (filter criteria, sorting, pagination, etc.) between different browsers and devices. On the other hand, if the APPSTATE_TRANSIENT is set to false, the Application State data is stored on the server, which requires regular cleanup in terms of server load and performance.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_3-1760100497133.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325605iB73824D0CEDF51C9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_3-1760100497133.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_3-1760100497133.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-651032350"&gt;6. References&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/a7b390faab1140c087b8926571e942b7/6107ee41f89a43c9af0aa279fe039cca.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Launchpad Configuration Parameters&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP KBA: &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3260742" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3260742 - Fiori appstate is not persisted across browser sessions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Help: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/a7b390faab1140c087b8926571e942b7/ffb437e68f464478bbd723ca144a22d7.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cleanup of Expired Application State&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/configuration-of-fiori-app-state-for-sharing/ba-p/14240470"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:29:01.636000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/want-to-earn-more-badges-let-s-discuss/bc-p/14242290#M929</id>
    <title>Re: Want to Earn More Badges? Let’s Discuss!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:29:19.980000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>carlbidwell</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2258733</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great topic! I would love to see a structured thread where people share which badges have been most valuable (for visibility, credibility, etc.) and how exactly they earned them (tips, strategies). That would make this discussion even more actionable for everyone.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/want-to-earn-more-badges-let-s-discuss/bc-p/14242290#M929"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:29:19.980000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/file-upload-for-items-in-fiori-elements-list-report/ba-p/14240957</id>
    <title>File upload for items in Fiori Elements List Report</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:30:19.100000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hironobu_nakayama</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/781777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1633604625"&gt;1. Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we'll show you how to upload, browse, and delete files on a row-by-line basis by having each row (item) have an item like an "attachment" in the SAP Fiori Elements List Report.&lt;BR /&gt;The data source for the List Report covers OData V4 services developed using the ABAP RESTful Application Programming Model (RAP) framework, and provides information about the implementation required to achieve file upload in RAP development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1437091120"&gt;2. Key points for implementing file upload&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the file upload implementation, two points are required: (1) define the table items required for file storage, and (2) provide appropriate annotations for file object storage fields and file type storage fields.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Defining the table items required to store files&lt;P&gt;Set the following three fields in the custom table (the field names are samples).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;File object storage field (abap.rawstring(0) if file size is not specified)&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;example：attachment: abap.rawstring(0);&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Field for file name&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;example：filename: abap.char(128);&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Field for file Type&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;example：mimetype: abap.char(128);&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Proper Annotation of File Object and File Type Fields in CDS View&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;File object storage field&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;example：&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@Semantics.largeObject : {
mimeType: 'Mimetype',
fileName: 'Filename',
contentDispositionPreference: #INLINE
}​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Field for file Type&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;@Semantics.mimeType: true&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1240577615"&gt;3. Implementation sample&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we will use the RAP Generator to simplify RAP development. RAP Generator is a tool that allows you to generate RAP objects such as CDS View and Behavior Definition from custom tables using only wizard settings. When using the RAP Generator to generate a RAP object, a service is generated that supports the Managed Runtime with a draft function. Therefore, the table definition must define the required fields for drafting functions and update processing. For more information about RAP Generator, please check the following SAP Help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-rap/generating-rap-business-service-with-generate-abap-repository-objects-wizard" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Generating a RAP Business Service with the Generate ABAP Repository Objects Wizards&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog is an example implementation based on the &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/abap-cloud/abap-rap/example-rap-business-service-generation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Example: OData UI Service Generation Based on a Database Table&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1302229548"&gt;1. Create a package to store objects by the RAP Generator.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_0-1760157013761.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325823iFF67EF8A7D119B10/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_0-1760157013761.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_0-1760157013761.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105716043"&gt;2. Create a custom table inside the package you created in 1.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_1-1760157057491.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325824i82D4DF7B553C56CD/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_1-1760157057491.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_1-1760157057491.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_2-1760157071905.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325825i0DDC00E4250B93BB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_2-1760157071905.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_2-1760157071905.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@EndUserText.label : 'Custom Table for file upload test'
@AbapCatalog.enhancement.category : #NOT_EXTENSIBLE
@AbapCatalog.tableCategory : #TRANSPARENT
@AbapCatalog.deliveryClass : #A
@AbapCatalog.dataMaintenance : #RESTRICTED
define table zpt_file_upload {

  key client            : abap.clnt not null;
  key customer_id       : /dmo/customer_id not null;
  first_name            : /dmo/first_name;
  last_name             : /dmo/last_name;
  title                 : /dmo/title;
  street                : /dmo/street;
  postal_code           : /dmo/postal_code;
  city                  : /dmo/city;
  country_code          : land1;
  phone_number          : /dmo/phone_number;
  email_address         : /dmo/email_address;
  attachment            : abap.rawstring(0);
  filename              : abap.char(128);
  mimetype              : abap.char(128);
  local_created_by      : abp_creation_user;
  local_created_at      : abp_creation_tstmpl;
  local_last_changed_by : abp_locinst_lastchange_user;
  local_last_changed_at : abp_locinst_lastchange_tstmpl;
  last_changed_at       : abp_lastchange_tstmpl;

}​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-909202538"&gt;3. Run the RAP Generator and follow the wizard to configure it.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Right-click on the target custom table → run it with "Generate ABAP Repository Objects..."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_3-1760157422206.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325826iC928155A8BCFAE9E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_3-1760157422206.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_3-1760157422206.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selecting a Service Type&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_4-1760157441952.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325827iF0BB085AA624F8A4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_4-1760157441952.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_4-1760157441952.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selecting a package for storing generated objects&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_5-1760157464387.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325828iCA1BEBBB2C283DDC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_5-1760157464387.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_5-1760157464387.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Review the generated object and rename or alias it as needed&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_6-1760157482071.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325829i0F2526AA45703F9D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_6-1760157482071.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_6-1760157482071.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_7-1760157495656.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325830i9C6952F5528E2BD6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_7-1760157495656.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_7-1760157495656.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-712689033"&gt;4. Add annotations for file upload to the generated data model (CDS View) and enable the CDS View.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@AccessControl.authorizationCheck: #CHECK
@EndUserText.label: '##GENERATED ZPT_FILE_UPLOAD'
define root view entity ZR_PT_FILE_UPLOAD
  as select from zpt_file_upload
{
  key customer_id           as CustomerID,
      first_name            as FirstName,
      last_name             as LastName,
      title                 as Title,
      street                as Street,
      postal_code           as PostalCode,
      city                  as City,
      country_code          as CountryCode,
      phone_number          as PhoneNumber,
      email_address         as EmailAddress,
      @Semantics.largeObject : {
            mimeType: 'Mimetype',
            fileName: 'Filename',
            contentDispositionPreference: #INLINE
          }
      attachment            as Attachment,
      filename              as Filename,
      @Semantics.mimeType: true
      mimetype              as Mimetype,
      @Semantics.user.createdBy: true
      local_created_by      as LocalCreatedBy,
      @Semantics.systemDateTime.createdAt: true
      local_created_at      as LocalCreatedAt,
      @Semantics.user.localInstanceLastChangedBy: true
      local_last_changed_by as LocalLastChangedBy,
      @Semantics.systemDateTime.localInstanceLastChangedAt: true
      local_last_changed_at as LocalLastChangedAt,
      @Semantics.systemDateTime.lastChangedAt: true
      last_changed_at       as LastChangedAt

}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-516175528"&gt;5. Publish the service binding.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_8-1760157523686.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325831i4F5DCB4410845F5A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_8-1760157523686.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_8-1760157523686.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-319662023"&gt;6. Select the entity and preview it.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_9-1760157563744.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325832iC927D9BEF8566E34/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_9-1760157563744.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_9-1760157563744.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-123148518"&gt;7. From the "Create" button, perform data registration and file upload.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_10-1760157593131.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325833i2D10826CA744794B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_10-1760157593131.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_10-1760157593131.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_11-1760157628831.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325834iCBF6028E63ADA10C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_11-1760157628831.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_11-1760157628831.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_12-1760157647311.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325835iC7286B9648C140C7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_12-1760157647311.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_12-1760157647311.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_13-1760157663896.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325836i33B8FE451D47FCBE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_13-1760157663896.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_13-1760157663896.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_14-1760157681275.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325837i22D13F546974AC37/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_14-1760157681275.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_14-1760157681275.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_15-1760157702526.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325838iBABEDFAC843FB59D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_15-1760157702526.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_15-1760157702526.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hironobu_nakayama_16-1760157721073.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325839i9A80962EABEC37F9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hironobu_nakayama_16-1760157721073.png" alt="hironobu_nakayama_16-1760157721073.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-438209658"&gt;4. Summary&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;By implementing the above, using the OData V4 service using the ABAP RESTful Application Programming Model (RAP), you can use the "Attachment" for each row (item) in the SAP Fiori Elements List Report. It is possible to upload, read, and delete files on a line-by-line basis. Please take advantage of it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-241696153"&gt;References&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAPUI5 Document: &lt;A href="https://sapui5.hana.ondemand.com/#/topic/b236d32d48b74304887b3dd5163548c1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Enabling Stream Support&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/file-upload-for-items-in-fiori-elements-list-report/ba-p/14240957"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:30:19.100000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-access-design-develop-and-manage-apis-after-completing/qaq-p/14242308</id>
    <title>Unable to Access “Design, Develop, and Manage APIs” After Completing Integration Suite Booster</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:36:14.437000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nayan106</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2259479</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m currently going through the SAP Integration Suite onboarding tutorials. I successfully completed all the steps in the &lt;STRONG&gt;“Enable the SAP Integration Suite”&lt;/STRONG&gt; booster, and the process completed with a success message.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, when I moved to the next tutorial: &lt;STRONG&gt;“Create an API Provider System”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, I got stuck at &lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which asks to open the &lt;STRONG&gt;API Management Portal&lt;/STRONG&gt; via &lt;STRONG&gt;“Design, Develop, and Manage APIs”&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s what I have already tried:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Verified Integration Suite is subscribed in my BTP subaccount&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tried re-opening via the “Go to Application” button&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cleared cache and tried Incognito mode&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Waited for some time in case it was a delay&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Checked tutorials again, but couldn't find what might be missing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I also tried searching the community and SAP Help, but couldn’t find a clear solution for this specific issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone faced a similar problem or can guide me on how to enable API Management properly so I can proceed with creating an API Provider?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/unable-to-access-design-develop-and-manage-apis-after-completing/qaq-p/14242308"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:36:14.437000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/f5104-no-master-record-was-created-in-company-code-quot-1993-quot-for/qaa-p/14242317#M4229293</id>
    <title>Re: F5104 No master record was created in company code "1993" for vendor number "4012</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:39:28.517000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Raphy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1494457</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello Dominik</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/f5104-no-master-record-was-created-in-company-code-quot-1993-quot-for/qaa-p/14242317#M4229293"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:39:28.517000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/f5104-no-master-record-was-created-in-company-code-quot-1993-quot-for/qaa-p/14242320#M4229294</id>
    <title>Re: F5104 No master record was created in company code "1993" for vendor number "4012</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:40:15.548000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Raphy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1494457</uri>
    </author>
    <content>How intercompany code transactions</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/f5104-no-master-record-was-created-in-company-code-quot-1993-quot-for/qaa-p/14242320#M4229294"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:40:15.548000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/start-your-scripting-journey-the-easy-way-with-sap-analytics-cloud-part/bc-p/14242324#M185335</id>
    <title>Re: Start Your scripting Journey The Easy Way With SAP Analytics Cloud | Part Four</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:42:10.573000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>muddassar91</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/796420</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Daniel,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you post some real complex requirements scripting based stuff on real time scenarios. Yours initial posts are really helpful and I appreciate it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you can create and post few more scenarios then it might be more helpful.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;shaik&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/start-your-scripting-journey-the-easy-way-with-sap-analytics-cloud-part/bc-p/14242324#M185335"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:42:10.573000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/characteristics-of-business-partner-through-classification/ba-p/14242328</id>
    <title>Characteristics of Business Partner Through Classification</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:44:38.310000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>muhammad_waseem</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/805493</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Business Partner screens in S4HANA allows to maintain various kind of information at diferent views, for example, General view, Company code view, Purchasing Organization view, Employee view etc. Under each level, you have certain tab groups and fields therein.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, you cannot maintain information that is non-standard format, comprising of custom attributes as per business needs, and especially in vast structured quantity. Here, the question is, does S4HANA offers any standard solution to maintain such structured data in a delicate way?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Answer is, Yes, certainly SAP has incorporated a standard functionality which offers to maintain even large size of data at&amp;nbsp;granularity level. And, its not just limited to Business Partner Master, you can do same in Material master and Equipment master too. In all places, we have one common function to approach the solution, that is, the Classification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's explore in detail, for Business Partner:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business comes up with a requirement to maintain BP master with certain data categroized in hierarchy and grouping. User require to maintain this data at BP Role level where role can either be standard or custom one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's say the data is in following shape:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Main Category: Civil&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sub-category:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;-&amp;nbsp;Infrastructural&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;-&amp;nbsp;Concrete&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;-&amp;nbsp;Precast Concrete&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Block&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lets construct the solution design, step-by-step:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Create Characteristics – &lt;STRONG&gt;CT04&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_0-1760351134308.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326670i7871737CA78F1AD8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_0-1760351134308.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_0-1760351134308.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Input the Characteristic ID&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_1-1760351191936.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326672i2716EC470650842E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_1-1760351191936.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_1-1760351191936.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_2-1760351205699.png" style="width: 28px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326673i6E31F0889304925B/image-dimensions/28x30/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="28" height="30" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_2-1760351205699.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_2-1760351205699.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;button,&amp;nbsp;and enter the Description&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_3-1760351245288.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326674i74965851ADC321B4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_3-1760351245288.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_3-1760351245288.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now select the Data Type CHAR&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_4-1760351265895.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326675i1F8771EFD352F1A7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_4-1760351265895.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_4-1760351265895.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the number of characters for Characteristic, and also values&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_5-1760351286446.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326676i1EA2210B7AA5157D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_5-1760351286446.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_5-1760351286446.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now go to tab&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_6-1760351301030.png" style="width: 81px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326678i68984CEA9A11E1B1/image-dimensions/81x29/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="81" height="29" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_6-1760351301030.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_6-1760351301030.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here assign all the required values for characteristics&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_7-1760351341909.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326679i07598F4F80DF73AE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_7-1760351341909.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_7-1760351341909.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Save the data,&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_8-1760351357957.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326680iA5F392AFC68D025D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_8-1760351357957.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_8-1760351357957.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, according to the hierarchy, let's design the sub-category, the same way:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Create Characteristics – &lt;STRONG&gt;CT04&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_10-1760351468960.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326682i2888E9EB93647ED5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_10-1760351468960.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_10-1760351468960.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Input the Characteristic ID&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_11-1760351495421.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326683i038FD84374E7B748/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_11-1760351495421.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_11-1760351495421.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_12-1760351510252.png" style="width: 35px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326684iF72782400E0744D3/image-dimensions/35x38/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="35" height="38" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_12-1760351510252.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_12-1760351510252.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;button, and enter the Description&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_13-1760351540339.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326685i82AFCAFEFC2D3606/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_13-1760351540339.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_13-1760351540339.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now select the Data Type CHAR&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_14-1760351556516.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326686i25C9619789F879FD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_14-1760351556516.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_14-1760351556516.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Specify the number of characters for Characteristic, and also values&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_15-1760351577327.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326688i020ADE8A84B2C334/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_15-1760351577327.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_15-1760351577327.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now go to tab&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_16-1760351594211.png" style="width: 72px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326689iA44C540F76D3EFA2/image-dimensions/72x26/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="72" height="26" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_16-1760351594211.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_16-1760351594211.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here assign all the required values for characteristics&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Save the data,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_17-1760351632195.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326690i6DA62D0E4063E6CD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_17-1760351632195.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_17-1760351632195.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. &lt;U&gt;Define Class and Assign Characteristics - CL02&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here define the Class title and specify the Class type as 010 – Vendor Class&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_18-1760351656629.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326691i0BB9EC608B5D1C8E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_18-1760351656629.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_18-1760351656629.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_19-1760351672341.png" style="width: 33px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326692i97A65DE69DB71099/image-dimensions/33x33/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="33" height="33" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_19-1760351672341.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_19-1760351672341.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;button&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter the description and validity period&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_20-1760351696025.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326693iBC8AD69991022B34/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_20-1760351696025.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_20-1760351696025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now go to Tab&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_21-1760351727926.png" style="width: 70px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326694i6185D3F6D255AD39/image-dimensions/70x30/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="70" height="30" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_21-1760351727926.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_21-1760351727926.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;and assign both characteristics created in step 1 &amp;amp; 2 above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_24-1760351801988.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326697i725DF9F5A8B43ABE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_24-1760351801988.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_24-1760351801988.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Save the entries&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_23-1760351774029.png" style="width: 315px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326696i37D80D106638AE30/image-dimensions/315x26/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="315" height="26" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_23-1760351774029.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_23-1760351774029.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. &lt;U&gt;Copy Role FLVN00 to Z0001&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of using General BP role 000000, you must copy either FLVN00 or FLCU00 because SAP supports Classification functionality only for Vendor and Customer roles, Check Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2561811" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2561811 - Fix for classification disabled in BP transaction - SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SPRO -&amp;gt; Cross-Application Components -&amp;gt; SAP Business Partner -&amp;gt; Business Partner -&amp;gt; Basic Settings -&amp;gt; Business Partner Roles -&amp;gt; Define BP Roles&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_25-1760351832813.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326698iB16FA857C701F32E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_25-1760351832813.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_25-1760351832813.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click Copy button to copy all settings&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Name the role Z0001 and click enter&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following message will appear&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_26-1760351869677.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326699iE3D42E10F517ED0D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_26-1760351869677.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_26-1760351869677.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click save button.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Z BP Role Z0001 will look like as below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_27-1760351886881.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326700i75A86B21C372105D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_27-1760351886881.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_27-1760351886881.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. &lt;U&gt;Testing in BP Master Data&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open Transaction BP for any existing or new Vendor&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select BP Role Z0001 – Sub Contractor&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_28-1760351908526.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326701iE021E965679B36D9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_28-1760351908526.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_28-1760351908526.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, from top menu, select Extras -&amp;gt; Classification&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_29-1760351923906.png" style="width: 214px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326702i6725E31C9DCC3CC8/image-dimensions/214x198/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="214" height="198" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_29-1760351923906.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_29-1760351923906.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following screen will appear:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_30-1760351947604.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326703i7A51D8EC96B9D0B1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_30-1760351947604.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_30-1760351947604.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use F4 search to find the Class we already created in &lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3 above.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_31-1760351961313.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326704iC5E07362DF1A0A51/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_31-1760351961313.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_31-1760351961313.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now hit the Enter key;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Both Characteristics assigned to class will show under Tab&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_32-1760351977650.png" style="width: 85px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326705i6FFD8A6C04A51ECB/image-dimensions/85x29/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="85" height="29" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_32-1760351977650.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_32-1760351977650.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_33-1760351999696.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326706i167451D70158A8D8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_33-1760351999696.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_33-1760351999696.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use F4 search to find all the values of each characteristic&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_34-1760352017754.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326707i92F91BB0A2EE2F30/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_34-1760352017754.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_34-1760352017754.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, for first characteristic “Subcontractor Main Category”, all its values will pop-up&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s select first characteristic “CIVIL”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_35-1760352032978.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326708i3D1EA6E084FD7DB8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_35-1760352032978.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_35-1760352032978.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on ok button&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_36-1760352065755.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326709iEC67BBE9FB25D4C8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_36-1760352065755.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_36-1760352065755.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly, select second characteristic “Subcontractor Sub-Category” and click F4 search&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_37-1760352196330.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326710i1C6A39990C653DD3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_37-1760352196330.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_37-1760352196330.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All values assigned to this characteristic are shown.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s select first value “INFRASTRUCTURAL”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_38-1760352213951.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326711i9721704EF0A8EA34/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_38-1760352213951.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_38-1760352213951.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on ok button&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="muhammad_waseem_39-1760352245835.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326712i8710CE881476282B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="muhammad_waseem_39-1760352245835.png" alt="muhammad_waseem_39-1760352245835.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since both main category and subcategory characteristics are assigned, so click on F3 button to reach back to main screen of BP and save it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conclusion: Using Classification, you can assign and maintain Characteristics of BP, in an orderly manner, with its respective values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope, you enjoyed the read and flow of stream is clear.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me know for any feedback and suggestions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/characteristics-of-business-partner-through-classification/ba-p/14242328"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:44:38.310000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/demand-forecasting-for-festivals/qaq-p/14242329</id>
    <title>Demand forecasting for festivals</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:46:24.591000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PSahay</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1430382</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please suggest how to configure multivariate forecast algorithms in SAP IBP for festivals with varying dates every year like Eid, Diwali etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prabhat Sahay&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/demand-forecasting-for-festivals/qaq-p/14242329"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:46:24.591000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/bc-p/14242332#M185336</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP test cockpit (ATC) recommendations for governance of clean core ABAP development</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:50:13.308000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OlgaDolinskaja</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6638</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/207270"&gt;@gerardo_martingozalo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;it looks like your checked ECC system is still missing prerequisites for&amp;nbsp; "Usage Of APIs" check execution.&amp;nbsp; Please open a ticket to get this investigated in detail.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks and kind regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Olga.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/bc-p/14242332#M185336"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:50:13.308000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-migrating-integrations-to-sap-integration-suite-via-quot-migrate/qaq-p/14242338</id>
    <title>Issue Migrating Integrations to SAP Integration Suite via "Migrate Process Orchestration Artifacts"</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:56:21.423000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dinis_falcao</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2122590</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m currently facing an issue while trying to migrate integrations from &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Process Orchestration (PO)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Migrate Process Orchestration Artifacts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have successfully configured the connection to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Process Orchestration System&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and the &lt;STRONG&gt;connection test is successful&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In Step 2 of the migration wizard, I can see and select the integration scenarios available in &lt;STRONG&gt;PO&lt;/STRONG&gt; without any issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt; step, where I should be able to select an integration pattern, &lt;STRONG&gt;no options are displayed&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as shown in the image below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="printscreenError.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326713i3ECAEB91A12FD8FD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="printscreenError.png" alt="printscreenError.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone in the community faced a similar issue? Are there any additional &lt;STRONG&gt;prerequisites or configurations required&lt;/STRONG&gt; to have the &lt;STRONG&gt;integration patterns&lt;/STRONG&gt; show up correctly in this step?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Thanks in advance for your help!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/issue-migrating-integrations-to-sap-integration-suite-via-quot-migrate/qaq-p/14242338"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:56:21.423000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-what-is-happening-week-2/bc-p/14242339#M1006</id>
    <title>Re: Devtoberfest 2025 - What is Happening Week 2</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:57:10.859000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KevinR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423549</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/173946"&gt;@Sookriti_Mishra&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;this tutorial got removed from the activities during Week 2 because of that reason.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;KR&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-what-is-happening-week-2/bc-p/14242339#M1006"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:57:10.859000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/learning-with-heart-and-structure-patrizia-rossi-s-story/ba-p/14240258</id>
    <title>Learning with Heart and Structure: Patrizia Rossi’s Story</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:57:44.817000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>margherita_gallucci34</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In 2020, Patrizia Rossi welcomed a tiny puppy into her life in Rome. “He was so small and tender that just looking at him made me feel better,” she recalls. What began as playful walks and teaching simple commands soon grew into something more substantial. By combining instinct with structured training, Patrizia discovered a whole new world. In time, she and her dog even became &lt;STRONG&gt;agility champions,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;something she never imagined at the beginning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Patrizia and her puppy training" style="width: 176px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325491i8A4444BC9A3854B4/image-dimensions/176x311/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="176" height="311" role="button" title="Agility.jpg" alt="Patrizia and her puppy training" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Patrizia and her puppy training&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;That joyful chapter came during a challenging time, after the loss of her younger brother and her mother. The puppy became more than a companion. He was a source of comfort and a reminder that growth often comes from pairing passion with structure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For Patrizia, the parallel with her SAP-related career was clear. Twenty years earlier, she began her career as an ABAP developer in Turin, learning by doing. Over the years, she specialized in SAP Fiori and SAP Business Technology Platform. Like with her dog, instinct and practice alone weren’t enough for her full potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“To really grow, I needed structured learning, a path that combined hands-on experience with theory,” she explains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That approach shaped her career. Until 2024, Patrizia was an SAP consultant, supporting clients on backend and frontend solutions. Recently, she joined the &lt;STRONG&gt;European Space Agency&lt;/STRONG&gt; as an SAP Solution Architect. Her role now demands concrete, reliable solutions, and SAP Certifications give her that foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="sappress.jpg" style="width: 195px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325502i0497913479774538/image-dimensions/195x260/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="195" height="260" role="button" title="sappress.jpg" alt="sappress.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;She recently earned the &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP BTP Solution Architect certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;, adding to several certifications. For her, certifications aren’t just credentials; they build confidence. "When you know the theory, you don’t just work better, you become an added value. You support colleagues, propose stronger solutions, and solve problems faster."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That difference was clear when she activated &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Work Zone Advanced Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Since she was also preparing for the SAP Build Work Zone certification, she was able to solve issues quickly that practicing alone wouldn’t have prepared her for.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Those are the moments when you feel like you’ve won the lottery,” she laughs. “After banging your head against a problem, you run a test and… it works!”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Patrizia remembers a colleague who encouraged her. Every time she cracked a tough problem, he would laugh and shout: "MONSTER!" Though he is no longer here, Patrizia keeps the tradition. "Whenever I solve something impossible, I still whisper: ‘MONSTERRR!’"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For Patrizia, certifications and structured learning turned her from a consultant who once relied on instinct to a solution architect trusted at the highest levels. Just like in dog training, practice matters—but theory and structure make you unstoppable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Want to become the next “monster” problem solver?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Explore structured learning paths and certifications at the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/learning-with-heart-and-structure-patrizia-rossi-s-story/ba-p/14240258"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:57:44.817000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/alumni-screen-to-be-setup-in-ec/qaq-p/14242340</id>
    <title>Alumni screen to be setup in EC</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:59:52.134000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ashwanigupta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/34829</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is a feature being released in 2H 2025 for Alumni set up, can you please let us know guide to set up or video, like URL or service which need to be provided or permission in RBP and how it looks like or access to an end user in EC.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/alumni-screen-to-be-setup-in-ec/qaq-p/14242340"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:59:52.134000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/fun-for-week-1-the-devtoberfest-scavenger-hunt/bc-p/14242341#M1007</id>
    <title>Re: 🟡 Fun for Week 1: The Devtoberfest Scavenger Hunt 🔨🪙</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:00:02.420000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>gerardminari</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172124</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Hi,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;It wasn’t easy, but I finally cracked the SAP Devtoberfest Scavenger Hunt secret phrase. Proud to be a SAP developer — persistence, logic and a bit of ABAP spirit got me through! Proud to be part of the SAP developer community where curiosity and code meet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="gerardminari_0-1760352925450.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326715i5388748BB48D1D74/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="gerardminari_0-1760352925450.png" alt="gerardminari_0-1760352925450.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/fun-for-week-1-the-devtoberfest-scavenger-hunt/bc-p/14242341#M1007"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:00:02.420000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/nigerian-currency-not-available-as-an-option-in-wfa/qaa-p/14242342#M48646</id>
    <title>Re: Nigerian currency not available as an option in WFA</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:00:28.128000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lola_Alao</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/118572</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thank you &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17486"&gt;@YSE-1&lt;/a&gt; support has rectified the issue</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/nigerian-currency-not-available-as-an-option-in-wfa/qaa-p/14242342#M48646"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:00:28.128000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/switch-debug-user-via-adt-shows-popup-h-reactivate-extd-dbg-kind-user-user/m-p/14242344#M61</id>
    <title>Re: Switch debug user via ADT shows popup /H_REACTIVATE_EXTD_DBG KIND=USER USER=SAP_WFRT</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:02:49.356000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Armin_Beil</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/228228</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Sandra,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;thanks for the excellent problem description and for your analysis. I have the same reproducible behavior in our system, so we can take a look at this. This might take a while because I don't consider the issue as high priority currently. Please correct me if my assumption should be wrong.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In general, it is normal and expected that ADT sends special ok-codes into all currently open embedded GUI windows. The specific code /H_REACTIVATE_EXTD_DBG KIND is intended to inform the GUI windows about the change in the debug settings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Normally ADT-users should not see these ok-codes at all and also ST05 as a transaction/program should not "see" or handle these codes. We have to check why ST05 shows a different behaviour here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding the warning "User mismatch - debugging will not work for current logon session.":&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you know, debugging only works if the username that is configured in the debug-settings matches the username of the debuggee (= sy-uname of the to-be-debugged ABAP process). In case of an embedded GUI the debuggee user / sy-uname will be the logon user of your ADT project. The warning informs you if this username does not match the one in your debug settings, which is a useful warning in my personal opinion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The text "... debugging will not work for current logon session" might be a bit unclear because it is not necessarily clear to the user what "current logon session" means in this case. Maybe this could be improved. However from a purely technical perspective the text is not wrong, because it refers to the ABAP logon session of the embedded GUI window / set of embedded GUI windows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Armin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/switch-debug-user-via-adt-shows-popup-h-reactivate-extd-dbg-kind-user-user/m-p/14242344#M61"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:02:49.356000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/customer-master-data-sap-s-4-hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14242350#M4929099</id>
    <title>Re: Customer Master Data - SAP S/4 HANA PUBLIC CLOUD</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:14:44.386000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1486433"&gt;@Tehreem_Fatima1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Partner functions are not included in Business Partner. In SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud Edition, load them using the Customer migration objects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In Migrate Your Data – Migration Cockpit, add Customer (or Customer – Extend by Sales Area).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Please download the template and complete the 'Sales Area → Partner Functions' tab (AG = Sold-to, SH = Ship-to for each row).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Upload and migrate.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Useful SAP documentation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The list of Available Migration Objects (Cloud Public Edition) includes all the objects that have been delivered, such as Customer / Customer – Extend by Sales. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d5699934e7004d048c4801b552f3b013/20607b6de19a4d34a41b0abec6186b01.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Data Migration-Available Migration Objects&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customer – add new organisational levels to an existing record using Cloud help for the Customer extension object (sales-area data; cross-references to other BPs). Use this when updating sales areas or partners for customers that already exist. &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d5699934e7004d048c4801b552f3b013/b127a62235874379bd4f8fbaf1cea619.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Customer - extend existing record by new org levels&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F3473')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Migrate Your Data (Migration Cockpit)&lt;/A&gt; – app overview/how-to. Use this to create a project, add the object, and download the current template.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP deck: S/4HANA Migration Cockpit – Cloud Public Edition – official overview of approaches and usage. &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2020/07/7a263781-a67d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP-SAP S/4HANA Migration Cockpit - Migrate Your Data to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the Partner Functions tab doesn’t appear after adding the Customer object, refresh the migration content, remove and re-add the object, and then re-download the template. Please send me a screenshot of your project’s object list and template tabs if the error persists&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/customer-master-data-sap-s-4-hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14242350#M4929099"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:14:44.386000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/unable-to-post-direct-activity-allocation-to-event-based-investment-project/qaq-p/14242351</id>
    <title>Unable to Post Direct Activity Allocation to Event-Based Investment Project WBS Element</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:14:54.467000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Veronica_VidalTorres</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1776090</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;HI,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am working in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; and encountering an issue when trying to post costs to an investment project using the app &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Direct Activity Allocation (F3697A)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The receiver is a WBS element that belongs to an &lt;STRONG&gt;event-based investment project&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Event-Based Settlement of Investment Projects and Assets Under Construction).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Despite using the same cost center, activity type, and account as in other successful postings (including &lt;SPAN&gt;Overhead Projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;Projects with Revenue&lt;/SPAN&gt;, and non-event-based Investment Projects), the system throws the following errors:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;KI153 - Account assignment to activity types not active in CO area A000 in 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Diagnosis:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Assignment to activity types is not active in fiscal year 2025 in controlling area A000.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Procedure:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The system suggests activating account assignment to activity types in the fiscal-year-dependent settings for CO area A000.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Account 55110000 0030 is blocked for posting&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, I believe the issue is not related to the activity type or the account itself, since the same configuration works correctly in other projects. The only difference is the receiver WBS element, which in this case belongs to an &lt;STRONG&gt;event-based investment project&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you please advise if there are any restrictions or additional configurations required for direct activity allocation in event-based investment projects in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance for your support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vero&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/unable-to-post-direct-activity-allocation-to-event-based-investment-project/qaq-p/14242351"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:14:54.467000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/flexible-workflow-for-sales-for-public-cloud-complete-guide/bc-p/14242352#M72128</id>
    <title>Re: Flexible Workflow for Sales for Public Cloud - Complete Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:15:02.094000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BrigitteH_29</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253072</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135158"&gt;@Elkhawanky&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;I've set up a sales order approval workflow on Public Cloud 2508 based on your guideline and it works great. However, I'v noticed that the default Launchpad notifications (not the emails) started showing the variables instead of the actual values:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Release of Sales Order {SALES_DOCUMENT} - Net Value: {cl_sd_apm_convert.convert_valu01}...&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BrigitteH_29_0-1760354143588.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326719iF93473C636A754D6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="BrigitteH_29_0-1760354143588.png" alt="BrigitteH_29_0-1760354143588.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do you have any idea why that would be and how I can fix it?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/flexible-workflow-for-sales-for-public-cloud-complete-guide/bc-p/14242352#M72128"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:15:02.094000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/attach-invoice-to-dunning-letter/qaa-p/14242354#M4229295</id>
    <title>Re: Attach invoice to dunning letter</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:16:33.336000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CathWilson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1570163</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi.&amp;nbsp; Did you ever get a solution for this? Thanks in advance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cath&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/attach-invoice-to-dunning-letter/qaa-p/14242354#M4229295"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:16:33.336000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-condition-contract-final-settlement-question/qaq-p/14242356</id>
    <title>SAP Condition contract Final settlement question</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:20:51.105000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chinmay7</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2074674</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello CCM Gurus,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have an issue performing final settlement for our customers at the end of the year. We issue quarterly partial settlements to our customers for the sales done in the preceding quarter (Q1, Q2 and Q3). The partial settlements consider the business volume correctly. The issue arises when we issue final settlements to our customers (Q4 only), but the credit note considers the business volume of the entire year thereby causing us to issue dual credit to the customer for the volume for which credit is already done.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please guide us in solving this confusing issue&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sap-condition-contract-final-settlement-question/qaq-p/14242356"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:20:51.105000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/salvador-events/meet-up-comunidade-sap-salvador-e-esse-tal-de-fiori/ec-p/14242365#M10</id>
    <title>Re: Meet UP- Comunidade SAP Salvador- E esse tal de Fiori?!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:28:46.889000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ismar_ads</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/767774</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Infelizmente não me atentei as notificações da comunidade e perdi esse evento. Mas se tiver gravado, vai ser muito bom.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/salvador-events/meet-up-comunidade-sap-salvador-e-esse-tal-de-fiori/ec-p/14242365#M10"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:28:46.889000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/queue-display-not-supported-for-function-scwm-qdecided-fup-process/qaq-p/14242366</id>
    <title>Queue Display not supported for function /SCWM/QDECIDED_FUP_PROCESS</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:29:16.888000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaghavanKathamuthu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17050</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Getting the issue 'Queue Display not supported for function /SCWM/QDECIDED_FUP_PROCESS and registered program /SPE/QUEUE_DISPLAY_TOOLS' While displaying logs in SMQ2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="RaghavanKathamuthu_0-1760354681419.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326722i602514B76F221388/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="RaghavanKathamuthu_0-1760354681419.png" alt="RaghavanKathamuthu_0-1760354681419.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After doing quality UD getting this issue.&amp;nbsp;Error during follow-up action; See application log&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="RaghavanKathamuthu_1-1760354767216.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326723i1473F829A88AFF14/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="RaghavanKathamuthu_1-1760354767216.png" alt="RaghavanKathamuthu_1-1760354767216.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Checked the notes&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3618250/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3618250&lt;/A&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3392556/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3392556&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;But still no solution.&lt;BR /&gt;Maintained the below in&amp;nbsp;/n/SCWM/ACTLOG&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="RaghavanKathamuthu_2-1760354875175.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326725i9CD7D7C14484C260/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="RaghavanKathamuthu_2-1760354875175.png" alt="RaghavanKathamuthu_2-1760354875175.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Is anything else missing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/queue-display-not-supported-for-function-scwm-qdecided-fup-process/qaq-p/14242366"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:29:16.888000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/the-profit-center-is-automatically-assigned-with-an-unintended-value/qaa-p/14242369#M255769</id>
    <title>Re: The profit center is automatically assigned with an u...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:32:16.802000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AT_1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2100740</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;normally&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;COBL_CODINGBLOCK_CHECK does not hard code the profit center 9999, but it is a function module that will validate an complete the process. that means that in the system, somewhere PC 9999 it`s contained in other routines that derive the Pc. You can start by checking substitution rules OKC9, derivation rules KEDR/3KEI and account assigment logic in OKB9 &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/the-profit-center-is-automatically-assigned-with-an-unintended-value/qaa-p/14242369#M255769"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:32:16.802000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/schema-categories-shows-the-blank-names-and-descriptions/qaa-p/14242370#M4929100</id>
    <title>Re: Schema categories shows the blank Names and Descripti...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:34:11.089000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>svankina</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1956193</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Richard,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based your feedback that a few German words were still present within the English language file, I logged into the system using the &lt;STRONG&gt;German language session&lt;/STRONG&gt; and verified the schema. Interestingly, in the German session, the &lt;STRONG&gt;MLC schema correctly displays the names and descriptions&lt;/STRONG&gt;. I have since manually translated these entries into English directly in &lt;STRONG&gt;CRM_UI&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is quite unexpected behaviour that a file uploaded under the English language context reflects only when accessed through the German language session. Could you please help analyze this behavior and advise what might be causing this language inconsistency?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;BR /&gt;Srinivas V&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/schema-categories-shows-the-blank-names-and-descriptions/qaa-p/14242370#M4929100"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:34:11.089000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/bc-p/14242372#M185338</id>
    <title>Re: ABAP test cockpit (ATC) recommendations for governance of clean core ABAP development</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:37:50.176000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>albertmink</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/141289</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/207270"&gt;@gerardo_martingozalo&lt;/a&gt;The message you see at the bottom is simply informational, however contributes to the check failure count. It serves as a reminder that the system will always verify if release information is available, especially for any non-SAP objects you might be working with. Whether you're declaring a C1 release for partner-specific or your proprietary objects, the check will automatically attempt to ascertain their release status. The SAP objects are checked according to the configures data source for released API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On a positive note, I've got some great news! The setup that was previously mentioned by &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6638"&gt;@OlgaDolinskaja&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;has been completed successfully.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/bc-p/14242372#M185338"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:37:50.176000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/effective-approach-to-managing-cross-process-requirements-in-projects/bc-p/14242373#M185339</id>
    <title>Re: Effective Approach to Managing Cross-Process Requirements in Projects</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:40:30.274000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Niladri_B_Nayak</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170723</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;How about User stories ? I can't assign 1 user stoey to mulyiple team, at present I can see only 1 option to select from the drop down.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/effective-approach-to-managing-cross-process-requirements-in-projects/bc-p/14242373#M185339"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:40:30.274000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-show-if-doc-attached-to-floc-in-ih01/qaa-p/14242374#M4229298</id>
    <title>Re: How to show if Doc attached to FLOC in IH01</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:43:23.694000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RAHEEL_BABAR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2971</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No, by default IH01 does not show document attachments for Functional Locations (FLOC) in the structure view like it shows BOM explosion icons. It isn’t just a user setting. you need to customize screen with help of ABAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-show-if-doc-attached-to-floc-in-ih01/qaa-p/14242374#M4229298"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:43:23.694000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-pipo-7-5-rfc-setup-sender-to-rfc-receiver/qaa-p/14242376#M4929101</id>
    <title>Re: SAP PIPO 7.5 RFC Setup Sender to RFC Receiver</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:44:02.088000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marksmyth</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/97409</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Refer to the online help page for details on the configuration requirements: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_NETWEAVER_750/5cf7d2de571a45cc81f91261668b7361/676d0540ba5ee569e10000000a155106.html?q=rfc+adapter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring the Sender RFC Adapter | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;"Under Application Server (Gateway), specify the Gateway host name of the sender system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under Application Server Service (Gateway), specify the Gateway service of the sender system.&lt;P class=""&gt;Specify the numerical description of the service port in the sender system or the alphanumerical equivalent.&lt;BR /&gt;For example, enter sapgwXX where XX is the system number of the sender system."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;BR /&gt;Mark&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-pipo-7-5-rfc-setup-sender-to-rfc-receiver/qaa-p/14242376#M4929101"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:44:02.088000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/thrilled-to-join-the-sap-community/td-p/14242380</id>
    <title>Thrilled to join the SAP Community</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:50:23.942000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>milan17</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2259433</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hey everyone! I'm excited to be a part of this community of SAP enthusiasts and professionals. With a strong interest in the SAP domain,&amp;nbsp;I’m eager to learn, share insights, and grow alongside all of you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to connecting, collaborating, and driving innovation together!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-discussions/thrilled-to-join-the-sap-community/td-p/14242380"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:50:23.942000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/make-ppr0-mandatory-so-cannot-be-saved-if-ppr0-is-missing/qaa-p/14242383#M4229299</id>
    <title>Re: Make PPR0 Mandatory (SO cannot be saved if PPR0 is mi...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:53:22.777000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RAHEEL_BABAR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2971</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;have you set Required check box in V/08 for conditions?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="RAHEEL_BABAR_0-1760356370005.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326733i73C903582D6C6355/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="RAHEEL_BABAR_0-1760356370005.png" alt="RAHEEL_BABAR_0-1760356370005.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/make-ppr0-mandatory-so-cannot-be-saved-if-ppr0-is-missing/qaa-p/14242383#M4229299"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:53:22.777000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/evolving-data-integration-with-sql-services-and-cds-external-entities/ec-p/14242387#M1186</id>
    <title>Re: 🟢 Evolving data integration with SQL services and CDS external entities</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:56:37.558000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>juttigab</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2255684</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Nice presentation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/evolving-data-integration-with-sql-services-and-cds-external-entities/ec-p/14242387#M1186"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:56:37.558000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/promotion-data-export-option-is-visible-in-manage-worksheet/qaa-p/14242388#M48647</id>
    <title>Re: Promotion Data Export option is visible in Manage Worksheet</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:56:57.102000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DavidSomelofske</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1427721</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Unfortunately, I don't believe you can disable. I have checked in my demo system in RBP and that functionality did not appear as something you can deselect or select. I might suggest submitting a ticket or an enhancement request.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/promotion-data-export-option-is-visible-in-manage-worksheet/qaa-p/14242388#M48647"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:56:57.102000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-document-and-reporting-compliance-cloud-or-on-premise-not-an-either-or/bc-p/14242389#M185340</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Document and Reporting Compliance: Cloud or On-Premise? Not an “either or” option, but a str</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T13:59:30.342000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>erika_buson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/176294</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1290607"&gt;@seungho4lee&lt;/a&gt; thank you for reaching out. As per strategy explained in the blog, Singapore is enabled with SAP Document and Reporting Compliance, cloud edition and its license is required. The integration between ERP and&amp;nbsp;SAP Document and Reporting Compliance, cloud edition is available in standard:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-edition/sap-document-and-reporting-compliance-cloud-edition/integration?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-edition/sap-document-and-reporting-compliance-cloud-edition/integration?locale=en-US&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps. Thank you. Erika&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-document-and-reporting-compliance-cloud-or-on-premise-not-an-either-or/bc-p/14242389#M185340"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T13:59:30.342000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/make-ppr0-mandatory-so-cannot-be-saved-if-ppr0-is-missing/qaa-p/14242390#M4229300</id>
    <title>Re: Make PPR0 Mandatory (SO cannot be saved if PPR0 is mi...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:03:03.061000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NelsenW_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1511758</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2971"&gt;@RAHEEL_BABAR&lt;/a&gt;, yes i did, but it only give us warning if PPR0 is missing. i still can save my Sales Order. Im using S4HANA Public Edition btw</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/make-ppr0-mandatory-so-cannot-be-saved-if-ppr0-is-missing/qaa-p/14242390#M4229300"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:03:03.061000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/kerberos-spnego-for-sap-as-abap-in-a-multi-domain-environment/bc-p/14242391#M185341</id>
    <title>Re: Kerberos/SPNEGO for SAP AS ABAP in a Multi-Domain Environment</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:08:28.587000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>emourey-irsn</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/675118</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this configuration&amp;nbsp; applicable for SAP AS Java (Enterprise Portal)&amp;nbsp; ? SSO for users based two differents Active directory with a trusted relationship ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/kerberos-spnego-for-sap-as-abap-in-a-multi-domain-environment/bc-p/14242391#M185341"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:08:28.587000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/reinventing-b2b-customer-experiences-with-the-sap-b2b-self-service-portal/bc-p/14242392#M185342</id>
    <title>Re: Reinventing B2B Customer Experiences with the SAP B2B Self-Service Portal</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:08:42.931000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lokeshla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/316584</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Great Blog!!&amp;nbsp;The blog highlights an important evolution in B2B engagement — empowering customers through transparency and self-service. Reducing dependency on manual support while freeing up sales teams to focus on value-based conversations is exactly where modern B2B needs to head.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/reinventing-b2b-customer-experiences-with-the-sap-b2b-self-service-portal/bc-p/14242392#M185342"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:08:42.931000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/s4hana-green-field-implementation-activate-methodology-deliverables-3/bc-p/14242395#M72129</id>
    <title>Re: S4Hana Green field Implementation - Activate Methodology - Deliverables - 3 Pillars - Consultant</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:09:36.897000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>iamgayathri</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/836524</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;RaghavanKathamu&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;thu, really useful content. But the links aren't working, could you update the blog please?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/s4hana-green-field-implementation-activate-methodology-deliverables-3/bc-p/14242395#M72129"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:09:36.897000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-activate-the-feature-sd-sls-prnt-all-txt-lang/qaa-p/14242396#M4229301</id>
    <title>Re: How to activate the feature SD_SLS_PRNT_ALL_TXT_LANG</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:14:01.254000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>luizapereira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1394837</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Note: the feature SD_SLS_PRNT_ALL_TXT_LANG is designed to allow text content to be retrieved in a form template even if the text description is not maintained for the specific text ID in the output item's receiving language. It does not imply that all text in different languages will be retrieved for the order header and item. Before this feature release, it'd be necessary to maintain the text description in all languages used for output.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/how-to-activate-the-feature-sd-sls-prnt-all-txt-lang/qaa-p/14242396#M4229301"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:14:01.254000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/migration-steps-from-jdk-17-to-jdk-21-using-openrewrite-recipes-in-sap/bc-p/14242400#M14728</id>
    <title>Re: Migration steps from JDK-17 to JDK-21 using OpenRewrite recipes in SAP Commerce Cloud 2211</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:17:58.795000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DigitalClarity</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2238892</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1444361"&gt;@Karthi_Murugan&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;thanks for sharing this approach.&amp;nbsp; Can you share as to the location of where to down load the files you have mentioned?&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/migration-steps-from-jdk-17-to-jdk-21-using-openrewrite-recipes-in-sap/bc-p/14242400#M14728"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:17:58.795000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/welcome-to-the-future-the-2h-2025-home-page-redesign-in-successfactors/bc-p/14242406#M7217</id>
    <title>Re: Welcome to the Future: The 2H 2025 Home Page Redesign in SuccessFactors</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:23:44.312000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnyNou</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/136098</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Expert, Could you please advise on how my customer can activate the new Home Page?&lt;BR /&gt;They’ve informed me that it’s not visible in their preview instance. Are there any specific steps or a process they need to follow to enable it? Thank you in advance for your support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/welcome-to-the-future-the-2h-2025-home-page-redesign-in-successfactors/bc-p/14242406#M7217"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:23:44.312000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/clarification-on-hana-runtime-compliance/qaq-p/14242411</id>
    <title>Clarification on HANA Runtime compliance</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:29:48.020000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>moritzj_melasoft</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2259497</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am seeking clarification on two related topics regarding SAP Document and Reporting Compliance (DRC) and SAP HANA Runtime licensing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer runs &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA with HANA Runtime Edition for Applications &amp;amp; BW&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The customer &lt;STRONG&gt;does not have a DRC subscription&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A certified &lt;STRONG&gt;third-party Peppol Access Point&lt;/STRONG&gt; is used for sending and receiving electronic invoices (XRechnung / Peppol).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The integration add-on runs &lt;STRONG&gt;entirely within the SAP application layer (ABAP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, using standard IDoc/BAPI/RFC/Proxy interfaces — &lt;STRONG&gt;no direct database access, no XS, no SQL scripts, and no custom tables&lt;/STRONG&gt; in HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Questions:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is such an add-on architecture &lt;STRONG&gt;compliant under HANA Runtime licensing&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or would it require a &lt;STRONG&gt;Full Use Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For &lt;STRONG&gt;outbound e-invoicing (XRechnung/Peppol)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, is &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP DRC mandatory&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or can a &lt;STRONG&gt;third-party Access Point&lt;/STRONG&gt; be used directly with standard SAP interfaces?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If possible, I would appreciate &lt;STRONG&gt;an SAP Note reference or official clarification&lt;/STRONG&gt; on these points to help guide the architecture decision.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance for your insights.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/clarification-on-hana-runtime-compliance/qaq-p/14242411"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:29:48.020000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/innovations-in-master-data-governance-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private/bc-p/14242412#M185345</id>
    <title>Re: Innovations in Master Data Governance with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:37:30.352000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>0012anirban</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39679</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks Markus for sharing Insights!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding the rolling forward of changes from old edition to new edition, is there a note which we can refer to understand what are the changes? And is it only applicable for 2025 version or can it be down ported to 2023 for customers who are not immediately looking to upgrade.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anirban&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/innovations-in-master-data-governance-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private/bc-p/14242412#M185345"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:37:30.352000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cannot-enter-to-pi-sheet-loading-data/qaa-p/14242413#M4229302</id>
    <title>Re: cannot enter to PI Sheet(Loading data)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:38:51.271000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>janbuchmann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/190831</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Kindly check whether &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2224356" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP&amp;nbsp;note 2224356&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt; is applicable to your release&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/cannot-enter-to-pi-sheet-loading-data/qaa-p/14242413#M4229302"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:38:51.271000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/rap-restful-application-programming-model-projected-association-is-not/qaa-p/14242414#M4929102</id>
    <title>Re: RAP / Restful Application Programming Model: Projecte...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:40:50.269000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>raada</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/451889</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi colleagues,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was facing the same issue in my project. I was able to solve it with help of ZFE_TRAVEL_XXXXXX example and use of analogy. Since there is no more details about your project, there are some points to follow:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;use "&lt;SPAN&gt;redirected to parent _parent" &amp;lt;--&amp;gt; "redirected to composition child&amp;nbsp;_child" in your projection cds views&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;use "association _child { create; with draft` } and association _parent { with draft } in your behavior definition and bd projection files&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These steps helped me to solve the issue. More about it probably can be found by inspecting the&amp;nbsp;ZFE_TRAVEL_XXXXXX (namely composition between TRAVEL and BOOKING ) and further googling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hope this helps.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Radim&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/rap-restful-application-programming-model-projected-association-is-not/qaa-p/14242414#M4929102"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:40:50.269000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/replacement-of-string-amp-3-not-possible-in-cds-view/qaa-p/14242415#M4929103</id>
    <title>Re: Replacement of string '&amp;3' not possible in CDS View</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:41:38.994000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lukasmetzger</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/700379</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Sandra, thanks for point that out. Unfortunately, this was just a copy and paste error from one of my many attempts at a solution. Even with ‘&amp;amp;3’ as a simple string, the value is not replaced. I have adjusted my example in the question.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/replacement-of-string-amp-3-not-possible-in-cds-view/qaa-p/14242415#M4929103"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:41:38.994000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/timeline-for-universal-push-of-latest-experience-of-performance-management/qaq-p/14242417</id>
    <title>Timeline for universal push of Latest Experience of Performance Management Forms</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:42:50.342000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Clemens_Wieser</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/22688</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This post&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-and-customer-updates/universal-push-of-latest-performance-management-experience-planned-for-2h/ba-p/14097235" target="_blank"&gt;Universal Push of Latest Performance Management Ex... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;describes&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;the universal push of the&amp;nbsp; Latest Experience of Performance Management Forms to all customers in the 2H 2026 release.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please be aware that many customers start their annual performance cycles at the beginning of a year. Consequently, starting 2nd of January 2026 with the legacy design which maybe has not been fully tested with the Latest Experience by some customers could cause design troubles or at least irritation if the universal push is done just within the critical appraisal phase in November 2026 on PROD.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please re-think the date or urge customers to test their forms in the Latest Eperience thoroughly in Q4/2025 before the templates for 2026 are launched to avoid issues or confusion.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/timeline-for-universal-push-of-latest-experience-of-performance-management/qaq-p/14242417"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:42:50.342000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/switch-debug-user-via-adt-shows-popup-h-reactivate-extd-dbg-kind-user-user/m-p/14242418#M63</id>
    <title>Re: Switch debug user via ADT shows popup /H_REACTIVATE_EXTD_DBG KIND=USER USER=SAP_WFRT</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:43:57.418000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks a lot for all the details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I confirm that it's not urgent at all.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyway, if it's not fixed, I have posted this question so that people can find an explanation here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-forum/switch-debug-user-via-adt-shows-popup-h-reactivate-extd-dbg-kind-user-user/m-p/14242418#M63"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:43:57.418000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-datasphere-text-of-transitive-attribute-not-available-in-analytic-model/qaq-p/14242421</id>
    <title>SAP Datasphere: Text of transitive attribute not available in Analytic Model</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:46:23.097000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MKreitlein</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6583</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP Datasphere experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have come across an issue, which I found already in 2023... and it seems it re-occured, &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;or&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;the solution is perfectly hidden, so that I cannot find it&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":expressionless_face:"&gt;😑&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would really appreciate if someone is able to help me.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following scenario:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) I have one dimension "DI Material" which has attributes, e.g. the Supplier (here the key has also a text association).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DI_Material.png" style="width: 427px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326741i392DA8F0295D8EC5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DI_Material.png" alt="DI_Material.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) I have two different Fact View which both have the association to the DI Material.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3) I have two different Analytic Models on top of these, but only in one of both I can activate the attribute with its text field, and in the other this information (available text) is not shown:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AM_available_Material__Supplier.png" style="width: 854px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326742i0F628C767E81142C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AM_available_Material__Supplier.png" alt="AM_available_Material__Supplier.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Missing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AM_missing_Material__Supplier.png" style="width: 847px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326743i41A8E97F934D073E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AM_missing_Material__Supplier.png" alt="AM_missing_Material__Supplier.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We already deployed the DI Material again, the fact view and the Analytic Model but it does not change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We even tried creating a new AM out of the fact view ... also the new AM does not show the referenced text on "Lieferant EK-Infosatz".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What can be the root cause here? Why does it not work like expected, and how to solve it?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks, Martin&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-datasphere-text-of-transitive-attribute-not-available-in-analytic-model/qaq-p/14242421"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:46:23.097000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/is-2h-2025-sf-release-deployed-on-preview-environment/qaq-p/14242423</id>
    <title>Is 2H 2025 SF Release deployed on preview environment?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:50:47.658000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AvinashNale</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/120646</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Is 2H 2025 SF Release deployed on preview environment?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/is-2h-2025-sf-release-deployed-on-preview-environment/qaq-p/14242423"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:50:47.658000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/customer-master-data-sap-s-4-hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14242424#M4929105</id>
    <title>Re: Customer Master Data - SAP S/4 HANA PUBLIC CLOUD</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:51:36.101000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tehreem_Fatima1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1486433</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960"&gt;@Chuma&lt;/a&gt; Issue has been diagnosed. Thank you for your cooperation.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/customer-master-data-sap-s-4-hana-public-cloud/qaa-p/14242424#M4929105"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:51:36.101000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-maxattention-blog-posts/new-expert-guided-implementation-unlocking-joule-and-sap-business-ai-from/ba-p/14242425</id>
    <title>New Expert-Guided Implementation: Unlocking Joule and SAP Business AI from Strategy to Activation</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:51:50.787000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>paul_schropp44</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/807129</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As organizations look to harness the power of Artificial Intelligence (AI) to drive transformation, SAP Business AI stands at the forefront - embedding intelligence directly into business processes to deliver smarter decisions and measurable outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From finance and supply chain to HR, procurement, and customer experience,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;infuses&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;trusted, relevant, and responsible AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;across every process - ensuring each insight is contextual, every recommendation actionable, and every outcome aligned with enterprise goals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether leveraging&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP’s AI copilot, or&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-embedded scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;across your SAP applications, your path to becoming an intelligent and sustainable enterprise begins with understanding and activating SAP’s Business AI capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To help you unlock this value faster, we’re launching a new Expert-Guided Implementation (EGI):&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--2145749666" id="toc-hId--2144977113"&gt;&lt;A href="https://accounts.sap.com/saml2/idp/sso?sp=https://www.successfactors.eu/learninghub&amp;amp;RelayState=%2Fsf%2Flearning%3FdestUrl%3Dhttps%253a%252f%252fsaplearninghub%252eplateau%252ecom%252flearning%252fuser%252fdeeplink%255fredirect%252ejsp%253flinkId%253dCATALOG%255fSEARCH%2526sbArSel%253d%2526keywords%253dSUP_EDE_00011814%2526selKeyWordHeader%253dSUP_EDE_00011814%2526catSel%253d%2526srcSel%253dESAC%2526delMthSel%253d%2526ILDateFrm%253d%2526ILDateTo%253d%2526ILBlend%253d%2526ILSchd%253d%2526fromSF%253dY%26company%3Dlearninghub" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unlocking AI: Joule and SAP Business AI from Strategy to Activation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;This multi-day, expert-led workshop is designed to help you and your team unlock the full potential of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;across your SAP landscape. Guided by SAP experts, you’ll explore how to translate strategy into execution with practical exercises, live demonstrations, and activation guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1823621406" id="toc-hId-1824393959"&gt;Workshop Schedule&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;To accommodate global participants, this session will be offered in two time zones:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;October 20–22, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;|&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10:00am–12:00pm EMEA time zone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;November 3–5, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;|&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10:00am –12:00pm NY time zone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1627107901" id="toc-hId-1627880454"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What You’ll Learn&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Through this EGI, participants will gain hands-on experience and actionable knowledge in:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business AI Strategy &amp;amp; Foundation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;-&amp;nbsp;Understand SAP’s AI vision, architecture, and trusted approach to delivering responsible, embedded intelligence&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Commercial Model &amp;amp; AI Units&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Learn how to navigate Base vs Premium&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;models, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;AI Feature Catalog&lt;SPAN&gt;, and use the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;AI Estimator&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to plan your adoption journey&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule – AI Built for Business&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Explore Joule’s unified architecture&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;roadmap&lt;SPAN&gt;, and capabilities across Joule for Business,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Joule for Developers, and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Joule for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Consultants&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA AI &amp;amp; ML Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Experience ISLM in action through AI/ML demo use cases&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;designed to enhance decision-making and process automation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP AI &amp;amp; ML Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Discover how BTP AI Foundation&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Document AI&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;AI Services&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;AI Core&lt;SPAN&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;AI Launchpad&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;can help you extend and scale innovation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Activation &amp;amp; Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;- Gain a clear view of activation steps, prerequisites&lt;SPAN&gt;, and how to extend Joule with&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Document Grounding&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Joule Studio&lt;SPAN&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;AI Agents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1430594396" id="toc-hId-1431366949"&gt;Why Attend&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This workshop goes beyond theory—it’s&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;interactive, practical, and guided by SAP experts&lt;/STRONG&gt;. By the end, you’ll have:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A clear understanding of SAP’s Business AI strategy and product portfolio&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The ability to activate Joule and deploy AI scenarios across your landscape&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Actionable steps to integrate AI and Generative AI into your business workflows&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Insights into commercial models and AI unit management for smarter planning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you’re a business leader shaping AI strategy or a technical consultant implementing it, this EGI equips you to bridge the gap between&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;strategy and execution&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1234080891" id="toc-hId-1234853444"&gt;How to Register&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1038339939"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://accounts.sap.com/saml2/idp/sso?sp=https://www.successfactors.eu/learninghub&amp;amp;RelayState=%2Fsf%2Flearning%3FdestUrl%3Dhttps%253a%252f%252fsaplearninghub%252eplateau%252ecom%252flearning%252fuser%252fdeeplink%255fredirect%252ejsp%253flinkId%253dCATALOG%255fSEARCH%2526sbArSel%253d%2526keywords%253dSUP_EDE_00011814%2526selKeyWordHeader%253dSUP_EDE_00011814%2526catSel%253d%2526srcSel%253dESAC%2526delMthSel%253d%2526ILDateFrm%253d%2526ILDateTo%253d%2526ILBlend%253d%2526ILSchd%253d%2526fromSF%253dY%26company%3Dlearninghub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register here to secure your spot&lt;/A&gt;*&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;today to learn from SAP experts and gain the skills to bring&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business AI to life&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;across your enterprise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;*&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;You may need to register your S-user for access to SAP Learning Hub to access the EGI registration page.&amp;nbsp; It is a one-time registration, click&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy/learn.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-maxattention-blog-posts/new-expert-guided-implementation-unlocking-joule-and-sap-business-ai-from/ba-p/14242425"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:51:50.787000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/correct-config-to-release-returned-stock-from-blocked-to-unrestricted-in/qaq-p/14242426</id>
    <title>Correct config to release returned stock from Blocked to Unrestricted in S4HANA Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:52:39.133000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are facing an issue while performing QA for sales return orders (order type &lt;STRONG&gt;CBAR&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process Executed:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;PGR is completed successfully in EWM.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stock is posted into&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blocked Stock&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Issue Observed:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inspection lot is&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;not displayed&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in QA32 or in the Fiori App&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;“Process Inspection Lot”&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we try to change the stock type, the system shows the message:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“Selected line related to Inspection reference”&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Fiori App&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;“Enter Inspection Results – From Warehouse”&lt;/EM&gt;, the delivery is displayed, but we are unable to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Perform the follow-up activity in the delivery.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Execute decision codes to complete QA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During sales return order, required stock direct post to Quality stock not in block stock, and then quality team after inspection they post the stock from quality to block or unrestricted. But as of now stock direct go to block stock. then we further want to move this stock from block to unrestricted then system not allowing to move stock due to dependencies from quality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;B&gt;Learn more about the SAP Support user and program &lt;A target="_blank" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/maximizing-the-power-of-sap-community-at-product-support/ba-p/13501276"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/B&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/correct-config-to-release-returned-stock-from-blocked-to-unrestricted-in/qaq-p/14242426"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:52:39.133000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/correct-config-to-release-returned-stock-from-blocked-to-unrestricted-in/qaa-p/14242427#M4229304</id>
    <title>Re: Correct config to release returned stock from Blocked...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:52:46.817000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPSupport</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121003</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;I understand that your primary goal is to unblock the returned stock and move it to Unrestricted Use following the Quality Team's inspection, without initiating any further activities (such as scrapping, returning to the supplier, etc.) through the formal returns process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;System Finding (wrong behavior):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Follow-up Activity: “0031 – No further activities” could be set&amp;nbsp;during inspection, along with Inspection Code “OK”.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;“Material Received” flag is probably set on the returns order.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stock Transfer Dependency Error: The system is preventing a manual movement from Blocked to Unrestricted.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Technical Impact (Why it Fails):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This follow-up activity is designed to end the returns process without triggering a logistics movement. It lacks the built-in system logic to perform the mandatory stock posting change from Blocked/Returns Stock to Unrestricted Use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This flag is typically used for over-the-counter inspections where the inspection is done at the time of receipt, and no further warehouse inspection or follow-up activity is required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The stock is still tied to the original Sales Returns Order (SOS) and requires the formal returns process decision to release it. Attempts to use generic Material Management (MM) movement types (e.g., 321, 453, etc.) will result in an error indicating the stock is linked to Quality Management or the returns document.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommended Action:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Quality Team must use the correct follow-up activity that includes the stock posting logic, such as “0002 – Immediately Move to Free Available Stock”.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the intention is for the Quality Team to perform a later, formal inspection, this flag should NOT be set on the returns order item.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The only way to release this stock is through the designated Returns Inspection App (e.g., &lt;EM&gt;Enter Inspection Results - From Warehouse&lt;/EM&gt;) by selecting the correct Logistics Follow-up Activity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further details, please check the Blog Post below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/customer-returns-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-wm/ba-p/13554595" target="_blank"&gt;Customer Returns Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud WM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please let us know if you still have an issue with it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/correct-config-to-release-returned-stock-from-blocked-to-unrestricted-in/qaa-p/14242427#M4229304"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:52:46.817000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/i-am-not-able-to-assign-a-single-material-to-multiple-fixed-bins-in-the/qaq-p/14242428</id>
    <title>I am not able to Assign a Single Material to Multiple Fixed Bins in the Same Storage Type</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:54:46.349000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shubham120798</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1955054</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP Support Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was not able to assign a single material to &lt;STRONG&gt;multiple fixed bins within the same storage type&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example:&lt;BR /&gt;Material &lt;STRONG&gt;A000006447&lt;/STRONG&gt; is assigned to storage type &lt;STRONG&gt;VK01&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;We would like to assign it to the following fixed bins simultaneously:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;VK01_StackModul&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;VK02_VentilModul&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;VK03_VEModul&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;When using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Assign Fixed Bin&lt;/STRONG&gt; app, I added multiple fixed bin entries maintained for the same material within a single storage type,But stock was not moving to other different fixed bin.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/i-am-not-able-to-assign-a-single-material-to-multiple-fixed-bins-in-the/qaq-p/14242428"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:54:46.349000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-mobile-app-ios-version-1-11-23-permission-denied/qaa-p/14242429#M4929106</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Mobile App IOS Version: 1.11.23 - Permission Denied</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:55:30.818000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RicardoTorresDev</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2023127</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Good afternoon, I am unable to access the suggested links. Thank you</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-mobile-app-ios-version-1-11-23-permission-denied/qaa-p/14242429#M4929106"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:55:30.818000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/filter-for-joule-q-amp-a-document-grounding/qaq-p/14242430</id>
    <title>Filter for Joule Q&amp;A / Document Grounding</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:56:00.760000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Clemens_Wieser</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/22688</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am wondering how Joule Q&amp;amp;A / Document Grounding handles different target groups. So, how is it possible to display HR policies for managers or specific countries only to managers or to employees of specific countries? I expected a kind of tagging feature in the 2H25 release. Thank you for clarification.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/filter-for-joule-q-amp-a-document-grounding/qaq-p/14242430"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:56:00.760000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-cloudification-repository-viewer-for-clean-core-governance-and/bc-p/14242432#M185346</id>
    <title>Re: New Cloudification Repository Viewer for Clean Core Governance and Development</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:57:30.255000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>samedtekdemir3594</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/833554</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Nice Blog, Thanks. But I have a question. If object is released&amp;nbsp; &lt;U&gt;but&lt;/U&gt; "Use in Cloud Development" is "No" what is that mean? Can we use it or not? If yes, in what abap language version? Is it "Standard ABAP"? Because In&amp;nbsp;Cloudification Repository Viewer I see it as released but If I use it either I get an error while activating it or I get an ATC error(If ABAP language version is 'ABAP for cloud development').&lt;BR /&gt;And again for level B developments, which abap language version we should use in package or in custom objects?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-cloudification-repository-viewer-for-clean-core-governance-and/bc-p/14242432#M185346"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:57:30.255000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/start-your-scripting-journey-the-easy-way-with-sap-analytics-cloud-part/bc-p/14242434#M185347</id>
    <title>Re: Start Your scripting Journey The Easy Way With SAP Analytics Cloud | Part Four</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:58:25.603000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel_Davis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/197717</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;@&lt;SPAN&gt;muddassar91&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Into Q4 at the moment but a ood place to start is here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/18850a0e13944f53aa8a8b7c094ea29e/5f78d999c9da4f75b903271683f0793b.html?version=2025.18" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/18850a0e13944f53aa8a8b7c094ea29e/5f78d999c9da4f75b903271683f0793b.html?version=2025.18&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Will look at more content later this quarter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Daniel&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/start-your-scripting-journey-the-easy-way-with-sap-analytics-cloud-part/bc-p/14242434#M185347"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:58:25.603000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/where-can-i-find-this-app/qaa-p/14242436#M4929107</id>
    <title>Re: Where can I find this App ?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T14:59:24.042000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_w</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1397574</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1916544"&gt;@WUYIN&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;please follow the steps described in SAP Note:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/2787809" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2787809&lt;/A&gt;. After enabling of template development, the app will become visible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further details please check the following &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-extensibility-extensibility-templates/ba-p/13394379" target="_self"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards, Thomas&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/where-can-i-find-this-app/qaa-p/14242436#M4929107"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T14:59:24.042000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-maxattention-events/sap-maxattention-iws-transform-your-business-with-sap-business-ai-october/ev-p/14242437</id>
    <title>SAP MaxAttention IWS 'Transform your Business with SAP Business AI' (October 28, 2025)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:00:07.497000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>paul_schropp44</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/807129</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dear Valued Customer,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are pleased to invite you to the SAP MaxAttention Innovation Workshop &lt;STRONG&gt;“&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transform your &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business with SAP Business AI” &lt;/STRONG&gt;taking place virtually on 28th October 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please find the agenda of the workshop &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/embed/public/pdf/a/kKfoXGG?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1243213" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a unique opportunity to hear directly from our SAP executives and experts covering topics related to how SAP Business AI transforms work by integrating intelligence into everyday processes. You will learn about Joule, Agent Builder, embedded AI &amp;amp; many other capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our Workshops&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These sessions and workshop series focus on a specific topic and the purpose is to enable our customers to understand the product portfolio and innovative technologies of SAP in order to drive adoption and consumption. As specifically now, it is more important than ever to help companies to be successful and to respond to changing markets by transforming into intelligent enterprises in the experience economy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that the 'Attend' button which can be found within this blog post does&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;serve as a formal registration for the event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To officially register, please reach out to me,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0070f2"&gt;&lt;U&gt;paul.schropp@sap.com&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;and I will ensure that your registration is properly processed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We look forward to having you join us for our upcoming events and thank you for your understanding!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feel free to share your feedback and thoughts in the comment section below.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-maxattention-events/sap-maxattention-iws-transform-your-business-with-sap-business-ai-october/ev-p/14242437"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:00:07.497000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/limit-the-use-of-compensation-executive-review-filters-rbp/qaa-p/14242438#M48651</id>
    <title>Re: Limit the use of Compensation executive review filter...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:00:13.127000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>3596977</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35542</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Update: an enhancement request has been created for this &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/358422/?section=sectionDetails" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/358422/?section=sectionDetails&lt;/A&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/limit-the-use-of-compensation-executive-review-filters-rbp/qaa-p/14242438#M48651"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:00:13.127000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/limit-the-use-of-compensation-executive-review-filters-rbp/qaa-p/14242439#M48652</id>
    <title>Re: Limit the use of Compensation executive review filter...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:00:54.943000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>3596977</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35542</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello, a new enhancement has been created for this : &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/358422/?section=sectionDetails" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/358422/?section=sectionDetails&lt;/A&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/limit-the-use-of-compensation-executive-review-filters-rbp/qaa-p/14242439#M48652"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:00:54.943000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/collecting-vaccine-data-from-onboardee-with-sap-successfactors-onboarding/bc-p/14242441#M9307</id>
    <title>Re: Collecting Vaccine Data from Onboardee with SAP SuccessFactors Onboarding</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:03:52.754000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NatalieVR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/84155</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi! Your blog was very helpful while setting up a similar requirements. The main difference is we needed the possibility to add multiple records and hence worked with a parent-child object. While this works perfectly in EC and ONB, the integration doesn't cover all use cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How would you set this up to collect all records from ONB and put them in EC?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Natalie&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/collecting-vaccine-data-from-onboardee-with-sap-successfactors-onboarding/bc-p/14242441#M9307"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:03:52.754000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/batch-derivation-in-process-manufacturing/bc-p/14242443#M72131</id>
    <title>Re: Batch Derivation in Process Manufacturing</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:04:40.123000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Swapnil1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/156018</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have a question. I followed each step, and the process works correctly in the scenario where the process order for the component is created and the goods receipt (GR) is already posted before creating the process order for the header material. However, in another scenario where the process order for the component is created but the GR is still pending, and we then create the process order for the header material and assign the component batch, the issue occurs. When we later post the GR for the component first and then for the header material, the batch derivation process for SLED does not work, even though all the details are entered correctly.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/batch-derivation-in-process-manufacturing/bc-p/14242443#M72131"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:04:40.123000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/the-profit-center-is-automatically-assigned-with-an-unintended-value/qaa-p/14242444#M255771</id>
    <title>Re: The profit center is automatically assigned with an u...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:04:53.770000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AT_1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2100740</uri>
    </author>
    <content>And not to forget, FAGL3KEH</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/the-profit-center-is-automatically-assigned-with-an-unintended-value/qaa-p/14242444#M255771"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:04:53.770000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/capturing-2-stip-emp-group-on-worksheet-in-sap-sf-vpay/qaa-p/14242448#M48653</id>
    <title>Re: Capturing 2 STIP EMP group on Worksheet in SAP SF VPay</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:07:54.339000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RituSingh12</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1395772</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks, Xavire, for the input—and apologies for the delayed response. I’ll definitely try this out. I also wanted to highlight that the current system isn’t displaying the STIP employee group at either the entry level or assignment level. Right now, we’re reviewing bonus plan details at the assignment level, but the payment isn’t an aggregate of all bonus plans. On the customer side, this setup is slightly different.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/capturing-2-stip-emp-group-on-worksheet-in-sap-sf-vpay/qaa-p/14242448#M48653"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:07:54.339000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/fun-for-week-2-petoberfest/bc-p/14242449#M1008</id>
    <title>Re: 🟡 Fun for Week 2: Petoberfest 🐱🐶🐵🐷🐻🐸🐔🐴🦬🦎🐠🦜🐧🐌🐛</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:07:57.659000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Swetha__Balusamy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1487178</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;My Bunny is getting hands-on on SAP Tech.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Gemini_Generated_Image_lrbzrtlrbzrtlrbz.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326750i88BAF12EEE1F1797/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Gemini_Generated_Image_lrbzrtlrbzrtlrbz.png" alt="Gemini_Generated_Image_lrbzrtlrbzrtlrbz.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/fun-for-week-2-petoberfest/bc-p/14242449#M1008"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:07:57.659000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/grouping-multiple-dunning-letters-into-a-single-notice/qaa-p/14242450#M255772</id>
    <title>Re: Grouping Multiple Dunning Letters into a Single Notice</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:08:32.666000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JonathanEemans</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/173593</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The field 'Account Number of the Dunning Recipient' at company code level of the Business Partner, allows you to enter the account number of the customer who is to be the recipient of the dunning letters&amp;nbsp;if dunning letters are not sent to the customer who owes the receivables.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Jonathan&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/grouping-multiple-dunning-letters-into-a-single-notice/qaa-p/14242450#M255772"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:08:32.666000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/make-ppr0-mandatory-so-cannot-be-saved-if-ppr0-is-missing/qaa-p/14242461#M4229306</id>
    <title>Re: Make PPR0 Mandatory (SO cannot be saved if PPR0 is mi...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:23:46.278000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Juwin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/169790</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Assign the value of PPR0 to an unused Subtotal field. After that, you may implement a BADI to check if the Subtotal field is blank or not and then throw error accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/make-ppr0-mandatory-so-cannot-be-saved-if-ppr0-is-missing/qaa-p/14242461#M4229306"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:23:46.278000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/upload-customer-open-items-f4051-error-ki235-account-requires-relevant-to/qaq-p/14242473</id>
    <title>Upload Customer Open Items (F4051). Error KI235 Account requires relevant to cost accounting</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:28:31.383000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marco_correa2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/248473</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm writing this issue that I been having from a while in fiori app&amp;nbsp;Upload Customer Open Items (F4051), in a system where CO-PA is active.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Full message is:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1891824898"&gt;Account &amp;amp; requires an account assignment relevant to cost accounting&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Message No. KI235&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1695311393"&gt;Diagnosis&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;You have not defined a CO account assignment for an account that is relevant to cost accounting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1498797888"&gt;System Response&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Account &amp;amp; is defined as a cost element.&lt;BR /&gt;This means that you must always specify a CO account assignment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1302284383"&gt;Procedure&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Enter one of the following CO account assignments:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Order&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cost center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;cost center/ activity type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales order item&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(for a project or cost relevant)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Project&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;WBS element&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cost object (Process manufacturing)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network&lt;/STRONG&gt;/&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network activity&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Profitability segment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real estate object&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The posting row affected is 000, account &amp;amp;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/upload-customer-open-items-f4051-error-ki235-account-requires-relevant-to/qaq-p/14242473"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:28:31.383000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extend-the-manage-purchase-order-fiori-app-f0842a-with-an-existing-field/qaa-p/14242472#M4929108</id>
    <title>Re: Extend the Manage Purchase Order FIORI app (F0842A) w...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:28:36.776000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jay_d1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/592778</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hello,</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extend-the-manage-purchase-order-fiori-app-f0842a-with-an-existing-field/qaa-p/14242472#M4929108"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:28:36.776000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sampling-scheme-iso-sampling-templates/qaa-p/14242475#M4229308</id>
    <title>Re: sampling scheme ISO sampling templates</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:29:06.764000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1489983"&gt;@Haily&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for the follow-up. Here’s how this works in S/4HANA Public Cloud Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;ISO templates&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;S/4HANA Cloud doesn’t ship pre-configured ISO 2859/AQL sampling templates like ByDesign. You model your own Sampling Scheme and use it via a Sampling Procedure (classic apps QDP1/QDP2 and QDV1 in the launchpad). &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/s4hana-best-practices/create-quality-inspection-plan-bnq-9e1260523b19973ec4afb5e39659f16a/24604ba603594869b91caa4cf993e35b.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2502" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Create Quality Inspection Plan (BNQ)-Create Sampling Procedure (Optional)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;What the C/D columns signify (C1/D1, C2/D2, ...) and how the system selects them.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For attributive plans: C equals acceptance number, D equals rejection number. C1/D1 apply to the first evaluation; if the result is inconclusive, the system can use C2/D2 with a second sample, and so on (double or multiple sampling). For a single-sample plan that can auto-decide, set D1 as C1 plus 1. &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/configuring-sap-s-4hana-quality-management/setting-up-sample-determination" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning-Setting up Sample Determination&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which &lt;EM&gt;row&lt;/EM&gt; is used comes from your lot-size band, which &lt;EM&gt;table/stage&lt;/EM&gt; (reduced/normal/tightened) comes from the Dynamic Modification Rule (DMR) and current quality level. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d1e58be39d884a0dbf75a7526a9acbf4/196cb65334e6b54ce10000000a174cb4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Quality Management-Creating a Dynamic Modification Rule&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Make it automatic -no manual Usage Decision&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configure the Sampling Procedure for attributive valuation so the system can decide to accept/reject from your C/D numbers when results are saved. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/s4hana-best-practices/create-quality-inspection-plan-bnq-9e1260523b19973ec4afb5e39659f16a/24604ba603594869b91caa4cf993e35b.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2502" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal-Create Quality Inspection Plan (BNQ)-Create Sampling Procedure (Optional)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the Usage Decision (UD) itself, run the Schedule Automatic Usage Decisions (For Production) job to post UDs automatically for eligible lots. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/d1e58be39d884a0dbf75a7526a9acbf4/889dd87ab30c458ead57e61940dda908.html?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With kind regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/sampling-scheme-iso-sampling-templates/qaa-p/14242475#M4229308"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:29:06.764000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/unable-to-post-direct-activity-allocation-to-event-based-investment-project/qaa-p/14242477#M255773</id>
    <title>Re: Unable to Post Direct Activity Allocation to Event-Ba...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:30:03.176000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMMED_BASER</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2253375</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Vero,&lt;BR /&gt;As per my understanding after reviewing your message and you are right, there are specific restrictions and configuration requirements for direct activity allocation to event-based investment projects in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud. These differ from traditional project types and may prevent postings even if cost center, activity type, and account settings are correct.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please follow below mentioned points for Event-Based Investment Projects&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Event-Based Settlement Behavior&lt;BR /&gt;Event-based investment projects use event-driven posting logic for settlement and capitalization. This differs from periodic settlement used in traditional investment projects. Direct activity allocation (via F3697A) may not be supported for WBS elements in event-based investment projects because the system expects costs to be posted through event-based mechanisms like time confirmations or procurement events.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Account Assignment Activation (KI153)&lt;BR /&gt;The error KI153 indicates that account assignment to activity types is not activated for fiscal year 2025 in CO area A000. Even if this setup works for other project types, event-based projects may require explicit activation of account assignment for each fiscal year due to their unique posting logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can check this in the configuration under:&lt;BR /&gt;SSCUI: Activate Account Assignment to Activity Types&lt;BR /&gt;Path: Manage Your Solution &amp;gt; Configure Your Solution &amp;gt; Application Area: Controlling &amp;gt; Sub Area: Cost Center Accounting&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Account Blocked for Posting&lt;BR /&gt;The error about Account 55110000 0030 being blocked suggests that the account is either, Not allowed for postings to investment projects with event-based settlement or Blocked for specific transaction types or object classes (e.g., WBS elements with investment profile).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You should verify the account settings in:&lt;BR /&gt;SSCUI: Manage G/L Account Master Data&lt;BR /&gt;Check: Posting Block, Validity Period, and Allowed Object Types&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;4. WBS Element Configuration&lt;BR /&gt;Event-based investment WBS elements may have restrictions on cost object types that can post to them.&lt;BR /&gt;Ensure the WBS element is, Released and not locked.&lt;BR /&gt;Assigned to an investment profile that allows internal activity allocation.&lt;BR /&gt;Not marked exclusively for procurement or asset under construction postings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this will help you to configure Event-Based Investment Projects&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/unable-to-post-direct-activity-allocation-to-event-based-investment-project/qaa-p/14242477#M255773"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:30:03.176000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extend-the-manage-purchase-order-fiori-app-f0842a-with-an-existing-field/qaa-p/14242478#M4929109</id>
    <title>Re: Extend the Manage Purchase Order FIORI app (F0842A) w...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:34:05.212000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jay_d1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/592778</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks for the response. But the field is not a custom field. It's a standard field BEDNR in EKPO.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extend-the-manage-purchase-order-fiori-app-f0842a-with-an-existing-field/qaa-p/14242478#M4929109"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:34:05.212000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/replacement-of-string-amp-3-not-possible-in-cds-view/qaa-p/14242479#M4929110</id>
    <title>Re: Replacement of string '&amp;3' not possible in CDS View</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:35:04.141000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Why don't you want to follow my recommendations? Again, split in many lines (don't keep all compressed), and you'll see the differences. Line 12: missing "AS". Why having different lengths 73 and 76? (code in my answer edited)&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/replacement-of-string-amp-3-not-possible-in-cds-view/qaa-p/14242479#M4929110"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:35:04.141000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/help-needed-your-apps-are-affected-by-google-play-s-16-kb-page-size/qaa-p/14242480#M4929111</id>
    <title>Re: Help Needed : Your apps are affected by Google Play's...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:35:50.710000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Folidol</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1456165</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Jitendra, When is it going to be resolved for Free Edition? (16 KB page size requirements for Google Play)</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/help-needed-your-apps-are-affected-by-google-play-s-16-kb-page-size/qaa-p/14242480#M4929111"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:35:50.710000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/routine-of-a-production-planning-tips/qaa-p/14242483#M207609</id>
    <title>Re: Routine of a production planning + tips</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:37:17.682000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GAAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2179600</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Just saw you comment now! I'll read! thank you &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/routine-of-a-production-planning-tips/qaa-p/14242483#M207609"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:37:17.682000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-awarded-g2-s-fall-2025-badges/ba-p/14242442</id>
    <title>SAP BTP Awarded G2’s Fall 2025 Badges</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:37:38.010000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrisGrundy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171629</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Following a welcome long summer, Autumn has arrived and with it so have &lt;A href="https://www.g2.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;G2&lt;/A&gt;’s Fall badges. And continuing the trend of positive results, &lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/btp" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt; (SAP BTP) has again been recognized with a number of badges, indicating that our wonderful customers continue to report good things about us. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="G2 Fall Badges.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326745i21C11634C21B9DAD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="G2 Fall Badges.png" alt="G2 Fall Badges.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As ever, the SAP BTP team is thrilled to receive badges of recognition from G2, and thankful for the customer feedback that has led to us receiving these.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762742085"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP in our customers’ words&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reviews left on the G2 platform vary widely by industry and use case, as well as in terms of the length and detail that customers offer concerning their experience with the SAP BTP services that they use.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking through these reviews however reveals some interesting statements, which perhaps gives some indication concerning why they rate SAP BTP so highly:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“…overall, it's the best platform I have seen during my professional experience”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; Engineer EE Software&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.g2.com/products/sap-business-technology-platform/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-review-11645691" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Sep 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px lia-align-right" style="padding-left : 60px; text-align : right;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“…the platform has boosted our operational efficiency, fostered better collaboration among teams, and sped up our digital transformation efforts”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; Engineer, &lt;A href="https://www.g2.com/products/sap-business-technology-platform/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-review-11779657" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Oct 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“…this means fewer integration headaches, faster development of custom applications, and the ability to deliver solutions that are both agile and enterprise-ready”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; Consultant, &lt;A href="https://www.g2.com/products/sap-business-technology-platform/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-review-11669903" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Sep 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px lia-align-right" style="padding-left : 60px; text-align : right;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“The primary benefit is having a single, unified platform to manage the entire lifecycle of a spare part order”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Network Development Specialist,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.g2.com/products/sap-business-technology-platform/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-review-11638425" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Sep 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“SAP BTP has helped us unify data and processes from multiple SAP and non-SAP systems without having to build complex integrations from scratch”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Associate,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.g2.com/products/sap-business-technology-platform/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-review-11546690" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;August 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px lia-align-right" style="padding-left : 60px; text-align : right;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“…it’s helped improve efficiency, reduce errors, and create a more connected, intelligent business environment”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.g2.com/products/sap-business-technology-platform/reviews/sap-business-technology-platform-review-11775726" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;July 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With positive statements like these concerning efficiency, agility and connectivity, SAP BTP is clearly hitting the mark with these customers. And this is simply a snapshot of the reviews available.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope that you enjoy reading more SAP BTP customer reviews on the &lt;A href="https://www.g2.com/products/sap-business-technology-platform/reviews#reviews" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;G2 Platform&lt;/A&gt;. And&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;“thank you”&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;to all of the SAP BTP customers who take time to leave reviews and comments for us with G2.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chris Grundy, Product Marketing, SAP BTP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-awarded-g2-s-fall-2025-badges/ba-p/14242442"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:37:38.010000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extend-the-manage-purchase-order-fiori-app-f0842a-with-an-existing-field/qaa-p/14242486#M4929112</id>
    <title>Re: Extend the Manage Purchase Order FIORI app (F0842A) with an existing field from EKPO</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:39:24.067000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jay_d1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/592778</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Thanks for the response. But the field is not a custom field. It's a standard field BEDNR in EKPO.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/extend-the-manage-purchase-order-fiori-app-f0842a-with-an-existing-field/qaa-p/14242486#M4929112"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:39:24.067000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/replacement-of-string-amp-3-not-possible-in-cds-view/qaa-p/14242487#M4929113</id>
    <title>Re: Replacement of string '&amp;3' not possible in CDS View</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:40:56.375000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra_Rossi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145194</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Which ABAP version are you using?</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/replacement-of-string-amp-3-not-possible-in-cds-view/qaa-p/14242487#M4929113"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:40:56.375000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/video-data-story-a-brand-new-way-of-story-telling-in-sap-analytics-cloud/bc-p/14242491#M185350</id>
    <title>Re: Video Data Story, a brand-new way of story telling in SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:44:10.622000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>salmann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2259492</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/178378"&gt;@Lothar_Koeder&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; can you please provide the direct link to where I can find the permission for the &lt;STRONG&gt;Video Data Story&lt;/STRONG&gt; article? I searched on the SAP Help but couldn't find it.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I'm trying to use this feature but even after enabling Video Data Story in the story settings the option is not showing up.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in Advance,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Amr&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/video-data-story-a-brand-new-way-of-story-telling-in-sap-analytics-cloud/bc-p/14242491#M185350"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:44:10.622000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/need-guidance-on-bank-reconciliation/qaa-p/14242492#M4229310</id>
    <title>Re: Need guidance on Bank reconciliation</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:45:10.966000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nithin_pranesh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1439309</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Hi Baser, Thank you for the solution. I have a few queries for clarification: When uploading an MT940 bank statement, what is the connection between the transactions in the MT940 file and the external transaction type? Regarding processing types — in one-step and two-step processing — if we use the one-step processing method, it clears the open item from the bank sub-account and posts it to the bank account. While creating the processing rule, I believe I need to select "Clear in sequence". Is that correct? Thank you for your continued support. Best regards, Nithin</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/need-guidance-on-bank-reconciliation/qaa-p/14242492#M4229310"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:45:10.966000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/reimagining-sap-mdg-field-validations-low-code-approach-ui-field-control/bc-p/14242494#M175935</id>
    <title>Re: Reimagining SAP MDG Field Validations Low-Code Approach | UI Field Control Made Dynamic Yet Simp</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:45:34.837000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>NS3403</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1643609</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Is this way of maintaining validation rules on custom field is considered clean core ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/reimagining-sap-mdg-field-validations-low-code-approach-ui-field-control/bc-p/14242494#M175935"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:45:34.837000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/rewards-and-recognition-remove-redemption-site/qaq-p/14242498</id>
    <title>Rewards and Recognition-Remove Redemption Site</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:47:56.585000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Olskar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1428485</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My customer is interested in a recognition program that includes a points system, but they do not want a redemption site. Has anyone implemented a similar solution or knows if this is feasible?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Olga&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/rewards-and-recognition-remove-redemption-site/qaq-p/14242498"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:47:56.585000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/upload-customer-open-items-f4051-error-ki235-account-requires-relevant-to/qaa-p/14242500#M4229311</id>
    <title>Re: Upload Customer Open Items (F4051). Error KI235 Accou...</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:49:46.382000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marco_correa2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/248473</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I was using a revenue account with category 12-Sales deduction (CSKB-KATYP), and the system was showing an error. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After many tests, I changed it to an account with category 01-Primary costs/cost-reducing revenues (CSKB-KATYP)., and the app post documents without any problems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This means that the program requires the revenue account has category 01-Primary costs/cost-reducing revenues (CSKB-KATYP).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/upload-customer-open-items-f4051-error-ki235-account-requires-relevant-to/qaa-p/14242500#M4229311"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:49:46.382000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/welcome-to-the-future-the-2h-2025-home-page-redesign-in-successfactors/bc-p/14242506#M7218</id>
    <title>Re: Welcome to the Future: The 2H 2025 Home Page Redesign in SuccessFactors</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:57:32.625000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SachinPachauri</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/24035</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/136098"&gt;@AnnyNou&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; I just noticed this option is not visible under company and logo settings.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/welcome-to-the-future-the-2h-2025-home-page-redesign-in-successfactors/bc-p/14242506#M7218"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:57:32.625000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/restriction-for-changing-specific-material-master-data/qaa-p/14242508#M4229312</id>
    <title>Re: Restriction for changing specific Material Master data?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:57:50.802000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chuma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1572960</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1469394"&gt;@Kazuhiro_F&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In S/4HANA Public, you cannot restrict access by individual material ID (e.g., YB-0000, YP-0000). Instead, public cloud enforces restrictions based on business roles using attributes such as organisation levels, product groups, and material types, rather than specific material numbers. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/53e36b5493804bcdb3f6f14de8b487dd/8980ad05330b4585ab96a8e09cef4688.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help-Identity and Access Management-Maintain Business Roles&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is included and what actions you might want to take,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Segment and restrict based on the attribute.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Assign sensitive SKUs to a specific product group or material type, then set Write = Restricted for that attribute in Maintain Business Roles. If you're controlling by product group, make sure the Authorisation Group for the Product Group is properly maintained; otherwise, the restriction will not be enforced. &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/implementing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/defining-restrictions-for-business-roles" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning-Defining Restrictions for Business Roles&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lock the product master (blanket lock).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In &lt;A href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/#/detail/Apps('F1602')/S35" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Manage Product Master&lt;/A&gt;, use &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/f86dc2eb1f8b48c880a7607213104b27/01aeec57f7f2f032e10000000a441470.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Product Master&lt;/A&gt; is locked to prevent edits; you can mass-apply via product maintenance. If you don’t see the checkbox, add the missing catalogue noted in the KBA.&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/f86dc2eb1f8b48c880a7607213104b27/5976593a7c3047e2bb1334a23f7184f0.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help-Master Data-Locking Product Master Fields&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use governance or workflow if approvals are needed.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For change approvals and audit trail, route edits through SAP Master Data Governance, cloud edition (change request workflow). &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/master-data-governance/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Master Data Governance, Cloud Edition FAQ&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chuma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/restriction-for-changing-specific-material-master-data/qaa-p/14242508#M4229312"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:57:50.802000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/gurugram-events/sap-aidevcon-2025-dates-announced/ev-p/14242510</id>
    <title>SAP AIDevCon 2025 - Dates Announced</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T15:58:07.180000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChandraBhushanSingh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/123700</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am happy to announce that SAP AIDevCon 2025 will be happening in the month of November 2025 - Tentatively 1st Nov 2025 at SAP Labs, Gurgaon, Vatika Tower. This is a strictly a REGISTRATION-ONLY event. Unfortunately due to the event attributes and logistic arrangement, we will NOT BE able to accomodate any last minute requests.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If you are interested to attend, kindly respond to this event invite on or before 27th Oct 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join this super immersive experience enriched event at SAP Labs, Gurgaon. As we promised, you will gain:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hands-on Training&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dedicated Mentorship&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Real-world Problem Solving&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hackathon&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To all college students and lecturers across India, we will be providing access to invaluable, no-cost, industry- and job-oriented SAP certifications. Just come with your college IDs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here's how it'll work:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Phase 1: Fill the Survey&amp;nbsp;(Completed) - I have received several responses on LinkedIn and on my email for extension of registration and I am glad to say you can still register for the event from this SAP Community page.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Phase 2: Online Session (Mandatory instructions before the event - &lt;I&gt;3rd week of Oct)&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Phase 3: In-person SAP AIDevCon 2025 (At SAP Labs, Gurugram - &lt;I&gt;&lt;I&gt;1st week of Nov)&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Just bring your learning enthusiasm and your laptop! I'll be your "AIDevBuddy" to help you at every step.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Important Note: This event is open to participants from across India. However, please be aware that no travel, boarding, or lodging will be offered.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/gurugram-events/sap-aidevcon-2025-dates-announced/ev-p/14242510"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T15:58:07.180000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
