<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/members/developer-advocates/thomas_jung.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Thomas Jung</title>
  <updated>2025-07-25T11:30:48.563850+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Thomas Jung in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-january-23rd-2025/ba-p/13994568</id>
    <title>SAP Developer News, January 23rd, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-01-23T21:10:00.156000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FBO4qZLxBPG4%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DBO4qZLxBPG4&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FBO4qZLxBPG4%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="Dev Survey, Cloud SDK for AI, CodeConnect, Wait in BPA, Integration Group | SAP Developer News" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1209403396"&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Podcast: &lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/sap-developers/2025/01/23/sap-developer-news-january-23rd-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://podcast.opensap.info/sap-developers/2025/01/23/sap-developer-news-january-23rd-2025/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Developer Insight Survey &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Blog Post &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/the-2025-sap-developer-survey-is-live-contribute-now/ba-p/13993753" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/the-2025-sap-developer-survey-is-live-contribute-now/ba-p/13993753&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Survey: &lt;A href="https://sapinsights.eu.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_6AxTBFzfczfuoJg" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://sapinsights.eu.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_6AxTBFzfczfuoJg&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Release of the SAP Cloud SDK for AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SDK Release Notes &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/ai-sdk-js/releases/tag/v1.6.0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/SAP/ai-sdk-js/releases/tag/v1.6.0&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Code Connect 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Conference website &lt;A href="https://code-connect.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://code-connect.dev/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Storm Éowyn &lt;A href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/weather/articles/cr46z2dv606o" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.bbc.co.uk/weather/articles/cr46z2dv606o&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;My post-news-item run route &lt;A href="https://www.strava.com/activities/13430153502" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.strava.com/activities/13430153502&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“Wait for an API Call” Step in SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Daniel’s blog post on the new process step: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/new-quot-wait-for-api-call-quot-integrates-processes-with-external-systems/ba-p/13992848" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/new-quot-wait-for-api-call-quot-integrates-processes-with-external-systems/ba-p/13992848&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New SAP Community interest group - Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration interest group: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration/gh-p/integration" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/integration/gh-p/integration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Certification Prerequisite for SAP Build Low-Code Certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Description: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/sabrina-brueck_sapcertification-sapbuild-lowcodenocode-activity-7287391385630982145-4G-c" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/sabrina-brueck_sapcertification-sapbuild-lowcodenocode-activity-7287391385630982145-4G-c&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1012889891"&gt;CHAPTER TITLES&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;0:00 Intro&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;0:10 2025 Developer Insight Survey&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1:14 Code Connect 2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2:32 New Release of the SAP Cloud SDK for AI&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3:17 “Wait for an API Call” Step in SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4:23 New SAP Community interest group - Integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4:47 New Certification Prerequisite for SAP Build Low-Code Certification&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-816376386"&gt;Transcription&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Intro]&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is the SAP Developer News for January 23rd, 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Riley]&lt;/STRONG&gt; The annual SAP Developer Insight Survey is live now. This is the sixth annual running of the survey for us. If you've taken it before, you'll see many familiar questions, things that we use to track trends over time. There's also a deeper exploration this year of topics like generative AI for developers and also developer enablement. In the description section below, you're going to do that. to find two links. The first is actually a link to last year's report. If you haven't looked at that yet, I think you'll find the results interesting. The second link, of course, is to this year's survey. It will take about 12 to 15 minutes of your time to complete. The survey is going to be open for about six weeks. At the end of that time, we'll go off and analyze the data and produce a report that we'll share with you. So I look forward to seeing your comments at the point that we do that. In the meantime, dive into the links, explore it, and we appreciate your feedback. It's important because it helps us shape the programs that we use within the community for 2025. Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[DJ]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Good morning. Storm Éowyn is on its way. It's already bitterly cold. It's starting to rain and the winds are gathering. But I've just got time before I got on my run to tell you about the grassroots annual SAP Tech Conference of the year. That is, of course, Code Connect. Happy way again this year, in the usual place, certainly unruped, in Germany, near Walldorf. In the usual time of year, it's the first full week in July, and we have two usual suspect one-day conferences, the awesome recap and the amazing UI5con, and Code Connect is joined this by a new conference HANA TechCon. So we're also planning to run a couple of CodeJams on the Monday, the first day of the Code Connect week. So let us know if you're interested in those too. For those traveling from afar, there's also an early bird ticket application process. Anyway, all the links are in the description. I'm going to be there and I hope to see you there too.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Thomas]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hey, I wanted to tell you about the new release of the SAP Cloud SDK for AI. This is a great tool for JavaScript developers to be able to build your own custom AI orchestration services and interactive applications. In this new 1.6 release, we see the inclusion of image recognition in the orchestration service, as well as screaming. capabilities in the orchestration client. So if your JavaScript developer looking to get started with SAP AI capabilities, be sure to check out this new release of the SAP Cloud SDK for AI. AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Daniel]&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Build Process Automation is introducing a new type of process step. Wait for an API call. The step lets you pause a process automation. and then let an external system call an API to resume it. When you add this type of step to your process, you are creating a new trigger. But instead of this trigger creating a new process instance, it merely resumes an existing instance that had already been paused by the step. The idea is to allow process automation to integrate with external systems and let those systems take over part of the process and then signal back to the process instance that it has finished. It seems like it'll open up a world of possible integration scenarios with process automation. I've written a blog on how to use it, step by step, and I will leave a link to the blog post in the description.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Antonio]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Holla, SAP developers. Did you know that there is a new interest group in SAP community which focuses completely on the integration topic? This is our place to share and connect with a collaborative community of integration developers. Now, what are you waiting for? Go and join a new group. I'm including the link in the description.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Thomas]&lt;/STRONG&gt; I'd like to tell you about a new edition into the certification experience, particularly for SAP build low code no code certification. SAP is adding a new hands-on practical portion of the certification experience. This is a free learning course that comes with system access to allow you to execute exercises to get hands-on practical experience. This is part of a new effort by SAP to bring more practical capabilities and testing as part of the certification experience. So check out the links in the show notes for the addition to the certification, the particular certification that's involved, as well as the free experience learning journey that you can take to get ready for that certification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-january-23rd-2025/ba-p/13994568"/>
    <published>2025-01-23T21:10:00.156000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-january-30th-2025/ba-p/14002173</id>
    <title>SAP Developer News, January 30th, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-01-30T21:25:58.740000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F8RqkYsvTQ1M%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D8RqkYsvTQ1M&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F8RqkYsvTQ1M%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="What's New in SAP Build &amp;amp; Build Code, CAP Jan 2025, Community on Bluesky | SAP Developer News" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1830869629"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New in SAP Build: Q4 2024 Webinar&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Webinar Recordings (for Public)&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://workzone.one.int.sap/site#workzone-home&amp;amp;/groups/zJfVxkPC5b2kQfs6YahqyX/content?folder_id=TfxCd7kH9hdfZ1hdvxFyBU&amp;amp;view_mode=list" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://workzone.one.int.sap/site#workzone-home&amp;amp;/groups/zJfVxkPC5b2kQfs6YahqyX/content?folder_id=TfxCd7kH9hdfZ1hdvxFyBU&amp;amp;view_mode=list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Blog post&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-builders-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-sap-build-q4-2024-edition/ba-p/13980162" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-builders-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-sap-build-q4-2024-edition/ba-p/13980162&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Code – What’s New January 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product Updates for SAP Build Code – January 2025 Edition: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/product-updates-for-sap-build-code-january-2025-edition/ba-p/13993021" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/product-updates-for-sap-build-code-january-2025-edition/ba-p/13993021&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Deprecation of Java Tools in SAP Web IDE: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/deprecation-of-java-tools-in-sap-web-ide/ba-p/13997766" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/deprecation-of-java-tools-in-sap-web-ide/ba-p/13997766&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Build Code Joule Evolves: Unveiling Multi-Agent Support for Advanced CAP Application Generation: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/sap-build-code-joule-evolves-unveiling-multi-agent-support-for-advanced-cap/ba-p/13995395" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/sap-build-code-joule-evolves-unveiling-multi-agent-support-for-advanced-cap/ba-p/13995395&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Upcoming CAP January Release 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;npm &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;/cds-dk&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap/cds-dk" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap/cds-dk&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CAP Release page &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/releases/jan25" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;January 2025 | capire&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Community active on Bluesky social media&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Community Account on Bluesky: &lt;A href="https://bsky.app/profile/sapcommunity.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://bsky.app/profile/sapcommunity.bsky.social&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Starter Pack SAP Community:&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://bsky.app/starter-pack/sapcommunity.bsky.social/3lfnowo7ykb2l" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://bsky.app/starter-pack/sapcommunity.bsky.social/3lfnowo7ykb2l&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Starter Pack SAP Developer Advocates:&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://bsky.app/starter-pack/sapcommunity.bsky.social/3lgbebsq43a2x" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://bsky.app/starter-pack/sapcommunity.bsky.social/3lgbebsq43a2x&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Starter Pack SAP Champions:&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://bsky.app/starter-pack/sapcommunity.bsky.social/3lgbesf6hqa2r" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://bsky.app/starter-pack/sapcommunity.bsky.social/3lgbesf6hqa2r&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Starter Pack SAP Mentors:&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://bsky.app/starter-pack/sapcommunity.bsky.social/3lgbem6f4u32p" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://bsky.app/starter-pack/sapcommunity.bsky.social/3lgbem6f4u32p&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1634356124"&gt;CHAPTER TITLES&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;0:00 Intro&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;0:10 What’s New in SAP Build: Q4 2024 Webinar&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2:13 SAP Build Code What’s New Jan 2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5:11 Upcoming CAP January Release 2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;6:14 SAP Community active on Bluesky social media&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1437842619"&gt;TRANSCRIPTION&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Intro]&lt;/STRONG&gt;This is the SAP Developer News for January 30th, 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Shrini]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hello SAP developers. I hope many of you got a chance to watch the webinar yesterday on the new SAP Build features released in Q4 2024. There were updates on product-specific highlights on tools such as SAP Build Process Automation, build code, build apps, and WorkZone with some cool demos on the new features. Here are some of my favorites. The design time UI in build apps has been redesigned allowing for a more intuitive user experience. Different pages in an app are easily accessible via drop down. Less frequently used tasks are positioned under app settings. Preview and publish options are now more prominent. In the process automation, now you can create and manage process variants. Process variants allow a variant template developer to create processes with pre-configured settings and a variant management user, usually a business configuration expert can modify the template variant to suit his needs which changes like change or order of variance, modify the start condition, release and deploy variants, etc. In WorkZone standard edition, the integration of Joule is a game changer. Joule in WorkZone provides answers and insights from any connected system via prompts, eliminating the need to switch between different tools and user interfaces. Note that this feature is not available in the free trial. Joule integrated in SAP Build Code, now it's seamless migration of SAP UI5 applications from JavaScript to TypeScript. SAP Build Code has an adaptation editor tool which is a new tool for extending SAP UI5 applications. It replaces the SAP UI5 Visual Editor. There are many more features. release in the last quarter, do check out the webinar recording and the blog post explaining all the features, the link to which are in the description below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Thomas] &lt;/STRONG&gt;My colleague, Shri has already brought you some of the news about SAP build enhancements that were released in January of this year. I want to do a little breakout there on specific enhancements for SAP build code. Of course, build code is part of SAP build build and a little bit. bit of the news was covered in his segment, but for professional developers, I want to give you a little additional information. First of all, in SAP Build Code, we see the new project overview. This is to really replace the project Explorer and give you a better visualization of your project and in particular match up the structure to what you're seeing when you're using the storyboard editor. Next, we see improvements when working with remote function calls. There we've added the ability for the run configuration to be updated automatically as well as support both basic and principle propagation. Next, we see the inline editing for CDS entities. This allows you to edit entities and their attributes without having to switch between the graphical editor and the text or code-based editor. And we see the deprecation of Java tools for SAP WebIDE Now, this is an important note because this has to do with the deprecation of the SAP Java BuildPack version 1. Now, that deprecation is going to take place in June of 2025, and at that time, the older tools in the SAP Web IDE for Java development will also be deprecated. Now, this just means that you need to be using the SAP Business Application Studio, which we recommend that you use anyway. So by June 2025, please plan on moving your CAP Java and other Java-based, uh, tooling-based projects to the business application studio. And finally, the last item has to do with the Joule code generative, uh, capabilities in SAP build code. We see the agent, uh, are the, Joule assistant going multi-agent with the latest enhancements, particularly we see this in the CAP, new project generation. And now what you can do is you can give it a robust description of what you want in your entire CAP application to do, and in a single prompt, it will respond by both generating the application, generating sample data, and generating application logic for what you described. This used to be several different calls and interactions that you'd have to have with the Joule assistant and now, with it being multi-agent, you can do that in all one prompt. So look for all these enhancements in SAP Build Code. And of course, the blog post are all in the links to the show note of this episode.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[&lt;STRONG&gt;Kevin] &lt;/STRONG&gt;The January 2025 cap releases right around the corner and we got some great release notes for you. The new CDS parser replacing ANTLR is almost done. With the new parser, you will get reduced installations and faster parsing, as well as improved code completion. And with the new release, you will also be able to use enum symbols when defining a default value. More enum symbols support will come in the future. And on the Java side, you can now use predicates as select items to evaluate Boolean expressions on the database. Odata v401 allows you to invoke functions using implicit parameter aliases, and this invocation style is now also supported by the CAP Java runtime. And CDS debug has been extended for Java, so you can easily debug local and remote Java applications. And lastly, I want to mention that IntelliJ has now SAP CDS language support. There are even more great news about the upcoming release, and you can read all about them in detail on the CAP release page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Josh]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hey there, it's Mr. Bluebeard, and I hope you are enjoying the blue sky. It is very windy and cold. outside today, so I came inside to talk to you about Blue Sky, not that Blue Sky, but about the social media site, Blue Sky. SAP is getting more and more active on Blue Sky. We've got the SAP community there. They've had a great feature called starter packs. So if you don't want to follow just the SAP community site, but also a bunch of individuals within other groups, you can quickly grab a starter pack for something like the SAP mentors, champions, developer advocates, or you can just continue to follow individuals. I've got an account there along with a bunch of other people that are inside of those other groups. It's just a great place where information can go and live freely. It was started by some people that started at different social media site years ago. And this is just basically a reboot of a place to go for short, micro -blogging, links, pictures, videos to things you care about. So follow accounts like the SAP community or maybe the UI5 group if you're into that. So there are more and more groups popping up every day. And Blue Sky is not just a song by a great band called ELO Right, DJ? It's a great place to go and share information. We'll see you there. Bye.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-january-30th-2025/ba-p/14002173"/>
    <published>2025-01-30T21:25:58.740000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-discussions/wrap-up-and-winner-announcement-did-i-miss-it/m-p/14002205#M1734</id>
    <title>Re: Wrap up and Winner announcement . did  I miss it?</title>
    <updated>2025-01-30T21:47:42.195000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I'm afraid we haven't yet been able to publish the winner details as we are still in the process of legal validation of all the winners.&amp;nbsp; Just one left to go, so hopefully we are close to being able to share that info.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-discussions/wrap-up-and-winner-announcement-did-i-miss-it/m-p/14002205#M1734"/>
    <published>2025-01-30T21:47:42.195000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/sap-codejam-2025-in-herne/m-p/14014468#M778</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Codejam 2025 in Herne</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T21:35:41.562000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I've recorded and connected this with an expert on the team. They will be in touch to discuss further logistics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/sap-codejam-2025-in-herne/m-p/14014468#M778"/>
    <published>2025-02-11T21:35:41.562000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/codejam-in-royal-eswatini-sugar-corporation-eswatini/m-p/14014471#M779</id>
    <title>Re: CodeJam in Royal Eswatini Sugar Corporation (Eswatini)</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T21:38:41.486000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We don't have any experts that can conduct CodeJams in this region. There is an outside chance that we might have an event with South Africa user group later this year and could possibly combine with this request. But nothing is confirmed yet.&amp;nbsp; I can place this in the backlog and contact you if something looks possible. But right now I can't commit to this location.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/codejam-in-royal-eswatini-sugar-corporation-eswatini/m-p/14014471#M779"/>
    <published>2025-02-11T21:38:41.486000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/sap-codejam-2025-in-krakow-poland/m-p/14014478#M780</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CodeJam 2025 in Krakow, Poland</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T21:47:01.605000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have recorded this quested and assigned it to a topic expert who will be in touch to discuss logistics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/sap-codejam-2025-in-krakow-poland/m-p/14014478#M780"/>
    <published>2025-02-11T21:47:01.605000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/sap-codejam-2025-in-paris-france/m-p/14014479#M781</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CodeJam 2025 in Paris, France</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T21:48:13.946000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I believe you've already been in touch with Kevin about this request. I'll enter an issue in our tracking board and connect it with him to ensure it's all being planned.&amp;nbsp; Thanks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/sap-codejam-2025-in-paris-france/m-p/14014479#M781"/>
    <published>2025-02-11T21:48:13.946000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/hosting-codejam-in-krakow-poland/m-p/14014483#M782</id>
    <title>Re: Hosting CodeJam in Krakow, Poland</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T21:55:00.726000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I've recorded your request and assigned an expert.&amp;nbsp; We have two recent requests for Krakow, Poland. Although different topics.&amp;nbsp; Perhaps we can combine them into a single trip for one expert.&amp;nbsp; The expert will be in touch to discuss logistics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/hosting-codejam-in-krakow-poland/m-p/14014483#M782"/>
    <published>2025-02-11T21:55:00.726000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/codejam-in-royal-eswatini-sugar-corporation-eswatini/m-p/14016359#M786</id>
    <title>Re: CodeJam in Royal Eswatini Sugar Corporation (Eswatini)</title>
    <updated>2025-02-13T16:26:59.396000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I'm afraid not.&amp;nbsp; The CodeJam is designed to be an in person experience and doesn't translate well to virtual.&amp;nbsp; For virtual learning we have materials available on learning.sap.com, developer tutorials on developers.sap.com, and of course many videos on the SAP Developers YouTube channel.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/codejam-in-royal-eswatini-sugar-corporation-eswatini/m-p/14016359#M786"/>
    <published>2025-02-13T16:26:59.396000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-march-6th-2025/ba-p/14035999</id>
    <title>SAP Developer News, March 6th, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-03-06T21:10:00.155000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F0fMn7EEqa4k%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D0fMn7EEqa4k&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F0fMn7EEqa4k%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="AI/ML Roadshow, Dev Challenge March, Function Programming, CodeConnect | SAP Developer News" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Podcast Version:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/sap-developers/2025/03/06/sap-developer-news-march-6th-2025/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://podcast.opensap.info/sap-developers/2025/03/06/sap-developer-news-march-6th-2025/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1833737321"&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI / ML Roadshow – India&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP CodeJam Community Group: &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Developer Challenge March - SAP Community Escape House - AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Blog post &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning-blogs/sap-developer-challenge-march-sap-community-escape-house-ai/ba-p/14030669" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning-blogs/sap-developer-challenge-march-sap-community-escape-house-ai/ba-p/14030669&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Code Connect – Call For Proposals closing on 10 March&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Code Connect website &lt;A href="https://code-connect.dev/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://code-connect.dev/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flat Josh travels from Heidelberg to Philly and to NSQ SAP office&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Functional Programming episodes on Hands-on SAP Dev?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hands-on SAP Dev show episodes &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6RpkC85SLQABOpzhd7WI-hMpy99PxUo0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6RpkC85SLQABOpzhd7WI-hMpy99PxUo0&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Art and Science of CAP with Daniel Hutzel series &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6RpkC85SLQAe45xlhIfhTYB9G0mdRVjI" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6RpkC85SLQAe45xlhIfhTYB9G0mdRVjI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1637223816"&gt;CHAPTER TITLES&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;0:00 Intro&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;0:10 AI / ML Roadshow - India&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1:28 SAP Developer Challenge March - SAP Community Escape House – AI&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2:08 Functional Programming episodes on Hands-on SAP Dev?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3:03 Flat Josh travels from Heidelberg to Philly and to NSQ SAP office&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5:04 Code Connect – Call For Proposals closing on 10 March&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1440710311"&gt;Transcription&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Witalij, Nora and Sheena]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Namaste! Greetings from Kolkata, where we had first two SAP CodeJams of our ML/AI tour. Nora, what did we do today? We have the Generative AI CodeJam today, where we use the Python SDK of Generative AI Hub, and we also used the orchestration service of Generative AI Hub. we also implemented a retrieval-augmented generation use case, and we even looked into AI agents. What did we do yesterday? Yesterday we had more fun. More fun than today? I'm kidding. Just wanted to check that we are still alive at the end of these two days, and luckily we are. So yesterday we focused on HANA embedded machine learning, and basically we were going through several cycles of training the machine learning model with the best parameters. And I think that the feedback was great both yesterday and today, but this is not the end of our show. So, Sheena, where are we going next? Yeah, we are heading out to Pune to conduct another AI CodeJam at Bloomberg. And we are not stopping there. We are coming back to Bangalore and conducting two other CodeJams on ML and AI at TCS. So see you soon. See you. Bye.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Shilpa]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hi, Nora and Witalij. Welcome to India and I'm glad you're having some great CodeJams here. While you're on the way to the next CodeJam, I want to talk about the March developer challenge on your behalf. So with that, hello SAP developers. A new escape room in the SAP community escape house has been unlocked and it's the AI room. If you want to try your hands on the Generative AI hub on SAP AI core, learn how to use orchestration service and SAP HANA vector engine, then do check out the challenge. The room will be unlocked until the end of March. Check it out, have fun and escape the room.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[DJ]&lt;/STRONG&gt; The developer advocates run a live stream show called Hands on SAP Dev, as I'm sure some, hopefully many of you already know. Recently, we've been running a series called the Art and Science of Cap with Daniel Hutzel, where we've discussed and talked about and dug into in great depth lots of different influences that have shaped CAP its design. from an art and science perspective. One of these influences is functional programming. And there was chat in the most recent episode, that's part 10, as to whether we should also do some functional programming episodes in general, not specific to CAP. Some folks in the chat during the live stream, let me know that they would like to see some of these episodes. If you want to see some sessions on functional programming from us, then let us know in the comments. Thanks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Josh]&lt;/STRONG&gt; It's a long way from Philly to Heidelberg. It's also a long way back from Heidelberg to Philly. Luckily, we've got our best. Well, we've got this guy on it. Oh, sorry, Josh.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[DJ]&lt;/STRONG&gt; Code Connect, the annual conference for SAP technical practitioners around the world is taking place again in July. First of all, we have a warm-up in the form of a CodeJam, two CodeJams in fact. Then we have UI5Con, followed by reCAP, followed by HANA TechCon. Now, for these three conferences, UI5Con, reCAP and HANA TechCon, there's currently a call for proposals, talks, talk submissions. But the call for proposals is ending shortly, March the 10th. So get your submissions in to one, two or all three of these one-day conferences. The possible session types are many unvaried, short talks, long talks, demos, workshops, hands-on sessions, all sorts of different possibilities. So check out the CodeConnect website, wave and jump to each of the individual. conferences and find the call for proposals submission forms. Good look and I'll see you there.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-march-6th-2025/ba-p/14035999"/>
    <published>2025-03-06T21:10:00.155000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/can-you-pass-sy-subrc-as-parameter-in-class-constructor/m-p/14088632#M2041722</id>
    <title>Re: Can you pass sy-subrc as parameter in class constructor?</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T17:33:18.527000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Personally, I'd use the intermediate variable.&amp;nbsp; sy-subrc's value gets changed so easily and so often.&amp;nbsp; Even doing pass by value as you are, maybe sy-subrc's value is actually getting changed by the start of the call of the constructor even before the parameter is assigned.&amp;nbsp; If you really need a stable sy-subrc value, then copy it to a local variable as you are doing.&amp;nbsp; That's the only way to assure it stays at that particular value state.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-discussions/can-you-pass-sy-subrc-as-parameter-in-class-constructor/m-p/14088632#M2041722"/>
    <published>2025-04-28T17:33:18.527000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-new-york-new-york-usa/ev-p/14099369</id>
    <title>🇺🇸 Getting started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core (New York, New York, USA)</title>
    <updated>2025-05-12T20:14:21.069000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CodeJam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;event is on&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Getting Started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and Python. You do not need any background in the topic, but you should have&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;a lot of curiosity!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this CodeJam, you will learn how to use the Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core to implement retrieval-augmented generation (RAG). This approach improves the responses of large language models (LLMs) and reduces hallucinations. You will learn how to deploy an LLM and the orchestration service on SAP AI Core, and how to query it via SAP AI Launchpad and the Python SDK. Additionally, you will gain insights into key generative AI concepts and learn how to enhance RAG responses.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;free&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;in-person event&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and is planned for&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monday, June 23rd&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;in&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;New York&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;from&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;09:00 to 16:00 US Eastern&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;The language of the event and the content will be in English.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The event is kindly hosted by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.mark9solutions.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mark 9&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. Thank you!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Location:&lt;BR /&gt;315 Madison Avenue 3rd &amp;amp; 4th Floors, New York, NY 10017, United States&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that spaces are limited; we can only accommodate&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;25 attendees&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Register here at the event page using the "Will you be attending?" functionality.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prerequisites:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Any Chromium-based web browser, such as Microsoft Edge, Google Chrome etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Visit the SAP&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;CodeJam group&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for more information on SAP CodeJam events, to ask questions, and to chat with your fellow attendees.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-new-york-new-york-usa/ev-p/14099369"/>
    <published>2025-05-12T20:14:21.069000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-palo-alto-ca-usa/ev-p/14101603</id>
    <title>🇺🇸 Getting started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core (Palo Alto, CA, USA)</title>
    <updated>2025-05-14T19:21:23.841000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CodeJam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;event is on&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Getting Started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and Python. You do not need any background in the topic, but you should have&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;a lot of curiosity!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this CodeJam, you will learn how to use the Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core to implement retrieval-augmented generation (RAG). This approach improves the responses of large language models (LLMs) and reduces hallucinations. You will learn how to deploy an LLM and the orchestration service on SAP AI Core, and how to query it via SAP AI Launchpad and the Python SDK. Additionally, you will gain insights into key generative AI concepts and learn how to enhance RAG responses.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;free&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;in-person event&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and is planned for&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wednesday, June 25rd&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;in&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Palo Alto, CA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;from&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;09:00 to 16:00 US Pacific&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;The language of the event and the content will be in English.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The event is kindly hosted by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.mark9solutions.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mark 9&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. Thank you!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Location:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Labs, Inc. - Palo Alto&lt;BR /&gt;Building #1 -&amp;nbsp;Pebble Beach&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3410 Hillview Avenue&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Palo Alto, CA 94304&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;USA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that spaces are limited; we can only accommodate&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;30&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;attendees&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Register here at the event page using the "Will you be attending?" functionality.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prerequisites:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Any Chromium-based web browser, such as Microsoft Edge, Google Chrome etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Visit the SAP&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;CodeJam group&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for more information on SAP CodeJam events, to ask questions, and to chat with your fellow attendees.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-palo-alto-ca-usa/ev-p/14101603"/>
    <published>2025-05-14T19:21:23.841000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-houston-tx-usa/ev-p/14101612</id>
    <title>🇺🇸 Getting started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core (Houston, TX, USA)</title>
    <updated>2025-05-14T19:27:03.995000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CodeJam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;event is on&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Getting Started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and Python. You do not need any background in the topic, but you should have&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;a lot of curiosity!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this CodeJam, you will learn how to use the Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core to implement retrieval-augmented generation (RAG). This approach improves the responses of large language models (LLMs) and reduces hallucinations. You will learn how to deploy an LLM and the orchestration service on SAP AI Core, and how to query it via SAP AI Launchpad and the Python SDK. Additionally, you will gain insights into key generative AI concepts and learn how to enhance RAG responses.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;free&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;in-person event&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and is planned for&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Friday, June 27th&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;in&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Houston, TX&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;from&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;09:00 to 16:00 US Central&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;The language of the event and the content will be in English.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The event is kindly hosted by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.mark9solutions.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mark 9&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. Thank you!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Location:&lt;BR /&gt;2800 Post Oak Blvd, Houston, TX 77056&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that spaces are limited; we can only accommodate&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;25 attendees&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Register here at the event page using the "Will you be attending?" functionality.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prerequisites:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Any Chromium-based web browser, such as Microsoft Edge, Google Chrome etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Visit the SAP&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/gh-p/code-jam" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;CodeJam group&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for more information on SAP CodeJam events, to ask questions, and to chat with your fellow attendees.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-houston-tx-usa/ev-p/14101612"/>
    <published>2025-05-14T19:27:03.995000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-sapphire-2025-notes-from-day-1-keynote-with-a-focus-on-developers/ba-p/14107097</id>
    <title>SAP Sapphire 2025: Notes from Day 1 Keynote with a focus on Developers</title>
    <updated>2025-05-20T19:09:02.780000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;If you're a developer working in or around SAP, Sapphire can feel like drinking from a firehose of buzzwords. But if you zoom in a bit, this year had quite a bit that’s relevant if you build, extend, or operate on SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This isn’t a recap of every announcement. Just the ones that I thought matter most to folks writing code, managing extensions, or figuring out how all this new AI stuff fits together. It was often the items that I found our team of Developer Advocates discussing in our back channel as we watched the Keynote together this morning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1859646840"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3212.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/263983iBBD32CAE1159DA61/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IMG_3212.jpg" alt="IMG_3212.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember2196" id="toc-hId-1663133335"&gt;AI Runtime, Prompt Optimization, and a Foundation for Builders&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;One of the more impactful announcements this year was the launch of the newly, updated &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire/innovation-guide/ai.html#new-ai-foundation-provides-an-operating-system-for-sap-business-ai" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Foundation&lt;/A&gt;. This isn’t a single tool, it’s a collection of services meant to help developers build, extend, and run AI more effectively across SAP. Personally, I'm looking forward to playing around with this soon. Maybe seeing it some of our upcoming &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/eb-p/codejam-events" target="_self"&gt;CodeJams&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The most interesting piece of the AI Foundation might be the &lt;STRONG&gt;AI Agent Runtime in SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It gives you a way to run AI agents natively, not as one-off scripts or sidecar tools. Alongside that, SAP introduced a &lt;A class="" href="https://www.notdiamond.ai/blog/launching-prompt-adaptation" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prompt Optimizer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, which can take vague prompt ideas and turn them into tuned, testable input saving hours of trial and error. This also promises to make your prompts model agnostic, doing for AI what SAP has done for years when it comes to running applications on different operating systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire/innovation-guide/business-technology-platform.html#new-ai-capabilities-and-enhancements-boost-sap-build" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Studio&lt;/A&gt;, part of &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/build.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;, now supports skill and agent creation with low-code tools, hooks into SAP data, and context via the Knowledge Graph. You can bet we will see a whole more about Joule Studio later this year at SAP TechEd!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3437766/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;OSS Note 3437766: Availability of Generative AI Models&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire/innovation-guide/ai.html#new-ai-foundation-provides-an-operating-system-for-sap-business-ai" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sapphire Innovation Guide 2025 | Business AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember2202" id="toc-hId-1466619830"&gt;Joule Agents: More Than a Copilot&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Joule is evolving. This year, the story was about &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;; modular, task-specific AI workers that will observe, reason, and act.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;These agents are powered by SAP’s reasoning models, built on top of structured enterprise data, and connect across systems. They’re not stuck inside SAP thanks to &lt;A class="" href="https://news.sap.com/2025/04/sap-google-cloud-enterprise-ai-open-agent-collaboration-model-choice-multimodal-intelligence/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Agent2Agent&lt;/A&gt;, a new protocol developed with Google, agents from different vendors can work together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire/innovation-guide/ai.html#sap-expands-agentic-ai-footprint-across-sap-business-suite" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Full SAP Joule Agents announcement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember2206" id="toc-hId-1270106325"&gt;Business Data Cloud: Structuring for AI at Scale&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;AI is only useful if it understands your data. That’s where &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; fits. It’s a harmonized foundation of curated, governed data built specifically to fuel AI-powered scenarios across SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This year’s additions include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://go4.events.sap.com/intelligentapplications/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Intelligent apps like People Intelligence and Spend Control Tower&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A knowledge graph that gives agents and analytics the ability to understand data relationships&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Availability across &lt;A class="" href="https://news.sap.com/?p=233970" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Google BigQuery&lt;/A&gt;, AWS, and Azure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire/innovation-guide/data-cloud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Explore the full BDC announcement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember2211" id="toc-hId-1073592820"&gt;Perplexity Partnership: Smarter Answers with a Wider Context&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP and &lt;A class="" href="https://www.perplexity.ai/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Perplexity AI&lt;/A&gt; are working together to bring a new kind of search-and-answer capability to Joule. The idea is to combine SAP's structured business data with trusted real-time external content to generate more complete, context-aware answers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;So, if you’re asking Joule about something happening within your business, you’re not limited to internal systems. Joule can pull in relevant external information from the web with full sourcing details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.perplexity.ai/hub/blog/perplexity-and-sap-turbocharging-joule-with-real-time-answers-for-every-enterprise" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Details on SAP + Perplexity partnership&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember2215" id="toc-hId-877079315"&gt;SAP BTP: Better Tools, Cleaner Extensions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Plenty of updates to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; this year, most of them developer-relevant:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire/innovation-guide/business-technology-platform.html#new-ai-capabilities-and-enhancements-boost-sap-build" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;is getting more capable. Joule Studio lets you build agents. New tools help you extend apps with less wiring.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-assisted ABAP tooling&lt;/STRONG&gt; helps you migrate ECC code and align with clean core expectations. (&lt;A class="" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OwtRsMRLPYU&amp;amp;list=PL6RpkC85SLQAt9lvPw0gF4E3nwbJD0EUe" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;See recent videos on SAP Developers Channel for examples&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire/innovation-guide/business-technology-platform.html#sap-integration-suite-accelerates-productivity-with-new-ai-capabilities-and-enhancements" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; adds predictive monitoring for APIs and an AI adapter that lets you slot in your own LLMs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;And finally, &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP services will be available through hyperscaler marketplaces&lt;/STRONG&gt; like AWS and GCP later this year.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire/innovation-guide/business-technology-platform.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Full BTP update details&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember2219" id="toc-hId-680565810"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Sapphire 2025 sets the stage for TechEd 2025, naturally. If you want to get your hands-on with many of the announcements from today, then already start planning to attend TechEd or one of the TechEd on Tour events.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Some of the things we can look forward to trying out soon:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;An AI runtime with tooling&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agentic AI that spans systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A data layer built for AI use, not just reporting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BTP enhancements that feel aligned with how developers work&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;If you’re working on AI extensions, modernizing ABAP, or trying to get your data story right; this is the time to get ready to learn!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-sapphire-2025-notes-from-day-1-keynote-with-a-focus-on-developers/ba-p/14107097"/>
    <published>2025-05-20T19:09:02.780000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-sapphire-2025-notes-from-day-1-keynote-with-a-focus-on-developers/bc-p/14107827#M49882</id>
    <title>Re: SAP Sapphire 2025: Notes from Day 1 Keynote with a focus on Developers</title>
    <updated>2025-05-21T13:48:17.503000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/65578"&gt;@VictorHo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- You can watch the replay here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/events/7313561204143120385/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;(3) LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-sapphire-2025-notes-from-day-1-keynote-with-a-focus-on-developers/bc-p/14107827#M49882"/>
    <published>2025-05-21T13:48:17.503000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/sap-codejam-request-for-hamburg-abap-cloud-amp-abap-restful-application/m-p/14119084#M831</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CodeJam Request for Hamburg - ABAP Cloud &amp; ABAP RESTful Application Programming Model</title>
    <updated>2025-06-04T16:37:39.253000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1962728"&gt;@maxstreifeneder1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- nice to see you around the Community.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/sap-codejam-request-for-hamburg-abap-cloud-amp-abap-restful-application/m-p/14119084#M831"/>
    <published>2025-06-04T16:37:39.253000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-topics/bc-p/14127437#M685</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CodeJam Topics</title>
    <updated>2025-06-13T22:12:05.905000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/138844"&gt;@Josh90&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;@That is not a topic we plan to add at this time&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-topics/bc-p/14127437#M685"/>
    <published>2025-06-13T22:12:05.905000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-houston-tx-usa/ec-p/14132176#M903</id>
    <title>Re: 🇺🇸 Getting started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core (Houston, TX, USA)</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T18:13:56.359000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We will supply all backend system access. You just need to bring a laptop to work from.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-houston-tx-usa/ec-p/14132176#M903"/>
    <published>2025-06-19T18:13:56.359000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-topics/bc-p/14142731#M690</id>
    <title>Re: SAP CodeJam Topics</title>
    <updated>2025-07-02T15:17:05.476000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_jung</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10287"&gt;@Jan-WillemK&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;I'm afraid that we have limited capacity to create and maintain CodeJam topics.&amp;nbsp; While this is a very good idea for a topic, it wouldn't be something we can add in the near future.&amp;nbsp; We are currently focused on adding new topics around Joule Studio and Joule for Developers in the near term.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-topics/bc-p/14142731#M690"/>
    <published>2025-07-02T15:17:05.476000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
