<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Artificial-Intelligence-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Artificial Intelligence</title>
  <updated>2025-09-07T23:10:08.286219+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Artificial Intelligence/pd-p/c3c3a408-33ea-4c2a-ae6f-05461e76982d" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Artificial Intelligence blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-assisted-note-corrections-for-project-billing/ba-p/14183763</id>
    <title>AI-Assisted Note Corrections for Project Billing</title>
    <updated>2025-08-19T14:14:10.840000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AjithaNaduvath</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1466698</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Relevant for SAP Cloud ERP 2508.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing GenAI features in Project Billing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the 2508 release of SAP Cloud ERP, we are excited to introduce new intelligent features in Project Billing (4E9) that will revolutionize the way you process your bills. These enhancements are designed to make billing more efficient and accurate, saving you valuable time and effort.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Role of Billing Specialists&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Billing Specialists play a crucial role in reviewing cost postings recorded by consultants working on customer projects and preparing the bill. This process involves verifying the correct net rate, deciding which cost postings to include in the billing cycle, and determining the amount to bill.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart Notes&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One of the most time-consuming tasks in this process of bill preparation is manually reviewing the notes maintained by consultants in the hundreds of cost postings considered for billing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is where the Smart Notes feature in Project Billing comes to your rescue. Smart Notes is an AI-assisted feature that proposes grammatically corrected notes for items of the Time &amp;amp; Expenses (T&amp;amp;E) billing method with notes. These proposed notes are not only grammatically correct but also free from spelling errors.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The biggest advantage of Smart Notes is that you can get these note proposals with a single click of the Smart Notes button in the Prepare Billing screen of the Manage Project Billing app. We support up to 500 T&amp;amp;E items with notes for note proposals in a single click.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexibility and Control&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Billing Specialists have the flexibility to decide which note proposals should be accepted and saved, and which ones should be updated before saving. This way, we leverage the capability of GenAI to make your billing preparation faster while ensuring that the final decision on what notes are saved rests with the Billing Specialist.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The feature best works for notes in English language. But do let us know your feedback for note proposals for notes in other languages.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The notes saved in the Manage Project Billing app are also propagated to the Billing Document itemized list. This means that the note proposals reviewed and saved by the Billing Specialists can be made available in&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the Billing Document shared with your customer. This ensures that the notes are clear, self-explanatory and professional, reducing the time to settle the bill due to unclear communication.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Do check the documentation in the Help portal for more details on this feature&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" title="The Smart Notes feature in the Manage Project Billing app assists billing specialists by proposing grammatically correct notes for project billing request items that have existing notes." href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/baaa95fc66a147689e80e6527f22c0f9.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2508.00" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-Assisted Smart Notes for Project Billing&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_7ujih89v" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To activate the Smart Notes feature, the following prerequisites must be in place:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP AI Units&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule Premium for Financial Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activation Steps&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can get the Smart Notes feature activated via &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP for Me&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; by navigating to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dashboard- Portfolio &amp;amp; Products&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Look for the feature – Note Corrections for Project billing, in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Request Activation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Smart Notes feature in the SAP Cloud ERP 2508 release is set to transform the billing process, making it more efficient and accurate. By leveraging GenAI, we ensure that your billing preparation is faster and the communication with your customers is clear and professional.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We hope you find this new feature exciting and beneficial. Happy billing!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-assisted-note-corrections-for-project-billing/ba-p/14183763"/>
    <published>2025-08-19T14:14:10.840000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/stop-ai-model-disasters-the-application-owner-s-guide-to-bulletproof/ba-p/14182784</id>
    <title>Stop AI Model Disasters: The Application Owner's Guide to Bulletproof Deployments</title>
    <updated>2025-08-19T19:54:00.503000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HadiHares</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8085</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Co-Author: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1779166" target="_self"&gt;Lukas Pätz&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, you've deployed a fantastic application, leveraging the power of SAP‘s &lt;A href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/docs/ref-arch/e5eb3b9b1d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Generative AI Hub&lt;/A&gt; (linked reference architecture)! That's a significant step towards building intelligent business processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a quick reminder: SAP’s Generative AI Hub is part of the AI Foundation. SAP’s &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-foundation-os.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Foundation&lt;/A&gt;, similar to an operating system provides the means to build, extend, and run custom AI solutions and agents at scale. It includes the generative AI Hub in SAP AI Core, which is a rich set of AI capabilities (40+ frontier AI models, orchestration, SDKs, etc.), for productive purpose, running on SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your application runs on BTP, and LLM technology powers the intelligence behind it. But here's what you can't delegate: managing the LLM’s Lifecycle for your application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1608727308"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understanding Model Lifecycle: A Key Distinction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into the model lifecycle, let's clarify the different ways you can leverage AI models:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your self-hosted Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;: You &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning-blogs/bring-open-source-llms-into-sap-ai-core/ba-p/13655167" target="_self"&gt;bring your own models&lt;/A&gt; (e.g., fine-tuned open-source models, proprietary models) and deploy them. This is akin to a Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) offering, where you manage the model artifacts, their dependencies, and their whole lifecycle on your own. &amp;nbsp;This gives you maximum flexibility: you can select, customize, and optimize models to fit your exact needs, including full control over versioning and performance. However, with that freedom comes responsibility. You’re in charge of the full lifecycle — from infrastructure and scaling to security, compliance, monitoring, costs and updates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Managed Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This is comparable to a Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) offering. The Generative AI Hub provides pre-integrated, managed access to various LLMs from leading providers (i.e Azure OpenAI GPT-5, Google Gemini 2.5 Pro, AWS Claude Sonnet 4, etc.). It's important to understand that &lt;STRONG&gt;you do not need to acquire separate licenses for these LLMs&lt;/STRONG&gt;; SAP handles the commercial agreements and technical integration. Furthermore, SAP takes on the responsibility for data privacy and security or confidentiality standards, related to the LLMs consumed through the Generative AI Hub, significantly reducing your operational burden.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the following we focus on the latter. LLMs, the powerful engines behind generative AI, are constantly evolving. Model providers release new versions, older versions might be retired, and factors like performance and cost can change, as indicated by the graphic below. This dynamic environment means that the specific LLM version your application relies on today might not be available tomorrow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AI model releases.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301896i73E7AB56597E6F83/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AI model releases.png" alt="AI model releases.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1412213803"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Does This Matter to You, the Application Owner?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here's the reality: AI models get retired. Your application depends on them. Without a lifecycle management strategy, you're one model retirement away from downtime —and missing out on better quality from newer models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moreover, different model versions may offer significantly better performance. A newer model might produce more accurate summaries which can directly impact your application's quality, user satisfaction, and business outcomes. Not updating could mean missing out on substantial improvements in capability, efficiency, or cost-effectiveness.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344783017"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your Role: Stay Informed, Be Prepared&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your primary responsibility regarding the model lifecycle is to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stay informed&lt;/STRONG&gt; about the models supported by the SAP’s Generative AI Hub, including their versions, capabilities, cost, and most importantly, their retirement dates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Have a plan&lt;/STRONG&gt; for upgrading your application's model configuration when necessary.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's have a look on how you can fulfill these responsibilities using the tools and information available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1148269512"&gt;Staying Informed: Where to Find Model Information&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s Generative AI Hub provides several ways to discover and understand the available LLMs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1080838726"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Notes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;The central source of truth for supported models is &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Note 3437766&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This note provides comprehensive information, including the list of available models, supported versions, token conversion rates, rate limits, and retirement dates. Regularly checking this note is essential. You can access it via &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3437766" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3437766&lt;/A&gt;. Crucially, you can subscribe to this SAP Note (indicated by the star icon) to receive automatic notifications via email about any changes, ensuring you're always up-to-date.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AI model_blog.png" style="width: 766px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301899i3840C48146B28EE8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AI model_blog.png" alt="AI model_blog.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-884325221"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Launchpad (UI):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;It's the natural place for an application owner to explore the Model Library and discover available models and their details. The Model Library also supports through comparison functionalities like the Leaderboard tab. Here you can see similar or better performing models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AI model_blog1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301999i9F964308FCE0DE25/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AI model_blog1.png" alt="AI model_blog1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-687811716"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discovery API Endpoint:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;For programmatic access or detailed inspection, you can use the discovery API endpoint. By sending a GET request to the &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;{{apiurl}}/v2/lm/scenarios/{scenarioid}/models&lt;/FONT&gt; endpoint, you can retrieve a list of all available models, their versions, capabilities, and retirement dates. This is a powerful tool for checking information dynamically. Find further information about that on the &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/AI_CORE_API/path/scenario" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AI model_blog2.png" style="width: 762px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301910i685A4F8E1A5E5001/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AI model_blog2.png" alt="AI model_blog2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By utilizing these resources, you can proactively identify when the model your application relies on is approaching its retirement date and plan your next steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-362215492"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Taking Action: Upgrading Your Model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When it's time to switch to a newer model version (preceded by tests/benchmarks), you have two main strategies, decided during the initial deployment configuration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-294784706"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Auto Upgrade (&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;modelVersion: &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;latest&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works&lt;/STRONG&gt;: When you create your generative AI configuration for a specific LLM, either through &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-ai-core/sap-ai-core-service-guide/orchestration-workflow-v2?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;orchestration API&lt;/A&gt; or as a deployment, you can set the modelVersion parameter to latest. This will automatically use the most recent version of the specified model that is supported.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pros&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Less manual effort. As we support newer versions, your deployment will automatically shift, potentially giving you access to model improvements without intervention.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cons&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Less control. Your application might suddenly start using a new model version which, although intended to be compatible, could introduce subtle changes in behavior or performance that you haven't explicitly tested. This can be particularly problematic if your application relies on consistent LLM output behavior. Furthermore, it won't help in the situation of moving to different models (i.e. GPT-4.1 to GPT-5).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-98271201"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manual Upgrade (Specify &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;modelVersion&amp;gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works&lt;/STRONG&gt;: When creating your orchestration configuration, you specify a &lt;STRONG&gt;particular &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;modelVersion&lt;/STRONG&gt;, like "2024-05-13". When this specific version is close to retirement, you will need to:&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select a suitable newer model version based on your benchmarks using the SAP Note, Discovery API and/or UI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Via our harmonized API in orchestration, it is easy for you to change your configuration to a newer, specific model version.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;And only if you handle your custom defined endpoint:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Patch upgrade your existing deployment to the &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;configurationId&lt;/FONT&gt; you created newly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pros&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Full control. You decide exactly which model version your application uses and when to make the change, allowing for thorough testing beforehand. This is especially important for production systems where behavioral changes in LLMs can have significant impacts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cons&lt;/STRONG&gt;: More manual effort. You must actively monitor retirement dates and perform the upgrade steps yourself.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-413332341"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Choosing Your Strategy: Best Practices&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The best strategy depends on your application's needs for stability versus automatically receiving updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For most production applications, especially those sensitive to potential behavioral changes in LLMs, &lt;STRONG&gt;specifying a fixed &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;modelVersion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Manual Upgrade) has emerged as a best practice&lt;/STRONG&gt;. While it requires more manual effort, it provides the necessary control and predictability. Most application owners prefer not to use the latest parameter due to the risk of unexpected behavior shifts with new LLM versions. By fixing the version, you safeguard against such changes and can plan updates proactively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If stability and controlled changes are paramount, opt for &lt;STRONG&gt;Manual Upgrade&lt;/STRONG&gt; by specifying a fixed modelVersion and plan for scheduled updates. This allows you to thoroughly test new model versions in a controlled environment before deploying them to production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If minimizing operational overhead and automatically getting the latest model version is preferred for non-critical or exploratory applications, use &lt;STRONG&gt;Auto Upgrade&lt;/STRONG&gt; with modelVersion: latest. However, remain aware that behavior might change with new versions and you need to change from model to model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-216818836"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an application owner, understanding and managing the LLM model lifecycle is key to your application's longevity and reliability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Regularly consult &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Note 3437766&lt;/STRONG&gt; and/or the &lt;STRONG&gt;Discovery API&lt;/STRONG&gt; (or the UI) to track model versions and retirement dates. Remember to &lt;STRONG&gt;subscribe to the SAP Note for automated updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose an appropriate &lt;STRONG&gt;upgrade strategy&lt;/STRONG&gt; (latest for automatic updates or specifying a modelVersion for manual control) when setting up your configuration and deployment. &lt;STRONG&gt;For production scenarios, specifying a fixed &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;modelVersion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; is generally recommended as a best practice.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If using manual upgrades, proactively change your configuration within orchestration and if custom deployment is used you need to patch/upgrade the current model version before it expires.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By staying informed and prepared, you can ensure your generative AI application continues to deliver value seamlessly, leveraging the latest innovations from the SAP’s Generative AI Hub.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We recommend keeping a close eye on the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-ai-core/sap-ai-core-service-guide/what-s-new-for-sap-ai-core?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What's new section&lt;/A&gt; for upcoming release announcements and implementation guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/stop-ai-model-disasters-the-application-owner-s-guide-to-bulletproof/ba-p/14182784"/>
    <published>2025-08-19T19:54:00.503000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-assisted-smart-notes-in-manage-project-billing/ba-p/14187340</id>
    <title>AI-Assisted Smart Notes in Manage Project Billing</title>
    <updated>2025-08-22T08:26:15.495000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shubham1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132064</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am writing this article to give some insights on generative AI assistance features embedded in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud products like Professional Services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Overview&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Smart Notes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;feature in the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Manage Project Billing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;app proposes grammatically correct notes for project billing request items that already have notes maintained.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Billing specialists need to manually review the maintained notes in the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Note&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;field in the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Prepare Billing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;page of the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Manage Project Billing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;app. This process can be very time-consuming because of the high volume of postings.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What's New&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the introduction of the new&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Smart Notes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;feature, you can get grammatically correct note proposals for project billing request items. When you accept the proposed notes, the updated notes are available immediately, thereby making the process more efficient.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;U&gt;How to access the feature&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;To access the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Smart Notes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;feature, your business user needs to have the following authorizations assigned in the business role by an Administrator:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Business catalog:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Project Billing — Smart Notes Feature&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP_PS_BC_BILLG_AI_SNOTE_PC&lt;/SPAN&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;IAM app:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Project Billing Request (Object Page)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;F4456_SNOTE_TRAN&lt;/SPAN&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To access this generative AI feature within&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, an additional entitlement and authorization may be required.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;More information can be found here --&amp;gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/99bb1ef3b5ce46c08e64fcfdc6d3882f.html?state=TEST&amp;amp;version=2508.00" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/99bb1ef3b5ce46c08e64fcfdc6d3882f.html?state=TEST&amp;amp;version=2508.00&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition+Professional+Services/pd-p/a421aaac-1912-4fca-b725-00056d7dadc3" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="235-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Professional Services&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition/pd-p/08e2a51b-1ce5-4367-8b33-4ae7e8b702e0" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1199-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shubham&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-assisted-smart-notes-in-manage-project-billing/ba-p/14187340"/>
    <published>2025-08-22T08:26:15.495000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/first-experiences-genai-driven-extensibility-assistant-for-custom-fields/ba-p/14186697</id>
    <title>First Experiences GenAI-driven extensibility assistant for Custom Fields and Custom Logic app</title>
    <updated>2025-08-22T12:37:59.455000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VijayCR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/38084</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These are my first experiences with the extensibility assistant&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use within Custom Fields:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2025-8-21_17-21-50.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303838i783F57E2EB3AE8BC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image-2025-8-21_17-21-50.png" alt="image-2025-8-21_17-21-50.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;You can call the extensibility assistant in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom Fields&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;app start screen, and in the details screen of a single custom field.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calling the extensibility assistant in the start screen:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example Prompt :Create a Z field in the Journal Entry Item Level , Field Name : Reference1 and Field Description : Reference 1_HD , Data Type : Char/Text Field Length : 20 and Enable it for the RAP BO I_JOURNALENTRYTP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the initial screen of the Custom Fields app&amp;nbsp;on the button bar at the top right of the custom field list, you'll find a open assistant button.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2025-8-21_17-12-17.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303839iF3F193801B5C6429/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image-2025-8-21_17-12-17.png" alt="image-2025-8-21_17-12-17.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter the prompt it will preselect Business context&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303829i0ADA22C69C95D8D8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture2.png" alt="Picture2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;After selecting the right context accept the proposal from SAP it will create the field and enable to edit for detail screen&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VijayCR_2-1755798609746.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303715iFBA5BCD94FD90144/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VijayCR_2-1755798609746.png" alt="VijayCR_2-1755798609746.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Calling the extensibility assistant in the details screen&lt;/SPAN&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the button bar at the bottom of the screen, you'll find the diamond button.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VijayCR_3-1755798609760.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303717i8596D6F600936D58/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VijayCR_3-1755798609760.png" alt="VijayCR_3-1755798609760.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;if you want to ask about a custom field displayed on the details screen, you can refer to it using expressions like&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;“this field”&lt;/SPAN&gt;. A common use case is seeking assistance to expose the field through an OData service, UI, CDS view, or SOAP API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VijayCR_4-1755798609772.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303719iD00F7BA0D236F47D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VijayCR_4-1755798609772.png" alt="VijayCR_4-1755798609772.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VijayCR_5-1755798609784.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303718i388E3F194060BEAC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VijayCR_5-1755798609784.png" alt="VijayCR_5-1755798609784.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once selected Press save and publish manually . As you see from the below the field is automatically extended in the SOAP API section based on the prompt .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VijayCR_6-1755798609795.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303720i6EC0323A18B8088F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VijayCR_6-1755798609795.png" alt="VijayCR_6-1755798609795.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use within Custom Logic:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start the extensibility assistant in the&amp;nbsp;Custom Logic&amp;nbsp;app by clicking the&amp;nbsp;Open Assistant&amp;nbsp;button on the implementations table toolbar&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VijayCR_7-1755798609800.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303721i898B43E0622D493C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VijayCR_7-1755798609800.png" alt="VijayCR_7-1755798609800.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;The extensibility assistant will show a list of BAdIs that fit your request or a message if no BAdIs were found.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VijayCR_8-1755798609806.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303722i732E59809D9CE75A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VijayCR_8-1755798609806.png" alt="VijayCR_8-1755798609806.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select and create implementation . This will only help to find right BADIs not generation of the coding in the BADI &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/first-experiences-genai-driven-extensibility-assistant-for-custom-fields/ba-p/14186697"/>
    <published>2025-08-22T12:37:59.455000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-user-experience-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14188085</id>
    <title>SAP User Experience in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-08-22T21:01:41.538000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>maria_silipo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/805536</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Every successful business knows that an exceptional user experience is the crown jewel of their operations. Not only does it enhance efficiency and productivity, but it also fosters customer satisfaction, ultimately leading to sustained growth and success in the competitive market.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/highlights-of-the-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-release/ba-p/14163726?emcs_t=S2h8ZW1haWx8a3Vkb3N8TURSM1RaRlpBQVkyUkl8MTQxNjM3MjZ8S1VET1N8aEs" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; introduces a range of innovative enhancements, tailored to refine user interactions and optimize business processes with the help of artificial intelligence. Let's dive into these user experience highlights that will make your business shine.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;TLDR? Check out this video made by my digital twin to get an overview of my highlights:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_26pcvuqs" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1867064766"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Joule for business&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Speaking of jewels, SAP’s very own AI co-pilot, Joule, introduces advanced intelligent assistance to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, allowing business users to engage with their systems using natural language for quicker and more impactful results. By integrating artificial intelligence within the system, Joule serves as a digital assistant, revolutionizing the way users navigate and utilize business applications. It eliminates technical obstacles by understanding user intent and providing contextually relevant outcomes through intuitive, conversational interactions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/382ChL5?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1166611" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="maria_silipo_0-1755889179821.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304102i54924E2B5E587B9C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="maria_silipo_0-1755889179821.png" alt="maria_silipo_0-1755889179821.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1670551261"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Joule for consultants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule for consultants is specifically designed to speed up project delivery by offering instant access to a unique, expertly curated SAP knowledge base. This includes over 200,000 pages of documentation and content from SAP communities, helping consultants find answers quickly and saving up to 1.5 hours daily. It also features SAP-specific code intelligence, reducing code interpretation time by up to 40%. Overall, Joule can accelerate project timelines by up to 14%, cutting a typical 12-to-18-month project by 1.5 to 2.5 months.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/HRLdeuL?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1200468&amp;amp;includeRelatedAssets=true" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="maria_silipo_1-1755889229983.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304103i66D6940D8390725C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="maria_silipo_1-1755889229983.png" alt="maria_silipo_1-1755889229983.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1474037756"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule for developers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule for developers is integrated within the ABAP development tools to enhance productivity by aiding in faster code writing, testing, and delivery for ABAP Cloud. For environments like SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, it reduces development time and effort, speeding up value realization. Key features include predictive code completion, a chat feature for natural language queries, code explanation, and support for generating and improving ABAP unit tests and test classes for CDS entities, ensuring reliable applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1277524251"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Design updates for SAP Business Suite consistency&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Navigation has become more seamless than ever with a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;newly designed navigation menu&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; that removes the extra click previously needed to reach &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My Home&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Users can now effortlessly access their favorite apps and folders from anywhere within the platform, enhancing efficiency. Additionally, personalization through "All Spaces" further improves ease of use. The introduction of the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;new shell bar&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; maximizes vertical space while prominently displaying the product name. This update needs to be activated using "/UI2/SHELL_BAR_TOGGLE." Please note that adjustments may be necessary for automated testing. The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;user menu&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; has been overhauled for greater intuitiveness, featuring larger images, improved spacing, and an easily accessible sign-out button. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Notifications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; have also been refined for better management, allowing users to sort by date or importance with clear categories such as "Today" and "Yesterday." Finally, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;visual enhancements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in Search and Error handling bring a modern touch to the interface, providing users with a smoother and more guided experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1081010746"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recap feature on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My Home&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Moving on to user-centric improvements, the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recap feature &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;is all set to transform how business users stay updated with their &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My Home&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; enhancements. With a focus on saving time, this intelligent feature highlights the changes since the user’s last login by comparing current data with the past 24 hours. It brings tasks needing attention right to the forefront, streamlining decision-making and increasing productivity by allowing users more time for strategic work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-884497241"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage News app on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My Home&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Meanwhile, the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage News app&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; strikes at the heart of timely communication. It centralizes internal messages and key updates by enabling the creation and dissemination of news articles directly on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My Home&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Here, administrators can control visibility, categorization, and the targeted audience of news content, facilitating consistent and streamlined communication across teams. This leads to greater connectivity and informed decision-making within the workforce.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-687983736"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-assisted UX features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-user-experience-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2502/ba-p/14109621" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In my last blog post&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, I introduced some of our AI-assisted UX features&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, which aim &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to enhance user interactions by making them more intuitive and efficient through AI-driven capabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; With the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; release&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;these&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; AI-assisted &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;UX &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;features are now generally available!&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;We structure them in base features and premium features:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Base features:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AI-assisted enterprise search&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; (available through &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;beta testing in 2502 release&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Users can access business data efficiently via natural language queries&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; enhancing productivity and user experience. Enabling this search feature allows employees to dig through data with queries &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;such as &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Show me sales orders in overall status in process" or "Show me open sales orders that have a net value greater than 100 EUR&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; offering seamless data discovery.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/asset/preview/5036b26df958f4ee2af3e8e904d68003d03e0575?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1166515" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="maria_silipo_4-1755887548085.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304090iFD7C29C1998812BC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="maria_silipo_4-1755887548085.png" alt="maria_silipo_4-1755887548085.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AI-assisted easy filter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;(available &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;through limited promotion in 2502&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; release)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;: This feature &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;elevates &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;your &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;user experience by allowing filters through natural language, reducing time spent on manual input. Users can enjoy intuitive interactions and explore complex filters with criteria such as currency or date range all supported by generative AI. Access to recent and favorite queries further &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;optimizes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; user interactions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/asset/preview/1ca29683ca519d47533648f1d7cb63d9e22c5e64?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1165618" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="maria_silipo_2-1755887351720.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304088i23B3271C19F27656/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="maria_silipo_2-1755887351720.png" alt="maria_silipo_2-1755887351720.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-assisted &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;mart summarization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;(&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;also available through limited promotion in 2502&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; release)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;It&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; simplifies data presentation through rich text summaries of object pages&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This allows&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; for better business data understanding and efficient sharing across productivity platforms&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; ensuring smooth collaboration between co-workers and customers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/asset/preview/5eb5315a29cf741b5630da4a417d895bcef216f2?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1166391" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="maria_silipo_7-1755887717673.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304095iE2F04825D6718663/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="maria_silipo_7-1755887717673.png" alt="maria_silipo_7-1755887717673.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Kick &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;start&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; your AI journey &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;as a&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;n &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; customer or partner&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; by using the base AI-assisted features at no &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;additional&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; costs. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The only &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;required&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; action from your side is the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://sapit-iex-prod-lizard.launchpad.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/9003c169-62d4-4285-b392-9e939ca5d535.workflowexternal.workflowexternal/preship/index.html#/create/1260" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;a&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;cceptance of SAP AI &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;t&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;erms for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;b&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ase AI-assisted &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;f&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;eatures in SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; (by one &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;S&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;-user of your company). Afterwards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; we will reach out to you with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;a confirmation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; of the activation and send over the required, minimal, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;last mile configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; on your side.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Premium features:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AI-assisted smart p&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ersonalization of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;My Home&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; for insights cards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;(available through beta testing in 2502 release): &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Personalizing your &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;My Home &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;receives a smart upgrade through generative AI, adding insights cards directly &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;a mere click. It supports various SAP Fiori applications, offering previews for data consistency ensuring quality.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/asset/preview/1ac19b560d24b84e6a76ce8e7ba25ad71dea1e09?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1165611" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="maria_silipo_3-1755887462698.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304089iE3D0F324C34A9C6F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="maria_silipo_3-1755887462698.png" alt="maria_silipo_3-1755887462698.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;And, as we cannot get enough of our AI-assisted UX, we have some more features&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; waiting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; for you &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;in&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; beta testing&lt;/STRONG&gt; in this release a&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s well!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AI-assisted smart solutions for situations on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;My Home&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This feature &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;enhance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; task efficiency by intelligently adapting the interface for rapid situation resolution. Leveraging AI-driven insights directly from the SAP S/4HANA Cloud &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Public Edition &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;homepage, users gain easy access to essential information and actionable steps. This innovation fosters a seamless user experience, reducing &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the time&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; and effort &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;required&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; for decision-making.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/asset/preview/c75963c4a648d04c71d260fe25026de46a2e07bf?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1206840" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="maria_silipo_0-1755887213978.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304085iEE9CC0AE50031BA2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="maria_silipo_0-1755887213978.png" alt="maria_silipo_0-1755887213978.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-assisted smart personalization of &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;My Home &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;for applications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;You can &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;leverage&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; AI &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to efficiently incorporate applications through natural language instructions. It allows users to preview and select AI-recommended applications swiftly, significantly enhancing the setup process. This feature is particularly useful for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;new users&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, making their interaction with the platform smoother and more intuitive.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/asset/preview/20c5c0442c04a474a698dc41b8f79e877959c189?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1224308" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="maria_silipo_5-1755887617013.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304091i8DA2E4BC9BD14201/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="maria_silipo_5-1755887617013.png" alt="maria_silipo_5-1755887617013.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;A&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;I-assisted easy fill&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This innovation &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;revolutionizes form completion by using natural language input to automatically map text to appropriate fields, minimizing navigation time and errors. This results in improved accuracy and efficiency in data entry, as users can &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;maintain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; focus and streamline processes without tedious form-checking.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/asset/preview/7aa44512af50f48e0008ac24c33878551ceec1c4?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1224347" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="maria_silipo_6-1755887663444.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304093i98F28FFAD6A573F7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="maria_silipo_6-1755887663444.png" alt="maria_silipo_6-1755887663444.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AI-assisted error explanation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; This feature &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;aids in understanding and solving errors within SAP Fiori applications by delivering AI-generated resolution suggestions embedded within the error messages. This &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;facilitates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; quicker problem-solving and enhances user understanding, particularly for newer users needing guidance on error resolution&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/asset/preview/20924d1b41a6ecd5ae4b74f3c087158f1c14ca90?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1166518" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="maria_silipo_1-1755887282900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304087iDB13F45D276E960E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="maria_silipo_1-1755887282900.png" alt="maria_silipo_1-1755887282900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Our b&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;eta testing &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Public Edition &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;offers &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;early access&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to new features and innovations, allowing users to experience enhancements firsthand and give feedback to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;shape the final product. Participants play a key role in influencing development to ensure it &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;meet&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; practical business needs, creating a collaborative link between developers and users for continuous improvement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Want to be part of this journey? Sign up for the beta testing here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3910" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3910&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-491470231"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Collaborative ERP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;: To&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Dos in Microsoft Teams&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Speaking of collaboration, t&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;he To&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Dos functionality within Microsoft Teams &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;gives&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; users the ability to receive notifications of new tasks directly within their activity feed, enhancing responsiveness and efficiency. This integration &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;facilitates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; seamless approval processes, allowing end-users to act on situations swiftly, whether it be within Microsoft Teams or directly through SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition. Th&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;is aims &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to streamline workflows, support decision-making based on real-time data, and improve team connectivity by centralizing task management within familiar interfaces.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These enhancements in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 are designed not only to transform but also to ignite the user experience, bringing an elegant polish to the platform that goes beyond traditional bounds.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find out more about SAP User Experience in this blog series by &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149639" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thomas Reiss&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Want to learn more about Artificial Intelligence? Check out these blog posts by &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/exploring-ai-and-next-gen-cloud-erp-innovations-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public/ba-p/14162730" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Yannick Peterschmitt&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/artificial-intelligence-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14185486" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sang Dao&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Refer to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/Fj7aYy9?h=&amp;amp;ltr=a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;this document&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for more information.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;️ &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From July 21-25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for SAP User Experience as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://chart-bdmaicr0au.dispatcher.eu2.hana.ondemand.com/index.html?hc_reset" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="2502_EnablementWheel (2).jpg" style="width: 372px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304080i437CA085D96F8FA3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="2502_EnablementWheel (2).jpg" alt="2502_EnablementWheel (2).jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-user-experience-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14188085"/>
    <published>2025-08-22T21:01:41.538000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/lead-in-the-age-of-ai-start-with-your-data/ba-p/14193369</id>
    <title>Lead in the Age of AI, Start with Your Data</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T20:39:06.257000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JustinSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1793692</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;At a Glance: Lead in the Age of AI, Start with Your Data&lt;/STRONG&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is only as powerful as the data it runs on. Inaccurate context, broken semantics, or outdated master data can turn automation from an advantage into a risk—costing companies millions each year in delays, errors, and lost trust. &amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud provides a trusted data foundation by preserving semantics, logic, and context of enterprise data. This eliminates manual data work, accelerates decision-making, and enables CFOs, COOs, and CIOs to act on accurate, contextual data. &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Leading companies are already replacing manual workarounds with reusable data products, harmonized KPIs, and automated reconciliations.&amp;nbsp; SAP Business Data Cloud is launching a hands-on webinar series to help organizations unleash speed, trust, and impact with their data.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more:&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5049141/155E33D499506054AF6FD5A553C2BD38/6298861?partnerref=blog" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Getting Started Series: Experience SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Full article: Lead in the Age of AI, Start with Your Data&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Imagine an AI that automatically optimizes pricing to clear inventory while protecting margins—without human input. Now imagine that AI running on inaccurate data: the wrong currency, outdated master data, or misaligned cost centers. Suddenly, automation isn’t an advantage—it’s a risk.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is why data can no longer be treated as a back-office IT asset—it’s a strategic business capability. The companies leading in AI aren’t the ones with the most data, but the ones with the right data, at the right time, with the right context.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When Poor Data Foundations Impact the Bottom Line&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;According to Forrester, poor data quality&amp;nbsp;costs organizations over $5 million annually. Even more alarming, 7% report losses of $25 million or more (&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.forrester.com/report/millions-lost-in-2023-due-to-poor-data-quality-potential-for-billions-to-be-lost-with-ai-without-intervention/RES181258%20" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Forrester, 2024&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;). Gartner research reinforces this reality. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;In a 2020 study&lt;SPAN&gt;, Gartner found that poor data quality costs organizations an average of $12.9 million annually (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.gartner.com/en/data-analytics/topics/data-quality" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Gartner 2020&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;).&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It’s rarely the volume of data that slows organizations down—it’s the lack of business context. Poorly managed master data, disconnected hierarchies, missing lineage, and duplicated logic all contribute to fragmented views that undermine trust, delay decisions, and increase cost.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The typical workaround? Manual fixes:&amp;nbsp;recreating data context,&amp;nbsp;writing custom scripts, and rebuilding SAP’s logic in other tools. These solutions are often fragile, expensive, manual and error prone. When systems change or org structures realign, the fixes can break—and IT has a new project all over again.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The result: every decision takes longer, and every delay carries a cost.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The consequences are real:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Product profitability becomes unreliable if cost and pricing data use different hierarchies&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regional forecasting fails when customer hierarchies are inconsistent&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;KPIs vary between teams because each is working with different assumptions&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The impact on business leaders:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CFOs risk inaccurate forecasts, delayed closes, and loss in profits&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;COOs waste time waiting on reconciling reports instead of driving execution&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CIOs / CDOs see mounting costs as teams duplicate work, rebuild logic, and rely on shadow systems&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Leading companies are changing course—not by rebuilding data outside SAP, but by activating the trusted business logic already in place.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unleash Speed, Trust, and Impact with SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud helps organizations turn fragmented data into a trusted foundation for decision-making. By unifying data across systems and preserving the business context that gives it meaning it significantly reduces the need for manual reconciliation or reengineering.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The result is now reversed because the data is accurate, and actionable, enabling faster execution, stronger alignment, and higher return on data investments.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How SAP Business Data Cloud strengthens enterprise data foundations:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Preserve context natively: context, semantics, logic, and hierarchies stay intact—no rework needed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Deliver trusted, reusable data products: Instead of manually preparing data for every model or report, teams can access governed, curated assets that reflect real business truth.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Empower intelligent applications: With high-quality, harmonized data at their core, applications for planning, forecasting, sustainability, and operations drive insights where decisions happen real time—not after the fact.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Transformation in Action&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Discover how leading organizations are transforming their business with trusted data. Here’s a collection of customer testimonials showcasing how SAP helps companies tackle opportunities across industries—whether through modernization, real-time decision-making, or unlocking new growth powered by SAP Business Data Cloud.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/customer-stories.html?tag=software-product%3Atechnology-platform%2Fsap-business-data-cloud%2Fsap-business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Featured Stories for Business Data Cloud&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Experience SAP Business Data Cloud First-Hand:&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;To experience the power of SAP Business Data Cloud, join a hands-on webinar series designed to accelerate data strategies. Across a series of interactive modules, here SAP’s product and leadership teams guide participants through practical steps to unlock business value from their data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Topics include:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build and simulate outcomes with Intelligent Applications&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerate AI innovation with SAP Databricks&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create analytical models and data products in SAP Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn directly from some of the industry experts on how to turn data into a true business driver.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Learn more: &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5049141/155E33D499506054AF6FD5A553C2BD38/6298861?partnerref=blog" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Getting Started Series: Experience SAP Business Data Cloud&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/lead-in-the-age-of-ai-start-with-your-data/ba-p/14193369"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T20:39:06.257000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-blog-posts/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-sap-young-professionals-program/ba-p/14167164</id>
    <title>Everything You Need to Know About the SAP Young Professionals Program</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T12:40:25.205000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>IrisSanchez</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1443638</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you’re an ambitious graduate looking to launch your tech consulting career, the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/mena/training-certification/digital-skills-center.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Young Professionals program&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;might be the opportunity you’ve been waiting for! This free, immersive training experience opens doors to become an SAP Associate Consultant and kick-start your career among SAP's.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is the SAP Young Professionals program?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is a free, 2-3 month intensive training initiative from the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/mena/training-certification/digital-skills-center.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Digital Skills Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;that aims to equip recent university graduates (with less than 3 years of graduation) with SAP knowledge, soft skills, and certifications that prepare them for SAP consulting-related position within the EMEA region.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Graduates are trained in SAP technologies such as:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/73554900100800000266" target="_blank"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Analytics+Cloud/pd-p/67838200100800006884" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Artificial+Intelligence/pd-p/c3c3a408-33ea-4c2a-ae6f-05461e76982d" target="_blank"&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Technology+Platform/pd-p/73555000100700000172" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;within others ((&lt;EM&gt;Modules may vary by cohort or region&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who is eligible for the program?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Applicants typically need to meet the following criteria.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hold a university degree (Bachelor’s or higher).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Be a recent graduate (within the past 3 years).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Be currently unemployed or underemployed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Show strong English proficiency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Be citizens or legal residents of the country where the program is being offered.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note: Specific requirements may vary depending on country and region.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What does the program include?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Over the course of 2–3 months, participants will:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Earn globally recognized certifications&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gain access to SAP Learning Hub and be trained&amp;nbsp;by SAP specialists&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Develop soft skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Have the possibility of starting your career as Associate Consultant in SAP's ecosystem (partners + customers)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Is the program really free?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes. The SAP Digital Skills Center delivers this program at no cost to participants as part of SAP’s mission to close the digital skills gap and support sustainable employment. SAP invests in rising talent to help drive digital transformation across industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Is employment guaranteed after completing the program?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While job placement is not guaranteed, one of the key goals of YPP is to connect graduates with SAP partners and customers who are actively hiring. Many graduates secure employment within the SAP ecosystem shortly after completing the program. However, success depends on the graduate's performance, certification results, and engagement throughout the course.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to apply?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Applications are submitted via&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/mena/training-certification/digital-skills-center.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Digital Skills Center portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keep an eye on the website or SAP’s social media channels for announcements about new program cohorts in your region.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Written by Valentina Guevara.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-blog-posts/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-sap-young-professionals-program/ba-p/14167164"/>
    <published>2025-08-27T12:40:25.205000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/end-to-end-business-transformation-with-sap-ai-tools-a-practical-example/ba-p/14195195</id>
    <title>End-to-End Business Transformation with SAP AI Tools: A Practical Example</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T19:13:13.366000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sushilgupta857</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/720925</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737749421" id="toc-hId-1738817187"&gt;About Me&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hare Krishna&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":folded_hands:"&gt;🙏&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;I am an SAP BTP Cloud Architect sharing practical insights, solutions, and real-world experiences from the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1542303682"&gt;Introduction: Simplifying Grocery Business with AI 🥦&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":shopping_cart:"&gt;🛒&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Grocery businesses handling food items and eatables want to deliver products faster, reduce mistakes, and delight customers. SAP offers a suite of AI tools that can automate, predict, and optimize business processes. In this example, we’ll show how a large &lt;STRONG&gt;grocery chain&lt;/STRONG&gt; can transform its &lt;STRONG&gt;Order-to-Cash (O2C)&lt;/STRONG&gt; process—from receiving orders to delivering products and receiving payments—using SAP AI tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; O2C is the flow where a customer places an order, the company delivers the product, and receives payment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1345790177"&gt;1. Organizing Data with SAP Datasphere &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":office_building:"&gt;🏢&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":floppy_disk:"&gt;💾&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Combine data from sales, inventory, shipments, and suppliers into one view.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Connect SAP systems and external sources (like supply chain partners and e-commerce platforms) &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transform raw data into business-friendly models for orders, deliveries, and payments &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":card_index_dividers:"&gt;🗂&lt;/span&gt;️.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit for growth:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A grocery chain can &lt;STRONG&gt;reduce stock-outs and overstock&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_decreasing:"&gt;📉&lt;/span&gt;, understand customer buying patterns &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":shopping_bags:"&gt;🛍&lt;/span&gt;️, and ensure timely deliveries &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":delivery_truck:"&gt;🚚&lt;/span&gt;. With a &lt;STRONG&gt;single source of truth&lt;/STRONG&gt;, managers make faster and more informed decisions 🧠.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analogy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Central nervous system – integrates and harmonizes all data from multiple sources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1149276672"&gt;2. Managing AI Services with SAP AI Foundation &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":gear:"&gt;⚙️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_increasing:"&gt;📈&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Provide infrastructure and services to deploy, monitor, and orchestrate AI models efficiently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP AI Foundation handles model orchestration, monitoring, logging, and deployment pipelines &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":desktop_computer:"&gt;🖥&lt;/span&gt;️.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Works seamlessly with AI Core, ML DI tenants, and other AI services &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":counterclockwise_arrows_button:"&gt;🔄&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit for growth:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The grocery chain can &lt;STRONG&gt;scale AI solutions reliably&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;, ensuring smooth operations across multiple stores and warehouses &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":department_store:"&gt;🏬&lt;/span&gt; without disruptions. Managers can monitor model performance in real-time 🕵️, improving efficiency and reducing costs &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":money_bag:"&gt;💰&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analogy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; AI control center – orchestrates and monitors AI models and workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-952763167"&gt;3. Predicting Outcomes with SAP AI Core &amp;amp; ML DI Tenants &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":satellite_antenna:"&gt;📡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":crystal_ball:"&gt;🔮&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Predict delivery delays, demand spikes, or payment issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Build predictive models in SAP AI Core 🧩.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use ML DI tenants to access pre-trained AI models or train new ones using integrated data from SAP Datasphere &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":file_cabinet:"&gt;🗄&lt;/span&gt;️.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit for growth:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The grocery chain can &lt;STRONG&gt;anticipate high-demand periods&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_increasing:"&gt;📈&lt;/span&gt;, avoid perishable food wastage 🥬&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cross_mark:"&gt;❌&lt;/span&gt;, and ensure timely replenishment &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":articulated_lorry:"&gt;🚛&lt;/span&gt;. Predictive insights also help in identifying potential payment delays &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":credit_card:"&gt;💳&lt;/span&gt; or customer churn &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":counterclockwise_arrows_button:"&gt;🔄&lt;/span&gt;, boosting revenue and trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analogy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Predictive brain – builds and deploys AI models for forecasting and insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-756249662"&gt;4. Automating Tasks with SAP Build Process Automation &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":counterclockwise_arrows_button:"&gt;🔄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":memo:"&gt;📝&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reduce manual work and speed up processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Automate routine O2C tasks like approving orders &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;, sending invoices 🧾, and following up on payments &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":open_mailbox_with_raised_flag:"&gt;📬&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrate AI predictions to trigger actions automatically &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit for growth:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The grocery chain can &lt;STRONG&gt;process orders faster&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":stopwatch:"&gt;⏱&lt;/span&gt;️, minimize human errors &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cross_mark:"&gt;❌&lt;/span&gt;, and focus staff on higher-value tasks &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;. Automation ensures smoother operations and higher customer satisfaction &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face_with_big_eyes:"&gt;😃&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analogy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Workflow robot – automates repetitive tasks and business processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-559736157"&gt;5. Guiding Employees with SAP Joule &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt;🧑‍&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Provide real-time insights and recommendations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Joule offers suggestions, such as which deliveries might be delayed &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hourglass_not_done:"&gt;⏳&lt;/span&gt; or which customers need follow-up &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":telephone_receiver:"&gt;📞&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Employees can take immediate, informed actions 🏃‍&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":male_sign:"&gt;♂️&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit for growth:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Employees &lt;STRONG&gt;make smarter decisions faster&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;, improving delivery efficiency &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":delivery_truck:"&gt;🚚&lt;/span&gt;, customer loyalty &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":red_heart:"&gt;❤️&lt;/span&gt;, and operational agility &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":department_store:"&gt;🏬&lt;/span&gt;. Real-time guidance reduces mistakes and accelerates response times &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":stopwatch:"&gt;⏱&lt;/span&gt;️.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analogy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Smart advisor – gives insights in real-time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-363222652"&gt;6. Integrating Security &amp;amp; Identity with SAP BTP IAS/IPS &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":locked:"&gt;🔒&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":shield:"&gt;🛡&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":key:"&gt;🔑&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Secure AI and process automation tools while ensuring correct user access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;IAS manages Single Sign-On (SSO) &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":locked_with_key:"&gt;🔐&lt;/span&gt; for employees interacting with SAP AI tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;IPS ensures only authorized users are provisioned into the system &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bust_in_silhouette:"&gt;👤&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit for growth:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The grocery chain &lt;STRONG&gt;protects sensitive customer and supplier data&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":card_index_dividers:"&gt;🗂&lt;/span&gt;️, ensures compliance &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":clipboard:"&gt;📋&lt;/span&gt;, and safely enables access to AI tools across multiple locations &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analogy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Security gatekeeper – ensures authorized access to AI tools &amp;amp; data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-166709147"&gt;7. Monitoring &amp;amp; Continuous Improvement with SAP Cloud ALM &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":desktop_computer:"&gt;🖥&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ensure the system works well and keeps improving.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Track AI model performance and automated workflows using SAP Cloud ALM &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_increasing:"&gt;📈&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use feedback and metrics to refine AI models and automations &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":counterclockwise_arrows_button:"&gt;🔄&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit for growth:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The grocery chain can &lt;STRONG&gt;continuously improve operations&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":department_store:"&gt;🏬&lt;/span&gt;, adapt to market changes &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":counterclockwise_arrows_button:"&gt;🔄&lt;/span&gt;, and maintain high customer satisfaction &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_face_with_big_eyes:"&gt;😃&lt;/span&gt;. Monitoring helps spot inefficiencies before they affect operations &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analogy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; System monitor – tracks performance &amp;amp; supports continuous improvement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--29804358"&gt;8. Enabling Real-Time Events with SAP Event Mesh &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ensure real-time communication between systems and trigger actions instantly across the O2C process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Event Mesh enables &lt;STRONG&gt;event-driven messaging&lt;/STRONG&gt;, connecting orders, inventory updates, delivery notifications, and payment confirmations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Works seamlessly with SAP Build Process Automation and AI predictions to trigger automated workflows immediately.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit for growth:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The grocery chain can &lt;STRONG&gt;respond instantly to order changes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, prevent stockouts, and ensure customers get accurate delivery updates &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":delivery_truck:"&gt;🚚&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":mobile_phone_with_arrow:"&gt;📲&lt;/span&gt;. Real-time events also help coordinate multiple stores and warehouses efficiently &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":department_store:"&gt;🏬&lt;/span&gt;, improving overall operational agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analogy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Real-time traffic controller – directs information instantly to where it’s needed, keeping the flow smooth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-120936494"&gt;9. Business Insights with SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Turn all collected data and AI predictions into actionable dashboards and reports.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAC connects to SAP Datasphere and AI Core models to provide &lt;STRONG&gt;interactive dashboards&lt;/STRONG&gt;, forecasts, and KPI tracking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Managers and executives can visualize order trends, inventory levels, and delivery performance in real-time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit for growth:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The grocery chain can &lt;STRONG&gt;make data-driven strategic decisions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, optimize promotions, plan inventory better, and track overall performance &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_increasing:"&gt;📈&lt;/span&gt;. This strengthens customer satisfaction and profitability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analogy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Digital dashboard – shows the full picture at a glance for informed decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--75577011"&gt;Architecture Diagram&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;     ┌──────────────────────────────────────────────┐
     │  🏢💾📊 SAP Datasphere                        │
     │  (Central Nervous System – integrates &amp;amp;      │
     │   harmonizes data from multiple sources)     │
     └───────────────┬──────────────────────────────┘
                     │
                     ▼
     ┌──────────────────────────────────────────────┐
     │  ⚙️🛠️📈 SAP AI Foundation                     │
     │  (AI Control Center – orchestrates &amp;amp; monitors│
     │   AI models and workflows)                   │
     └───────────────┬──────────────────────────────┘
                     │
                     ▼
     ┌──────────────────────────────────────────────┐
     │  🤖📡🔮 SAP AI Core &amp;amp; ML DI                   │
     │  (Predictive Brain – builds &amp;amp; deploys AI     │
     │   models for forecasting &amp;amp; insights)         │
     └───────────────┬──────────────────────────────┘
                     │
                     ▼
     ┌──────────────────────────────────────────────┐
     │  🔄🤖📝 SAP Build Process Automation          │
     │  (Workflow Robot – automates repetitive tasks│
     │   and business processes)                    │
     └───────────────┬──────────────────────────────┘
                     │
                     ▼
     ┌──────────────────────────────────────────────┐
     │  💡📌🧑‍💼 SAP Joule                             │
     │  (Smart Advisor – provides real-time insights│
     │   and recommendations to employees)          │
     └───────────────┬──────────────────────────────┘
                     │
                     ▼
     ┌──────────────────────────────────────────────┐
     │  🔒🛡️🔑 SAP BTP IAS / IPS                     │
     │  (Security Gatekeeper – ensures authorized   │
     │   access to AI tools &amp;amp; data)                 │
     └───────────────┬──────────────────────────────┘
                     │
                     ▼
     ┌──────────────────────────────────────────────┐
     │  📊🖥️⚡ SAP Cloud ALM                          │
     │  (System Monitor – tracks performance &amp;amp;      │
     │   supports continuous improvement)           │
     └───────────────┬──────────────────────────────┘
                     │
                     ▼
     ┌──────────────────────────────────────────────┐
     │  🌐⚡ SAP Event Mesh                          │
     │  (Real-time Event Messaging – triggers       │
     │   workflows instantly)                       │
     └───────────────┬──────────────────────────────┘
                     │
                     ▼
     ┌──────────────────────────────────────────────┐
     │  📊💡 SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)               │
     │  (Business Insights – dashboards &amp;amp; KPIs)     │
     └──────────────────────────────────────────────┘&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--272090516"&gt;Industry Example / Use Case Snapshot 🥬&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":package:"&gt;📦&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A grocery chain receives an online order for fresh produce, including perishable vegetables and fruits.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;End-to-End Flow Using SAP Tools:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Integration (SAP Datasphere &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":office_building:"&gt;🏢&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":floppy_disk:"&gt;💾&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The order details, inventory levels, and supplier availability are immediately centralized.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Predictive Insights (SAP AI Core &amp;amp; ML DI &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI predicts potential delivery delays due to traffic or stock shortages and estimates optimal delivery routes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation (SAP Build Process Automation &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":counterclockwise_arrows_button:"&gt;🔄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system automatically confirms the order, checks stock, and triggers procurement if needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-Time Events (SAP Event Mesh &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Updates on stock, delivery status, and payment confirmations are shared instantly across all systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Employee Guidance (SAP Joule &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;🧑‍&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warehouse staff receive recommendations on packing priorities for perishable items to minimize spoilage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics &amp;amp; Reporting (SAC &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Managers monitor order fulfillment KPIs, customer satisfaction, and stock movement in dashboards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitoring &amp;amp; Continuous Improvement (Cloud ALM &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Performance metrics from this order feed into ongoing AI model tuning and process optimization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Outcome:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The perishable order is delivered fresh, on time, and with minimal wastage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Employees work efficiently guided by AI insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Managers gain actionable insights, helping the grocery chain &lt;STRONG&gt;increase customer satisfaction and reduce losses&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--468604021"&gt;Key Takeaways &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streamlined Operations &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":office_building:"&gt;🏢&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP tools optimize the entire Order-to-Cash workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart Decisions &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; AI predictions and dashboards support faster, data-driven choices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation &amp;amp; Real-Time &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":counterclockwise_arrows_button:"&gt;🔄&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Workflows run instantly with minimal manual effort.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Guided Workforce 🧑‍&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Employees get actionable insights in real time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Secure &amp;amp; Monitored &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":locked:"&gt;🔒&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Access is controlled and performance continuously tracked.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Satisfaction &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":delivery_truck:"&gt;🚚&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":red_heart:"&gt;❤️&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Faster fulfillment, fewer errors, and smarter operations boost growth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--665117526"&gt;Ask &amp;amp; Learn &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thinking_face:"&gt;🤔&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q1: What is Order-to-Cash (O2C)?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;It’s the process of taking a customer order, delivering the product, and receiving payment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q2: Do I need technical skills to use these SAP AI tools?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;No. Tools like SAP Joule and SAC provide simple insights and dashboards that non-technical employees can use.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q3: How does SAP Event Mesh help in this workflow?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Event Mesh enables real-time messaging between systems, triggering automated workflows instantly for faster operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q4: Can automation replace employees?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Automation handles repetitive tasks, allowing employees to focus on higher-value work and make smarter decisions with AI guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q5: How does SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) add value?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAC converts data and AI predictions into dashboards and KPIs, enabling strategic and operational decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q6: How is data security ensured?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP BTP IAS/IPS manages user authentication and provisioning, ensuring only authorized access to AI tools and sensitive data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q7: How do I measure improvement?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Cloud ALM tracks system performance, AI model effectiveness, and workflow efficiency for continuous improvement.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/end-to-end-business-transformation-with-sap-ai-tools-a-practical-example/ba-p/14195195"/>
    <published>2025-08-27T19:13:13.366000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/no-more-guesswork-joule-s-help-content-makes-sap-fieldglass-easy-to-use/ba-p/14195562</id>
    <title>No More Guesswork: Joule’s Help Content Makes SAP Fieldglass Easy to Use</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T21:00:08.741000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>HowardT</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/157893</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Joule for SAP Fieldglass is a productivity accelerator embedded directly into your SAP Fieldglass experience. Joule uses natural language processing to help users complete tasks, retrieve documentation, and make decisions faster—all without leaving the application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're creating job postings or navigating other tasks, Joule delivers smart, contextual guidance. It’s like having a support expert built right in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="usecaseimgoingoutonvacationhowdoiassignaproxy" id="toc-hId-1867903654"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Case: “I’m going out on vacation—how do I assign a proxy?”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a common need in SAP Fieldglass ensuring continuity for tasks while away.&amp;nbsp; Instead of digging through manuals users can ask Joule:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;“I’m going out on vacation—how do I assign a proxy?”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule delivers the relevant help documentation from the SAP Help Portal, complete with step-by-step instructions.&amp;nbsp;This access to help content empowers users to self-serve confidently—boosting adoption and user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HowardT_0-1756319728147.png" style="width: 316px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305642i1CDECD141D57FFA3/image-dimensions/316x512/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="316" height="512" role="button" title="HowardT_0-1756319728147.png" alt="HowardT_0-1756319728147.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="HowardT_1-1756319752963.png" style="width: 294px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305643i05004C8185D237DD/image-dimensions/294x534/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="294" height="534" role="button" title="HowardT_1-1756319752963.png" alt="HowardT_1-1756319752963.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Joule, SAP Fieldglass becomes intuitive, responsive, and user-friendly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="usecaseimgoingoutonvacationhowdoiassignaproxy" id="toc-hId-1671390149"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) To see more uses cases see the help documentation here -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/76e97fe0cccf4d37a5dadc652a375e33/e3dc12e0215447cfa4507eff66e8224b.html?q=joule+for+fieldglass&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/76e97fe0cccf4d37a5dadc652a375e33/e3dc12e0215447cfa4507eff66e8224b.html?q=joule+for+fieldglass&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) Register for the upcoming webinar entitled &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;AI in SAP Fieldglass – Current Capabilities &amp;amp; Innovations&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5044009/B1F114D7F58F199C9B327A0AF0C678ED/5192177?mr=s" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5044009/B1F114D7F58F199C9B327A0AF0C678ED/5192177?mr=s&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;or catch the replay:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4435612&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=A3DE53CEDE437303128D05B9BAC0AFFA&amp;amp;groupId=6091913&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4435612&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=A3DE53CEDE437303128D05B9BAC0AFFA&amp;amp;groupId=6091913&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3) Reach out to your Customer Success Manager for more information.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/no-more-guesswork-joule-s-help-content-makes-sap-fieldglass-easy-to-use/ba-p/14195562"/>
    <published>2025-08-27T21:00:08.741000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/process-aware-agentic-testing-of-sap-with-int4-suite/ba-p/14196856</id>
    <title>Process-Aware Agentic Testing of SAP with Int4 Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T10:55:30.207000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichalKrawczyk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45785</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process-Aware Agentic Testing of SAP with Int4 Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s start with a simple example every SAP consultant knows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Case: Create Standard Sales Order (VA01)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enter transaction code VA01 in the command box.&lt;BR /&gt;Expected Result: “Create Sales Order” initial screen is displayed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2:&lt;/STRONG&gt; On the initial screen, enter details like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Order Type: &amp;lt;ip_Order_Type&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales Organization: &amp;lt;ip_Sales_Org&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Distribution Channel: &amp;lt;ip_distr_channel&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Division: &amp;lt;ip_division&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Click Enter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enter header details such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PO Number: &amp;lt;ip_PO_number&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sold-to Party: &amp;lt;ip_sold_to_party&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ship-to Party: &amp;lt;ip_ship_to_party&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PO Date: &amp;lt;ip_PO_date&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enter item details:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Material: &amp;lt;ip_Material&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Order Quantity: &amp;lt;ip_Order_qty&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Plant: &amp;lt;ip_plant&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 6:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Click Save.&lt;BR /&gt;Expected Result: &lt;EM&gt;“Standard Order XXXXXX has been saved.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looks perfect on paper. But in real life, there are two big problems:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where to get the correct data to start the test?&lt;/STRONG&gt; A VA01 script needs valid values for customer, material, plant, and so on. Guesswork doesn’t work. The best source is historical data already posted on production by one of the integrations. Int4 Suite can use millions of these API transactions as the foundation for realistic tests.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="data_1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305816i65B1E447CC06E5A0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="data_1.png" alt="data_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What if the required master or stock data is missing in test?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Even with a historical sales order in hand, posting might fail because the material never existed in the test system, the customer master is missing, or there’s no stock. This is where Int4 Suite acts agentically: it can copy the missing material from production, create stock via another API, and retry posting automatically.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="screen.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305817iE9BFC67A44ABAE98/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="screen.png" alt="screen.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the heart of &lt;STRONG&gt;Process-Aware Agentic Testing&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Process-aware, because the software knows what data and conditions are needed for the test. Agentic, because it acts on its own to prepare that business context and complete the transaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And this problem is not limited to VA01. In many SAP projects, test automation still works in a very “dry” way. A tool calls a transaction with some example data and checks the response. Technically it works, but it’s not how real business runs. It’s like testing a car engine without fuel in the tank, without air in the tires, and without a driver inside. The engine starts, but you can’t really drive anywhere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dry testing always brings the same frustrations:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Functinal consultants must provide “reference data”,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;missing objects must be prepared manually – by functional consultants,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;results are very hard to repeat.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Int4 Suite changes this. With access to millions of historical API transactions and the ability to prepare business objects through SAP S/4HANA APIs, it makes every test run in full business context.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example 1:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Posting a historical sales order fails because the material is missing. Int4 Suite copies the material from production, creates stock, and retries the posting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example 2:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Testing a delivery fails because the sales order doesn’t exist in test. Int4 Suite can post a new sales order via API based on historical data, and then create the delivery.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For SAP S/4HANA projects, this is a new paradigm. Instead of brittle scripts and endless manual setup, you get &lt;STRONG&gt;agentic, process-aware testing&lt;/STRONG&gt;: tests that adapt, prepare their own data, and validate full business processes end-to-end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short: don’t just test if a transaction runs. Test if it runs &lt;STRONG&gt;with the right business context&lt;/STRONG&gt;. That’s the future of SAP testing with Int4 Suite.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/process-aware-agentic-testing-of-sap-with-int4-suite/ba-p/14196856"/>
    <published>2025-08-28T10:55:30.207000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/realizing-ai-s-potential-in-and-through-sap-integration-suite/ba-p/14193578</id>
    <title>Realizing AI’s Potential in and Through SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T12:23:42.890000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Elaine_w</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1779375</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1609678671"&gt;&lt;FONT size="6" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;izing AI’s Potential in and Through SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is reshaping how enterprises approach integration, simplifying complex processes, reducing manual effort, and unlocking new levels of agility. In SAP Integration Suite, AI is more than just a trend: it&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;is both a set of powerful capabilities enhancing in&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;tegration today, and a key enabler for intelligent, connected systems in the future.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI in Integration Suite&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – Intelligence is embedded directly into the product to enhance developer productivity, improve operational efficiency, and accelerate time to cloud through features like flow generation and optimization, anomaly detection, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;intelligent troubleshooting and monitoring.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration Suite for AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – SAP Integration Suite also plays a vital role in enabling next-generation AI scenarios. It acts as the integration foundation for orchestrating autonomous, context-aware agents and supporting seamless interaction between AI systems and enterprise landscapes, backed by the governance and scalability that modern businesses need.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog offers a practical overview of SAP Integration Suite’s evolving AI capabilities, highlighting how AI is embedded in SAP Integration Suite today, how it maps to key integration needs, and how it enables customers to build toward an AI-augmented future.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1542247885"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI in Integration Suite: Embedded Intelligence in Action&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is not an isolated feature in SAP Integration Suite, instead, it’s woven into the platform to enhance how integrations are designed, built, and operated. Our embedded AI capabilities focus on delivering real, day-to-day value across two core dimensions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Improve developer productivity&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Enhance operational excellence&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here’s how embedded intelligence is making an impact in these areas:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1474817099"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improve Developer Productivity&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Designing integrations can be &lt;FONT size="3"&gt;time-consuming,&lt;/FONT&gt; es&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;pecially when d&lt;/FONT&gt;ealing with complex mappings, unfamiliar systems, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;or writing custom scripts to handle specific logic&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. SAP Integration Suite embeds AI to streamline this process and help developers move faster with greater confidence.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/creating-integration-flow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;iFlow Creation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Developers can now generate integration flows simply by describing the scenario in natural language. This generative AI capability interprets the intent, assembles a draft iFlow with relevant flow steps, and gives developers a strong starting point, and significantly accelerating the design phase. Future enhancements are expected to include automatic generation of mappings, scripts, and other artifacts to further streamline the process. Check&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?range=2025Q1-2026Q3&amp;amp;PRODUCT=000D3A47875C1EDB98A8A910864AC24B&amp;amp;FT=AI&amp;amp;FT=GEN_AI&amp;amp;FT=INTEGRATION" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;the roadmap&lt;/A&gt; &lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;for new updates.&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Elaine_w_0-1756159016396.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304854i72C2DF8534B030E4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Elaine_w_0-1756159016396.png" alt="Elaine_w_0-1756159016396.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/generative-ai-based-script-optimization/ba-p/13970403" target="_blank"&gt;Script Optimization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Generative AI in SAP Integration Suite can help developers refine Groovy and JavaScript scripts by analyzing code in real time and suggesting best-practice optimizations. These recommendations reduce the need for manual tuning, streamline the coding process and help maintain high performance and quality from the outset.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/integration-advisor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Advisor&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Integration Suite is one of the first iPaaS to embed AI into capabilities for supporting B2B scenarios. Integration Advisor uses a machine learning-based, global knowledge pool to propose mappings between source and target structures. By learning from industry standards and past implementations, it dramatically reduces the time and effort required to configure B2B and A2A integrations, especially in complex message transformation scenarios.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-integration-flow-step-recommendations/ba-p/13474550" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flow Step Recommendations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;When developers build integration flows, AI recommends the next logical flow step, such as a Groovy script or End Message, based on usage patterns. This intelligent guidance accelerates the flow creation process, minimizes trial-and-error, and supports consistent design quality across teams.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Together, these capabilities significantly reduce repetitive tasks, speed up development, and help teams deliver high-quality integrations more efficiently, regardless of their experience level.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1278303594"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhance Operational Excellence&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Operational reliability is critical for scalable, enterprise-grade integration. SAP Integration Suite embeds AI to help teams proactively monitor, maintain, and optimize their integration landscapes, reducing manual troubleshooting and improving long-term performance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/api-anomaly-detection-in-sap-integration-suite/ba-p/13726636" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;API Anomaly Detection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Leveraging machine learning, the platform continuously monitors integration flows and APIs to detect unusual patterns, such as latency spikes, increased error rates, or unexpected traffic surges. This helps teams identify and address issues before they impact business processes, improving response time and reducing downtime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="anomalydetection.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304139i2D08AB462C650953/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="anomalydetection.png" alt="anomalydetection.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/leveraging-api-traffic-predictions-in-sap-integration-suite/ba-p/14012084" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;API Volume Prediction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;AI models analyze historical usage patterns to forecast, providing two distinct insights: one on historical usage trends and the other on predicted future volumes. The dual view helps developers and operations teams stay ahead of peak loads and avoid capacity-related disruptions, ensuring both long-term planning and real-time operational awareness.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/generative-ai-based-script-optimization/ba-p/13970403" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Script Optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Generative AI analyzes custom Groovy or JavaScript scripts used in integration flows, identifying potential performance bottlenecks or inefficiencies. It then recommends optimized versions of the code, enabling developers to improve execution quality without deep manual debugging or rewriting.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By embedding these intelligent capabilities, SAP Integration Suite supports a more proactive, data-driven approach to integration operations, allowing teams to deliver higher reliability with less overhead.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-952707370"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration Suite for AI: Enabling the Next Generation of Intelligent Automation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As the enterprise landscape evolves, agentic AI is emerging as a new class of autonomous systems that can reason, interact, and execute tasks on behalf of users. This shift is driving demand for more adaptable and intelligent integration backbones. To function effectively, these AI agents must be able to connect with enterprise systems, orchestrate business logic, access data, and execute workflows securely and reliably. This is where SAP Integration Suite becomes essential. It not only embeds AI to optimize development and operations, but also plays a foundational role in enabling agentic AI by providing the connective fabric that links intelligent agents with business applications and services.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Across the industry, we’re seeing a growing push toward agent-centric automation, from AI copilots to autonomous digital workers, and integration is the linchpin that determines whether these agents can truly act in context. SAP Integration Suite helps enterprises bridge this gap with built-in capabilities that simplify how AI agents discover, consume, and govern enterprise integrations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here are two ways it already supports this shift:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-adapter-for-sap-integration-suite/ba-p/14175843" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The AI Adapter enables seamless communication between SAP Integration Suite and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;generative AI services, provided by &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP’s AI Core or third-party providers like OpenAI. With minimal configuration, developers can embed AI capabilities, such as text generation, summarization, or classification, directly into integration flows.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;This makes it easier to enrich payloads with contextual insights, automate decision logic, and integrate AI-driven functionality within a governed framework. By removing the need for custom scripting or API handling, the AI Adapter boosts developer efficiency and expands the scope for advanced AI-powered use cases&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/integrations/discoverintegrations" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-Powered Content Recommendations in Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To help agents and developers access the right integration assets quickly, the SAP Business Accelerator Hub &lt;/SPAN&gt;features Joule &lt;SPAN&gt;for natural language search. Instead of browsing manually, users (or agents in the future) can ask questions like “How do I connect SAP S/4HANA to Salesforce?” and receive tailored recommendations across integration flows, APIs, and templates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;This AI-driven discovery process reduces time to integration and enhances reusability, which is the key requirement for agent-based automation where responsiveness and adaptability are critical.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Elaine_w_2-1755899230088.png" style="width: 928px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304138iE28D775208063670/image-dimensions/928x568/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="928" height="568" role="button" title="Elaine_w_2-1755899230088.png" alt="Elaine_w_2-1755899230088.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-756193865"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-559680360"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Where We’re Heading&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The evolution of AI in SAP Integration Suite is accelerating, expanding beyond foundational productivity and monitoring features into more adaptive, intelligent, and autonomous integration experiences.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;On the embedded AI front, we’re advancing how integrations are designed, optimized, and managed. Expect more powerful capabilities for automating integration development and API operations, along with intelligent migration from legacy systems like SAP Process Orchestration. These innovations are designed to further boost developer efficiency, reduce operational overhead, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;reduce time to cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At the same time, SAP Integration Suite is evolving to support agent-driven automation. As&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;part of this direction, we plan to enhance the API Management to allow AI systems to interact with enterprise tools and data. This will enable more dynamic, context-aware automation, built on a foundation of governance, scalability and future readiness.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the upcoming blogs, we’ll explore each of the two directions in depth, highlighting real-world use cases, customer stories, and innovations that are redefining integration in the era of AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/realizing-ai-s-potential-in-and-through-sap-integration-suite/ba-p/14193578"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T12:23:42.890000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/release-navigator-for-sap-btp-what-s-new-in-q3-2025/ba-p/14199379</id>
    <title>Release Navigator for SAP BTP - What's New in Q3 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T13:29:29.609000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chriskollhed</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6181</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Blog Header.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306539i8232E2E073389790/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog Header.png" alt="Blog Header.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Release Navigator for SAP BTP continues to evolve and expand, offering our customers improved resources and streamlined access to product updates. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the Q3 2025 update, we ensured all content is up-to-date and we are excited to announce the addition of a new product page for SAP Customer Data Solutions as well as some cosmetic UI updates. Read more about the details in this blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Check out the release navigator for SAP BTP" href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=book!BO_EC8330B09B97CDBE#slide!SL_120BDFE08096029D" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="What is the RN.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265537i23AA8349B1EA28DE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="What is the RN.png" alt="What is the RN.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="01_New Products.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265540iD87D0E02D3327B78/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01_New Products.png" alt="01_New Products.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Collaborating closely with SAP BTP experts, we've expanded the release coverage by introducing 11 new product pages. These pages compile links to all available release information, such as schedules, pre- and post-release communications, blogs, and more:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Customer Data Solutions, including&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Customer Data Cloud / SAP Customer Identity and Access Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Customer Data Platform&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read on to see what you can find on this new page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1868020934"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Customer Data Solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This page contains specific resources for SAP Customer Identity and Access Management, SAP Customer Data Platform, as well as release resources relevant across different SAP Customer Data Solutions. Here’s a list of all you can find on this page:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Customer Identity and Access Management (CDC)&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Roadmap Explorer: Upcoming Innovations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What’s New Viewer: Release Notes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer Influence Campaign&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Community Tag&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Customer Data Platform&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Roadmap Explorer: Upcoming Innovations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What’s New Viewer: Release Notes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer Influence Campaign&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Community Tag&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;General Customer Data Solutions Resources&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP Newsletter&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enablement Webcasts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Subscription link to Cloud Availability Center&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This page has previously been available via the &lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=book!BO_B3B4A4BF7E057D99#slide!SL_B62D843C1DD43A9A" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Release Navigator for Customer Experience&lt;/A&gt;. Adding this page to the Release Navigator for SAP BTP reflects the move of SAP Customer Data Solutions from the Customer Experience area to SAP BTP. The page in the Release Navigator for Customer Experience will stay online until the beginning of Q4 2025 for everyone to take note and switch out their potential bookmarks or saved links. After that, only the page within the Release Navigator for SAP BTP will remain available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Check out the new page for SAP Customer Data Solutions" href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=book!BO_EC8330B09B97CDBE#SL_CAAC3ED5C2293A81" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="chriskollhed_0-1756462658463.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306540iF2536BB5FBCAFAB9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="chriskollhed_0-1756462658463.png" alt="chriskollhed_0-1756462658463.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=book!BO_EC8330B09B97CDBE#SL_CAAC3ED5C2293A81" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Check it out.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="03_New UX Features.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/163275i474DE9BAA1B6321B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="03_New UX Features.png" alt="03_New UX Features.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this last round of updates, we added new visual elements to all release navigators. The UI updates in the Release Navigator for SAP BTP do not affect functionality or performance and are strictly cosmetical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the home page also known as the Product Specific page, you will notice that our &lt;STRONG&gt;Welcome&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Release Calendar&lt;/STRONG&gt; cards have received a facelift for a fresher look and feel.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Check out the changes in the Release Navigator for SAP BTP" href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?show=book!BO_EC8330B09B97CDBE#SL_120BDFE08096029D" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="chriskollhed_1-1756463442291.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306544i434F3B481F5CC574/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="chriskollhed_1-1756463442291.png" alt="chriskollhed_1-1756463442291.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="20240827_06_UI Elements_Lightbulb.png" style="width: 28px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/163285i9270D26ED228EC1F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="20240827_06_UI Elements_Lightbulb.png" alt="20240827_06_UI Elements_Lightbulb.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;On all pages where you can open informational text boxes by hovering over the lightbulb icon, you will see a slight update to the design of these boxes. Content and functionality remain the same.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="graphic UX changes bubbles.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306564i043B23259402D475/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="graphic UX changes bubbles.png" alt="graphic UX changes bubbles.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;As a reminder&lt;/STRONG&gt;: These pop-up boxes show up on every page with a lightbulb icon at the top and may be moved around on the page or closed once you are done reading them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="02_Update Plan.png" style="width: 906px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266396i7419E65D422332B0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="02_Update Plan.png" alt="02_Update Plan.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For centralized information regarding the release of new features for SAP BTP products and services, consult the &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3430170" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Consolidated Release Schedule for SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regarding the Release Navigator updates, refer to this update plan:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Content Plan.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306561iD6767BBF155595CC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Content Plan.png" alt="Content Plan.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;*Disclaimer: The schedule is subject to alterations without notice, including potential delays or the integration of changes in subsequent update windows. It doesn't establish a commitment, promise, or legal duty to deliver any material, code, or functionality. Looking into the remaining quarters of 2025, updates will focus on quarterly content maintenance and a steady extension of product coverage. No substantial UI updates are planned for the time being.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="03_Connect.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266399i2FA2535DDFAC6F87/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="03_Connect.png" alt="03_Connect.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Readiness@Scale team within SAP Enterprise Support is driven to ensure release readiness across the SAP Enterprise Support portfolio. Our mission is to empower SAP customers to effectively adopt and utilize innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have feedback or specific requests for content within the release navigator, feel free to contact us.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapinsights.eu.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_egtCPhgGOuO4Iwm?SolutionArea=SAPBTP" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="button provide feedback.png" style="width: 271px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266400i8AA2658279669BCB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="button provide feedback.png" alt="button provide feedback.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don't forget to explore our team’s blogs tagged under &lt;A href="mailto:Readiness@Scale." target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Readiness@Scale. &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy navigating!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Readiness@Scale &amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Enterprise Support&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/release-navigator-for-sap-btp-what-s-new-in-q3-2025/ba-p/14199379"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:29:29.609000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/introducing-the-devtoberfest-scavenger-hunt-coming-soon/ba-p/14183972</id>
    <title>Introducing the Devtoberfest Scavenger Hunt 🔨🪙 ... COMING SOON</title>
    <updated>2025-09-01T08:09:22.994000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dan_Wroblewski</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/72</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Devtoberfest Scavenger Hunt&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a chase around important SAP developer-related tools/sites, a challenge to construct a secret phrase, and a chance to win 1000s of points toward the Devtoberfest &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-grand-prize-trip-faq/ba-p/13781581" target="_self"&gt;grand prize&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;The hunt officially starts &lt;STRONG&gt;Sept. 25&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with the release of the first clue during that day's &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Developer News&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and you have until the end of Devtoberfest, &lt;STRONG&gt;Oct. 24&lt;/STRONG&gt;, to complete it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="2" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;To get all the clues make sure to &lt;STRONG&gt;SUBSCRIBE TO THIS POST!!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756392968630.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306022iE4681CFA8F3E546E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756392968630.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756392968630.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more about the&amp;nbsp; entire Devtoberfest event in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423549"&gt;@KevinR&lt;/a&gt;'s post&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-welcome/ba-p/14182817" target="_self"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 Welcome!&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="frame0004-Photoroom" style="width: 222px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303712iDEFAB5049DFD4CE1/image-dimensions/222x145/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="222" height="145" role="button" title="frame0004-Photoroom" alt="frame0004-Photoroom" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737841707"&gt;What you need to find&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have hidden a special phrase, which you need to figure out using the clues in the next section. Along your journey you will do the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visit about 10 different locations related to SAP developers, mostly web sites that are designed to help you in your daily SAP development.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;At each location, you will discover a set of hexadecimal digits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Concatenate the digits together (in the order of the missions) to get one, 37-digit hexadecimal number.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Multiply that hexadecimal number by another secret number, for which we will give a clue.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Take the resulting 38-digit hexadecimal product, and convert it into the secret phrase, using each pair of digits as ASCII characters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the phrase, exactly (case-sensitive, no extra spaces), into the &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-scavenger-hunt.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Scavenger Hunt tutorial&lt;/A&gt;.‌&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not until the SAP Developer News of Oct. 16 will you have all the pieces to be able to complete the phrase.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1670410921"&gt;Example Mission&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an example of what you will have to do, here's a short sample mission (just a warm-up, no points will be earned).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;Mission&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;No. Digits&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;SAP Web Property&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Instructions&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="289px"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="289px"&gt;7&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="289px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#7C484A"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Developers YouTube Channel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="289px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to our &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/@sapdevs/videos" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Developer YouTube channel&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/156020"&gt;@Rekha_DR&lt;/a&gt;'s video "&lt;A href="https://youtu.be/1vElTfSxGWM?si=VO5Asnf6paocjKru" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build Process Automation (Part 1): Build your very first process&lt;/A&gt;". Watch it and find the secret 7-digit hexadecimal number in one of the info cards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756706383435.png" style="width: 580px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307154i7E73F36E50823BD8/image-dimensions/580x300/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="580" height="300" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756706383435.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756706383435.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#7C484A"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use the Developer Tools on your browser to inspect the words "SAP Community" in the previous column and find the 6-digit ASCII code for the color of the text.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756706325713.png" style="width: 565px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307152i1D8D7FDEE95C1713/image-dimensions/565x202/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="565" height="202" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756706325713.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756706325713.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;None (directly)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Concatenate the 2 sets of hexadecimal digits, in order, and multiply the resulting hexadecimal number by the number of original SAP founders (you can easily find the number on the &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SAP" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Wikipedia page&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Convert the resulting hexadecimal number into a phrase, converting each pair of digits into a character using ASCII codes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Post a comment/picture&amp;nbsp;about the phrase -- but NOT the phrase itself&amp;nbsp; (like your experiences with or opinion about the phrase, or a picture of something belonging to you that reminds you of the phrase) -- you won't get any points, but it will be fun and you will be ready for the real scavenger hunt. If you have any trouble with this example mission, post in the comments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;REMINDER:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The above is just an example of how the real scavenger hunt will work. The real scavenger hunt instructions will be described in the rest of this blog post, as clues become available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344814697"&gt;The (real) mission&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below are the instructions for finding the hexadecimal digits for the actual scavenger hunt. We will release clues as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the SAP Developer News of &lt;STRONG&gt;Sept. 25&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Oct. 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Oct. 9&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Oct. 16&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In this blog &lt;STRONG&gt;each Monday during the first 3 weeks of Devtoberfest&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;To be notified when a new clue is released,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SUBSCRIBE TO THIS POST!!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rule.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295882i3E2967613A5D1256/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rule.png" alt="rule.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;‌ &lt;SPAN&gt;When you find the secret phase, just enter it into this &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-scavenger-hunt.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest tutorial&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756261779255.png" style="width: 1009px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305319iF03452ECEE94B400/image-dimensions/1009x185/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="1009" height="185" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756261779255.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756261779255.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To guide you, we have created a &lt;A href="http://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-scavenger-hunt-checking.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;second tutorial&lt;/A&gt; -- you do not have to use it, nor do you get any points from it. But you can enter the 1 to 6 digits from each mission to check if you received the correct digits for that mission.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756261827758.png" style="width: 984px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305320i6D6063DA1D7F3A96/image-dimensions/984x185/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="984" height="185" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756261827758.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756261827758.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rule.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295882i3E2967613A5D1256/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rule.png" alt="rule.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1406466630"&gt;Here are your missions:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;Mission&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;No. Digits&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;SAP Web Property&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Instructions&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Developer News&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6RpkC85SLQAVBSQXN9522_1jNvPavBgg" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Developer News&lt;/A&gt; comes out each Thursday with the latest about ABAP, CAP, BTP, SAP Build, UI5, Fiori, AI, and all your favorite SAP developer topics. All delivered by some of your favorite Developer Advocates, like DJ, Shilpa Shankar, Thomas Jung, Antonio Maradiaga, Nora von Thenen and the rest of the gang.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Most episodes about 5 minutes. Also available as a &lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/sap-developers/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Podcast&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Watch the Developer News of Sept. 25&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Sept. 29&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Sept. 29&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Watch the Developer News of Oct. 2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;5&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Oct. 6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Oct. 6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;7&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Watch the Developer News of Oct. 9&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;8&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Oct. 13&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;9&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Oct. 13&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;10&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;None (directly)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Watch the Developer News of Oct. 16&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Good luck!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_cat_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😸&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/introducing-the-devtoberfest-scavenger-hunt-coming-soon/ba-p/14183972"/>
    <published>2025-09-01T08:09:22.994000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-joule-agents-the-gift-of-memory-with-hana-cloud/ba-p/14203144</id>
    <title>Give your Joule Agents 🤖 the gift of Memory 💭, with Hana Cloud ✨</title>
    <updated>2025-09-01T14:39:31.510000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Raphael_Caillon</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16672</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;When Joule agents can write/read memories in &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, they:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Remember business facts at scale (supplier habits, contract quirks, SLA exceptions) &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Retrieve them&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;fast &amp;amp; accurately&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HANA Cloud Vector Engine&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":high_voltage:"&gt;⚡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Keep memories &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;human-readable&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, sortable, and dead-simple to implement 🧩&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;That means fewer repeated mistakes, smarter suggestions, and agents that actually &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;learn with your business&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; over time.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An example of some memories for an invoice exception agent.&lt;BR /&gt;You can make them as detailed or a simple as you want in the agent prompt!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Raphael_Caillon_1-1756730055160.png" style="width: 792px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307408i9C3E1F37CA6E71EA/image-dimensions/792x327/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="792" height="327" role="button" title="Raphael_Caillon_1-1756730055160.png" alt="Raphael_Caillon_1-1756730055160.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759074911"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A simple “Memories” table&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Human-readable text + metadata (who/what it’s about, when learned, importance, TTL, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Optional: a vector column for semantic search.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vector search for recall&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Store an embedding of each memory → use &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;approximate nearest neighbor (ANN)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; to fetch the right facts instantly (“Which supplier often uses expired POs?”). BM25 or other strategies are available. I love BM25's reliability for same-language and same-topic knowledge meshes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;One tool your agent calls&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Add a tool (below) so your agent can &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;append or update&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; memories whenever it learns something new.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update the Agent prompt to have it use the memory well!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Something like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Before answering, search (memory.search_hana) with a concise query (supplier/invoice/PO terms; limit top_k≤8); 
use the results to tailor your response. 
Only write when you learn a new, stable, factual business detail; 
upsert (memory.upsert_hana) instead of inserting duplicates—treat as duplicate if normalized context matches or vector similarity ≥0.86 and the same entity (supplier/invoice/PO) is involved; 
if duplicate, refresh last_seen_at (and occurrence_count if available). Format memories as one dense sentence in context 
(e.g., YYYY-MM-DD | INV-XXXX | Supplier ABC | PO 4500001123 | 4,980.00 EUR | expired PO used) 
and a brief actionable description; keep context ≤220 chars, use present tense. 
Set importance 1–5 (5 = critical risk) and ttl_days (low importance decays, 0 = never expires). 
Do not store ephemeral chatter or sensitive data; prefer patterns over one-offs. 
If you update or add a memory, mention it briefly to the user; otherwise be concise and never dump full tables unless asked.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1562561406"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add two memory tools (Joule Skills)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Add Memory" is a simple SQL Write&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Raphael_Caillon_0-1756727276672.png" style="width: 785px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307396i19514443D22727FB/image-dimensions/785x331/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="785" height="331" role="button" title="Raphael_Caillon_0-1756727276672.png" alt="Raphael_Caillon_0-1756727276672.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Retrieve Memory" is a simple SQL Read, with semantic search (BM25+Embeddings)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1366047901"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced memory patterns (that HANA makes easy) &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disappearing memories (decay/TTL)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: small quirks fade unless they’re re-observed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hierarchical memories&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: supplier-site → supplier → region → global policy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;World representations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: keep a simple &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;graph&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; of relationships (supplier↔plant, approver↔cost center), or materialize views for fast joins.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning from mistakes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;: tag memories with &lt;I&gt;resolution outcome&lt;/I&gt; so the agent prefers strategies that worked.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1169534396"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Result:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A living, human-readable &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;knowledge fabric&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; your Joule agents can trust.&lt;BR /&gt;It's fast, explainable, and always improving. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-joule-agents-the-gift-of-memory-with-hana-cloud/ba-p/14203144"/>
    <published>2025-09-01T14:39:31.510000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-that-works-for-you-how-sap-fieldglass-is-redefining-workforce-management/ba-p/14203557</id>
    <title>AI That Works for You: How SAP Fieldglass Is Redefining Workforce Management</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T10:59:51.351000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Thanh_Huynh</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1634002</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Fieldglass is redefining how companies manage their external workforce, thanks to the power of AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smarter Talent Matching&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI-driven resume assessment and skills extraction help hiring managers to instantly identify top candidates. No more manual filtering, just intelligent recommendations that align with your job needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generative AI for Job Descriptions &amp;amp; SOW creation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Need a Job Posting or Statement of Work? AI can draft, translate and tailor documents in seconds, saving time and ensuring consistency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule: Your AI Assistant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule is SAP's a&lt;SPAN&gt;ssistant that leverages generative AI capabilities that&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;lets you run reports, retrieve information and helps you complete tasks using conversational interactions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discover how AI can transform the way you hire, manage and optimise your external workforce with SAP Fieldglass.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more about all things AI in SAP Fieldglass, check out:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/d90e4d56084b4540b73e72fc822b8fc9/106101493785428ba305a583c320ad2a.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI and Machine Learning Capabilities at SAP Fieldglass&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/76e97fe0cccf4d37a5dadc652a375e33/e3dc12e0215447cfa4507eff66e8224b.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule in SAP Fieldglass&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-that-works-for-you-how-sap-fieldglass-is-redefining-workforce-management/ba-p/14203557"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T10:59:51.351000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-2025-slip-on-speed-up-the-next-decade-of-business/ba-p/14204442</id>
    <title>SAP TechEd 2025: 👟 Slip On, Speed Up: The Next Decade of Business</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T14:16:17.305000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lauramarwood</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44830</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1343831468" id="toc-hId-1888190302"&gt;The world is in sprint mode ...&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;.... AI cycles flip every quarter, supply chains get bendy, climate shocks rewrite plans. As Lenin put it, "there are weeks when decades happen." Winning 2030 isn’t about hoarding data or demo sparkle. It’s about &lt;STRONG&gt;cutting friction&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;staying focused&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;moving as one&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s 2030 play:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI that removes grind -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;copilots, automation, anomaly detection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data you can trust -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;clean, connected, decision-ready.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Networks that sync the ecosystem -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;suppliers, partners, customers moving together&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The metaphor? &lt;STRONG&gt;Lock laces.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Triathletes don’t stop to tie shoes. They slip on and go. In finance, AI is the lock lace: auto-recs, instant cleanup, fewer errors. Hours back. Focus up. Strategy on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the shift: from tying shoes to breaking records. From reconciling ledgers to reshaping the business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753971252933001gofy" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Join &lt;STRONG&gt;Paul Saunders&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Laura Marwood Ph.D.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;at SAP TechEd 2025 to see how we’re building for that future - because in 2030, every second (and every decision) will count.&lt;BR /&gt;__________________________________&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Can't make it to Berlin? Dial in for SAP TechEd Virtual!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you can’t make it to Berlin, we’ve still got you covered. &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual&lt;/A&gt; is a free online event that’ll help you broaden your technical expertise and explore SAP’s latest innovations&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="asasa.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307878iC9DEC57B450EDCDE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="asasa.jpg" alt="asasa.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-2025-slip-on-speed-up-the-next-decade-of-business/ba-p/14204442"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T14:16:17.305000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/boost-your-cap-development-with-ai-introducing-the-mcp-server-for-cap/ba-p/14202849</id>
    <title>Boost your CAP Development with AI: Introducing the MCP Server for CAP</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T09:45:05.665000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BirgitS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/41902</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Imagine the following: You are an experienced developer, working on SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP) projects. You use AI agents, such as Claude Code, opencode, or GitHub Copilot, to support you in your daily work. Wouldn't it be cool if the used LLM can help you develop CAP applications? With our new MCP server for CAP, we can provide more context about your project as well as relevant CAP examples to steer the LLM in doing the right thing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is an MCP Server?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An MCP (&lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/docs/getting-started/intro" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Model Context Protocol&lt;/A&gt;) server is designed to manage and deliver capabilities to Large Language Models (LLMs) via AI agents. It bridges the gap between LLMs and external resources such as services, tools, and data, enabling LLMs to interact with these resources. The newly introduced MCP server for CAP transforms AI agents into CAP development experts. It provides context-focused tools that aim to help the AI agent to answer questions such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which CDS (Core Data Services) services does my project expose and where are they served?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What are the entities about and how do they relate to each other?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How do I add columns to a select statement in CAP Node.js?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How can I register custom READ handlers in CAP Java?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The MCP Server for CAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the context of the assisted development introduced in the beginning, this means: You might ask the LLM to add, for example, a bound action `setToCompleted` to the entity `Orders`. Without our new MCP server for CAP, the LLM would hallucinate and could invent a new syntax and do a lot of file searches to find the relevant file. With the help of our new MCP server for CAP the LLM behaves as intended. To do so, the LLM generates a tool call to check the Orders entity and relevant information is returned, such as its elements and file location. It also generates a tool call to check the CAP documentation for bound actions. Based on the results, it generates the correct CDS code to add the bound action. This, of course, is just one example. We designed our MCP server for CAP to help you with arbitrary tasks instead of focusing on single commands.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For this purpose, our newly introduced MCP server for CAP provides the following two tools for AI-assisted development of CAP applications:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;search_model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This tool allows the AI model to perform a fuzzy search for CDS definitions (entities, services, actions) within a unified compiled CDS model of all your&amp;nbsp;.cds&amp;nbsp;files. This CDS model includes the model structure and relationships, annotations and metadata, and the generated HTTP endpoints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The fuzzy search algorithm matches definition names and supports partial matches, making it easy to find entities such as "Books" even when searching for "book".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;search_docs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This tool enables the AI model to perform a semantic search through the preprocessed&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CAP documentation&lt;/A&gt;, which is stored locally as embeddings. The search query is converted to an embedding vector. Finally, a similarity search is performed to find the relevant parts of the documentation, which have the highest semantic similarity to your query even if the exact keywords are not used.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note: These tools are meant to be used by AI models and do not constitute a stable API. But for experimental purposes, you can also use the tools directly from the command line as documented here: &lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-js/mcp-server?tab=readme-ov-file#cli-usage" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;MCP server for AI-assisted development of CAP applications&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Try it out&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you excited to try it out? Detailed instructions can be found here: &lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-js/mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;MCP server for AI-assisted development of CAP applications&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Important: Our MCP Server for CAP is designed to support professional developers in their daily work. As with all AI-generated information, you should check the generated results carefully to avoid unintended side effects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are excited to announce that the MCP Server for CAP is an open-source project, licensed under the Apache-2.0 license. Learn more about &lt;A href="https://opensource.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;open source at SAP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are very curious to see what you will do with our &lt;A href="https://npmjs.com/package/@cap-js/mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;MCP s&lt;U&gt;e&lt;/U&gt;&lt;U&gt;rver for CAP&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;! Please don't hesitate to provide your feedback here or report any issues in our &lt;A href="https://github.com/cap-js/mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Beyond CAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We also offer a &lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt; and an &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/open-ux-tools/tree/main/packages/fiori-mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;MCP server for SAP Fiori&lt;/A&gt;, ensuring that you have a comprehensive suite of tools to enhance your development workflow across various SAP technologies. You can find the packages here: &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@ui5/mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap-ux/fiori-mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;MCP server for SAP Fiori&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The introduction of the MCP servers for CAP, SAPUI5 and SAP Fiori marks a significant step forward in leveraging AI to enhance developer productivity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned for more updates. Happy coding!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/boost-your-cap-development-with-ai-introducing-the-mcp-server-for-cap/ba-p/14202849"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T09:45:05.665000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-tools-update-first-release-of-the-sap-fiori-mcp-server-for/ba-p/14204694</id>
    <title>SAP Fiori Tools Update – First Release of the SAP Fiori MCP Server for Agentic AI Workflows</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T09:45:49.103000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christoph_Gollmick</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’re excited to announce the &lt;STRONG&gt;release of the SAP Fiori MCP server&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a new capability that lets AI coding assistants directly create and edit &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Fiori applications. This marks the next milestone in our AI journey, following the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-idea-to-app-using-ai-powered-project-accelerator-to-develop-sap-fiori/ba-p/14095300" target="_blank"&gt;Project Accelerator&lt;/A&gt; introduced earlier this year. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is MCP — and why it matters?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Model Context Protocol (MCP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is an &lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/docs/getting-started/intro" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;open standard&lt;/A&gt; that standardizes how applications provide context to large language models. MCP is already supported by clients such as Claude, Cline, Cursor, and VS Code allowing AI-powered workflows to interact seamlessly with developer tools.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introducing the SAP Fiori MCP server&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Fiori MCP server (&lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap-ux/fiori-mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@sap-ux/fiori-mcp-server&lt;/A&gt;) is an open-source node.js module delivered as part of the &lt;STRONG&gt;open-ux-tools &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/open-ux-tools/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;repository&lt;/A&gt;. It enables developers using AI coding assistants to generate and adapt SAP Fiori elements applications with precision and context awareness. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It is not the only MCP server published by SAP. The &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP MCP server&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@cap-js/mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@cap-js/mcp-server&lt;/A&gt;) provides tools to create and modify CAP node.js projects, and the &lt;STRONG&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@ui5/mcp-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@ui5/mcp-server&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; allows AI assistants to write SAPUI5&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; code. Together, these servers provide complementary entry points into different areas of SAP application development, so that AI assistants can seamlessly &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;data models, SAP Fiori applications, and SAPUI5 code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information also have a look at the related blog posts:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/boost-your-cap-development-with-ai-introducing-the-mcp-server-for-cap/ba-p/14202849" target="_self"&gt;Boost your CAP Development with AI: Introducing the MCP Server for CAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;Give Your AI Agent Some Tools: Introducing the UI5 MCP Server&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the MCP servers in place, you can already try out scenarios such as:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Please add an SAP Fiori elements list report app to my CAP project.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Generate a new CAP project and SAP Fiori app based on my_sketch.png.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Add Flexible Column Layout to the app.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Enable initial load for the SAP Fiori app.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;⚠&lt;SPAN&gt;️ &lt;EM&gt;Note: The SAP Fiori MCP server is currently released in &lt;STRONG&gt;experimental state&lt;/STRONG&gt; and subject to rapid change and enhancements.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI assistants can discover and act on SAP Fiori projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The first release comes with a set of capabilities designed to let AI assistants both discover and act on SAP Fiori projects. The SAP Fiori MCP server provides tools to generate SAP Fiori elements applications for CAP node.js projects, finds SAP Fiori applications in the workspace, and allows to edit applications and pages inside applications. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To ensure that the AI produces correct results, we propose rules that guide the LLM’s behavior (see &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap-ux/fiori-mcp-server#rules" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;rules&lt;/A&gt;). These rules cover important aspects such as using proper SAP Fiori elements application patterns, ensuring data models are valid with UUID primary keys, generating sample data consistently, and preferring code-based modifications over screen personalization. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can configure the server to be directly called with npx or install it globally via npm (see &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap-ux/fiori-mcp-server#usage" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;usage&lt;/A&gt;). In both cases, it integrates easily into an MCP-enabled client such as Cline.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Example how the SAP Fiori MCP server is used in Cline." style="width: 765px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308017iA55B99B19DAD23CD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Christoph_Gollmick_1-1756821532142.png" alt="Example how the SAP Fiori MCP server is used in Cline." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example how the SAP Fiori MCP server is used in Cline.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Developers can build apps more quickly using MCP servers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By connecting directly into SAP Fiori projects through MCP, developers gain a much more cost-effective way to experiment with AI support. They can let LLMs execute complex tasks in context—while the built-in functions and rules ensure adherence to SAP Fiori best practices. This reduces the risk of hallucinations, accelerates prototyping, and makes it easier to iterate quickly on new ideas. Since the SAP Fiori MCP server is &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;with other MCP servers like UI5 and CAP, developers can benefit from a consistent AI-driven experience across different parts of the development process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is the first step on the MCP journey&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The current release is just the first step. We are already working on extending the server with a &lt;STRONG&gt;document search feature&lt;/STRONG&gt; that will make guidance from SAP documentation, tutorials, and examples directly available to the LLM. This means that the AI assistant won’t just follow rules embedded in the server but can also draw from the wealth of published learning content.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition, the &lt;STRONG&gt;generator functionality&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which in the first release is limited to CAP node.js projects, will be expanded to support &lt;STRONG&gt;any suitable OData source&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This will significantly broaden the scenarios in which the SAP Fiori MCP server can be applied, giving developers much more flexibility in how they use AI to create and adapt applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Try the SAP Fiori MCP server at SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can experience the SAP Fiori MCP server live at &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd Berlin&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In session &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749126322451001Fcbi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CA261 – Create great UX with AI, SAP Design System, SAP Fiori elements, and SAPUI5&lt;/A&gt;, we’ll guide you through using AI and MCP to generate applications, adapt them, and extend them with SAPUI5. It’s a hands-on workshop designed to show how these new capabilities come together in practice.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Closing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This release marks the start of a new era in SAP Fiori development, where AI assistants can not only suggest but also execute tasks reliably. With upcoming enhancements like doc search and broader generator support, we’re laying the groundwork for &lt;STRONG&gt;smarter, faster, and more flexible AI-driven development&lt;/STRONG&gt;. As an open-source project we also welcome your contributions. We encourage you to report any issues you encounter. Your feedback is invaluable to us.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We can’t wait to see how you experiment with it—and we look forward to meeting you at TechEd!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-tools-update-first-release-of-the-sap-fiori-mcp-server-for/ba-p/14204694"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T09:45:49.103000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-partners-fast-track-your-sap-business-technology-platform-certification/ba-p/14194751</id>
    <title>SAP Partners - Fast Track your SAP Business Technology Platform Certification Path</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T07:16:06.943000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OanaTudorascu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/78</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1867875753"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform Certification Path – From Beginner to Advanced &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you interested in getting your SAP Business Technology Platform ( SAP BTP) &amp;nbsp;certification, but unsure of where to begin?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we would like to give you a better overview of the available SAP BTP certifications and guide you how to progress from foundational level to professional expertise. Additionally, we will introduce several enablement offerings, specifically designed for SAP Partners, &amp;nbsp;that can help you fast track your SAP BTP certification.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Depending on your existing knowledge and skills, you can determine which of the three steps below is the ideal starting point for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="OanaTudorascu_0-1756282207059.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305435i63135E52E2DF56F4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="OanaTudorascu_0-1756282207059.png" alt="OanaTudorascu_0-1756282207059.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1671362248"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1- Entry-Level Certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;For partners who are new to SAP’s ecosystem, one of the best starting points to learn the basics of SAP Business Suite and the importance of SAP BTP is the entry level certification “Positioning SAP Business Technology Platform as part of the SAP Business Suite”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This certification takes you through the foundational courses of the SAP Business Technology Platform, enabling the enhancement of business processes through the integration of intelligent technologies, the development of innovative applications, and the analysis and visualization of data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For SAP Partners, we offer bi-weekly 90 minutes webinars that are led by SAP experts and will provide the clarity, focus, and key insights you need to approach the certification exam with confidence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jun/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010574.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Access the latest schedule.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1474848743"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1278335238"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2- Get Specialized with the Associate Level Certifications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;If you already have the foundational knowledge in SAP BTP, you can delve into specialized certification tracks based on their career goals and interests. Professionals choose from distinct areas, including Application Development and Automation, Integration Database and Data Management, and AI Foundation. Each specialization offers focused certifications and provide the skills required to address specific business needs and technical challenges, equipping learners with the knowledge to advance their SAP careers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For SAP Partners , you can join one of the Partner Get and Stay Certified Academies below that will help you with the certification exam.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jun/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010506.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Security Administrator&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/mar/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00009442.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Backend Developer – CAP &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/mar/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00009457.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build – LCNC&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/mar/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00009464.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration Developer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/jul/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00010652.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Backend Developer – ABAP Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1081821733"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-885308228"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3 - Become a SAP BTP Solution Architect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Experienced professionals can pursue the SAP BTP Solution Architect professional certification. From a career development perspective, this certification is marking the transition from a specialized skillset to a broader, strategic role. Solution architects are responsible for designing comprehensive SAP BTP implementations that align with business objectives and technical requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For SAP Partners - Access &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/mar/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00009748.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Partner Get Certified Academy for SAP BTP Solution Architect&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-partners-fast-track-your-sap-business-technology-platform-certification/ba-p/14194751"/>
    <published>2025-09-04T07:16:06.943000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-potential-of-sap-ai-in-procurement/ba-p/14206860</id>
    <title>Unlocking the Potential of SAP AI in Procurement</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T08:42:27.181000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mbeganyi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4127</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hello, Martin Beganyi here again, Program Lead at Procurement Adoption Office.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You may know me from my previous contributions as part of the Solution Value Advisory team for EMEA/MEE. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recently, I have transitioned to the newly established Procurement Adoption Office, where I now lead two global adoption programs: one focused on driving the adoption of SAP Ariba’s Category Management solution, and the second dedicated to accelerating the uptake of AI-powered features across SAP Procurement solutions, specifically SAP Fieldglass and SAP Ariba - This blog is dedicated to the latter, the transformative role of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI in Procurement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Through years, I’ve observed a consistent challenge: many organizations are unaware of the full suite of AI capabilities embedded in their SAP procurement solutions.&amp;nbsp; Despite the growing availability of these advanced features, adoption remain low or inconsistent, limiting the value customers can unlock.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To address this, we have launched a global program to help customers to adopt AI features in core solutions for example, Strategic Sourcing, Fieldglass, and Buying.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introducing the AI Toolkit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The cornerstone of our initiative is the AI Toolkit — a concise, easy-to-understand resource that compiles essential information about all available AI functionalities.&amp;nbsp; Designed for those new to AI, the toolkit cuts through the noise of overwhelming information, providing a clear starting point for customers and partners alike.&amp;nbsp; We encourage you to download, share, and leverage this toolkit within your teams:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/inmn3Zp?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1234612" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI in Procurement Toolkit (Aug2025).pdf&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Engage with Our Interactive Learning Opportunities&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To further support adoption, we host a series of live webinars where we delve into the value of individual AI features, demonstrate activation steps, and showcase practical usage scenarios. Here are some of the upcoming sessions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4435612&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=A3DE53CEDE437303128D05B9BAC0AFFA&amp;amp;groupId=5192177&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Registration for On24 Sessions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For our Preferred Success customers, we can offer a dedicated one-on-one expert led engagements, including hands-on activation of AI features aligned with your business needs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join Our Open Office Hours&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additionally, we run a recurring series of ‘Open’ hour to all SAP customers which offers a flexible way to ask questions, seek real-time answers, and gain clarity on AI capabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Upcoming ‘Open’ hours (EMEA/APAC):&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/d3d884b7-894c-431f-b34d-0e345be2d540@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sept 9th - Open Hour (EMEA/APAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/1381f3f8-25b3-4c13-accf-fc00ced16c31@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sept 23rd - Open Hour (EMEA/APAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/41ffb240-8527-4896-98d7-48c4a1697f3c@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Oct 7th – Open Hour (EMEA/APAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/80a6e926-2b73-4526-8b1c-302536209e06@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Oct 21st – Open Hour (EMEA/APAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/eeb77aa5-d88c-4a15-91b6-bb63961b66a8@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Nov 4th – Open Hour (EMEA/APAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/ef1f66e4-d51d-4b95-afd8-fe7f1a4a7475@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Nov 18h – Open Hour (EMEA/APAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/c9f06cc0-6ed9-40e6-96d5-d8323aeef472@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dec 2nd – Open Hour (EMEA/APAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/d8bef56c-b4df-40ce-b99f-563d82c489f6@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dec 16th – Open Hour (EMEA/APAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next Steps&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We invite you to explore our AI Toolkit, participate in the webinars, or attend the SAP ‘Open’ hours.&amp;nbsp; To schedule a dedicated session tailored to your organization’s needs, please reach out to your Customer Success Manager who can support you.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for your time and interest in advancing procurement with AI.&amp;nbsp; Together, we can unlock new efficiencies and drive strategic value across your supply chain.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Martin Beganyi&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-potential-of-sap-ai-in-procurement/ba-p/14206860"/>
    <published>2025-09-04T08:42:27.181000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
