<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Artificial-Intelligence-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Artificial Intelligence</title>
  <updated>2025-11-30T00:10:06.684444+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Artificial Intelligence/pd-p/c3c3a408-33ea-4c2a-ae6f-05461e76982d" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Artificial Intelligence blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/predicting-cycling-performance-sap-rpt-1-vs-ai-chat-models-and-strava/ba-p/14263679</id>
    <title>Predicting Cycling Performance: SAP RPT-1 vs AI Chat Models and Strava</title>
    <updated>2025-11-09T18:19:18.957000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VictorSevilla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15643</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This study compares the prediction accuracy of SAP RPT-1, Strava, and leading AI chat models (Copilot, ChatGPT, Gemini) for a real cycling route. Using historical data from 85 rides, each model predicted time and average speed for the next session. Results show that &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 delivered highly accurate, deterministic forecasts&lt;/STRONG&gt;, outperforming general-purpose LLMs and coming close to Strava’s specialized algorithm. These findings highlight SAP RPT-1’s potential for precise forecasting in structured data scenarios. Once the model reaches &lt;STRONG&gt;General Availability&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we will extend this analysis to real business datasets for even more impactful insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_2-1762709039472.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337641i327FE9B3F078E3CD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_2-1762709039472.png" alt="VictorSevilla_2-1762709039472.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This article was created with the support of Microsoft Copilot, but the results are based on a real-world experience.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Introduction&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predicting performance in cycling is not just a sports challenge - it’s a fascinating analogy for forecasting in business. Just like companies predict production or maintenance needs, cyclists can try to anticipate their next ride’s time and average speed. In this study, we explored how different prediction models perform when estimating these metrics for a real cycling route.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We compared five approaches:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Strava’s prediction engine, widely trusted by athletes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP RPT-1, a tabular model designed for structured data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Three popular AI chat models: Microsoft Copilot, ChatGPT, and Gemini.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The actual ride result, serving as the baseline.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The goal was simple: predict the route time and average speed as accurately as possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Methodology&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The dataset included 85 cycling routes recorded over four months, covering distances, times, speeds, and elevation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_3-1762707650344.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337631i61AE018FFF4014E5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_3-1762707650344.png" alt="VictorSevilla_3-1762707650344.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each model received the same prompt:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“I will give you a CSV file with all the data about my last 4 months with the bike. You should predict my route time and average speed during the route on the next Sunday. Label [PREDICT] identifies which data need to be predicted by you. Analyse and give me your expectations for this Sunday.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We then compared:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Predicted time (in seconds)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Average speed (in km/h)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Response time (how fast the model delivered its prediction)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, we benchmarked these predictions against the real ride, which covered 53.6 km with 765 m elevation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Results&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;The predictions from each model were compared against the actual ride, which covered 53.6 km with 765 m elevation. The key metrics analyzed were time (in seconds) and average speed (in km/h).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_4-1762707799840.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337632i20BE265FAA225038/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_4-1762707799840.png" alt="VictorSevilla_4-1762707799840.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The simplified comparison shows clear differences in accuracy:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strava&lt;/STRONG&gt; delivered the closest prediction to reality, with only minor deviations in time and speed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; performed impressively, producing deterministic results and staying very close to the real values.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gemini&lt;/STRONG&gt; was fast and understood units correctly, but its speed prediction deviated more than others.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Copilot&lt;/STRONG&gt; struggled with consistency and unit interpretation, leading to larger errors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/STRONG&gt; showed the biggest gap, especially in time prediction, due to misinterpretation of units.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These results underline the importance of structured models like SAP RPT-1 for numeric predictions and reveal the limitations of general-purpose LLMs when handling precise, unit-based data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Conclusions&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The comparison highlights clear patterns:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strava&lt;/STRONG&gt; remains the most accurate overall, with minimal deviation in both time and speed. Its specialized algorithm and access to large datasets give it a strong advantage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; stands out as a powerful alternative. It delivered deterministic predictions, handled structured data effectively, and achieved results very close to reality. This shows its potential for numeric forecasting beyond sports—think production planning or predictive maintenance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gemini&lt;/STRONG&gt; produced fast responses and understood units correctly, but its speed prediction was less precise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Copilot&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/STRONG&gt; struggled with numeric interpretation. Copilot showed inconsistent outputs, while ChatGPT had the largest error in time prediction, likely due to misunderstanding units.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The charts you will include (bar chart, dispersion plot, and error chart) reinforce these insights, showing how SAP RPT-1 consistently outperforms general-purpose LLMs in accuracy and stability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bar charts&lt;/STRONG&gt; reveal how predicted times and speeds compare to actual values.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_0-1762707354122.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337628i8B644837E098FA58/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_0-1762707354122.png" alt="VictorSevilla_0-1762707354122.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dispersion plots&lt;/STRONG&gt; show the spread of speed predictions across models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_1-1762707360892.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337629iC68FC11C79AA113A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_1-1762707360892.png" alt="VictorSevilla_1-1762707360892.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Error charts&lt;/STRONG&gt; make deviations in time and speed crystal clear.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_2-1762707379644.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337630i3641C96914E5FB53/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_2-1762707379644.png" alt="VictorSevilla_2-1762707379644.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key takeaway:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP RPT-1 has demonstrated a clear advantage over current LLM models by effectively leveraging structured data to deliver more accurate forecasts. Once the model reaches General Availability, we will be able to perform even more precise comparisons using real business datasets, unlocking its full potential for enterprise forecasting scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Annexes&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;To provide full transparency and context, this section includes screenshots of the responses&amp;nbsp;generated by each model during the experiment. These captures show the raw outputs based on the same prompt and dataset, highlighting differences in interpretation, numeric handling, and prediction logic.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;SAP RPT-1 output:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_11-1762708606838.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337639i1157CF5DA2D14298/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_11-1762708606838.png" alt="VictorSevilla_11-1762708606838.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Strava Forecast:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_5-1762708366431.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337633i8DD98DACD3CD4C8B/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_5-1762708366431.png" alt="VictorSevilla_5-1762708366431.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Microsoft Copilot output:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_10-1762708576612.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337638i6D2FFBD68206E617/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_10-1762708576612.png" alt="VictorSevilla_10-1762708576612.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Chat GPT output:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_9-1762708560976.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337637i6D6A1481E65303E7/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_9-1762708560976.png" alt="VictorSevilla_9-1762708560976.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Gemini output:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_8-1762708548724.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337636iF8C3822B419E4A83/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_8-1762708548724.png" alt="VictorSevilla_8-1762708548724.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Actual ride data from Strava:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_7-1762708533884.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337635iF2FC37CE18F60C7E/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_7-1762708533884.png" alt="VictorSevilla_7-1762708533884.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/predicting-cycling-performance-sap-rpt-1-vs-ai-chat-models-and-strava/ba-p/14263679"/>
    <published>2025-11-09T18:19:18.957000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-machines-learn-the-science-behind-model-training/ba-p/14261378</id>
    <title>How Machines Learn: The Science Behind Model Training</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T05:43:17.151000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ashishsingh1987</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/589094</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635475755"&gt;Understanding Model Training — A Step-by-Step Explanation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;One must have heard the buzzwords &lt;STRONG&gt;“Model Training”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;“Machine Learning"&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;"Model Learning”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or &lt;STRONG&gt;“AI Model”&lt;/STRONG&gt; quite often — whether in tech discussions, product demos, or data science talks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, when it comes to explaining what actually happens during this “training” process — in plain English or even in technical terms — most people are left guessing. Is the model memorizing data? Is it adjusting something inside? What exactly is it learning?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, let’s peel back the layers and understand what truly happens when a model is trained — step by step. We’ll start from a simple analogy and then gradually move into the math behind the learning process. The goal is to make the idea of “model training” not just familiar, but intuitively clear.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568044969"&gt;Analogy: A Child Learning to Throw a Basketball&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To understand the model learning process in a simple, non-technical way, imagine a child learning to throw a basketball into a hoop.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Initially, the child doesn’t know how much force to use. On the first try, the ball falls too short or goes too far. Depending on the outcome, the child adjusts slightly and tries again. After a few attempts, the child improves and starts hitting the target consistently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s exactly how a machine learning model gets trained — it starts with random guesses, measures how wrong it was, adjusts itself, and improves over many repetitions. It learns not because someone told it what’s right, but by learning from its own mistakes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371531464"&gt;Before We Begin Few Important Notes:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1433183397"&gt;Data as Numbers&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;To train any model — whether for image classification, prediction, or generative AI — data must be represented numerically (as integers, decimals, or vectors). In this blog, we’ll skip the mathematical details of data conversion to numeric format. As part of this blog we will take an example of data which is already in numerical form.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1236669892"&gt;Loss Function&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;A loss function is like a report card for a machine learning model. It tells the model how well or how poorly it performed on the training data by comparing its predictions with the actual answers. In simple terms, the loss function calculates the difference between what the model's predicted and what it should have predicted. The bigger the difference, the higher the loss — meaning the model is doing poorly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The whole idea of model training is to minimize the loss — that is, to reduce the gap between what the model predicted and what it should have predicted with every iteration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911073668"&gt;Optimizer&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;An optimizer is the part of the training process that helps the model to&amp;nbsp;learn from its mistakes. Once the loss function tells the model how wrong it was, the optimizer decides how to adjust the model’s &lt;STRONG&gt;internal parameters (like weights and biases)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to reduce that error in the next round.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think of it like the model’s coach or guide — after every attempt, it reviews the model’s performance (using the loss value) and gives it small, calculated corrections to move it closer to the right answer. Technically, an optimizer updates the model’s parameters ensuring that with every step, the model’s predictions improve.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Popular optimizers include &lt;STRONG&gt;Gradient Descent, Adam, RMSProp, and SGD&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-843642882"&gt;Optimization step &amp;amp; Learning rate&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-905294815"&gt;Optimization step&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;P&gt;An &lt;STRONG&gt;optimization step&lt;/STRONG&gt; is the actual moment when the model &lt;STRONG&gt;updates its internal parameters&lt;/STRONG&gt; (like weights and biases) based on what it learned from the loss function. The optimization step applies the gradients calculated in previous steps to make the model slightly better than before.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can think of it as the model taking one step forward in the right direction toward minimizing the loss.&lt;BR /&gt;Over many such steps (iterations or epochs), the model gradually “learns” the best parameter values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-708781310"&gt;Learning Rate&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;P&gt;The learning rate, often denoted by the Greek letter η (eta), controls how big each optimization step should be. It’s a small numerical value that determines how quickly or slowly the model updates its parameters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the learning rate is too high, the model might overshoot the optimal point and fail to converge.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If it’s too low, the model will learn very slowly and take a long time to reach good performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In simple terms —&lt;BR /&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;learning rate is like the step size&lt;/STRONG&gt; the model takes while learning.&lt;BR /&gt;A good learning rate ensures the model moves steadily&lt;STRONG&gt; toward lower loss&lt;/STRONG&gt; without jumping past the goal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mathematically:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;wnew = wold − η × (∂L/∂w)&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Now let's dive into the actual model training part.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4063071"&gt;Introduction — What Happens When a Model Trains&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we call below code in python:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;model.fit()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;we are asking the model to learn patterns that map inputs to outputs. Behind this simple command lies a mathematical cycle of prediction, error measurement, and gradual improvement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In essence:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Model training is about minimizing mistakes — by repeatedly predicting, comparing, and correcting.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To truly understand what “learning” means, let’s dive one level down in the layers with a simple example: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;linear regression&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, where a line is fit to the provided data points using &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;gradient descent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--146725226"&gt;Step 1: Getting the Historical Data and Understanding the Business Ask&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To begin any model training process, we need historical records which holds the input and output values required for model training.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s consider the below data points as our historical records, where x is the input and y is the output for our model training. It means that whenever x happened, what was the value of y.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;x&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;y&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business problem:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Build a model that predicts &lt;EM&gt;y&lt;/EM&gt; for any given &lt;EM&gt;x&lt;/EM&gt;, based on the historical data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--343238731"&gt;Step 2: Making Predictions (Forward Pass)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Making predictions in world of model training is also referred to as “Forward Pass”, where both true input and the true outputs (i.e. historical record samples) are provided to the model for it to start learning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since we are considering a linear regression as our example, we use the simple model equation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;ŷ = w·x + b&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ll start with random model parameters: &lt;STRONG&gt;w = 0&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;b = 0&lt;/STRONG&gt;, predictions for all (x, y) pairs are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For three training data points values i.e. in the pairing of (x,y) as per above mentioned historical records:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;(1,2), (2,4), (3,6)&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;x&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;y (Actual)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ŷ (Predicted)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;0&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;0&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;0&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The model predicts nothing correctly yet — it hasn’t learned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s break down one prediction for better understanding.&lt;BR /&gt;For example let us consider the pair (x,y) --&amp;gt; (1,2), where x is the input to the model equation and y is the expected output.&lt;BR /&gt;We have our parameters w and b both having value as “0”.&lt;BR /&gt;If we substitute values of w, x and b in above equation, since both w and b are “0”, the result will be “0”.&lt;BR /&gt;Same thing happens with other paired values of (x,y). Hence all the predicted values are “0”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--539752236"&gt;Step 3: Measuring the Error (Loss Function)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We measure how wrong the predictions are using &lt;STRONG&gt;Mean Squared Error (MSE),&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;which is given by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;L = (1/n) Σ(yᵢ − ŷᵢ)²&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Substituting the numbers:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;L = (1/3)[(2−0)² + (4−0)² + (6−0)²] = 18.67&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;So, the &lt;STRONG&gt;loss = 18.67&lt;/STRONG&gt; — quite high.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;The model now knows &lt;EM&gt;how bad&lt;/EM&gt; it is doing, but not &lt;EM&gt;how to improve&lt;/EM&gt;. That’s where gradients come in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--736265741"&gt;Step 4: Learning from Mistakes (Gradient Computation)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To improve, the model must figure out &lt;STRONG&gt;how changing each parameter (w, b)&lt;/STRONG&gt; affects the loss.&lt;BR /&gt;This is done using &lt;STRONG&gt;gradients&lt;/STRONG&gt; — the partial derivatives of the loss with respect to each parameter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;∂L/∂w = −(2/n) Σ xᵢ(yᵢ − ŷᵢ)&lt;BR /&gt;∂L/∂b = −(2/n) Σ (yᵢ − ŷᵢ)&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;At our current statue (w=0, b=0):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;∂L/∂w = - (2/3) × [(1)(2) + (2)(4) + (3)(6)] = - (2/3) × 28 = -18.67&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;∂L/∂b = - (2/3) × (2 + 4 + 6) = -8&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;This tells the model to &lt;EM&gt;increase&lt;/EM&gt; w and b to reduce the loss.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--932779246"&gt;Step 5: Updating the Model (Optimization Step)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now comes the &lt;STRONG&gt;optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt; step — where we update parameters in the opposite direction of the gradient, scaled by the &lt;STRONG&gt;learning rate (η)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lets take&amp;nbsp;η = 0.1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We update parameters using the learning rate (η):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;wnew = w − η(∂L/∂w)&lt;BR /&gt;bnew = b − η(∂L/∂b)&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Plugging in the values:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;w = 0 − 0.1(−18.67) = 1.867&lt;BR /&gt;b = 0 − 0.1(−8) = 0.8&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;After iteration 1: &lt;STRONG&gt;w = 1.867, b = 0.8&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Training doesn’t stop after one update.&lt;BR /&gt;We repeat the process (forward pass → loss → gradient → update) for several &lt;STRONG&gt;epochs&lt;/STRONG&gt;, each time bringing the model closer to the true pattern.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s perform one more iteration to see the progression.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1422695758"&gt;Iteration 2&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-2088952019"&gt;Forward Pass&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;ŷ = 1.867x + 0.8&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;x&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;y&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ŷ (Predicted)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2.667&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;4.534&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;6.401&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Loss after iteration 2:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;L = (1/3)[(2−2.667)² + (4−4.534)² + (6−6.401)²] ≈ 0.34&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Loss dropped from 18.67 → 0.34 in just one iteration!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1892438514"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compute Gradients&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;∂L/∂w = - (2/3) × [(1)(2−2.667) + (2)(4−4.534) + (3)(6−6.401)] = - (2/3) × [−0.667 − 1.068 − 1.203] = 1.86&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;∂L/∂b = - (2/3) × [(2−2.667) + (4−4.534) + (6−6.401)] = 1.73&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1695925009"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update Parameters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;w = 1.867 − 0.1 × (1.86) = &lt;STRONG&gt;1.681&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;b = 0.8 − 0.1 × (1.73) = &lt;STRONG&gt;0.627&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;After iteration 2: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;w=1.681, b = 0.627&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Loss has dropped sharply — the model is learning!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Loss Summary Table:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Iterations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;w&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;b&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Loss&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;1.867&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;0.800&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;18.67&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;1.681&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;0.627&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;0.34&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;If we finish the training process after two iterations, the model for the given data would be represented by the equation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ŷ = 1.681x + 0.627&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, the values &lt;STRONG&gt;1.681&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;0.627&lt;/STRONG&gt; are the learned parameters (weight and bias) that the model has adjusted during training to best fit the data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The animation attached shows how the regression line gradually adjusts during training for 10 iterations. With each iteration, the model updates its weight (w) and bias (b) to better fit the data points — moving closer to the true relationship between x and y.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1499411504"&gt;Additional Note:&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;For ease of explanation, we considered an example with just one input variable (x).&lt;BR /&gt;However, in real-world scenarios, models usually work with multiple input features, represented as x₁, x₂, x₃, …, where each represents a different attribute or factor influencing the prediction.&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1650273578"&gt;Intuitive Summary&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Model training is guided trial and error mechanism. Each iteration:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The model guesses (&lt;EM&gt;forward pass&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It checks how wrong it was (&lt;EM&gt;loss&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It learns from the error (&lt;EM&gt;gradient&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It updates itself slightly (&lt;EM&gt;optimization&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It repeats until mistakes are minimal.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;And that’s how a simple mathematical routine turns into a “&lt;STRONG&gt;learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;” machine or what we proudly call today a “&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Machine Learning Model.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-machines-learn-the-science-behind-model-training/ba-p/14261378"/>
    <published>2025-11-10T05:43:17.151000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 1 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T13:28:03.217000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joerg_Wilke1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/880183</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337983iB92DCD9ECB4F908E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: How&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Future Supply Chain Management Works &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More and more companies have recognized the critical power of supply chain management for business success – without viable supply chains, there are no satisfied customers, no successful product launches, and no stable value creation. Supply chains need to continuously evolve to meet these needs. Today, digital technologies open up numerous opportunities, which you could only dream of a few years ago: more accurate forecasts, fully connected partner networks, and near-autonomous operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the economic environment is changing at a rapid pace: geopolitical tensions, changing customer needs, and climate change pose additional challenges for companies. In ten years’ time, supply chain management will look different than today – more connected, data-driven, and more adaptable than ever before. But what exactly will change, and how can companies prepare for it today? To answer these questions, SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University conducted a comprehensive study last year, the results of which we present in today’s and the next five issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are building on a previous study in which we analyzed the visions of the future of companies in the middle of the “Digital SC Hypes” ten years ago. The mood was euphoric: From numerous conversations with supply chain managers, over 120 potential use cases arose – from 3D printed Lego stones to the use of social media data in sales forecasting to mini factories, ultra-fast BOM resolution, and last mile drone delivery. Companies were ready to invest and experiment with new technologies. Much was visionary, some sounded like science fiction – and yet the digital revolution in supply chains seemed tangibly close.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our follow-up study shows a significantly changed picture. Pragmatic realism has given way to the great euphoria. Over the last 10 years, many technologies have been introduced slower and to a lesser extent than expected. The reasons for this include underestimated complexity and misconceptions about the performance of digital solutions (e.g. augmented reality, 3D printing or IoT), as well as an often inadequate technological state of development in the companies. Often, immature technologies, talent shortages, and inconsistent data quality slowed down execution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course, there were also some pioneers – often from industries with high pressure to innovate – who secure an advantage with targeted investments and know-how. Success often correlated with a focus on clearly outlined use cases with rapid return on investment: better delivery reliability, fewer disruptions, quickly tangible value for the user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This has been further reinforced by the recent years of pandemic, geopolitical tensions and economic weaknesses. Digital solutions for increasing automation, building integrated planning platforms, or tools to improve the customer experience are now only introduced if their value is clearly demonstrated. Successful projects usually start small and are not scaled until they have a proven effect. Lack of data quality, talent shortages, and lack of system integration are some of the biggest hurdles. Consistent data and change management is indispensable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Between 2015 and 2025, the view of digital technologies has changed significantly: away from technology-driven euphoria, towards a use-oriented deployment. The potential to achieve true competitive advantage with new technologies in supply chain management is enormous. However, many companies are still lagging behind technology leaders today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of our study, several surveys were conducted with a total of approximately 660 supply chain experts to understand today’s situation and expectations for 2035. In a multitude of in-depth discussions on Plan, Source, Make, Deliver, and People, we identified measures that companies should implement immediately, regardless of the scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are some exciting insights for the 2035 supply chains. First, the foundation of any successful digital transformation is a significant improvement in data quality. Companies also need appropriate tools to leverage this data and not remain “data-rich but insights poor.” People will continue to be important in the future, but their roles are changing. When AI takes on most of the operational work, and employees primarily monitor and develop, they are responsible for tasks that they have never practically performed themselves. Value chain silos will disappear, and technology-driven planning enables seamless end-to-end control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Few innovation leaders like Amazon, Apple or Procter &amp;amp; Gamble will be able to set new standards on their own. Most organizations do not have comparable budgets, skills, or talents. They will make technological leaps, especially if they can use market-based standard solutions and thus participate in developments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless of the individual level of maturity, it is possible to record: If you want to play at the front in 2035, you must already start implementing “no-regret moves”: for example, establish robust data governance, standardize processes, and introduce employees specifically to AI tools. Companies that lay these foundations today will not only use technologies in 2035, but will use them strategically. Or, to say it with the words of Wayne Gretzky, “Good players skate to the puck. Great players skate to where the puck is going to be.“&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the second part of the series, we will show in the next issue why supply chain planning is becoming the decisive success factor, what gaps exist here today between ambition and reality, and how companies can prepare for 2035 with data, AI, and agents. In the subsequent expenditures, we will examine the key findings of our research in the areas of purchasing, production, distribution, and employees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340454iFD3D03812DA7B84A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) and Florian Diehlmann (SAP) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307"/>
    <published>2025-11-10T13:28:03.217000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-document-ai-accelerates-document-centric-business-processes-with/ba-p/14264358</id>
    <title>SAP Document AI accelerates document-centric business processes with Generative AI</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T13:54:41.812000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jacobahtan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2758</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Authors:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7024"&gt;@amagnani37&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16662"&gt;@merza&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you to everyone who joined our recent partner webinar, &lt;STRONG&gt;"Streamline document processing with SAP Document AI"&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This session was part of our ongoing partner webinar series, "&lt;A href="https://url.sap/crvdej" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Talk to your business with Generative AI&lt;/A&gt;", and the turnout and engagement were fantastic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For those who couldn't make it, or for anyone who wants a recap, we—&lt;STRONG&gt;Merza Klaghstan&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Alice Magnani&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Jacob Tan&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the BTP &amp;amp; AI Solution Architects team —wanted to share the key takeaways, demos, and technical insights from the session.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our goal was to go beyond a simple feature list and show you how SAP Document AI can be the centerpiece of a complete, end-to-end business solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s what we covered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565066"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 1: What is SAP Document AI and Why Does it Matter?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We kicked off by tackling the core business problem: a staggering &lt;STRONG&gt;70-80% of all enterprise information is unstructured&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Manually processing this data from documents, emails, and scans is not only slow but also expensive and prone to errors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Document AI, formerly known as Document Information Extraction (DOX), is SAP's AI-powered solution on the Business Technology Platform (BTP) designed to solve this. It goes far beyond simple Optical Character Recognition (OCR) to &lt;STRONG&gt;extract, classify, and validate data&lt;/STRONG&gt; with high precision.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568134280"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We highlighted several key features:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multiple Editions:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The service is available in &lt;STRONG&gt;Base AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Premium AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; (which includes Generative AI capabilities), and &lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded&lt;/STRONG&gt; editions to fit different use cases. We also want to highlight for our &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Partners&lt;/STRONG&gt; that the Premium AI edition is part of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Test, Demo, and Development (TDD) license&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which provides a much more convenient model for your non-productive and internal development purposes.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_0-1762748655159.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337670iAC7B14D2EA3F5CEC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_0-1762748655159.png" alt="jacobahtan_0-1762748655159.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The New "Workspace" UI:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We compared the classic "Basic" UI with the new, full-featured "Workspace," which is the future of the service and includes capabilities like email channel configuration and workflow management.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;It's the new, full-featured environment for all document processing tasks . We want to emphasize that &lt;STRONG&gt;from now on, all the latest SAP Document AI features will be available in the Workspace UI only&lt;/STRONG&gt;, so we strongly advise using it for all new projects.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_2-1762778617735.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338002i32C51D71B4CCA784/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_2-1762778617735.png" alt="jacobahtan_2-1762778617735.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pre-Configured &amp;amp; Custom Content (Schemas):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The service provides many pre-trained models (called "Schemas") for standard documents like invoices and purchase orders. The real power, however, comes from creating &lt;STRONG&gt;custom schemas&lt;/STRONG&gt; for any document type your business needs—from specialized licenses to internal forms.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_2-1762748655205.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337672iFABDFFF3FF0DDE1F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_2-1762748655205.png" alt="jacobahtan_2-1762748655205.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generative AI &amp;amp; Instant Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; For custom schemas, SAP Document AI leverages Generative AI and Large Language Models (LLMs) to understand and extract information. We also demonstrated &lt;STRONG&gt;"Instant Learning,"&lt;/STRONG&gt; where the model learns from your manual corrections &lt;EM&gt;immediately&lt;/EM&gt;. After one correction, it knows how to handle that document layout correctly the next time.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In our demo, we showed how the model initially struggled with a name containing a middle name and extracted the wrong federation name (full name vs. acronym) . After one manual correction and confirmation, it learned immediately. Technically, this feature uses &lt;STRONG&gt;few-shots prompting&lt;/STRONG&gt; to make the underlying LLM aware of your previously reviewed documents to improve accuracy on the next run.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2Fb3ZP-2bAqK0%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3Db3ZP-2bAqK0&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2Fb3ZP-2bAqK0%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="Instant Learning in SAP Document AI for Streamline document processing with SAP Document AI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538056"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 2: A Real-World Use Case: "Vertigo Travels"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make this real, we introduced &lt;STRONG&gt;"Vertigo Travels,"&lt;/STRONG&gt; a fictional travel agency specializing in sports and adventure holidays. Their key challenge is managing the various kind of documents required for subscriptions, such as ID cards, medical certificates, and diving licenses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_3-1762748655218.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337673i4B1770A465F5332A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_3-1762748655218.png" alt="jacobahtan_3-1762748655218.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175107270"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The solution architecture includes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Vertigo Travels website&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a frontend application,&amp;nbsp; deployed in Cloud Foundry, serving as entry point for Travelers to select travel packages and upload the necessary documents, such as ID cards or medical certificates. The backend logic is a &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP (Node.js)&lt;/STRONG&gt; application also deployed in a cloud Foundry.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Document AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;, for all document intelligence operations, communicating via &lt;STRONG&gt;API&lt;/STRONG&gt; with our backend application.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as a persistence layer for our application, to store all the entities involved in the subscription process.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Work Zone standard edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as the entry point for Vertigo Travels employees to supervise the process. From Work Zone, business users can access the Vertigo Travel website for admin operations, or the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Document AI workspace&lt;/STRONG&gt;, for instance to review documents. SAP Build Work Zone also allows business users to use SAP Document AI via mobile.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, to define business rules to automate some document validation checks. Although this could also be implemented as part of the &amp;nbsp;Vertigo Travels backend application, SAP Build Process Automation enables citizen developers to modify easily the business logics when required.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as the core SAP Cloud solution. The Vertigo Travels backend is integrated with modules such as Business Partners, Products, Sales Orders/Invoice, Customer Return for refund.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107676484"&gt;For the source code, you may refer &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-generative-ai-hub-use-cases/tree/main/53-vertigo-travels-documentai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here for reference&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;P.S. if you're planning to work on this prototype, please give us a shout out~! So at least we know somebody is trying our repository out!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_0-1762777602698.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337997i11A82F6B49B135F4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_0-1762777602698.png" alt="jacobahtan_0-1762777602698.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911162979"&gt;We demonstrated three end-to-end scenarios:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The E2E Flow:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A traveler, Mary, subscribes on the website and uploads her documents. A back-office employee, Barry, reviews and corrects one document in the Document AI Workspace. Once confirmed, a Sales Order is automatically created in S/4HANA Cloud.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multi-Channel Ingestion:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A traveler, Luca, visits an office. The employee uses &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Mobile Start&lt;/STRONG&gt; to scan his ID and medical certificate. The system then automatically emails Luca about a missing document. He simply replies to the email with his license attached, which is automatically ingested via the &lt;STRONG&gt;Inbound Channel&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A traveler, Claire, uploads an income statement to apply for a discount. &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt; runs a rule to check her eligibility. When she submits her final documents, they have a high confidence score and are &lt;STRONG&gt;auto-confirmed&lt;/STRONG&gt; without any manual review.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FfaKqdkL1UmI%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DfaKqdkL1UmI&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FfaKqdkL1UmI%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="113" scrolling="no" title="Use Case end to end demo for Streamline document processing with SAP Document AI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-456484036"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 3: How We Built It (The Technical Deep Dive)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518135969"&gt;For our developer community, we walked through the "how-to" for the key components.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-450705183"&gt;For the source code, you may refer &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-generative-ai-hub-use-cases/tree/main/53-vertigo-travels-documentai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here for reference&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;P.S. if you're planning to work on this prototype, please give us a shout out~! So at least we know somebody is trying our repository out!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Setup and Schema Management:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We started with the BTP setup, which involves managing entitlements, creating the service instance, and, critically, &lt;STRONG&gt;establishing trust with SAP Cloud Identity Service (IAS)&lt;/STRONG&gt; for user authorization. We then showed how to create the custom schemas that power the application.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;When you set up your entitlements, make sure to use the application subscription ending in &lt;STRONG&gt;-ias (Identity Authentication Service)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as this is the one that provisions the new Workspace interface.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. API-Driven Development:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Our CAP application's backend communicates directly with Document AI's APIs. We showed code snippets for uploading a file (using the FileService) and processing it against a schema (using the SchemaService).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to retrieve specific extracted values:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;While our demo UI showed a simple text extraction, your application will likely need specific, structured data (like "gross_family_income" or "number_of_kids"). The API makes this straightforward:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After processing the document, you get a Document ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can use this Document ID to retrieve the Document Version ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Using the Version ID, you can then query the Entities for that document. 4. Finally, you can retrieve the specific value by using the Entity ID (e.g., the ID for your "number_of_kids" field) .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is how our automation process, for example, was able to pull only the family income and number of kids to pass to the rules engine.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Configuring Email Ingestion:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We configured the "Channels" feature to monitor an email inbox. This required registering an app in Microsoft Azure, granting Mail.ReadWrite permissions , and then using the Document AI Workspace to map a specific email folder to our target schema.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F2CFz59M6QkE%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D2CFz59M6QkE&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F2CFz59M6QkE%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="113" scrolling="no" title="Email Ingestion by SAP Document AI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Enabling SAP Mobile Start:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This was a key integration for the in-office scenario. It involved three steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adding the Document AI dependency to SAP Build Work Zone within the IAS console.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Creating a specific BTP destination (sapdocumentaimobilestartintegration).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configuring the app tile in the Work Zone Site Manager with the correct navigation and visualization parameters (e.g., mobilestart.type = documentAi).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F6zSnSLFhono%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D6zSnSLFhono&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F6zSnSLFhono%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="113" scrolling="no" title="Document Scanning with SAP Mobile Start integrated with SAP Document AI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Automating Logic with SAP Build Process Automation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To keep our application logic flexible, we externalized our validation rules. We created a process in SAP Build Process Automation with a &lt;STRONG&gt;Decision Table (Rule)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to calculate the family discount based on income and number of kids. This process is exposed as an API and triggered by our CAP application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FULpiT681ooQ%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DULpiT681ooQ&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FULpiT681ooQ%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="113" scrolling="no" title="Decision Rules in Build Process Automation for Streamline document processing with SAP Document AI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_5-1762748655258.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337675iDE3C9EE786CF3B6B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_5-1762748655258.png" alt="jacobahtan_5-1762748655258.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-125108959"&gt;For the source code, you may refer &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-generative-ai-hub-use-cases/tree/main/53-vertigo-travels-documentai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here for reference&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;P.S. if you're planning to work on this prototype, please give us a shout out~! So at least we know somebody is trying our repository out!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-440170099"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 4: Conclusion, Best Practices, and What's Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We concluded with some key advice and a look ahead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--49746413"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best Practices &amp;amp; Responsible AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quality In, Quality Out:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The accuracy of extraction heavily depends on the quality of your scans.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Human in the Loop:&lt;/STRONG&gt; While automation is powerful, always design your processes with a "human in the loop" for validation, especially for critical data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Responsible AI:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We reiterated SAP's commitment to AI ethics. External LLM providers are carefully selected and are &lt;STRONG&gt;not permitted to store or retrain their models on customer data&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Features like continuous data sharing for model improvement are strictly opt-in and should not be used for sensitive personal data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--246259918"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started and Look Ahead&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are committed to helping our partners build on this platform. Here are the resources to get you started:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Document AI Official Help Page:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://url.sap/imohkv" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://url.sap/imohkv&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vertigo Travels GitHub Repository:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://url.sap/pi5vwn" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://url.sap/pi5vwn&lt;/A&gt; (The code for our demo app will be available here!)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Community for AI/ML:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://url.sap/ai-ml-grp" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://url.sap/ai-ml-grp&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The roadmap for SAP Document AI is packed with features, including more pre-built schemas, document workflows, custom LLM prompting, and deeper integration with Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, don't miss &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual&lt;/STRONG&gt;! Be sure to check out sessions &lt;STRONG&gt;AI821v&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;AI102v&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the latest roadmap and deep-dive innovations from the product team.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please feel free to leave any questions or feedback in the comments below!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-document-ai-accelerates-document-centric-business-processes-with/ba-p/14264358"/>
    <published>2025-11-10T13:54:41.812000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-handle-posting-issues-for-billing-documents-using-joule/ba-p/14258903</id>
    <title>How to Handle Posting Issues for Billing Documents Using Joule</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T07:47:22.168000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>emilyshi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/809418</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763849034"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Background Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a billing clerk, managing billing documents with posting issues can be frustrating sometime. Fortunately, Joule can streamline the process, making it more efficient and less stressful to resolves the posting issues.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Posting issues often arise when billing documents cannot be posted to the financial account due to errors like closed posting periods. Common errors include accounting errors (F5/286 and F5/903), which occur when the billing date falls outside the open period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule is an AI copilot designed to enhance interaction with SAP business systems. Joule delivers a unified user experience across SAP's solutions, offering conversational interactions to streamline information access, automate business processes, and improve both employee and customer satisfaction. For more information, see &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/joule-guide/what-is-joule" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What Is Joule&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567335529"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure you have the &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales - Billing Documents&lt;/STRONG&gt; business catalog (&lt;EM&gt;SAP_SD_BC_BIL_DOC_PC&lt;/EM&gt;) assigned. The &lt;STRONG&gt;Billing Clerk&lt;/STRONG&gt; role template (&lt;EM&gt;SAP_BR_BILLING_CLERK&lt;/EM&gt;) includes this catalog by default.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set up Joule in your environment. For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule/initial-setup" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Initial Setup.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370822024"&gt;Implementation Details&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow the steps below to try out this feature:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in to your Fiori Launchpad as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Billing Clerk&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Launch Joule. The method for launching Joule differs depending on your platform. See&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/serviceguide/using-joule?state=DRAFT&amp;amp;version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using Joule | SAP Help Portal.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ask Joule to find out billing documents with posting issues. You can narrow down your searching results by specifying criteria such as document type, issue type, or sales organization. Note that only the billing documents with accounting access error will be listed here.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;Post&lt;/STRONG&gt; button or chat commands to post a document. Only one document can be posted at a time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review the error message for more details.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;As an alternative solution, you can adjust the billing date to a valid date using the quick buttons. When the posting error is resolved, the document will be automatically posted. You can open the billing document to confirm the changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By following these steps, you can efficiently manage and resolve posting issues, ensuring a smooth billing process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watch the following video for step-by-step instruction:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_t2lq0d80" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-handle-posting-issues-for-billing-documents-using-joule/ba-p/14258903"/>
    <published>2025-11-11T07:47:22.168000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/vibe-coding-when-ai-writes-the-code-benefits-challenges-and-guardrails/ba-p/14266237</id>
    <title>Vibe Coding: When AI Writes the Code — Benefits, Challenges, and Guardrails</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:46:04.669000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>da_radix</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/703241</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From my experience leading engineering and delivery teams for high-value projects, I’ve understood that technology changes fast — and the way people leverage technology changes faster. Through the emerging rhythm of ‘Vibe coding’ developers &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;speed up each stage of the SDLC, minimize mundane work, and experiment while maintaining quality. It also helps programmers with intelligent code completions, pre-built templates, and l&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;everage AI suggestions, so thathey can &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;focus more on innovation, complex logic, and architecture. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://radixweb.com/blog/artificial-intelligence-statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;72% of global organizations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; use AI in at least one of their business domains. AI utilization is thrilling yet equally unnerving. The potential is remarkable, but it also comes with a huge responsibility.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, here’s my take on the opportunities, the risks, and the guidelines every organization needs to consider.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764706343"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why ‘Vibe Coding’ Matters Now&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;use cases of AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; have grown beyond its specific role to be a significant component of the dev team. Large language models, code generation tools, and specialized AI agents help draft modules, propose optimizations, and auto-generate tests. For enterprises prioritizing data sensitivity, integration, and complexity, this transformation is more than a strategic imperative. It helps change how we define value, delivery velocity, and team dynamics.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Speaking from my tech leadership experience, I’ve witnessed project schedules accelerate, and prototypes that took weeks to design are completed in a few days. This gave product owners and architects more time to think about long-term goals. However, speed without a structured approach is simply chaos. And that’s where expertise and experience are pressing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568192838"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Opportunities: Velocity, Innovation, and Scale&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are three big opportunities I often reflect on.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Velocity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; - AI-powered programming speeds up routine tasks like data-mapping code, unit tests, boilerplate, scaffolding, which further allows engineers to emphasize more on the challenging elements – business rules, edge-cases, and architecture. And for specific implementations, where orchestrations, BAPIs, and connector code are commonly used, code automation can drastically minimize time-to-value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Innovation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – When algorithms manage mundane activities, teams can innovate faster. You must ensure that your product teams improvise on &amp;nbsp;feature ideas with AI-enabled flow diagrams and mockups, streamlining the feedback process from stakeholders and clients. It’s seamless to experiment when testing a hypothesis becomes more cost-efficient.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scale &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– AI helps maintain standardization across extensive codebases and team structures. Trained models automatically recommend uniform code patterns; this keeps your enterprise's ‘coding vibe’ logical and seamless.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371679333"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Threat: Complacency, Drift, and Hidden Pitfalls&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, the flip side also demands attention.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Complacency&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – This drawback is real. If dev teams start accepting AI results on the surface, bugs emerge. I’ve observed that even the teams with good intentions might push out integration logic or autogenerated SQL that didn’t adhere to data sovereignty standards, edge inputs, and concurrency. These lapses might violate compliance or breach master data integrity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Drift &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Model drift and hallucinations are also the most significant concerns. AI sometimes might generate credible code or documentation that indirectly breaks security standards or business logic. If not checked early, these drifts enter production.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Human Risk &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– The biggest hidden pitfall is loss of skill. If engineers stop learning basic concepts, like debugging middleware, understanding BAPI contracts, or reading complex ABAP flows, it can erode the organization’s long-term strategic capability. This is a real issue that can be combatted only with a culture of continuous learning. Afterall, AI is here to compliment human abilities, but without human governance and intervention, it cannot make ethicll calls. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175165828"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Guidelines: Build for Trust, Not Just Speed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To experience the strengths while also managing the risks, development teams require an architecture of practice and governance. Drawing from our experience of working on specific projects, here are solid guardrails I would suggest.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define a ‘Trusted AI Baseline’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Refine&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; prompt libraries and train models using your organization’s secure patterns and best practices. I recommend managing a library of carefully designed model policies and prompt templates in line with your specific integration patterns, security controls, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://aws.amazon.com/what-is/service-level-agreement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;client SLAs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Default to Human Supervision &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Humans should first review every AI-generated modification&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. For design-based decisions, transfer outputs to product owners for verification against the business results. And for code, combine the AI’s recommendation tools with a named reviewer who has a good know-how of system invariants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Observability and Provenance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Maintain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; the record of suggestions made by AI, who approved it, and which version/model generated it. This traceability is non-negotiable for continuous improvements, debugging, and audits — particularly for businesses that majorly function under strict compliance demands.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ongoing Validation: Tests + Contracts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Go&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for automatic test generation alongside &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-based programming&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. For seamless integrations, you can design contract tests that help define throughput limits, expected error modes, and assert schemas. The automatic tests are like your safety net that lets you speed up while ensuring reliability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Talent Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keep your team members' skills honed by conducting frequent in-depth workshops on core topics, switching up team roles and responsibilities, and AI-based training for higher efficiency. We invest in resources for structured learning workflows that integrate AI-powered labs guided by experts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978652323"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How Can You Make it REAL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Try&amp;nbsp;implementing these principles across different initiatives and collaborations. Some proven strategies I advise using include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hybrid Pipelines -&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Incorporate AI into &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://about.gitlab.com/topics/ci-cd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CI/CD pipelines&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; so that AI-produced outputs prompt the same contract tests, security scans, and static analysis as human-generated code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Co-Created Models - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For long-term clients, continuously refine private models based on anonymized snippets of the code, architecture docs, and integration logs. This helps make AI-powered suggestions aligned to corporate frameworks and context-driven.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transparent Delivery -&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Every pull request AI assists or generates needs to be&amp;nbsp;identified, audited, and monitored, streamlining compliance and post-launch maintenance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Client Workshops - C&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;onduct governance and skills development training sessions that consist of red-team simulation exercises — deliberately coaxing AI toward risky results to train teams to identify and address potential issues.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782138818"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Human Equation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the race towards AI-led transformation, the human equation is of utmost importance. Cutting-edge technologies like AI help optimize decisions, analyze data at scale, and automate processes. Still, it is human perspective, ethical oversight, and creativity that unlock the real potential of AI. If you opt for AI-driven innovation, don’t just focus on deploying algorithms—keep your team members in the loop to ensure that teams guide, verify, and apply human context to machine outputs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, by focusing on seamless collaboration between AI and humans, businesses can align speed with responsibility, driving innovation while managing risks. Ultimately, it’s the amalgamation of human governance and AI capabilities that defines long-term evolution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-585625313"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Takeaway&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I’m optimistic! When powered by knowledge and structured by guardrails, Vibe Coding can revolutionize how dev teams build. It empowers humans to focus on things machines cannot - define objective, map out strategies, and employ critical thinking. The key for quick-moving businesses lies in striking the right balance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, if you’re considering integrating Vibe Coding, begin with pilot projects, capture all data, and keep humans in the loop. Well, the future isn’t humans vs. AI — it’s the seamless collaboration of AI with humans, vibing to design and develop more intelligent systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/vibe-coding-when-ai-writes-the-code-benefits-challenges-and-guardrails/ba-p/14266237"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:46:04.669000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-exploration-to-excellence-maturity-assessment-for-sap-btp/ba-p/14267457</id>
    <title>From Exploration to Excellence: Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T00:46:59.654000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>joanneks</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7268</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, SAP Community!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You've made the investment in SAP Business Technology Platform. You've implemented integrations, built extensions, and connected your enterprise landscape. But here's the question that keeps IT leaders up at night: &lt;STRONG&gt;Are you truly maximizing SAP BTP's potential, or are you leaving transformative value on the table?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For most organizations, the honest answer is somewhere in between—and that uncertainty is precisely the problem. Without a clear baseline of your current capabilities, it's nearly impossible to chart an effective course forward or justify additional resources to stakeholders who demand measurable results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To tackle this challenge, SAP introduced the &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/maturity-assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;at &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/A&gt;—a comprehensive technical evaluation designed to transform uncertainty into actionable insights. If you missed it during SAP TechEd, here are all the exciting details. Here's the On-Demand session of the SAP TechEd 2025&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752172006673001rFWp?token_type=bearer&amp;amp;client_id=08cbc601-1128-43a8-9587-150cadca5f52" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;XP100v | Accelerate adoption of SAP Business Technology Platform with confidence.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635655399"&gt;What You'll Get: Immediate Value, Strategic Direction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;You'll gain a precise understanding of your organization's maturity of SAP BTP utilization, allowing you to identify and address areas for improvement with tailored recommendations. Additionally, you'll align your platform strategy with broader business objectives, ensuring that every effort contributes to your digital transformation goals. Moreover, you'll uncover hidden operational efficiencies and innovative solutions that can drive tangible business value, elevating your role as a strategic tech leader within the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568224613"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_0-1762981526771.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339783iCD1165D9648DAB6F/image-dimensions/592x318/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="592" height="318" role="button" title="joanneks_0-1762981526771.png" alt="joanneks_0-1762981526771.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Roadmap Clarity&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Transform vague improvement intentions into a structured roadmap with prioritized actions based on your specific needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Investment Justification&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Develop compelling business cases for additional SAP BTP investments, armed with concrete data on maturity levels and improvement opportunities, aligned with your overall business objectives.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Uncover potential inefficiencies in how you're consuming SAP BTP services and discover opportunities to optimize SAP BTP utilization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Innovation Acceleration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Identify new use cases and innovative solutions you haven't considered based on your maturity profile.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242628389"&gt;Getting Started: The Assessment Process&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The online questionnaire takes only 10-15 minutes to complete, which is less time than your daily stand-up. No lengthy interviews or extensive documentation reviews—just focused questions that get to the heart of your implementation. Upon completion, you receive immediate scoring along with a comprehensive report.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Complete the Questionnaire&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Answer focused questions across five key dimensions in just 10-15 minutes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Receive Your Results&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Get immediate feedback and access your comprehensive report in PDF to find areas for improvement and instant recommendations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Take Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Use the tailored recommendations to act.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_1-1762981526787.png" style="width: 588px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339785iFC0ECBD7C92D23CB/image-dimensions/588x250/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="588" height="250" role="button" title="joanneks_1-1762981526787.png" alt="joanneks_1-1762981526787.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_2-1762981526794.png" style="width: 586px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339784i1517B29B39462E2E/image-dimensions/586x269/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="586" height="269" role="button" title="joanneks_2-1762981526794.png" alt="joanneks_2-1762981526794.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175197603"&gt;Maturity Levels Explained&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-11-12 at 3.25.41 PM.png" style="width: 801px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339822iFA25E39E159C4ECA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-11-12 at 3.25.41 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-11-12 at 3.25.41 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP is designed to provide organizations with a clear, current snapshot of how to utilize SAP BTP effectively. This snapshot is segmented into five distinct maturity levels, each representing different stages of adoption and integration within the organization. These levels serve as indicators of an organization's ongoing journey towards digital transformation and innovation. By understanding and leveraging these levels, organizations can strategically evolve their usage of SAP BTP, ensuring that they derive maximum value from the platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_3-1762981526796.png" style="width: 910px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339786i29A35524113346AA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="joanneks_3-1762981526796.png" alt="joanneks_3-1762981526796.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Getting Started&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This initial phase involves early exploration of the platform, where learning and testing ideas occur in an ad hoc manner. Organizations at this level are in the discovery phase, familiarizing themselves with the platform's capabilities and potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In this stage, foundations begin to form as growing platform adoption occurs, although key practices are still maturing. Organizations start to incorporate SAP BTP more consistently into their operations, paving the way for broader implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Standardization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: At this level, clear processes and shared approaches are established across teams, ensuring consistent and strategic SAP BTP usage. This marks a critical point where the platform becomes an integral part of the organization's technology stack, contributing to more streamlined and effective operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Scalable Execution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Here, SAP BTP is deployed reliably at scale, driving innovation across the organization. This stage reflects a higher level of maturity, where the platform is not only used but also leveraged to achieve strategic business objectives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Center of Excellence&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The pinnacle of SAP BTP maturity, this level signifies that the organization recognizes SAP BTP as a strategic driver of its business. Enterprise architecture, operations, and delivery capabilities are optimized around SAP BTP, fostering an environment of continuous innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/maturity-assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; serves as a valuable tool for organizations to evaluate their current standing and plan for future growth. It not only aids in identifying areas for improvement but also provides actionable insights to enhance the platform's utilization, ultimately supporting the organization's continuous process of evolution and thriving in the digital landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849601379"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Act Now&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The role of SAP Business Technology Platform in driving intelligent enterprises continues to expand, with new capabilities emerging regularly—from enhanced integration patterns to advanced AI agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organizations with a clear understanding of their current maturity level can evaluate these innovations strategically, adopting what drives value while avoiding distraction. The objective is not only to assess your BTP maturity but also to create a continuous improvement cycle rather than being forced to react when gaps become critical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In conjunction with the new &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/maturity-assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;,&amp;nbsp; SAP BTP Adoption Phases are introduced on &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/guidance-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; as a beta version for SAP TechEd. This will provide a clear path to align the phases of SAP BTP adoption with &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.leanix.net/en/wiki/tech-transformation/sap-activate-methodology" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Activate Methodology&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Activate Methodology also offers additional common accelerators (e.g., project management templates) and an integrated tool chain (e.g. with SAP Cloud ALM) to run larger SAP implementation projects. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To illustrate the relationship between the Future Ready Enterprise Model, the new Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP, and the Adoption Phases, here’s a TAM of the process:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_4-1762981526803.png" style="width: 668px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339787i0318FA5CB215AF8A/image-dimensions/668x452/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="668" height="452" role="button" title="joanneks_4-1762981526803.png" alt="joanneks_4-1762981526803.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-653087874"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your Next Steps: From Assessment to Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/10/sap-connect-btp-ai-business-suite/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bharat Sandhu, CMO of SAP BTP, notes&lt;/A&gt; that developers struggle to effectively utilize AI due to difficulties in integrating it with business-specific data and processes, resulting in diminished benefits. Additionally, the time and cost of building applications, along with the challenge of managing fragmented systems, underscore the need for a more robust AI-powered development platform. To solve those challenges, knowing precisely where your organization stands today is crucial for maximizing the transformative potential of SAP BTP. The Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP is designed to deliver this insight, helping you determine if your organization is fully harnessing its capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're at the beginning of your SAP BTP journey or looking to optimize mature investments, this assessment provides a comprehensive technical baseline alongside the strategic clarity, objective data, and actionable recommendations you need to move forward with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the SAP TechEd On-Demand Session: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Watch the On-Demand session&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752172006673001rFWp?token_type=bearer&amp;amp;client_id=08cbc601-1128-43a8-9587-150cadca5f52" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;XP100v | Accelerate adoption of SAP Business Technology Platform with confidence &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for a demo of the Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Engage with the Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Join &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;upcoming webinars and workshops&lt;/A&gt; where SAP experts and peers discuss assessment findings and share best practices for advancing BTP maturity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leverage Additional Resources&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/use-cases.html?sort=latest_desc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;existing SAP BTP use cases&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the corresponding&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Discovery Center missions with accelerators.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read about SAP Discovery Center Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everything-you-need-to-know-about-sap-discovery-center-before-teched/ba-p/14249744#M185626" target="_blank"&gt;Read this blog&lt;/A&gt; to learn all of the notable updates on SAP Discovery Center in preparation for SAP TechEd 2025.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-585657088"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Take the first step by visiting &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; today and unlock the insights that will drive your next breakthrough&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-exploration-to-excellence-maturity-assessment-for-sap-btp/ba-p/14267457"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T00:46:59.654000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-smarter-support-experience/ba-p/14266192</id>
    <title>A Smarter Support Experience</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T05:36:37.206000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>feliciashafiq</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1401024</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Your support experience is evolving. Key changes and what you need to know.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;As part of our ongoing efforts to make &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;support from SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;smarter and easier for you&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, we have been piloting new ways to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;optimize&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the support experience and better connect you with the right channels and the right experts. We are excited to share that these improvements &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;are &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;now &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;live&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s changing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As your entry point, the “Get Support” application has been enhanced to make it easier to create and manage your support cases.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A clearer, unified navigation structure now guides you through case creation, with each step accessible from the left-hand pane.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The detailed description field has been moved to the beginning of the process—helping you provide important context earlier and improving the quality of AI-driven recommendations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Improved UI consistency and AI disclosure messages to make the interface more transparent, intuitive, and ready for future innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In particular, the Incident Solution Matching (ISM) service has been further enriched with generative AI (GenAI) capabilities. Based on the information you provide, the service compiles relevant solutions and summarizes them into a single, easy-to-read answer—complete with links to the original knowledge articles used.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The GenAI feature is being rolled out to customers in phases, starting with a limited group and expanding over time. It includes a feedback option to continuously refine your experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When you create a case, you may receive a recommended priority based on your case details. This helps guide your selection so your case can reach the right experts and most suitable support channel, helping to enhance the overall resolution time. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You remain in full control and can always adjust the priority &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;to reflect your business impact or urgency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="New customer view in 'Get Support' application" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339083iF3732ACBE394B697/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NewGetSupport_SCT_Combined_Submit.png" alt="New customer view in 'Get Support' application" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;New customer view in 'Get Support' application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Set up your case for faster resolution&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To help ensure your case reaches the right experts as quickly as possible:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Write a concise title for the issue that states the key symptom.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use the detailed description section to provide evidence, error messages, recent changes, and attempted fixes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select the correct system that is affected by the technical issue you want to report&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select the most accurate product, function, or component.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clearly describe the business impact, along with any workarounds in place&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keep your case updated if conditions change and add feedback if you adjust the proposed priority.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for partnering with us as we continue to transform support from SAP into an experience that is smarter and more effective for you.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-smarter-support-experience/ba-p/14266192"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T05:36:37.206000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445</id>
    <title>Joule in SAP Build Code can now create freestyle UI5 apps</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:58:38.496000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndreasKunz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Last year, we&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-for-freestyle-sapui5-development-in-sap-build-code/ba-p/13650005" target="_blank"&gt;introduced the SAPUI5 extension for the Joule coding assistant in SAP Build Code&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/now-ai-helps-you-developing-sapui5-applications/ba-p/13649767" target="_blank"&gt;wrote about how to use it&lt;/A&gt;. Over time, it has received more features, like the AI-supported &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sapui5-meets-typescript-a-smooth-migration-journey-with-joule/ba-p/13958872" target="_blank"&gt;conversion of UI5 apps to TypeScript&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and setting up new pages and the respective navigation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The latest improvement, available from November 2025, lets you&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;create new freestyle UI5 apps&lt;/STRONG&gt; according to your requirements. The feature is not absolutely groundbreaking, as there are other tools doing a similar job like the &lt;A href="https://github.com/ui5-community/generator-easy-ui5" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Easy-UI5 templates&lt;/A&gt; and the recently published &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;UI5 MCP Server&lt;/A&gt;. But:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It brings the functionality right to the fingertips of developers using SAP Build Code—no other tools needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It extends the template capabilities beyond what the Easy-UI5 templates provide.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementing it within the Build Code Joule environment yielded interesting insights and further improvements. More on this in my &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_self"&gt;other article&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565993"&gt;The feature&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule makes specific features available using "slash commands". The new one is &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt;. When you open the Joule panel in SAP Build Code and start typing &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5&lt;/FONT&gt;, you might see it suggested, as well as other UI5 features. But which commands appear depends on the context. While some are only available &lt;EM&gt;within&lt;/EM&gt; UI5 apps, this new feature is only available when you are &lt;EM&gt;not&lt;/EM&gt; in a UI5 app. It won't be available e.g. in a workspace which has a ui5.yaml at top-level, or when you have a UI5 controller open in the code editor!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" style="width: 368px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338077i84DC1A2BF1286B93/image-dimensions/368x637/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="368" height="637" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Try it in a workspace with a &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/about/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;CAP&lt;/A&gt; project at root level, so you see some of its magic immediately: as soon as you finish typing the slash command or select it from the suggestion list, another suggestion list with sample prompts comes up. These are based on the actual data structures of the CAP project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" style="width: 470px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336598i81FF249A52996728/image-dimensions/470x310?v=v2" width="470" height="310" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means you can simply select the desired entity and service, then the actual full prompt will automatically be entered into the field(but of course you can also write your own prompt!). This full prompt includes even more details than the short prompt in the suggestion list did.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" style="width: 426px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336599iE4DE35FC0A4A5C5B/image-dimensions/426x146?v=v2" width="426" height="146" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that the prompt includes a concrete list of properties and the service URL. This information has been extracted from CAP using good old deterministic code—no Large Language Model (LLM) used. In fact, this is an area where AI would likely make up ("hallucinate") property names which do not actually exist. Acquiring all this information in advance in a deterministic way not only gives you the chance to review and adjust the prompt with little effort, but also leads to a more reliable functionality overall.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The paradigm: use LLMs (Large Language Models) where they excel—processing and "understanding" language—and use deterministic code for hard facts and well-defined operations, where possible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI part starts soon enough, when you submit this prompt. It proposes a specific app setup, highlighting the key choices for you to review. For example, it will suggest a sensible name (if you didn't provide one) or suggest the best location inside the project structure (which it knows from its context).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" style="width: 419px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336631iE19FE81A151525DB/image-dimensions/419x840?v=v2" width="419" height="840" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" alt="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But you can do more than just review those &lt;EM&gt;parameters&lt;/EM&gt;.&amp;nbsp;A suggested version of the app has already been created behind the scenes, so you can scroll through the 30+ files listed in the box at the bottom and click those you want to preview. If the result already looks fine to you—perfect. Just press the "Accept Application" button and the app will be set up in your workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439052488"&gt;Refining the app&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;But of course you are free to continue the conversation and tweak the result. The LLM in Joule will put its true strength at work, mapping its understanding of your request to what the underlying template can do. No need to type "change parameter x to value y": LLMs also understand you when you are less formal and direct. Look at the below screenshot for an example: it responds almost too compassionately to the developer who is "hesitant about new technologies" and recreates the app with changed parameters—using JavaScript instead of TypeScript. The user did not even mention the programming language specifically, but still the LLM decided that changing it would be the best way to accommodate the app code to the user's preferences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" style="width: 453px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336633i0D1C4439BEED17A1/image-dimensions/453x307?v=v2" width="453" height="307" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" alt="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this stage, you can refine the setup of the initial app—within the limits imposed by the application template used behind the scenes, which only has limited degrees of freedom. We want this &lt;EM&gt;initial&lt;/EM&gt; app to be robust and follow best-practice code. We also want those 30+ files to be created in &lt;EM&gt;one&lt;/EM&gt; fast step. Hence the code is not written by AI, but by using predefined template files we are back in the world of traditional deterministic coding here. You have plenty of opportunity for using AI later on to extend the app from this solid starting point.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule is aware of its limits in this step, so it will not say "yes" to every request you throw at it. Asking for "a trillion tables" or other features beyond the template scope will be politely rejected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" style="width: 444px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336641i7605E4A29BE73A9E/image-dimensions/444x350?v=v2" width="444" height="350" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" alt="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538983"&gt;Accepting the app&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the preview looks good and you have pressed the &lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" style="width: 120px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336642i611B7F59F8108180/image-dimensions/120x28?v=v2" width="120" height="28" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;button, the job of this &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; assistant is done. After app setup has finished (which may take a while because the dependencies need to be installed), it concludes with hints how to continue, including instructions on how to start the app in your respective workspace setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" style="width: 433px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336644i28549BEB965E64F1/image-dimensions/433x492?v=v2" width="433" height="492" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The created application looks roughly like this, with a table and a detail form below. Note: only OData V4 services are supported at this time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" style="width: 852px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336941iA1EC68BDFAA86432/image-dimensions/852x529/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="852" height="529" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You get this kind of UI when you specify an OData V4 service and entity. If you don't, then there is just a generic "Hello World" success page instead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course this UI structure might not be exactly what is desired in the app or even requested in the prompt, but this is what the template can do. When an OData service and entity but no properties are requested, then the tool tries to detect existing properties. If this fails, the table will be empty (no columns at all)—but Joule's success message should then mention this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046025478"&gt;After creation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the assistant suggests, please move to the other Joule assistants&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5&lt;/FONT&gt; and &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-page&lt;/FONT&gt; for developing the app further. In order to create more apps, reset the conversation with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" style="width: 23px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336645iB9B5AF8D09E44E81/image-dimensions/23x23?v=v2" width="23" height="23" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;button at the top of the Joule pane.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;EM&gt;knows&lt;/EM&gt; that it cannot modify the app or re-create it, it will politely guide you to the options you have, no matter what your request is. It may even give instructions on how to achieve the given goal within a UI5 app, but it will not be able to modify the code and it will make this clear when needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849511973"&gt;AI Learnings&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;While there is not much more to say about this feature—simply try it!—there are some facts and learnings about its implementation! If you are curious, head over to the second part of this blog post:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_self"&gt;Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:58:38.496000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447</id>
    <title>Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:00:38.750000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndreasKunz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565995"&gt;Flashback: the feature&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a &lt;EM&gt;"making of"&lt;/EM&gt; article about the implementation of the new&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; slash command available within Joule in SAP Build Code. In short, this new feature enables a conversation between AI assistant and application developer about a new freestyle UI5 application to build, with a full-fledged best-practice application starting point as result.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To see screenshots of this feature in action and understand it better, feel invited to read &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445" target="_self"&gt;my previous blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are just here for the background and AI-related learnings—go ahead!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439052490"&gt;General considerations&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;With open‑ended prompting, users aren’t restricted to predefined interactions. The user could ask for &lt;EM&gt;anything&lt;/EM&gt;. In contrast to traditional programming, a prompt input field can’t be handled with a sprawling web of if/else logic trying to cover all possible use-cases. Attempting this will lead to a frustrating user experience where the user often gets an "I do not understand your request".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some developers try to mimic this traditional programming pattern when crafting prompts and contexts for LLMs, telling an LLM "&lt;EM&gt;if the user asks for x, then answer y&lt;/EM&gt;". Instead, as demonstrated below, tell the LLM what it &lt;EM&gt;can&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;cannot&lt;/EM&gt; do and give it a goal to achieve. It's "smart" enough to figure out a suitable response to whatever the user will throw at it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538985"&gt;A fundamental choice&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking at this specific feature in the specific environment, the implementation options on the table were (for a variety of reasons) these two:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Either just provide a system prompt (a prompt that is added behind the scenes in addition to what the user typed) without interfering with the specific prompts and replies entered during the conversation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Or adopt a new way of creating an "agentic" multi-step execution plan. Similar to a guided activity, this would allow phases of data collection, possibly in different steps for different data, then an app creation step and so forth.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Surely "agentic" and "well-defined steps" sound good for app creation from a template, no? In fact, the initial implementation started like this, but it was soon apparent that this would neither provide the expected flexibility nor allow for a truly intelligent app creation experience. Defining phases in which to acquire specific information and having the application code created at a specific stage in this process did not feel right. The user would still feel like clicking through a traditional template creation process, as something specific was expected from the user at every stage, instead of giving the user the freedom to tweak every aspect at every stage. The true power of AI, on the other hand, would be totally underused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But then again... just a system prompt and that's it? No file read access to explore the environment, no dynamically updated instructions? Is this enough for an intelligent coding assistant?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046025480"&gt;Creating an "AI agent" out of nothing&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consider the now common definition of an "AI agent" which has settled over the course of this year: it's nothing more than "&lt;A href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/395657404_An_LLM_Agent_Runs_Tools_in_a_Loop_to_Achieve_a_Goal_A_Comprehensive_Semantic_Framework_for_Defining_AI_Agents_and_Agentic_Systems_by_Simon_Willison_and_Leading_Research_Laboratories" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;an LLM with tools, called in a loop to achieve a goal&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;". The chat conversation provided by Joule can be our loop, an application template with its parameters is the tool and the goal of assisting the developer to create an app can be stated in the system prompt. Of course a real &lt;EM&gt;autonomous&lt;/EM&gt; agent would require the loop to run without user interaction, but for this feature a loop involving the user is just right.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system prompt used for this feature literally includes: "&lt;EM&gt;Y&lt;SPAN&gt;ou help users create new UI5 applications by analyzing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;their requirements and filling the project template parameters. [...]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your goal is to gather all necessary information to create a new UI5 application.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The application will be generated from a template which&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;has only one page and a hardcoded UI, but can optionally display data from an OData V4 service. [...]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You cannot create the application yourself, but the user will see a preview...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;". There you have it: the goal and the tool!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It then goes on with some behavioral hints and of course a detailed description of what exactly the template parameters do. Finally, it requests &lt;EM&gt;each reply&lt;/EM&gt; to contain a JSON object with the best choice of template parameters according to the current understanding of the user request. The JSON object could look like this example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;{&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "appNamespace": "com.myorg.myapp",&lt;/SPAN&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "basePath": "/path/to/workspace",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
   "createAppDirectory": true,&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "framework": "SAPUI5",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "frameworkVersion": "1.136.0",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "author": "John Doe",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "oDataV4Url": "https://services.odata.org/TripPinRESTierService/(S(s5xrj1t51r41s3ooztsynysq))/",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "oDataEntitySet": "Airports",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "entityProperties": ["Name", "Address"],&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "runNpmInstall": true,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "initializeGitRepository": true,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "typescript": true&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;}&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This JSON object is removed from the LLM response before displaying it, then the application is generated with these parameters, so the user can accept it or request changes. In an environment where tools with a well-defined interface like MCP servers are not enabled, this JSON object as part of the conversation is how the integration with the templating tool is achieved. It's basically a use-case-tailored alternative to MCP.&amp;nbsp; A note to make this very clear: this environment is &lt;EM&gt;not&lt;/EM&gt; the official SAP Joule assistant running inside end-user applications, as it is now also being enabled for development by customers. Instead, it is a sort of predecessor implementation specifically available in SAP Build Code since spring 2024 and about to be replaced by advanced solutions. So do not draw conclusions about SAP Joule based on this article.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some of these parameters in the JSON object are more important than others with regards to the user explicitly influencing them or having to accept them. Whether the app code is generated as TypeScript or JavaScript is something the user should not be surprised with &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; accepting the app! On the other hand, the author name, which is only written into package.json, can be reliably defaulted to the logged-in user name and also very easily changed later on if needed. Hence, the parameter descriptions explain not only &lt;EM&gt;what&lt;/EM&gt; they do, but also how much the user should be bothered with them. As result, Joule usually does not even mention half of the parameters, thus keeping the conversation focused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" style="width: 455px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339533i8B53DC0B3A50E913/image-dimensions/455x912/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="455" height="912" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849511975"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to stop the agent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regarding the state &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; the app was accepted, the prompt explains "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AFTER the user has generated the application, you **MUST NOT** continue discussing parameters for generation, but rather [...] i&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;n particular by referring the user to the '/ui5' command for most requests or '/ui5-create-page'&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for adding pages to the app, because they are much better than you in developing features, as they have the capability to automatically select a suitable context of files.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This means the transition in the overall process between refining parameters and "no more changes possible" is not a hardcoded step or denoted by changing the system prompt, but rather explained up-front. That's enough. Can you talk Joule into proposing another set of parameters after the app was accepted? Maybe. But its &lt;EM&gt;normal&lt;/EM&gt; behavior is just right: it will explain that the app can not be created again without restarting the conversation. Nevertheless, there are also non-AI guardrails in place to prevent the app from being generated again, thus causing trouble.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All in all, we shape Joule’s behavior by explaining the templating tool and its limits, by stating the goal and desired behavior towards this goal, and by explaining the general flow, in particular the state after app acceptance. This is enough to guide it to a suitable reaction for whatever the user requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Even if the user insists like this:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" style="width: 457px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339649i5AAFEF728BB75C51/image-dimensions/457x620/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="457" height="620" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-652998470"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Context, context, context!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To make the entire feature really user-friendly, however, it is not sufficient to write a good prompt, but the context must also provide enough information to the LLM to allow for informed decisions. Hence, information like the list of project root files and folders, whether a Git repository is present, plus CAP service/entity/property info, and more, are gathered (e.g. using the &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap-ux/project-access" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@sap-ux/project-access&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;package). This knowledge is provided as prompt context behind the scenes or used in another way (like as content of the suggested prompts). This makes Joule aware of the environment it acts in, leading to better responses, like automatically avoiding app names that would conflict with existing folder names.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agentic coding assistants like Cline, GitHub Copilot, Cursor etc. usually have the ability to read files and execute shell commands as needed to understand their environment. In this pure user request + LLM response environment this might have been a bit harder to build. Basically, more tools could have been defined, e.g. by describing other JSON object structures for invoking them. But control would not so easily return to the LLM until after the user has entered another prompt. Or, there could have been one "preprocessor" LLM request asking for needed files, like it is done for the other&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5*&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;commands.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But for a narrow scenario like app creation this wasn't necessary. Collecting the most relevant information up front not only provides sufficient context, but also improves performance and reliability by avoiding repeated tool calls and unpredictable LLM loops.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-456484965"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In-response prompting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The real-world context, however, changes over time. Specifically, once the app is created and accepted, there are new additional files present.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When developing the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt;, we observed that the agentic AI tool (e.g. Cline) using the MCP server often decided to inspect the new app directory tree after creation, causing several LLM roundtrips which cost time and tokens. Or it would run "npm install" again, even though it had already been executed. Or it would make specific coding errors very often in subsequent modifications. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To avoid this, we extended the response of the MCP server after creating the app. Normally, it contains just the success message. &lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server/blob/a5a06382e0b3b8b39beaf1f40e95f2d887b3b50b/src/tools/create_ui5_app/createSuccessMessage.ts#L30-L66" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;But now it includes&lt;/A&gt; a full list of generated files, it states that "npm install" was already executed and it instructs how to prevent those coding errors. Basically, the MCP server response added further updated instructions to the conversation context. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Exactly the same principle was applied in this new Joule feature. While there is no autonomous agent loop in this case which would inspect the new files, the knowledge &lt;EM&gt;which&lt;/EM&gt; files were created can be valuable for the conversation with the user. And while the&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; command doesn't modify any code after app creation (thus avoiding the coding issues), facts like whether "npm install" was already executed, or whether the created UI5 Table in the MainView is lacking any columns, are useful for giving the user hints how to continue. Therefore, the context is extended by adding a hidden message to the conversation history.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-259971460"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Traditional coding has its place(s)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition to the process of context collection, deterministic coding is also used &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; the app has been accepted by the user for making the app consumption as smooth as possible. When inside a CAP project, it for example ensures that the &lt;EM&gt;cds-plugin-ui5&lt;/EM&gt; is added as dependency. This allows the UI5 tooling, including TypeScript transpilation of the UI5 app when needed, to run as part of the "cds watch" or "npm start" script of the CAP project itself.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Also, this dependency and all the UI5 app dependencies need to be installed. Unfortunately, there is a wide range of options and specific setups which might be used for dependency management in the already existing app. Probably&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;npm&lt;/EM&gt;? With or without workspaces? &lt;EM&gt;yarn&lt;/EM&gt;? &lt;EM&gt;pnpm&lt;/EM&gt;? Others? The code detects what is used and tries to cover the 95% case. The initial setup might not be complete in &lt;EM&gt;every&lt;/EM&gt; scenario, but for most users it will “just work,” providing a good developer experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is fine and all, but sometimes one has to go the extra mile and do some coding.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-63457955"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use deterministic code where reasonable (because the space of possibilities is bounded and a deterministic and quick result is beneficial) .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use LLMs for language understanding or dealing with an unpredictable range of possible requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don't try to "program" the LLM with an if/else prompt, but treat it like an intelligent human: state the goal, options and boundaries—and let it decide on its own.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Provide solid pre-collected context so the LLM can make good decisions reliably.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--133055550"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;P.S.:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For those who prefer graphics over text to gain an understanding of something, here is a depiction of the overall information flow inside this feature.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" style="width: 931px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340805i5BAE698E5DCD6369/image-dimensions/931x498/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="931" height="498" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:00:38.750000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-rpt-1-a-revolutionary-tabular-ml-model-and-owasp-ml-top-10-compliance/ba-p/14270750</id>
    <title>SAP-RPT-1: A Revolutionary Tabular ML Model and OWASP ML Top 10 Compliance</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:01:48.703000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AlexDevassy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2158816</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Note: This blog discusses &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;model, the enterprise version of the ConTextTab / SAP-RPT-1-OSS model architecture. The underlying technology is detailed in the &lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.10707" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ConTextTab research paper&lt;/A&gt; published by SAP, with an open-source implementation available as ConTextTab on &lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/SAP/contexttab" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Hugging Face&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/contexttab/tree/main" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765455978"&gt;The Challenge: Traditional Tabular ML's Security Dilemma&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the world of enterprise machine learning, tabular data represents the backbone of business intelligence from customer analytics to financial forecasting. However, traditional tabular ML approaches have long faced a fundamental security challenge: the need for extensive fine-tuning on customer data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When organisations deploy conventional ML models, they must:&lt;BR /&gt;- Fine-tune models using sensitive customer data, permanently modifying model weights&lt;BR /&gt;- Store customer information within model parameters, creating privacy risks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Manage complex security frameworks to protect against data poisoning, model inversion, and membership inference attacks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Navigate compliance requirements while maintaining model performance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This creates a paradox: the more effective the model becomes through fine-tuning, the greater the security risks it introduces.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568942473"&gt;Enter SAP-RPT-1: Redefining Tabular Machine Learning&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501511687"&gt;The Breakthrough: In-Context Learning for Tabular Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1&lt;/A&gt; represents a paradigm shift in tabular machine learning, introducing a revolutionary approach that eliminates the security-performance trade-off entirely. Built on the principle of In-Context Learning (ICL), SAP-RPT-1 achieves state-of-the-art performance without ever modifying its core model weights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304998182"&gt;How SAP-RPT-1 Works: A Security-First Architecture&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unlike traditional models that require fine-tuning, SAP-RPT-1 operates through a fundamentally different mechanism:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer provides data (tables) examples as context&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Model processes examples in real-time without storing or learning from them&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Predictions are made based on patterns identified in the provided context&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer data is immediately discarded after prediction completion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach delivers two critical advantages:&lt;BR /&gt;- Superior performance through semantic understanding of tabular relationships&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Inherent security advantages through its ephemeral processing approach, addressing several traditional ML vulnerability categories. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979401958"&gt;The Technical Innovation: Seven Pillars of Security-by-Design&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 revolutionary approach is built on seven fundamental characteristics that naturally eliminate most machine learning security risks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911971172"&gt;1. Specialized Architecture for Tabular Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 is fundamentally a classification and regression model designed specifically for structured data, not a Large Language Model. This focus makes it subject to the OWASP ML Top 10 security framework rather than LLM-specific vulnerabilities, providing a clearer security assessment pathway.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715457667"&gt;2. In-Context Learning vs. Traditional Fine-Tuning&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The core innovation lies in SAP-RPT-1 learning approach:&lt;BR /&gt;- Traditional Fine-tuning: Permanently modifies model weights using customer data, creating persistent security risks&lt;BR /&gt;- SAP-RPT-1 ICL: Uses customer data as contextual examples within the input, without modifying any model parameters&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Security Advantage: Eliminates risks associated with model weight manipulation and data persistence&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518944162"&gt;3. Enterprise API-First Security Model&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Fully managed API service: SAP handles all infrastructure, security, and model management while customers interact exclusively through secure, authenticated API endpoints&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Enterprise-grade security: Leverages SAP's proven security frameworks and compliance standards to safeguard SAP-RPT-1, while the base architecture remains transparently published through the open-source SAP-RPT-1-OSS version&lt;BR /&gt;- Controlled environment: All predictions occur within SAP's secure infrastructure&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-322430657"&gt;4. Customer Data Dependency as a Security Feature&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 ICL architecture creates an inherent security advantage:&lt;BR /&gt;- No standalone inference: Model requires customer-provided historical examples for every prediction&lt;BR /&gt;- Customer data control: Prediction quality directly depends on customer-provided context&lt;BR /&gt;- Reduced poisoning risk: Traditional attacks like model poisoning and data poisoning become significantly limited&lt;BR /&gt;- Contextual relevance: Model can only make predictions within the scope of provided examples&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-125917152"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;5. Ephemeral Processing Architecture&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every SAP-RPT-1 inference follows a secure, temporary processing model:&lt;BR /&gt;- Memory-only processing: Customer data exists solely during the inference request&lt;BR /&gt;- No weight updates: Model parameters remain completely unchanged throughout operation&lt;BR /&gt;- Zero persistence: No traces of customer information remain in the model&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--145827722"&gt;6. Enterprise-Grade SAP Management&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a SAP-provided service, SAP-RPT-1 &lt;/SPAN&gt;benefits from comprehensive enterprise security controls:&lt;BR /&gt;- Supply chain security: Direct SAP control over model development, training, and distribution&lt;BR /&gt;- Model integrity: Protection against unauthorised modifications and tampering&lt;BR /&gt;- Data governance &amp;amp; compliance: &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt; SAP ensures that all data used to train its Foundation Model follows strict regulations to protect privacy and meet legal standards. SAP has robust security policies to manage data safely when developing its applications.&lt;BR /&gt;- Quality assurance: Professional model validation and continuous security testing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--342341227"&gt;7. Secure Semantic Processing Pipeline&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 employs a mathematically based data processing approach that eliminates code execution risks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All inputs (strings, numbers, dates, etc.) are transformed into embeddings (vector representations of the data), and these embeddings undergo pure mathematical transformations within the model with no code execution occurring during data processing, only mathematical operations on numerical vectors: Inputs (e.g., strings, numbers, dates) → Vector Embeddings → Mathematical Operations → Prediction Result.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Security guarantees:&lt;BR /&gt;- No code execution pathways in data processing&lt;BR /&gt;- Pure mathematical tensor operations throughout the pipeline&lt;BR /&gt;- Semantic understanding without security vulnerabilities&lt;BR /&gt;- Input sanitization through numerical conversion&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--245451725"&gt;SAP-RPT-1 &amp;amp; OWASP ML Top 10 Compliance&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With SAP-RPT-1 architecture established, we can now examine how these design principles address the industry-standard OWASP ML Top 10 security framework. This assessment demonstrates that SAP-RPT-1 innovative approach doesn't just match traditional security measures, it fundamentally eliminates most attack vectors entirely.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--735368237"&gt;SAP RPT-1 &amp;amp; OWASP ML Top 10 Compliance Overview&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;OWASP ML Top 10&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Risk &lt;SPAN&gt;Applicability&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to SAP RPT-1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;Risk Assessment&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;Technical Rationale&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Security Status&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML01: Input Manipulation Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="212px"&gt;Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Minimal exposure due to customer-controlled data model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers provide their own contextual examples, significantly reducing adversarial input scenarios. Risk limited to compromised customer environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="212px"&gt;Customer Managed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML02: Data Poisoning Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="212px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Architecture prevents traditional data poisoning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;In-Context Learning does not modify model weights. Customer data serves only as contextual input during inference, with no persistent model updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="212px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="165px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML03: Model Inversion Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="165px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="165px"&gt;No sensitive training data to extract&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="165px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer data is ephemeral and not embedded in model weights. No gradient information exposed through API.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="165px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="111px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML04: Membership Inference Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="111px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="111px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP regulated training data eliminates attack vector&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="111px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;No customer data persists in model, eliminating membership inference opportunities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="111px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML05: Model Theft&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP-managed infrastructure prevents model parameter access&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP-RPT-1 is provided and managed within SAP's secure infrastructure. Customers access only the API endpoint, never the model parameters &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Further since customer provided context is not saved in model due to ICL, model theft has no impact on customers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML06: AI Supply Chain Attacks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP as trusted model provider eliminates supply chain risk&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is the official model provider with direct control over development, training, and distribution. No third-party supply chain vulnerabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML07: Transfer Learning Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;No transfer learning in deployment architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In-Context Learning eliminates transfer learning attack vectors entirely..&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML08: Model Skewing &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer data quality responsibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Potential for unintentional bias in customer-provided data. Model leverages &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;patterns present in contextual examples, requiring customer awareness and data curation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Customer Managed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML09: Output Integrity Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Standard API security controls apply&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Risk can be mitigated through conventional authentication and authorization mechanisms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Customer Managed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML10: Model Poisoning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Immutable model architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pre-trained model weights remain completely unchanged during operation. Customer data cannot modify base model behaviour or parameters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--638478735"&gt;The Results: A New Standard for Secure ML&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1128395247"&gt;SAP-RPT-1 Security Achievement&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The OWASP ML Top 10 compliance reveals SAP-RPT-1 remarkable security profile:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Inherent Protection Against 7 out of 10 Major Threats&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP-RPT-1 In-Context Learning architecture provides built-in protection against most ML security risks. Unlike traditional systems that require extensive security hardening, SAP-RPT-1 design reduces the likelihood of most attack vectors by default.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Standard Controls for Remaining Risks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The three-remaining low-risk areas (Input Manipulation, Model Skewing, and Output Integrity) are addressed through conventional security measures that organisations typically already have in place:&lt;BR /&gt;- Input validation and API security controls&lt;BR /&gt;- Customer data governance&lt;BR /&gt;- Standard authentication and authorization mechanisms&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Empowerment Through Data Control&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Rather than creating security burdens, SAP-RPT-1 empowers customers by giving them direct control over model behaviour through their own data, while eliminating the risks associated with traditional model training.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://owasp.org/www-project-machine-learning-security-top-10/)" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;OWASP ML Security Top 10&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.10707" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1-OSS / ConTextTab Paper&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/SAP/contexttab" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1-OSS / ConTextTab Model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/contexttab/tree/main" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1-OSS / ConTextTab Github&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/tuH8Fj5?h=&amp;amp;ltr=a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1 Model FAQ&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;- Know more on SAP-RPT-1 Model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-rpt-1-a-revolutionary-tabular-ml-model-and-owasp-ml-top-10-compliance/ba-p/14270750"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:01:48.703000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/afsug-amp-sap-a-new-era-of-support-join-our-executive-series-and-onsite/ba-p/14271334</id>
    <title>AFSUG &amp; SAP: A New Era of Support — Join Our Executive Series and Onsite Event in Cape Town</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:53:14.999000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>oliverhuschke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35096</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636399148"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Bildschirmfoto 2025-11-17 um 18.50.41.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342021iCCD8EBA93D8F8328/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Bildschirmfoto 2025-11-17 um 18.50.41.png" alt="Bildschirmfoto 2025-11-17 um 18.50.41.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439885643"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AFSUG &amp;amp; SAP: A New Era of Support — Join Our Executive Series and Onsite Event in Cape Town&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together with AFSUG, the African SAP User Group, SAP’s Customer Support organization is launching a series of high-impact remote sessions — all leading up to an exclusive onsite event in Cape Town in March 2026. This program gives customers a unique opportunity to learn directly from SAP executives and experts, discover the future of support, and experience how AI, automation, and preventative practices are reshaping SAP’s entire support landscape. Whether you want to understand SAP’s proactive support strategy, get hands-on with the latest digital experiences, or explore agentic AI in real customer scenarios — this series is built for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372454857"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Series Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Support has evolved far beyond “break/fix.” Today, it is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A strategic advantage, not an insurance policy&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP customers choose us because we help them run better, scale smarter, and stay ahead.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Preventive and predictive by design&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Programs like Black Friday / Cyber Monday Readiness demonstrate how SAP reduces risk before issues arise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered, human-backed&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agentic AI, prescriptive guidance, and intelligent digital entry points give customers immediate access to insights and the right expertise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded across the entire lifecycle&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support is now a built-in value multiplier — from onboarding to transformation to continuous optimization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer outcomes at the center&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stability, performance, resilience, and continuous improvement aren’t extras — they’re expectations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A blueprint for operationalizing AI&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Customer Support is the frontrunner in adopting agentic AI inside SAP — and showing customers how to scale AI safely and practically in their own environments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join our experts as they unpack these themes in four remote sessions — each one providing unique insights and previews of what awaits at the onsite event in Cape Town.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046858633"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Remote Session Series&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108510566"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. November 27, 2025 — 3–4 PM CET / 4-5 PM SAST&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782914342"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From Reactive to Proactive: How SAP’s Support Strategy &amp;amp; Agentic AI Are Reshaping the Future&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Stefan Steinle, EVP &amp;amp; Head of Customer Support &amp;amp; Cloud Lifecycle Management, SAP SE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Support is shifting from reactive problem-solving to strategic enablement. Stefan Steinle will walk attendees through SAP’s future support strategy — one that is predictive, preventative, and deeply infused with agentic AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;You’ll learn:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How SAP is moving toward proactive and preventative support models&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How agentic AI analyzes telemetry, detects risks, and takes safe autonomous action&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How disciplines from BF/CM Readiness are expanding into daily operations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A live demo on proactive support identifying “Go-Live endangered” situations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A first look at what awaits at the Cape Town onsite event — including Support Accreditation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://afsug.com/product/afsug-sap-vs-from-reactive-to-proactive-how-saps-support-strategy-agentic-ai-are-reshaping-the-future/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt; now to secure your place.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715483556"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. December 11, 2025 — 3–4 PM CET / 4-5 PM SAST&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-389887332"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reinventing Support – Self-Services, Real-Time Assistance &amp;amp; the Power of AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Mohammed Ajouz, SVP &amp;amp; Global Head of Technical Support, SAP Americas&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditional support is being reinvented. Mohammed Ajouz will showcase how SAP delivers intelligent, connected, and customer-centric services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In this session, you’ll explore:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Smarter, always-available self-services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Live channels for real-time engagement&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agentic AI that supports — and acts — on your behalf&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How AI and LLMs transform knowledge, case resolution, and insights&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ll also get a preview of the onsite workshops and simulations — and how to earn the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Support Accreditation Certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Cape Town.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://afsug.com/product/afsug-sap-vs-reinventing-support-self-services-real-time-assistance-the-power-of-ai/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt; now&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;to secure your place&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-322456546"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. January 21, 2026 — 3–4 PM CET / 4-5 PM SAST&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--3139678"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM as Your Transformation Execution Platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Sören Ruder, SVP &amp;amp; CPO, Global Head of Customer Experience &amp;amp; Solutions, SAP SE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transformation succeeds when tools work together — not in silos. This session shows how SAP Cloud ALM unifies processes, architecture, testing, and operations into a single AI-infused orchestration layer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn how Cloud ALM:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Aligns Signavio processes directly with project scope&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Synchronizes landscape models from SAP LeanIX&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Coordinates manual and automated testing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Orchestrates ABAP and non-ABAP change processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uses intelligent event processing to reduce noise and automate remediation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Delivers real-time dashboards with embedded analytics&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sören Ruder will also preview deep-dive workshops happening onsite in Cape Town.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://afsug.com/product/afsug-sap-vs-sap-cloud-alm-as-your-transformation-execution-platform/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt; now for the January session.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--145801833"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. February 26, 2026 — 3–4 PM CET / 4-5 PM SAST&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--48912331"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Front Door Thinking&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Michelle Lewis-Miller, Head of SAP Support Digital Experience &amp;amp; Voice of Customer, SAP SE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every customer journey starts with a digital front door — and SAP is reinventing it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This session includes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Live demos of SAP for Me, the Get Support App, and the SAP Support Portal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Insights into personalization, streamlined access, mobility, and new navigation patterns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The debut of the SAP Support Accreditation Program&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is your best opportunity to get ready for certification onsite in Cape Town.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://afsug.com/product/afsug-sap-vs-intelligent-front-door-thinking-empowering-users-with-sap-for-me-get-support-app-accreditation/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt; now for the February session.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-47977171"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_showing_europe_africa:"&gt;🌍&lt;/span&gt;March 26, 2026 — Onsite in Cape Town, South Africa&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--148536334"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AFSUG &amp;amp; SAP: From Insights to Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;All remote sessions lead to this highly interactive onsite event — bringing together SAP executives, experts, and customers for a full day of hands-on learning, networking, and certification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Onsite Highlights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keynote by Stefan Steinle&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;EM&gt;The Future of Support — Intelligent, Preventive, and Built for the Cloud Era&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multiple expert deep-dives&lt;/STRONG&gt; on:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP for Me &amp;amp; Built-In Support&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Self-Services, Live Channels &amp;amp; AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Preventive Support &amp;amp; Agentic AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Cloud ALM and the Integrated Toolchain&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet-the-Expert stations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct networking with SAP executives&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Support Accreditation — completed onsite with printed certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the moment where everything comes together — strategy, demos, hands-on labs, customer stories, and the opportunity to connect directly with the people shaping the future of support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Registration opens soon — reserve the date now.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--345049839"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Join Us for the Full Journey&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;These remote sessions and the Cape Town onsite event offer an exceptional opportunity to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learn from SAP’s top executives&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See agentic AI in action&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Strengthen your SAP expertise&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Network with industry peers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Earn your official SAP Support Accreditation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Don’t miss your chance to be part of this evolution.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Register for the sessions, mark your calendar for Cape Town — and join us as we shape the next era of SAP Support together.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/afsug-amp-sap-a-new-era-of-support-join-our-executive-series-and-onsite/ba-p/14271334"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:53:14.999000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-2-of-6/ba-p/14271554</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 2 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T09:09:46.257000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bereitw</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/713212</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" style="width: 760px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342097iB3F1A04EBC22CFFD/image-dimensions/760x208/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="760" height="208" role="button" title="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" alt="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: How Data, AI, and Agents are Changing Supply Chain Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the discussion about the future of supply chain management, one area is increasingly at the center: planning. Supply chain planning not only affects operational efficiency, but directly influences a company’s service quality, fixed capital and responsiveness. Our joint study from SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University clearly shows that companies that are already planning proactively today can avoid bottlenecks, optimize costs, and exploit potential in a targeted manner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain planning is the central lever for anticipating problems before they arise. Companies that anticipate bottlenecks and proactively manage capacity, inventory and resources avoid hectic “fire fighting” in day-to-day operations. Planning thus acts as an early warning system that not only enables stable service, but also more efficient use of resources and proactive action. Effective planning also requires seamless integration and evaluation of a variety of internal and external data sources – from granular sales data to basic economic data, to production, procurement, and distribution plans. Different planning levels and horizons need to be connected, and this is where there are huge opportunities for artificial intelligence that can process data volumes, identify patterns, and improve predictions. Advanced planning processes will become a matter of course over the next ten years. If you do not achieve at least a modern, integrated planning level by 2035, you risk not only a competitive disadvantage, but also the loss of operational control capability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our survey of supply chain decision-makers (see figure) provides a clear picture of the future. Many expect planning to be much simpler and more intuitive in 2035 than today. More than half expect generative AI and GPT models to have a significant impact on planning processes, and much of it sees data quality as a critical factor in planning decisions. In addition, many expect the breakthrough of new AI-powered forecasting tools that incorporate additional data sources and significantly improve demand planning. Around a quarter expect advanced risk analysis to provide the ability to proactively detect and mitigate disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, the status quo shows how big the gap between aspirations and reality is. Only a small number of companies rated their planning as mature in our survey. Similarly, few are actively experimenting with GenAI or GPT applications in the planning environment. Only a minority has very accurate planning data harmonized from different sources. Highly automated demand planning with minimal human intervention is the exception, as are planning systems that provide clear recommendations for action in the event of disruptions. This discrepancy shows that the path to truly modern, intelligent planning is still long and requires targeted investment, clear priorities and structured action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to close this gap, different approaches must be pursued. Companies where planning is a strategic core process or requires very individual processes can realize enormous potential with agent-based AI. With the advent of new agency tools, most repetitive, error-prone work is automated, allowing planners to focus on value-added analytics and decisions. Companies with standardized processes and a low strategic relevance of planning will be able to procure their planning function more as a service in the future. Technology and platform models could enable true end-to-end planning across company boundaries for the first time. Simulations and digital twins will also play a growing role. Although these often fail today due to complexity, modeling effort, and scalability, AI-powered modeling agents could significantly accelerate and improve the accuracy of simulation creation and updates in the future, making their use more practical in larger networks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless of the individual target image, there are measures that every company should tackle immediately (“no-regret moves”). This includes building robust data governance and harmonizing master data as the foundation for any data-driven planning. Unfortunately, the principle of “garbage in, garbage out” also applies with AI: without high-quality data, even the best AI system cannot deliver meaningful value. A consistent, company-wide IBP system enabling a S&amp;amp;OP process provides the basis for a common planning goal. Initial pilot projects with agent-based sales forecasting help gather experience with AI-powered planning approaches. Finally, it is important to actively link existing planning platforms, such as SAP IBP, with AI services to unlock integration potential early on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain planning is now more important than ever and will become a key differentiator between successful companies and those left behind by 2035. The technologies to make planning smarter, faster, and more resilient already exist – but they must be combined with clear goals, a resilient data foundation, and organizational readiness for change. Those who lay the foundations today will not only be able to plan faster and more precisely tomorrow but can also act strategically before others can even react.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342098i554F3BCC37F9CF93/image-dimensions/592x285/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="592" height="285" role="button" title="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" alt="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure: Results of an online survey of 119 SC managers with people responsibility, conducted on 01/2025 as part of a joint SAP KLU study&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-2-of-6/ba-p/14271554"/>
    <published>2025-11-18T09:09:46.257000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/pioneering-work-on-enhancing-code-reasoning-with-search-and-self-correction/ba-p/14272703</id>
    <title>Pioneering Work on Enhancing Code Reasoning with Search and Self-Correction</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T17:16:23.842000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GraceQin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1465342</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Large language models (LLMs) for code generation and understanding can be boosted by training on search-like reasoning traces and by self-correction mechanisms. Recent work has framed code tasks as iterative decision processes, using fine-tuning or reinforcement learning (RL) to teach models to identify errors and explore alternative solutions. For example, &lt;STRONG&gt;Stream-of-Search (SoS)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tree-of-Thoughts (ToT)&lt;/STRONG&gt; reasoning organizes intermediate “thoughts” into a search tree, allowing LMs to branch on different solution paths and backtrack when needed&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2305.10601v2#:~:text=framework%20for%20language%20model%20inference%2C,or%20search%3A%20Game%20of%2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[1]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03683" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[4]&lt;/A&gt;. As shown in the ToT schematic design, multiple partial solution “thoughts” are generated and evaluated, greatly improving performance on tasks requiring planning or search. Similarly, code models can be trained on annotated search traces, e.g. execution logs or error-flagged drafts, to internalize debugging strategies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765515408"&gt;Our Work&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our team, &lt;STRONG&gt;the Research &amp;amp; Innovation team at Palo Alto led by Yaad Oren and Alexander Schaefer&lt;/STRONG&gt;, collaborate with Dr. Noah Goodman's CoCoLab from &lt;STRONG&gt;Stanford HAI institution&lt;/STRONG&gt;, exploring and bringing the pioneering work on the foundational reasoning capability enhancement of LLMs to SAP. Recently we got one paper accepted by NeurIPS 2025 Foundations of Reasoning workshop, titled by &lt;STRONG&gt;"Smaller Models, Smarter Rewards: A Two-Sided Approach to Process and Outcome Rewards"&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;(&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.23083" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;arxiv link&lt;/A&gt;). The following is our abstract as a teaser:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;Generating high-quality code remains a challenge for Large Language Models (LLMs). For the evolution of reasoning models on this task, reward models are a necessary intermediate step. These models judge outcomes or intermediate steps. Decoder-only transformer models can be turned into reward models by introducing a regression layer and supervised fine-tuning. While it is known that reflection capabilities generally increase with the size of a model, we want to investigate whether state-of-the-art small language models like the Phi-4 family can be turned into usable reward models blending the consideration of process rewards and outcome rewards.&lt;BR /&gt;Targeting this goal, we construct a dataset of code samples with correctness labels derived from the APPS coding challenge benchmark. We then train a value-head model to estimate the success probability of intermediate outputs. Our evaluation shows that small LLMs are capable of serving as effective reward models or code evaluation critics, successfully identifying correct solutions among multiple candidates. Using this critic, we achieve over a 20% improvement in the search capability of the most accurate code out of multiple generations.&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569001903"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372488398"&gt;Supervised Fine-Tuning on Search Traces&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A key idea is to &lt;STRONG&gt;supervise models on entire search trajectories&lt;/STRONG&gt; instead of only correct solutions. For example, Qin et al. train a backtracking model on DFS-generated reasoning traces and a direct model on final solutions&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=strategies%2C%20we%20train%20,outperforms%20the%20direct%20solution%20model" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;. They find this trace-based SFT can bias models into particular strategies: on CountDown puzzles the backtracking model overfits the training search path and underperforms, while on Sudoku it generalizes better. In general, learning from explicit annotated chains-of-thought (CoT) can encourage rich reasoning, but may also lock in suboptimal habits (e.g. verbosity or fixed search biases). Qin et al. show two pitfalls: (1) Prescribed search bias – fixed traces can constrain exploration, and (2) Excessive verbosity – writing out every step can discourage internal reasoning&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=Through%20controlled%20experiments%2C%20we%20identify,Beyond%20these%20factors%2C%20we%20demonstrate" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;. Notably, they observe that reinforcement learning fine-tuning can overcome these issues: a backtracking model fine-tuned with RL discovers new strategies and improves substantially, whereas a direct model improves one-shot accuracy but fares worse under parallel sampling&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=Extending%20beyond%20supervised%20learning%2C%20we,term%20reasoning%20capabilities" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other supervised approaches include synthetically augmenting data with error annotations or ‘hints’. For instance, Sahni et al. train models with error-infused examples (marking lines with potential bugs) to improve debugging&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19055v1#:~:text=manifest%20as%20bugs%20that%20we,describe%20each%20component%20in%20detail" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[3]&lt;/A&gt;. In code repair tasks, models have been fine-tuned on (input, buggy code, fix) triplets to internalize common corrections. However, most of these rely on proprietary data or strong verifiers. Self-contained supervised traces for code are still scarce; researchers often generate them on-the-fly (e.g. solving puzzles to get traces) or use execution feedback.&lt;STRONG&gt; In our work, we also used Claude and Phi to generate similar reasoning hints to augment our training data.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175974893"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979461388"&gt;Reinforcement Learning for Self-Correction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To leverage dynamic feedback, many recent works use &lt;STRONG&gt;reinforcement learning&lt;/STRONG&gt; on self-generated data. One line of work (e.g. &lt;STRONG&gt;Stream-of-Search&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03683" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[4],&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SCoRe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.12917#:~:text=behavior%20that%20is%20often%20not,model%20to%20generate%20a%20policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[5]&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;CoCoS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.23060v1#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20we%20propose%20an%20online,implementation%20can%20be%20accessed%20at" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[6]&lt;/A&gt;) explicitly frames code generation as a multi-turn Markov decision process where the model can iteratively revise its code. These methods train the code model end-to-end using rewards that encourage fixing mistakes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stream-of-Search (Kanishk et al. 2024)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;proposes a unified search trace design, demonstrated through the game of Countdown. The streams of search logs the state transitions, actions and reward scores when making each computation step in the game. The highlight is that this scoring always considers the impact from different branching choices through &lt;STRONG&gt;backtracking.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Through pre-training a transformer-based language model on streams of search, and then applying further fine-tuning with policy improvement methods led to a significant improvement of correct solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SCoRe (Kumar et al. 2024)&lt;/STRONG&gt; introduces a two-stage RL process for code and math. A base LLM first learns to produce correction traces by iterative self-evaluation (often in multiple turns) and then undergoes &lt;STRONG&gt;policy optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt; using its own feedback. Simply fine-tuning on offline “correction” traces does not work well, so SCoRe employs online PPO with shaped rewards for partial correctness&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.12917#:~:text=first%20show%20that%20variants%20of,correction%20on%20test%20problems.%20SCoRe" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[5]&lt;/A&gt;. They report substantial gains on MATH and HumanEval pass@1 after RL. This shows small LMs can learn to “self-correct” if trained under their own error distribution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CoCoS (Cho et al. 2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt; focuses on small open-source models. They propose an RL fine-tuning objective where each turn’s reward reflects cumulative progress: the model is encouraged to maintain correct outputs and also to improve any incorrect outputs incrementally&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.23060v1#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20we%20propose%20an%20online,implementation%20can%20be%20accessed%20at" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[6]&lt;/A&gt;. Specifically, CoCoS uses an &lt;STRONG&gt;accumulated reward (discounted sum over turns) and a progressive reward&lt;/STRONG&gt; for fine-grained improvements, rather than just binary success. In experiments on MBPP and HumanEval with 1B models, CoCoS yields large improvements over baselines. The authors release code and RL data (on GitHub) enabling reproducibility&lt;A href="https://github.com/jeonghun3572/CoCoS#:~:text=Download%20the%20datasets%3A" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[7]&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RLEF (Gehring et al. 2024)&lt;/STRONG&gt; frames code synthesis as an interactive RL problem. The model repeatedly proposes code, receives &lt;STRONG&gt;execution feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt; (unit test results) as the environment response, and is updated via PPO to maximize passing tests. This end-to-end RL causes models to ground in test feedback rather than ignore it&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2410.02089v2#:~:text=Large%20language%20models%20,time%20behavior" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[8]&lt;/A&gt;. RLEF training on the CodeContests benchmark produces state-of-the-art solve rates with 8B and 70B models, while drastically reducing the number of samplings needed. Critically, RLEF models learn to adapt code based on errors – e.g. using caches or fixing off-by-one errors – without human hints. The gains generalize: after RLEF, models also improve on HumanEval+ and MBPP+ by leveraging feedback.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Satori (Shen et al. 2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt; combines supervised format-tuning with RL. It first imitates a “Chain-of-Action-Thought” (COAT) format by training on synthetic multi-agent demonstrations, teaching the model to use special tokens like &amp;lt;|reflect|&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;|explore|&amp;gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori#:~:text=%2A%20Chain,action%20tokens%20to%20guide%20reasoning" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[9]&lt;/A&gt;. Then it applies RL with a &lt;STRONG&gt;Restart-and-Explore (RAE)&lt;/STRONG&gt; strategy: the model is periodically reset to intermediate states (including failed ones) and trained to explore new branches, with rewards for eventual correctness and penalties for repeating mistakes&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori#:~:text=2.%20Self,RL" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[9]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.18458v2#:~:text=Similarly%2C%20Satori%C2%A0%5B351%5D%20introduces%20Chain,Llama8B" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[10]&lt;/A&gt;. The final 7B Satori model (based on Qwen) achieves SOTA on challenging math reasoning tasks, showing that an LLM can “internalize search”&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori#:~:text=1,Imitation%20Learning" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[9]&lt;/A&gt;. The full Satori code, model checkpoints, and RL data (including rollouts from RAE) are publicly released for community use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These RL methods set examples for online self-improvement: the model generates its own traces (code attempts, feedback, or self-reflections), evaluates them via an automatic reward (tests or proxy reward models), and uses that to update its policy. In all cases, models get reward signals across multiple turns – for example, RLEF only awards a final reward but uses intermediate test feedback as observations, while CoCoS and SCoRe explicitly shape rewards at each revision step. This multi-turn RL contrasts with one-off prompting: the model learns that reflecting on errors and branching can yield higher expected reward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782947883"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-586434378"&gt;Empirical Gains and Benchmarks&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Overall, trace-based training and self-correction in the mentioned work yield significant empirical improvements across diverse benchmarks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Coding tasks&lt;/STRONG&gt;: HumanEval/HumanEval+&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.03374" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[11]&lt;/A&gt;, APPS[&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09938" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;12&lt;/A&gt;], TACO&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14852" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[13]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mathematical reasoning&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Sudoku&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=strategies%2C%20we%20train%20,outperforms%20the%20direct%20solution%20model" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;. MATH-500&lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/datasets/HuggingFaceH4/MATH-500" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[15],&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;GSM8K&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.14168" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[16]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, results also reveal nuances and limitations. The “backtracking vs direct” study shows that task structure matters: on some problems (CountDown) naive backtracking hurt performance&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=Through%20controlled%20experiments%2C%20we%20identify,Beyond%20these%20factors%2C%20we%20demonstrate" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;. Many methods still rely on test or verifier oracles (e.g. to score branches), which will invalid this whole method when such oracles don’t exist. Also, RL training can be sample-inefficient and sensitive to reward hacking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-389920873"&gt;Discussion and Outlook&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Annotating search and correction steps enables deep reasoning in code LMs, but challenges remain. Key gaps include robust reward design, scaling to very large models, and generalizing for tasks with unclear oracles. Most existing methods focus on code generation. We hope future work in the community would apply more effort on code understanding (e.g. program analysis, code review, translation, documentation). It is also important to study the trade-offs: extensive backtracking can be quadratically expensive, and some tasks favor direct answering. Moreover, as the “when to backtrack” analysis shows&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=Through%20controlled%20experiments%2C%20we%20identify,Beyond%20these%20factors%2C%20we%20demonstrate" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;, blindly encouraging self-correction is not always beneficial.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nonetheless, models that learn from their own mistakes via annotated traces or RL often outperform “single shot” models. By combining supervision with tree-based reasoning traces through RL, systems can achieve autoregressive search capabilities without human prompts&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori#:~:text=%2A%20Chain,action%20tokens%20to%20guide%20reasoning" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[9]&lt;/A&gt;. Overall, these advances point toward autonomous code agents that can plan, check, and correct – closing the gap toward human-like programming workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-193407368"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2305.10601v2#:~:text=framework%20for%20language%20model%20inference%2C,or%20search%3A%20Game%20of%2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[1]&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Tree of Thoughts: Deliberate Problem Solving with Large Language Models&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2305.10601v2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2305.10601v2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=strategies%2C%20we%20train%20,outperforms%20the%20direct%20solution%20model" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;To Backtrack or Not to Backtrack: When Sequential Search Limits Model Reasoning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19055v1#:~:text=manifest%20as%20bugs%20that%20we,describe%20each%20component%20in%20detail" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[3]&lt;/A&gt; Effective Large Language Model Debugging with Best-first Tree Search&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19055v1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19055v1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03683" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[4]&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Stream of Search (SoS): Learning to Search in Language&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03683" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03683&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.12917" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[5]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;Training Language Models to Self-Correct via Reinforcement Learning&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.12917" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.12917&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.23060v1#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20we%20propose%20an%20online,implementation%20can%20be%20accessed%20at" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[6]&lt;/A&gt; Self-Correcting Code Generation Using Small Language Models&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.23060v1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/html/2505.23060v1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/jeonghun3572/CoCoS#:~:text=Download%20the%20datasets%3A" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[7]&lt;/A&gt; GitHub - jeonghun3572/CoCoS: This is the official implementation of the paper "Self-Correcting Code Generation Using Small Language Models"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/jeonghun3572/CoCoS" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/jeonghun3572/CoCoS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2410.02089v2#:~:text=Large%20language%20models%20,time%20behavior" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[8]&lt;/A&gt; [2410.02089] RLEF: Grounding Code LLMs in Execution Feedback with Reinforcement Learning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2410.02089v2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2410.02089v2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori#:~:text=%2A%20Chain,action%20tokens%20to%20guide%20reasoning" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[9]&lt;/A&gt; GitHub - satori-reasoning/Satori: [ICML 2025] Satori: Reinforcement Learning with Chain-of-Action-Thought Enhances LLM Reasoning via Autoregressive Search&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.18458v2#:~:text=Similarly%2C%20Satori%C2%A0%5B351%5D%20introduces%20Chain,Llama8B" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[10]&lt;/A&gt; Data × LLM: From Principles to Practices&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.18458v2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/html/2505.18458v2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.03374" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[11]&lt;/A&gt; Evaluating Large Language Models Trained on Code&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.03374" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.03374&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09938" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;12&lt;/A&gt;]&amp;nbsp;Measuring Coding Challenge Competence With APPS&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09938" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09938&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14852" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[13]&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;TACO: Topics in Algorithmic COde generation dataset&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14852" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14852&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.06770" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[14]&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;SWE-bench: Can Language Models Resolve Real-World GitHub Issues?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.06770" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.06770&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/datasets/HuggingFaceH4/MATH-500" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[15]&lt;/A&gt; MATH-500&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/datasets/HuggingFaceH4/MATH-500" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://huggingface.co/datasets/HuggingFaceH4/MATH-500&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.14168" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[16]&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Training Verifiers to Solve Math Word Problems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.14168" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.14168&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/pioneering-work-on-enhancing-code-reasoning-with-search-and-self-correction/ba-p/14272703"/>
    <published>2025-11-19T17:16:23.842000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-rpt-1-context-model-vs-training-classical-models-the-models-battle/ba-p/14268507</id>
    <title>SAP RPT-1 Context Model vs. Training Classical Models: The Models Battle (Python Hands-on)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T07:50:27.670000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nicolasestevan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1198632</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764768715"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":collision:"&gt;💥&lt;/span&gt;The Models Battle&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_5-1763206328497.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341535i2A2C9A98D24BF43B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_5-1763206328497.png" alt="nicolasestevan_5-1763206328497.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predictive modeling is becoming a built-in capability across SAP, improving how teams handle forecasting, pricing, and planning. &lt;STRONG&gt;Many SAP professionals, however, aren’t machine-learning specialists&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and traditional models often demand extensive setup, tuning, and repeated training, which slows down new ideas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; offers a simpler path. It’s a pretrained model from SAP, also available in an OSS version, that lets developers and consultants produce predictions with far less technical effort, no deep ML background required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've explored SAP RPT-1 hands-on, comparing it with traditional regressors using Python and a real public vehicles price dataset.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goal:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To see (as a non Data Scientist) how &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; behaves in practice, what advantages and limits it shows, and when it could make sense in a predictive scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Usually for real-world scenario, the right approach would be consume the SAP RPT-1 though the available and simplified API, but for studies proposal and fair comparision over othe traditional ML models, the &lt;STRONG&gt;OSS&lt;/STRONG&gt; fits perfectly for it:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568255210"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thinking_face:"&gt;🤔&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP RPT-1 vs Traditional Machine Learning - Core Differences&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into the code, let’s quickly revisit how&lt;STRONG&gt; traditional ML&lt;/STRONG&gt; models work:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Training-based models like Random Forest, LightGBM, and Linear Regression learn patterns directly from data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;They require hundreds or thousands of examples to tune their internal parameters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Their performance depends heavily on data quantity and quality.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The more relevant examples they see, the smarter they get.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the other hand, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 f&lt;/STRONG&gt;ollows a different philosophy. It’s part of the RPT (Representational Predictive Transformer) family, pretrained on a wide variety of business and contextual data. This means:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You don’t "train" it in the traditional sense. Instead, it uses context embeddings to predict outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It can be used immediately, even with smaller datasets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The OSS version allows developers to experiment directly in Python.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No special SAP backend required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Outcome:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Traditional ML models learn from high amount of data. SAP RPT-1 already knows how to deal with small context amount of data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371741705"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":desktop_computer:"&gt;🖥&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;The Experiment - Setup &amp;amp; Dataset&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-container"&gt;&lt;a class="lia-spoiler-link" href="#" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Spoiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;noscript&gt; (Highlight to read)&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-border"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-content"&gt;Don't worry on "playing puzzles" copying + pasting code below. The full version is available for download at end!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-container"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-content"&gt;Don't worry on "playing puzzles" copying + pasting code below. The full version is available for download at end!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make this comparison tangible, I built a simple yet realistic Python experiment to predict vehicle selling prices using a public dataset containing car attributes like make, model, year, transmission, and mileage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why vehicle pricing? Because it’s an intuitive example where both traditional machine learning and pretrained AI models can be applie, and it helps visualize how prediction quality evolves as the sample size grows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This entire analysis runs on a local Python environment&amp;nbsp;with the following stack:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import os
import gc
import warnings
import pandas as pd
import numpy as np
import matplotlib.pyplot as plt
from datetime import datetime
from sklearn.model_selection import train_test_split
from sklearn.metrics import r2_score
from sklearn.ensemble import RandomForestRegressor
from sklearn.preprocessing import LabelEncoder
from sklearn.linear_model import LinearRegression
from sap_rpt_oss import SAP_RPT_OSS_Regressor
import lightgbm as lgb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;pandas&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;numpy&lt;/STRONG&gt; for data manipulation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/STRONG&gt; for classical ML regressors (R&lt;STRONG&gt;andom Forest, Linear Regression&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;LightGBM&lt;/STRONG&gt; for gradient &lt;STRONG&gt;boosting&lt;/STRONG&gt; comparison&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;sap_rpt_oss&lt;/STRONG&gt; — the open-source Python version of &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP’s RPT-1 model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;matplotlib&lt;/STRONG&gt; for all &lt;STRONG&gt;visualizations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 OSS &lt;/STRONG&gt;can be downloaded installed following official Hugging Face:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://huggingface.co/SAP/sap-rpt-1-oss?library=sap-rpt-1-oss" href="https://huggingface.co/SAP/sap-rpt-1-oss?library=sap-rpt-1-oss" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://huggingface.co/SAP/sap-rpt-1-oss?library=sap-rpt-1-oss&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;. Python can be installed with executable download on Windows, or via &lt;STRONG&gt;Home Brew&lt;/STRONG&gt; for Mac and &lt;STRONG&gt;apt&lt;/STRONG&gt; commands for Linux. Libraries dependencies can be downloaded with &lt;STRONG&gt;pip&lt;/STRONG&gt; commands. Googling it may not be a road blocker.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;We use a sample&amp;nbsp;vehicle sales dataset. The complete file is about to 88Mb but for such experiment a restricted sample of 20k as it's more than enough to prove our the concept, still it's faster and consuming less computing resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="498px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;year&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Vehicle model year&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;make&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Brand (e.g., Toyota, Ford, BMW)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;model&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Specific model name&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;body&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Type (SUV, Sedan, etc.)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;transmission&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Gear type&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;odometer&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Vehicle mileage&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;color&lt;/CODE&gt;, &lt;CODE&gt;interior&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Visual attributes&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;sellingprice&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;The target variable to predict&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Dataset Download:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/syedanwarafridi/vehicle-sales-data?resource=download" href="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/syedanwarafridi/vehicle-sales-data?resource=download" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/syedanwarafridi/vehicle-sales-data?resource=download&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The dataset is loaded and preprocessed in a few simple steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;df = pd.read_csv("car_prices.csv").sample(n=20000, random_state=42)

# Fill missing values for categorical columns
fill_defaults = {
    'make': 'Other', 'model': 'Other', 'color': 'Other',
    'interior': 'Unknown', 'body': 'Unknown', 'transmission': 'Unknown'
}
for col, val in fill_defaults.items():
    df[col] = df[col].fillna(val)

X = df[["year", "make", "model", "body", "transmission", "odometer", "color", "interior"]]
y = df["sellingprice"]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this point, the stage is set:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The data is clean.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The environment is ready.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All models, traditionals and SAP RPT-1, are ready to be tested under identical conditions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175228200"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Training the Models - Three different ones&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the dataset ready, the &lt;STRONG&gt;next step&lt;/STRONG&gt; is to run each model under the same conditions: &lt;STRONG&gt;same features, same target, same train/test split and same random seed&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This ensures the comparison is fair and repeatable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We evaluate prediction performance using &lt;STRONG&gt;R² (coefficient of determination)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which indicates how much of the price variation the model can explain (1.0 = perfect prediction).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107797414"&gt;Training Model #1 - Random Forest&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Random Forest is often the first model used in tabular ML. It works by creating &lt;STRONG&gt;many decision trees&lt;/STRONG&gt; and averaging their predictions. Before training, categorical variables need to be &lt;STRONG&gt;label-encoded&lt;/STRONG&gt; into numbers, a common requirement for classical ML models:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_random_forest(X, y):
    X = X.copy()
    cat_cols = ["make", "model", "body", "transmission", "color", "interior"]
    le = LabelEncoder()

    for col in cat_cols:
        X[col] = le.fit_transform(X[col].astype(str).fillna("Unknown"))

    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = RandomForestRegressor(
        n_estimators=150, max_depth=20, random_state=42, n_jobs=-1
    )

    try:
        model.fit(X_train, y_train)
        preds = model.predict(X_test)
        r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)
    except Exception as e:
        preds, r2 = np.zeros_like(y_test), 0

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911283909"&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_3-1763206176248.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341502i82216AA724092E03/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_3-1763206176248.png" alt="nicolasestevan_3-1763206176248.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714770404"&gt;Up to 7067 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_8-1763206511155.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341538iF2A25E0C0EBE0612/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_8-1763206511155.png" alt="nicolasestevan_8-1763206511155.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518256899"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="RandomForest_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341551i3A2C874AFAF47388/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="RandomForest_20251115_092355.gif" alt="RandomForest_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-321743394"&gt;Training Model #2 - LightGBM&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;LightGBM is one of the most powerful models for tabular data. Unlike Random Forest (many independent trees), LightGBM builds trees &lt;STRONG&gt;sequentially&lt;/STRONG&gt;, each correcting the errors of the previous one. It supports categorical features natively, which simplifies preprocessing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_lightgbm(X, y):
    X = X.copy()
    cat_cols = ["make", "model", "body", "transmission", "color", "interior"]
    for col in cat_cols:
        X[col] = X[col].astype(str).fillna("Unknown").astype("category")

    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = lgb.LGBMRegressor(
        n_estimators=500, learning_rate=0.05, num_leaves=31,
        subsample=0.8, colsample_bytree=0.8, random_state=42
    )

    try:
        model.fit(X_train, y_train, categorical_feature=cat_cols)
        preds = model.predict(X_test)
        r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)
    except Exception:
        preds, r2 = np.zeros_like(y_test), 0

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-125229889"&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_2-1763205951324.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341474i1AAB214E2D01C2B2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_2-1763205951324.png" alt="nicolasestevan_2-1763205951324.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--146514985"&gt;Up to 7067 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_7-1763206474860.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341537i0ACD453B96C87ADF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_7-1763206474860.png" alt="nicolasestevan_7-1763206474860.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--343028490"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="LightGBM_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341552i30BC4DE94C4988F6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="LightGBM_20251115_092355.gif" alt="LightGBM_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--539541995"&gt;Training Model #3 - Linear Regression&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not fancy and even not complex, Linear Regression provides a baseline that shows:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;“If the relationship between attributes and price is roughly linear, how well can a simple model perform?”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_linear_model(X, y):
    X = X.copy()
    cat_cols = ["make", "model", "body", "transmission", "color", "interior"]
    for col in cat_cols:
        X[col] = LabelEncoder().fit_transform(X[col].astype(str).fillna("Unknown"))

    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = LinearRegression()
    X_train = X_train.fillna(X_train.mean(numeric_only=True))
    X_test = X_test.fillna(X_test.mean(numeric_only=True))

    try:
        model.fit(X_train, y_train)
        preds = model.predict(X_test)
        r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)
    except Exception:
        preds, r2 = np.zeros_like(y_test), 0

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--736055500"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_1-1763205857765.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341472i81AFB2D0BE770F90/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_1-1763205857765.png" alt="nicolasestevan_1-1763205857765.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--932569005"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 7067 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_6-1763206428099.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341536iC708165AEAE11D46/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_6-1763206428099.png" alt="nicolasestevan_6-1763206428099.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1129082510"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="LinearModel_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341553i0849B4C842A417EE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="LinearModel_20251115_092355.gif" alt="LinearModel_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1032193008"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chequered_flag:"&gt;🏁&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP RPT-1 OSS: Context Model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where things get interesting. SAP RPT-1 does &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; rely on learning patterns from the dataset. Instead, it uses a pretrained transformer architecture to infer relationships directly through &lt;STRONG&gt;context embeddings&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Lean and simple, "for non-Data Science PhD":&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_sap_rpt1(X, y):
    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = SAP_RPT_OSS_Regressor(max_context_size=8192, bagging=8)
    model.fit(X_train, y_train)

    preds = model.predict(X_test)
    r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1522109520"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_0-1763205729558.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341471i4AC7007DCA5A0F76/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_0-1763205729558.png" alt="nicolasestevan_0-1763205729558.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1718623025"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 2055 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_4-1763206228416.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341505i9ADE9D2D2B38C363/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_4-1763206228416.png" alt="nicolasestevan_4-1763206228416.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1915136530"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SAP_RPT1_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341566i0BE0E0D666836951/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP_RPT1_20251115_092355.gif" alt="SAP_RPT1_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1650063337"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Running Experiments at Multiple Sample Sizes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section breaks down how the iterative experiment loop works, why the SAP RPT-1 OSS model has a max-context limit, and how performance changes as we scale up the dataset. By running the same models across several sample sizes, we can see where traditional ML shines, where RPT-1 stays competitive, and how both behave as the data grows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;sample_sizes = np.linspace(50, len(X), 200, dtype=int)
results, max_r2_rpt1, max_sample_rpt1 = [], 0, 0

for n in sample_sizes:
    idx = np.random.choice(len(X), n, replace=False)
    X_sample, y_sample = X.iloc[idx], y.iloc[idx]


    # SAP RPT-1 OSS (limited sample size)
    if n &amp;lt;= rpt1_limit:
        rpt_res = train_sap_rpt1(X_sample, y_sample)
        fn = plot_predictions(rpt_res[2], rpt_res[0], rpt_res[1], "SAP_RPT1", n)
        video_frames["SAP_RPT1"].append(fn)
        r2_rpt1 = rpt_res[1]
        max_r2_rpt1 = max(max_r2_rpt1, r2_rpt1)
    else:
        r2_rpt1 = max_r2_rpt1
        if max_sample_rpt1 == 0:
            max_sample_rpt1 = n

    # Train and plot models
    rf_res = train_random_forest(X_sample, y_sample)
    fn = plot_predictions(rf_res[2], rf_res[0], rf_res[1], "RandomForest", n)
    video_frames["RandomForest"].append(fn)

    lgb_res = train_lightgbm(X_sample, y_sample)
    fn = plot_predictions(lgb_res[2], lgb_res[0], lgb_res[1], "LightGBM", n)
    video_frames["LightGBM"].append(fn)

    lin_res = train_linear_model(X_sample, y_sample)
    fn = plot_predictions(lin_res[2], lin_res[0], lin_res[1], "LinearModel", n)
    video_frames["LinearModel"].append(fn)

    results.append((n, rf_res[1], r2_rpt1, lgb_res[1], lin_res[1]))

    # Early stop if traditional model reaches SAP RPT-1
    if rf_res[1] &amp;gt;= max_r2_rpt1 or lgb_res[1] &amp;gt;= max_r2_rpt1 or lin_res[1] &amp;gt;= max_r2_rpt1:
        break
    gc.collect()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This loop compares SAP RPT-1 OSS with traditional ML models as sample sizes increase. Each iteration randomly selects a subset of the data and trains all models on the same slice for a fair comparison. SAP RPT-1 can only run up to its max-context limit, so once the sample size exceeds that threshold, it stops retraining and simply carries forward its best R². The traditional models continue training at every step. The loop ends early when any traditional model matches or surpasses RPT-1’s best score, making the experiment efficient while showing how performance evolves as data grows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1846576842"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":end_arrow:"&gt;🔚&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Conclusion and Final Thoughts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP RPT-1 OSS stands out because it performs well with small datasets, requires minimal code, and can generate useful predictions with just an API call and a bit of context. This makes it ideal for jump-starting predictive use cases early on, delivering fast business value without a full ML pipeline. Traditional models, however, still shine when projects mature, data grows, and fine-tuned control becomes important. It’s not about choosing one over the other, but understanding where each approach brings the most value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aspect&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 OSS&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Traditional ML (RF, LGBM, Linear)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Data Requirements&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Low (performs well with small samples)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Medium/High (performance scales with data&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Setup Effort&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Minimal (API call + context)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Higher (preprocessing, encoding, tuning)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Training Process&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;None (pretrained context model)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Full training pipeline required&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Speed to Insights&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Very fast&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Moderate to slow&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Best Use Case&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Early-stage predictive cases, quick baselines&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Mature pipelines, high control and customization&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Flexibility&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Limited tuning / plug-and-play&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Highly customizable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Business Value&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Immediate, fast, accessible&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Strong when optimized and scaled&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;This experiment highlights a simple truth: &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 isn’t here to replace traditional ML, it jump-starts it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;With a pretrained, context-driven approach, RPT-1 delivers fast, reliable insights with very little data and almost no setup. Traditional models still excel in mature, data-rich scenarios, but RPT-1 shines as a rapid accelerator and early-value generator inside SAP landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1958473942"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt;Open for Exchange&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you're testing RPT-1, exploring predictive cases, or want the full code, feel free to reach out.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Happy to connect, compare experiences, and push this topic forward together.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-rpt-1-context-model-vs-training-classical-models-the-models-battle/ba-p/14268507"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T07:50:27.670000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/keep-the-blue-side-up-building-trust-in-ai-through-transparency-responsible/ba-p/14269929</id>
    <title>Keep the blue side up: Building trust in AI through transparency (Responsible AI blogpost series)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T16:01:34.302000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BettinaLaugwitz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/176876</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764802414"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="277483_277483_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341246i23A9003A522ED815/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="277483_277483_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" alt="277483_277483_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568288909"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flying has been a dream of humankind&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for ages, and how it can be achieved has tickled the minds of many visionaries and engineers. Part of the fascination is the possibility that humans push boundaries of what is physically possible. But physical laws are still in place, and accidents end fatally when something goes wrong, due to heights of dozens or thousands of meters or speeds needed for starts and landings. How much risk is the dream worth taking?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On December 17, 1903, Orville Wright conducted his historic flight with an airplane successfully. Just a few days earlier, Orville and his brother Wilbur had crashed in a test flight – one of the first documented aviation accidents in history.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today, many decades later, &lt;STRONG&gt;using aircrafts is considered one of the safest travel options&lt;/STRONG&gt; (measured by distance traveled &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aviation_safety" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aviation_safety&lt;/A&gt;) – thanks to curious engineers, learnings from accidents and incidents, scientific progress, publication of relevant regulations and industry standards, and of course an ever-attentive approach to safety and security checks and improvements. We can trust planes to be safe – not per se (the owl Archimedes has a point here &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KLI46yMdtmU" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KLI46yMdtmU&lt;/A&gt;) but because we have found ways to make them safe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;fascination for machines that work similarly to the human mind&lt;/STRONG&gt; has been around for ages. The potential of Artificial Intelligence (AI) for adding efficiency, creativity, and inspiration to persons’ lives is immense. The nature of the technology brings also specific risks and can be scary: machines that reason and learn imply a loss of human control – a challenge that is not only (science) fiction (&lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HAL_9000" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;HAL 9000&lt;/A&gt; being just one example; for more see e. g. &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence_in_fiction" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence_in_fiction&lt;/A&gt;) but reality (e. g. &lt;A href="https://www.aiaaic.org/aiaaic-repository" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AIAAIC Incident Repository&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://github.com/daviddao/awful-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Awful AI List&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://incidentdatabase.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://incidentdatabase.ai/&lt;/A&gt; ).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Artificial intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; has still a long way until it can be considered a matured technology which is as safe as air traffic has become. When it comes to AI today and going forward, we definitely want to &lt;STRONG&gt;trust, but verify&lt;/STRONG&gt;: what are the implications when implementing a specific AI system; what is the system doing and why; in case of incidents: what was causing the issue; etc. Iteratively improving technical standards and procedural governance, considering ethical and legal requirements, will enhance safety for people, environment, and society going forward. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every framework that discusses how to make AI systems safe for usage includes a section that has to do with &lt;STRONG&gt;transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt;, including the &lt;A href="https://www.unesco.org/en/artificial-intelligence/recommendation-ethics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UNESCO Recommendation&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the Ethics of AI&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html?pdf-asset=940c6047-1c7d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff&amp;amp;page=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP’s Guiding Principles&lt;/STRONG&gt; for Artificial Intelligence&lt;/A&gt;, or the &lt;A href="https://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/dae/document.cfm?doc_id=60419" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Ethics Guidelines for Trustworthy AI by the High Level Expert Group on Artificial Intelligence set up by the &lt;STRONG&gt;European Commission&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; (HLEG AI Ethics Guidelines). &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to the HLEG AI Ethics Guidelines, “[t]rustworthy AI has &lt;STRONG&gt;three components&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which should be met throughout the system's entire life cycle: (1) it should be &lt;STRONG&gt;lawful&lt;/STRONG&gt;, complying with all applicable laws and regulations (2) it should be &lt;STRONG&gt;ethical&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring adherence to ethical principles and values, and (3) it should be &lt;STRONG&gt;robust&lt;/STRONG&gt;, both from a technical and social perspective.” Transparency requirements play a role in all three components, so let’s use these angles to have a closer look.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371775404"&gt;Lawful: Transparency requirements in regulatory and legal areas&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the 1920s, barnstorming and so-called flying circuses were very popular: stunt shows with daredevil pilots and acrobats executing spectacular and risky maneuvers with the plane (loopings etc.) and on the plane (wing walking). Early legislation related to civil air transportation addressed the most common causes of fatal accidents, including lack of pilot qualification and stunt practices that put the spectators’ lives at risk. Over the years, laws were passed, updated, and complemented which intended to improve aviation safety and with that, the trust of the public in the technology, with the &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_government_role_in_civil_aviation#Air_Commerce_Act" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Air Commerce Act&lt;/A&gt;, issued in 1926, as an early example, and the &lt;A href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/reg_impl/2025/920/oj" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) 2025/920&lt;/A&gt; for sure not the last.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Defining and implementing regulation for technologies is inherently slower than the subject it is supposed to regulate. In the context of AI, luckily some laws that provide important guardrails to protect individuals have been in place for some time, &lt;SPAN&gt;or &lt;A href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB853" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The California AI Transparency Act AB 853&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; are examples of regulation which targets the specific risks and challenges related to AI. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Individuals and legal entities have a need and partly also (will have) a &lt;STRONG&gt;right to transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt; when it comes to decisions and AI; valid questions of stakeholders include: Which role does AI play in a decision that may &lt;STRONG&gt;affect my life&lt;/STRONG&gt; going forward, and am I okay with that? Can I make an informed decision when I give &lt;STRONG&gt;consent&lt;/STRONG&gt; to using an AI system as an individual? Do I have the transparency I need to &lt;STRONG&gt;diagnose&lt;/STRONG&gt; the functioning / malfunctioning of an AI system, so that we can &lt;STRONG&gt;learn from issues&lt;/STRONG&gt; and fix them going forward? How can &lt;STRONG&gt;Terms &amp;amp; Conditions&lt;/STRONG&gt; help understand scope and limitations of AI systems?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175261899"&gt;Robust: Making AI systems secure and robust&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Aircrafts are subject to thorough inspection based on sophisticated protocols that prove their respective &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Airworthiness" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;airworthiness&lt;/A&gt; before they are permitted to operate. Insights from past incidents, e. g. through &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flight_recorder" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Flight Recorder&lt;/A&gt; data, are an important resource of input for improvements of hardware, software, or procedures, to help prevent future damage and harm.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Software systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; need to be reliable in the sense that they work as designed and the potential risks related to their usage are minimized. &lt;STRONG&gt;Quality management&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;software&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;security &lt;/STRONG&gt;efforts and &lt;STRONG&gt;governance&lt;/STRONG&gt; in general play a critical role when creating robust software. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The same applies to the development of&lt;STRONG&gt; AI systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;, plus some extra aspects that have to do with the specific nature of those systems, in particular when they involve &lt;STRONG&gt;machine learning&lt;/STRONG&gt; capabilities or are generating output &lt;STRONG&gt;autonomously&lt;/STRONG&gt; (for definitions / distinctions of AI / ML / genAI / Agentic AI see e. g. the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/03/7211ee96-647e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI Ethics Handbook&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What role does transparency play? For example, without transparency, testing AI system robustness and reliability are a critical challenge. At the same time, we are speaking of &lt;STRONG&gt;‘black box’ systems&lt;/STRONG&gt; – how can we even understand what is going on in the system and if that is what we expect in terms of reliability, security and safety?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security testing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; of AI systems should not only look at the outcome or effect, but ideally have a certain level of insight in the processes and methods inside the system to identify root causes and potential &lt;STRONG&gt;systematic threats&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &lt;STRONG&gt;Benchmarking&lt;/STRONG&gt; of models or AI systems help understand / ‘diagnose’ the quality and reliability and trigger mitigation as needed, runtime &lt;STRONG&gt;monitoring and traceability&lt;/STRONG&gt; help prevent unintended and unwanted shifts in an AI system’s performance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Software companies can leverage guidelines and recommendations (e. g. &lt;A href="https://owasp.org/www-project-ai-testing-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OWASP AI Testing Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;), applicable industry standards (i.e &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso:9001:ed-5:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ISO 9001 Quality Management System&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso-iec:27001:ed-3:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ISO/IEC 27001 Security Management System&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;), and adjust and complement according to the specifics of e. g. the industry or the regional context. Documenting the &lt;STRONG&gt;compliance&lt;/STRONG&gt; with relevant standards, including &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;NIST AI Risk Management Framework RMF&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso-iec:42001:ed-1:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ISO/IEC 42001 AI Management Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, helps build trust in the responsible development of AI systems in customers (see e. g. the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Trust Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) and the general public. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978748394"&gt;Ethical: Human oversight&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;How come airplane engineers invent seatbelts for pilots and passengers, and why was there an affordance to adjust law and regulation to reduce accidents and harm related to air traffic? Costs related to damages and injuries may have played a role, but without doubt also: empathy and ethical considerations. Situations where people lose loved ones, suffer from severe injury or face damages to their property are something to be avoided, and there is a strong motivation to reduce risks leading to them and to strengthen the public’s &lt;STRONG&gt;trust in the technology and its operation&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, there are AI-related legal requirements for transparency, and technical robustness is a prerequisite for AI systems that can be trusted. Relying on current or upcoming (known) regulation only when working on AI safety is not a sustainable approach: Technology is evolving too fast to allow regulatory processes to keep up and put legal boundaries in place. Thinking only in terms of current rules and potential gaps between them will turn legally compliant innovation into a ‘jigsaw puzzle with moving parts’: Legal gaps you designed for may be closing in due course, and every new regulation poses a threat to the products in the portfolio or on the roadmap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The ethical perspective on the other hand changes the focus from legal texts and fear of being sued, towards the vision to what we want the technology to do and what needs to be avoided. AI Ethics principles help &lt;STRONG&gt;inform legislation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but also provide &lt;STRONG&gt;guidance for technical innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Not just do what is feasible, but think what is acceptable and desirable going forward&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, for us as individuals, for us as a company, and for us as a society. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One example: The &lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HLEG AI Ethics Guidelines&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; name &lt;STRONG&gt;fairness&lt;/STRONG&gt; as an &lt;STRONG&gt;ethical imperative for trustworthy AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; as early as&lt;STRONG&gt; 2016&lt;/STRONG&gt;. SAP committed to fairness in the Guiding Principles for the Ethics of AI in &lt;STRONG&gt;2018&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The &lt;STRONG&gt;EU AI Act&lt;/STRONG&gt; entered into force in 2024, with certain provisions applying immediately and others phased in over time, reaching full applicability by &lt;STRONG&gt;2027&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Given the risks related to AI, we want to ensure that &lt;STRONG&gt;humans&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;control AI systems as needed, and not the other way around&lt;/STRONG&gt;. A prerequisite to ensure human agency and oversight: Transparency. You can’t control what you don’t know or understand. Measures like &lt;STRONG&gt;explainability&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;interpretability&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;traceability&lt;/STRONG&gt; are required to allow humans in their respective capacity and interaction with AI systems to stay in control, acquire knowledge, and gain &lt;STRONG&gt;trust&lt;/STRONG&gt; and confidence that the AI is &lt;STRONG&gt;not creating any harm&lt;/STRONG&gt;, neither to the &lt;STRONG&gt;individual&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;society&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;,&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; nor &lt;STRONG&gt;environment&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782234889"&gt;Different perspectives on transparency for responsible AI&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The blogpost series will take the perspective of &lt;STRONG&gt;different stakeholders in the lifecycle of AI systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;, including those who are “designing, developing, deploying, implementing, using or being affected by AI” (&lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;HLEG AI Ethics Guidelines&lt;/A&gt;). SAP experts will shed light on different aspects and approaches, from a &lt;STRONG&gt;legal&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a&lt;STRONG&gt; technical&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or an&lt;STRONG&gt; ethical &lt;/STRONG&gt;viewpoint, providing insights into challenges and solutions, considering &lt;STRONG&gt;organizational practices&lt;/STRONG&gt; as well as &lt;STRONG&gt;user needs &lt;/STRONG&gt;and &lt;STRONG&gt;customer expectations&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Examples from &lt;STRONG&gt;real SAP use cases&lt;/STRONG&gt; will illustrate the practical relevance and the efforts SAP is taking to build AI systems responsibly and create transparency so that stakeholders are enabled and empowered to understand risks and benefits, and execute on human oversight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blogpost will be updated with references whenever a new post is available to make it easy to get notified and find the information you are interested in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-585721384"&gt;Closing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When on an airplane, in most situations you would want to know that the skies are above you and the ground is beneath you (exceptions include flying circuses, see above). In any case, at least the pilot should know about the current orientation of the aircraft, even if weather conditions are blocking the sight of the actual surroundings. If the physical horizon is not visible, the attitude indicator, an instrument mimicking the blue skies above an artificial horizon and a brown ground below, will help adjust the plane’s orientation. &lt;STRONG&gt;Blue side up&lt;/STRONG&gt;, brown side down means that the plane is not going astray, neither upwards nor downwards – a means to keep orientation and an &lt;STRONG&gt;indicator of aviation safety&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We trust airplanes not because they are perfect and unbreakable. But because we know about their challenges, weaknesses, what to check, what to look at, how to optimize human-machine collaboration. And we have found ways to surface the information that is needed – by pilots, by engineers, by passengers, or in other words: leverage transparency to foster safety.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Meaningful transparency is ‘in the eye of the beholder’. Its design needs a human-centered approach to provide just the right angle, level, and amount of information that is relevant and helpful for individuals to interpret the situation, to “&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;make sense, or derive meaning, from a given stimulus […] so that the human can make a decision”&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; (&lt;A href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2021/NIST.IR.8367.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Broniatowski, 2021&lt;/A&gt;) – a prerequisite for human oversight and trustworthy AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="295087_GettyImages-95757310_medium_jpg.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343645i5F0DF1C8D73EB027/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="295087_GettyImages-95757310_medium_jpg.jpg" alt="295087_GettyImages-95757310_medium_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let us share how &lt;STRONG&gt;AI transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt; helps &lt;STRONG&gt;keep_the_blue_side_up&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned for the next post of the series about&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Engineering AI Transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-260125160"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-63611655"&gt;References and further readings&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--3819131"&gt;Responsible AI challenges&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.aiaaic.org/aiaaic-repository" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AIAAIC Incident Repository&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/daviddao/awful-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Awful AI List&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://incidentdatabase.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://incidentdatabase.ai/&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence_in_fiction" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence_in_fiction&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-146921721"&gt;Responsible AI guidelines&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;UNESCO Recommendation on the Ethics of AI: &lt;A href="https://www.unesco.org/en/articles/recommendation-ethics-artificial-intelligence" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.unesco.org/en/articles/recommendation-ethics-artificial-intelligence&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Guiding Principles for AI Ethics / Policy / Handbook: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;HLEG on Artificial Intelligence (European Commission) – Ethics Guidelines for Trustworthy AI: &lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--49591784"&gt;Lawful&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;General Data Protection Regulation GDPR &lt;A href="https://gdpr.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://gdpr.eu/&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;European Union Artificial Intelligence Act (EU AI Act): &lt;A href="https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/ai-act-explorer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/ai-act-explorer/&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AB-853 California AI Transparency Act: &lt;A href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB853" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB853&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--246105289"&gt;Robust&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso:9001:ed-5:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ISO 9001 Quality Management System&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso-iec:27001:ed-3:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ISO/IEC 27001 Security Management System&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso-iec:42001:ed-1:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ISO/IEC 42001 AI Management Systems&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OWASP &lt;A href="https://owasp.org/www-project-ai-testing-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://owasp.org/www-project-ai-testing-guide/&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://owaspai.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://owaspai.org/&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;NIST AI RMF &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Trust Center: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--442618794"&gt;Ethical&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Guiding Principles for AI Ethics / Policy / Handbook: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Understandability blog post: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/trustworthy-ai-how-to-make-artificial-intelligence-understandable/ba-p/13576857" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/trustworthy-ai-how-to-make-artificial-intelligence-understandable/ba-p/13576857&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Broniatowski, D. A. (2021): Psychology of Explainability and Interpretability. &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2021/NIST.IR.8367.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2021/NIST.IR.8367.pdf&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/keep-the-blue-side-up-building-trust-in-ai-through-transparency-responsible/ba-p/14269929"/>
    <published>2025-11-21T16:01:34.302000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-industrial-manufacturing-blog-posts/sap-cloud-erp-as-fundamental-part-of-sap-business-suite-for-industrial/ba-p/14258161</id>
    <title>SAP Cloud ERP as fundamental part of SAP Business Suite for Industrial Manufacturing (2508 Release)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-25T04:05:50.160000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nico_Dahl</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1433541</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763841530"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Industrial manufacturing is at a crossroads. The industry faces mounting pressures from global market shifts, technological advancements, and the imperative to operate more sustainably. At the same time, new opportunities are emerging for those ready to embrace change. As the industry evolves, the ability to adapt quickly, innovate continuously, and build resilient operations has become essential. This post explores how SAP Cloud ERP as part of SAP Business Suite is enabling industrial manufacturers navigate this transformation, drawing on the latest insights from our industry update with the 2508 release.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Watch the full recording here: &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/industrial-manufacturing-industry-update-pet-h2-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Industrial Manufacturing Industry Update - PET H2 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567328025"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Evolving Landscape of Industrial Manufacturing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Industrial manufacturing companies are defined by their ability to transform raw materials into finished goods at scale, serving a wide range of markets from household appliances to heavy equipment. Many organizations operate across several industry subsegments, often as a result of mergers and acquisitions, which adds complexity to their operations and increases the demands placed on their ERP systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today’s manufacturers are not only expected to deliver high-quality products efficiently but also to manage increasingly complex supply chains, comply with evolving regulations, and respond to rapid changes in customer demand. The need for robust, flexible, and integrated business systems has never been greater.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370814520"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Challenges and Industry Trends&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recent industry studies and ongoing engagement with customers have highlighted several persistent challenges. Business growth remains a top priority, with manufacturers seeking to attract new customers and enter new markets. However, legacy systems often lack the capabilities needed to support new business models or the localization required for global expansion. Supply chain resilience is another critical concern. Manufacturers are striving to build closer relationships with suppliers and gain deeper visibility into their supply chains, but many lack the systems to enable real-time insights or to streamline the onboarding of new partners.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Operational efficiency is also under pressure. Companies are looking to maximize the effectiveness of both machines and workforce, often through automation and upskilling. Yet, manual processes and limited visibility into production capacity can hinder progress. Finally, technology adoption remains a challenge. Many manufacturers are still reliant on inflexible legacy systems, with data locked away in silos and not easily accessible for business decision-making. The transition to cloud-based, data-driven operations is essential for unlocking new value and staying competitive with the help of AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174301015"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP’s Approach: Building the Intelligent, Sustainable Enterprise&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Cloud ERP is designed to address these challenges head-on. The solution provides a strong foundation for industrial manufacturers, offering pre-configured, ready-to-run, end-to-end scenarios that can be deployed quickly and adapted as business needs evolve. Integration with SAP Business Technology Platform and a broad ecosystem of SAP and Partner solutions ensures that customers can support their unique processes while benefiting from continuous innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A key strength of SAP’s approach is its support for both headquarter scenarios and subsidiaries through two-tier ERP models. This enables organizations to maintain strict governance and standardization at the corporate level while allowing subsidiaries the flexibility to operate in ways that best suit their local markets or distinct business models.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977787510"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;End-to-End Scenarios for Modern Manufacturing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Cloud ERP supports a wide range of manufacturing archetypes, each tailored to the specific needs of different industry segments. E.g. for component manufacturers, make-to-stock scenarios enable efficient production planning, procurement, and sales from inventory. Machinery manufacturers benefit from assemble-to-order and configure-to-order processes, which provide the flexibility to meet individual customer requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;End-to-end scenarios are designed to span the entire industrial manufacturing value chain, from idea to market, source to pay, plan to fulfill, and lead to cash. By connecting every part of the business, manufacturers gain greater visibility, control, and the ability to respond quickly to changing conditions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781274005"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Innovations in the SAP Cloud ERP 2508 Release&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The latest release of SAP Cloud ERP brings several important enhancements for industrial manufacturers. In production planning and execution, the capacity scheduling board introduces activity coloring, allowing production planners to distinguish between setup, production, and teardown times at a glance. This provides clearer insights into operations and helps optimize resource utilization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_1cb6ppu9" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Component availability checks have also been added to the capacity scheduling table, enabling planners to verify that all necessary parts are on stock before scheduling production orders, thus reducing the risk of costly delays.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_k3t51ak9" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-Assisted Processing of Incoming Quality Certificates with SAP Document AI automatically processes incoming quality certificate documents. By leveraging SAP Document AI on BTP, the data extraction and automatic attachment of certificates to relevant receipts become a hassle-free reality. This allows to handle certificates more efficiently and helps ensure that nothing is lost or overlooked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_8iqjpmzs" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In sales management, SAP’s AI copilot, Joule, can now handle expiring prices, automate renewals, and identify fulfillment issues in sales orders, helping sales teams work more efficiently and proactively.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_hobyopp3" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Advanced Variant Configuration capabilities have also been enhanced. Multi-level bills of materials can now be downloaded for easier comparison, and configurations can be imported from sales documents for reuse, streamlining the process of managing complex product variants.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_y3oac71z" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_y14d5m35" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584760500"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer Success Stories: Real-World Impact&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The value of SAP Cloud ERP is best illustrated through the experiences of leading industrial manufacturers. &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/07/8ecec030-147f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DINE Inc.&lt;/A&gt;, a South Korean manufacturer specializing in high-precision machining tools, faced challenges with an outdated ERP system that hindered digital transformation and data reliability. By implementing SAP Cloud ERP, DINE achieved unified accounting management across global operations, standardized workflows, and enhanced data visibility. The results included a doubling of profit and loss analysis accuracy, a 1.5-fold increase in inventory turnover rate, and a 10% reduction in spare parts inventory value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2025/09/0cb9afb9-1f7f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Tetra Pak eBeam Systems AG&lt;/A&gt;, headquartered in Switzerland, sought to modernize operations after being acquired by Tetra Pak in 2020. By adopting SAP Cloud ERP and leveraging the SAP Activate methodology, the company reduced upgrade preparation time from eight hours to two, improved user experience, and enabled IT resources to focus on strategic initiatives.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Other customers, such as &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/H1GJdct?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=68&amp;amp;doi=SAP1117756" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Acceleron&lt;/A&gt; and Ferrotec, have also realized significant benefits. Acceleron consolidated more than 20 ERP systems into a single global business foundation in the cloud, enabling unified processes across 40 countries. &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2024/10/f0cffe1d-e07e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Ferrotec Manufacturing Malaysia Sdn. Bhd.&lt;/A&gt; improved finance team productivity by 40%, procurement efficiency by 90%, and reduced supply chain costs by half.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-388246995"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Takeaways for Industrial Manufacturers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The journey to becoming an agile, intelligent, and sustainable enterprise is both challenging and rewarding. SAP Cloud ERP serves as a catalyst for transformation, enabling manufacturers to adapt quickly, streamline operations, and unlock new business models. Artificial intelligence and automation are driving efficiency and resilience, reducing manual effort and empowering teams to make better decisions. Integrated, end-to-end processes ensure that every part of the business is connected, delivering greater visibility and control.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Perhaps most importantly, the experiences of leading manufacturers demonstrate real world impact and measurable value. From improved operational efficiency to enhanced compliance and accelerated growth, SAP Cloud ERP is helping organizations to future-proof their businesses for continuous growth and thrive in a rapidly changing world.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-191733490"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Industrial manufacturing is evolving at an unprecedented pace. The path to sustainable growth and long-term success lies in embracing digital transformation and building resilient, data-driven operations. SAP Cloud ERP and the entire SAP Business Suite continues to evolve with innovations which empowers manufacturers to meet today’s challenges and seize tomorrow’s opportunities. By working together with SAP, we can deliver exceptional value and shape the future of industrial manufacturing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information on how SAP can support your transformation journey, we invite you to connect with our team or visit our website: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/industries/industrial-manufacturing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Industrial Manufacturing Industry Software | SAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4780015"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Want to know more?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bert Schulze shared the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/highlights-of-the-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-release/ba-p/14163726" target="_blank"&gt;Highlights of the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release&lt;/A&gt;, my colleague Markus Oertelt shared what’s new in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/manufacturing-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14161093" target="_blank"&gt;Manufacturing in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508&lt;/A&gt; and my colleague Leonie Peterka has written the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/quality-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14167949" target="_blank"&gt;Quality Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;blog post. Here you will find even more innovations for industrial manufacturers and other businesses.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-industrial-manufacturing-blog-posts/sap-cloud-erp-as-fundamental-part-of-sap-business-suite-for-industrial/ba-p/14258161"/>
    <published>2025-11-25T04:05:50.160000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-3-of-6/ba-p/14277803</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 3 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T09:13:17.706000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marcus_mock</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/304566</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345278i64BEF6314EEBDD8F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" alt="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: Is Artificial Intelligence Determining Future Purchasing?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The third part of the joint study by SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University on the supply chain of the future deals with purchasing. We do not assume the future of purchasing looks the same for all companies. Rather, key trends and key technologies play a big role. Their impact varies greatly depending on the industry and business model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The shaping trends for purchasing (as well as for the other parts of the supply chain) include the global economic situation and geopolitical tensions, the growing importance of sustainability, the scarcity of raw materials, and the changes for the people involved. These issues are not new, but they will play a major role in the coming years and will sometimes become even bigger.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key technologies are in the focus, e.g. integrated transactional purchasing applications with new semantic data models, AI agents, AI-based data analyses, and insights from the evaluation of information from business networks. Artificial intelligence is not the only driving technology but will become increasingly relevant in the coming years. No process in modern purchasing organizations will remain unaffected by its influence. Against this background, purchasing organizations have to work out which trends and technologies are particularly important for their company to plan the path to a successful future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The study conducted an online survey of 174 supply chain managers with people responsibility (April 2025). There was a clear discrepancy between ambitious visions for the future and the sad reality. On the one hand, 28% of respondents expected purchasing managers to play an important role in shaping corporate strategy and security of supply in 2035, while 31% expected buying organizations to achieve significantly better AI-driven outcomes with high quality data. On the other hand, only 12% say that procurement in their organization is now fully integrated into C-level decision-making, and only 3% think AI-powered purchasing analytics are great today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How should this discrepancy be dealt with? And how to deal with the uncertainty of every look into the future? The clear recommendation for all purchasing organizations is to do their homework first, to take decisions and to perform a couple of no-regret moves. It is clear that only purchasing organizations following these five important points are optimally positioned for the coming years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Firstly, clearly defined strategies and responsible people are in place for the most important categories and sub-categories. These category strategies must be kept up to date in suitable applications instead of gathering dust in presentations stored on shared drives. The strategies will be the trigger for activities, and the focal point for monitoring the progress of the activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Secondly, the operating model of the purchasing organization must be optimized by shifting personnel capacities from administrative activities to value-adding tasks. The goal is to work with a small but highly skilled workforce.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Third, clearly defined and standardized processes are required that exist in Business Process Model and Notation (BPMN) notation and are mapped in a process management solution, not a drawing tool. On this basis, simulations and comparisons of as-is and to-be can be carried out. Also, the processes can be linked to business requirements, test cases, application documentation, driving AI based automation in these related activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fourth, modern purchasing applications should be used to support end-to-end processes, without media breaks and with a steadily growing degree of automation. An end-to-end flow of data and information is essential. Specifications and prices belong into the apps themselves, not in file attachments. These pieces of information are critical parts of the data that drives AI. Similarly, the apps must be integrated so data is not transferred manually or via bots.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fifth, all relevant data from various procurement apps and third-party data must be available for analysis. The key is that this data is available on an appropriate platform and mapped to a semantic model. This is the only way to get an overview of the entire purchasing process, to derive in-depth insights and to drive more AI use cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The last point is of particular importance. Only if data on purchasing processes is available in structured form, across all purchasing processes, in good quality, will the purchasing organization have a solid basis for using AI functionalities of any kind, especially AI-driven analytics and AI agents, which can take on complex tasks on their own.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI agents sound a bit like science fiction for many persons in the procurement space – that is why the figure below outlines an agentic AI scenario in strategic procurement. The CPO sets a task for a procurement orchestration agent which in turn sets tasks for other, more specialized procurement agents (e.g. spend analysis, sourcing activities, contract creation) to achieve an overall goal, the optimization of a specific sub-category.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly, all other parties involved in the purchasing processes can be supported. Requestors can interact with an operational purchasing agents to quickly and clearly describe their needs. That operational purchasing agent reaches out to other agents leveraging existing contracts or catalogs, adhering to all purchasing guidelines, and covering topics such as account assignment, tax determination, and transportation costs. With the help of their own agents, suppliers will find it easy to participate in complex tenders, bid in Dutch or Japanese auctions, negotiate and sign contracts, and provide price lists and catalogs in specific formats to the purchasing organization. Since suppliers will use their own AI agents, there will be an increasing frequency of interaction between multiple agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, it can be said that those purchasing organizations will be optimally positioned for the future, who correctly classify the relevance of future trends and technologies to their own business, and who conclude the five no-regret moves mentioned above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345277iDB02DA211AADEFBC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" alt="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure: AI agents implement a complex task in purchasing&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-3-of-6/ba-p/14277803"/>
    <published>2025-11-26T09:13:17.706000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/proactive-monitoring-that-integrates-retail-operations-in-a-data-driven/ba-p/14278750</id>
    <title>Proactive Monitoring that Integrates Retail Operations in a Data-driven World</title>
    <updated>2025-11-27T10:02:09.087000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JeaneFerreira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1759223</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Imagine a global retailer preparing for the holiday season, a time when system stability is paramount. In previous years, unexpected disruptions caused delays and customer dissatisfaction. This year, things are different. By implementing proactive monitoring powered by AI and Collective Intelligence, the retailer identified early signals of potential issues weeks before peak demand. This story exemplifies how proactive monitoring transforms support from reactive firefighting to predictive prevention.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2023859744"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Proactive Monitoring Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Proactive monitoring reduces escalations, improves customer confidence, and optimizes operations. Instead of waiting for incidents to occur, we anticipate them, ensuring uninterrupted business continuity. For example, during the Holiday Season Readiness Program, proactive monitoring helped SAP support teams detect anomalies in critical systems, preventing potential outages for major e-commerce customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1827346239"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How It Works&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The process begins with comprehensive data collection—telemetry from cloud systems, business process data, and historical case patterns. AI-driven algorithms then analyze these inputs to recognize patterns and correlate events. When anomalies are detected, automated workflows trigger alerts and initiate Preventive Customer Risk Mitigation actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1630832734"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Breaking Data Silos&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Success depends on breaking down data silos. Only by building a Collective Intelligence framework—where insights from global case data, configuration logs, and usage analytics converge—can this model be scaled across the entire customer base. As data needs to be used collaboratively, data sharing enables an environment where information is accessible in a timely manner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1434319229"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Among the benefits of proactive monitoring, they can range from faster root cause analysis to reduced mean time to resolution. The first refers to the process of identification of causes and reasons for an issue taking place, and the latter concerns the measurement of how quickly a system responds to a failure once it is recognized. Both play a part in refining the customer experience through invisible, but automated support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="JeaneFerreira_0-1764233626580.png" style="width: 706px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345763i03DC1DFD8A84FD58/image-dimensions/706x381/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="706" height="381" role="button" title="JeaneFerreira_0-1764233626580.png" alt="JeaneFerreira_0-1764233626580.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the proactive monitoring strategy anchored in AI, retailers can turn their peak shopping seasons from difficult periods into opportunities for improving customer engagement and operational resilience. A continued adoption of AI-driven capabilities is what will enable smarter planning and sustainable data-driven growth. strategic AI adoption and thoughtful implementation will drive retail excellence in an increasingly digital and data-driven world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;A special thanks to SAP experts Bharath Ramamurthy, Vice President of Strategic Initiatives, Customer Support, and Kartikaye Gomber, AI Solution Architect, for their contributions to this article.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/proactive-monitoring-that-integrates-retail-operations-in-a-data-driven/ba-p/14278750"/>
    <published>2025-11-27T10:02:09.087000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/to-the-left-to-the-left-setting-businesses-up-for-irreplaceable-success/ba-p/14278775</id>
    <title>To the Left, To the Left: Setting Businesses Up for Irreplaceable Success</title>
    <updated>2025-11-27T10:19:37.439000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JeaneFerreira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1759223</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Consider a scenario where a critical update is scheduled for a financial services customer ahead of a major fiscal event. Traditionally, risks would surface post-deployment, leading to costly escalations. That is where a shift to the left walks into the stage: as the testing and detection steps are moved earlier into the lifecycle, an eventual delay in release is avoided, as well as the increase in costs associated with fixings issues. In other words, shifting to left is like reserving the seat in the first rows for testing!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At first glance, it may appear that risks are put in the spotlight, much like nominees at an award show. However, in reality, this approach aims at reducing them. Early recognition of potential issues enables development teams to allocate more time to data cleansing and preparation, tasks that typically consume a significant part of their efforts. This proactive approach allows for more focus on generating valuable insights rather than dealing with escalations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2023859811"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Does Shift Left Mean?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shift Left involves moving risk detection and mitigation earlier in the lifecycle. This approach reduces downstream support costs and enhances customer satisfaction. During the Holiday Season Readiness Program, Shift Left strategies ensured that preventative controls were in place well before peak transaction periods. These strategies included:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementing Preventive Customer Risk Mitigation workflows for early alerts and automated case creation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrating with Cloud ALM for lifecycle event monitoring&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Defining governance models for clear ownership of risk mitigation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1827346306"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Predictive Intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predictive intelligence uses Collective Intelligence to aggregate insights from global case data and apply AI models for event-to-issue correlation. This enables proactive actions that prevent disruptions before they impact customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1630832801"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Breaking Data Silos for Scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scaling this model requires dismantling data silos. By pooling insights across teams and regions, we create a unified intelligence network capable of supporting our entire customer base efficiently. With reliable data through the software deployment process, customers can make well-informed decisions at all stages of their businesses, that could lead to better budget management likewise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1434319296"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This method is aligned with SAP’s vision for an effortless customer experience. It reduces escalations and downtime while improving operational efficiency. By incorporating recurrent tests at every step of the development process, the system is continuously reviewed and adjusted as needed. Just as filming involves many behind-the-scenes teams, a shift to the left ensures that the backstage engines are aware and constantly prepared for the result that customers witness.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In conclusion, the Shift Left approach changes traditional development and deployment processes by proactively addressing risks and issues earlier in the lifecycle. When customers operate their businesses smoothly and stay well-prepared, we join forces to lay the foundation for lasting success and sustained trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;A sincere thank you to SAP experts Bharath Ramamurthy, Vice President of Strategic Initiatives, Customer Support, and Kartikaye Gomber, AI Solution Architect, for their contributions to this article&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/to-the-left-to-the-left-setting-businesses-up-for-irreplaceable-success/ba-p/14278775"/>
    <published>2025-11-27T10:19:37.439000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
