<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Artificial-Intelligence-qa.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Artificial Intelligence</title>
  <updated>2025-10-17T23:10:19.350686+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Artificial Intelligence/pd-p/c3c3a408-33ea-4c2a-ae6f-05461e76982d" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Artificial Intelligence Q&amp;A in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/connect-an-aws-bucket-with-sap-ai-launchpad/qaq-p/13998480</id>
    <title>Connect an AWS bucket with SAP AI Launchpad</title>
    <updated>2025-01-27T18:25:16.754000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MarianaMartinez</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1920424</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;How can I connect my AWS bucket with SAP AI Launchpad and GitHub, in the Object Store Secret part?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/connect-an-aws-bucket-with-sap-ai-launchpad/qaq-p/13998480"/>
    <published>2025-01-27T18:25:16.754000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/predictive-ai-with-sap-ai-core/qaq-p/14000619</id>
    <title>Predictive ai with sap ai core</title>
    <updated>2025-01-29T16:53:12.710000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MarianaMartinez</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1920424</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Has anyone done the learning predictive ai with sap ai core tutorial on ingesting live data into your house price predictor with sap ai core, someone can help me because I'm stuck at step 15?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/predictive-ai-with-sap-ai-core/qaq-p/14000619"/>
    <published>2025-01-29T16:53:12.710000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/introducing-joule-sap-s-ai-copilot-for-seamless-business-interactions/qaq-p/14006623</id>
    <title>Introducing Joule: SAP’s AI Copilot for Seamless Business Interactions</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T12:03:07.495000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MonikaC</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1464273</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing Joule: SAP’s AI Copilot for Seamless Business Interactions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is transforming the way businesses interact with their systems with Joule, its AI-powered copilot designed to enhance productivity and simplify tasks. Joule serves as a centralized AI assistant across the SAP ecosystem, providing a seamless and context-aware user experience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Makes Joule Unique?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One AI Copilot for SAP: Joule integrates across SAP cloud solutions like SAP SuccessFactors and SAP S/4HANA Cloud, allowing users to interact naturally through language.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Out-of-the-Box &amp;amp; Native Integration: With pre-configured content, Joule is ready to use with minimal setup, making it instantly valuable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consistent User Experience: Whether accessed via SAP Start, mobile, or application UIs, Joule ensures a smooth and familiar interaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reliable &amp;amp; Context-Aware: Joule understands user roles, permissions, and the SAP products they use, ensuring relevant responses.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Responsible &amp;amp; Secure: With strict data protection policies, Joule does not use customer data for AI training or third-party purposes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How Does Joule Help?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provides context-aware responses based on business transactions and data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintains cross-application reasoning for efficient navigation across SAP solutions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leverages Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) for document-grounded responses.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensures data security &amp;amp; compliance by inheriting user authentication rights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Includes ethical AI guardrails to prevent bias, hate speech, and misuse.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By integrating Large Language Models (LLMs) with SAP’s rich business context, Joule enables employees to work 80% more efficiently. It empowers businesses with faster decision-making, streamlined workflows, and enhanced user interactions—truly revolutionizing the SAP experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Interaction Patterns&lt;/STRONG&gt; is the main starting point.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It branches into four types of interactions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transactional:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Supports CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Navigational:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Helps users find relevant SAP screens.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Informational:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Provides knowledge-based answers using SAP Help and Customer Content (Document Grounding).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytical:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enables data insights through SAP Analytics Cloud and JustAsk.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This flowchart visually simplifies the interaction patterns of Joule.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MonikaC_4-1738664473936.png" style="width: 734px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/221663i512A99DBC2728F90/image-dimensions/734x287?v=v2" width="734" height="287" role="button" title="MonikaC_4-1738664473936.png" alt="MonikaC_4-1738664473936.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unlocking Business Knowledge with Joule’s Document Grounding&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s workplace, quick access to accurate information is crucial. Joule’s Document Grounding feature ensures employees get the right answers based on company-specific documents—without the need for complex AI training or manual searching.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is Document Grounding?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Document Grounding allows businesses to upload important documents—like HR policies, travel guidelines, and FAQs—into Joule. When employees ask a question, Joule retrieves the most relevant information from these documents and delivers a clear, concise response with source citations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Does This Matter?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditional AI models rely on general knowledge, which may not always reflect company-specific policies. Grounding enhances AI by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt; Providing business-specific answers based on internal documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt; Citing sources, increasing transparency and trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt; Reducing misinformation by pulling directly from company-approved materials.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt; Eliminating costly AI retraining, as Joule dynamically retrieves the latest content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How It Transforms the Employee Experience?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For instance, in SAP SuccessFactors, employees can ask Joule questions about HR policies and receive instant, reliable answers. This saves time, reduces confusion, and enhances productivity—making company knowledge more accessible to everyone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/introducing-joule-sap-s-ai-copilot-for-seamless-business-interactions/qaq-p/14006623"/>
    <published>2025-02-04T12:03:07.495000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/access-event-log-case-attributes-via-api-to-perform-ml-based-predictions/qaq-p/14027178</id>
    <title>Access event log, case attributes via API to perform ML based predictions</title>
    <updated>2025-02-25T15:05:56.437000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ShubhamGuptaGenpact</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1821316</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am looking for options to access Business objects, event log created within Process Intelligence. I would require to access this data to perform ML based predictions or employ other AI based applications.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The idea is to perform all these computations in external notebook and push this data back to Process Intelligence so that we can show predictions or any other applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone worked on this kind of setup, how to access data from Process Intelligence and push it back to the model. Any kind of API provided or Python based setup available, please advise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1522801"&gt;@Process&lt;/a&gt; Intelligence&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt; Signavio&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/access-event-log-case-attributes-via-api-to-perform-ml-based-predictions/qaq-p/14027178"/>
    <published>2025-02-25T15:05:56.437000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/workflow-should-trigger-basis-on-another-mdf-object/qaq-p/14027505</id>
    <title>Workflow should trigger basis on another MDF Object</title>
    <updated>2025-02-25T22:15:33.790000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>niranjands</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/98997</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We have a requirement where, upon submission of a custom MDF object by a user, we need to trigger a workflow for another custom MDF object that serves as a feedback object. I'm looking for ways to achieve this, such as using intelligent services, CPI, or exploring other workarounds.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/workflow-should-trigger-basis-on-another-mdf-object/qaq-p/14027505"/>
    <published>2025-02-25T22:15:33.790000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/joule-extensibility-poc-for-sap-learning/qaq-p/14027680</id>
    <title>Joule Extensibility POC for SAP Learning</title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T06:32:43.310000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kaustubh22071999</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2009882</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;BR /&gt;We're considering a proof of concept that involves utilizing the Joule Extensibility feature in relation to the SAP Learning platform (&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learn SAP skills | SAP Learning&lt;/A&gt;). The idea is to implement a chatbot that enhances user experience by offering improved recommendations and roadmaps based on their search queries. I'm curious about the feasibility of this concept, given that Joule can currently be integrated only with SAP Line of Business products. Is it possible for us to proceed with this use case?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/joule-extensibility-poc-for-sap-learning/qaq-p/14027680"/>
    <published>2025-02-26T06:32:43.310000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/generate-ppt-presentation-using-ai-tool-with-sap-bw-dataflow/qaq-p/14054993</id>
    <title>Generate PPT(presentation) using AI tool with SAP BW Dataflow</title>
    <updated>2025-03-24T17:23:48.070000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vincent801</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/924106</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you please guide me, how to generate PPT using AI for SAP BW data flow diagram. Please let me know, which tool will support for this requirement ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, we have 3 ECC source systems (Countries - US, Asia, Africa) with same datasource connected to one BW system. And in BW system, there are 3 data flows merging to Multiprovider. As per new requirement, one more country is adding and need to create a PPT for new flow through AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/generate-ppt-presentation-using-ai-tool-with-sap-bw-dataflow/qaq-p/14054993"/>
    <published>2025-03-24T17:23:48.070000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/is-it-possible-to-connect-on-joule-instance-with-sap-ibp-and-sap-s-4-hana/qaq-p/14057441</id>
    <title>Is it possible to connect on Joule instance with SAP IBP and SAP S/4 HANA Public Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-03-26T14:21:33.358000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>akhthaaralibadhusha</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/889531</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Currently is it possible to connect same Joule instance with S/4HANA Public Cloud and SAP IBP system ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/is-it-possible-to-connect-on-joule-instance-with-sap-ibp-and-sap-s-4-hana/qaq-p/14057441"/>
    <published>2025-03-26T14:21:33.358000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/has-joule-cross-business-role-data-bleeding-been-addressed-and-how/qaq-p/14059870</id>
    <title>Has Joule cross business-role data bleeding been addressed, and how?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-28T11:12:49.046000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DennisBkgaard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2032334</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;With the case of Joule being embedded throughout the core of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public ecosystem, it's natural to assume that Joule has access to all the data in the underlying datastores - which makes sense. However, as with any LLM there substantial considerations regarding bleeding data, either directly or as derivatives. I'm not worried about out-of-organisation security issues, more so cross-organisation security complications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have been looking around for articles or blog posts regarding Joule's grasp on this / measures in place to prevent bleeding, but I haven't found any.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the most simple case, imagine two business roles;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Junior Procurement/Sourcing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Senior Procurement/Sourcing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The only difference is the junior does not have access to supplier contact information to protect business IP. Given both roles have access to Joule, I would expect outputs of Joule to be governed by similarly to defined access rights in the individual Business Role Access Categories.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this case, access rights to specific fields are relatively simple, and could essentially be dealt with in the same way as LLM's deal with copyright material / LORA's etc. However, this becomes increasingly complex, and is by no means trivial, as the amount of business roles, data access, data and output types increase.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. How - technically - does Joule enforce the same minimal-access principles as there exists around RBAC?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Does there exist generalized analytics/monitoring around Joule interactions to identify and act upon data-bleeding instances?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Does Joule always work across tenant-data, or is "Joule" an individual agent per. user/union of unique business role combinations scoped to only have access to the data a business role(s) has access to, and is it actively designed to prevent access to more data in the context window?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unless there exists a formal article on the technical implementation of this, which we can refer to with regards to data sensitivity, it must be assumed that data bleeding is at best possible and at worst not seriously considered in Joule.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/has-joule-cross-business-role-data-bleeding-been-addressed-and-how/qaq-p/14059870"/>
    <published>2025-03-28T11:12:49.046000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/exploring-sap-joule-integration-options-with-sap-datasphere/qaq-p/14075462</id>
    <title>Exploring SAP Joule Integration Options with SAP Datasphere</title>
    <updated>2025-04-14T15:07:03.690000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SAPranav</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/882477</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Hello SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I'm exploring the possibility of integrating &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt; — either via direct service availability or custom architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Specifically, I’m interested in understanding:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Is &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt; currently accessible as a standalone service on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt; or only embedded within specific SAP applications?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Are there any &lt;STRONG&gt;supported or recommended approaches&lt;/STRONG&gt; for using Joule’s capabilities in conjunction with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Does the roadmap include &lt;STRONG&gt;broader availability of Joule APIs or SDKs&lt;/STRONG&gt; that developers could leverage for custom integrations?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I’d appreciate any guidance, documentation links, or experience others have had exploring this kind of setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Joule/pd-p/d0136351-8a9c-4881-aebc-bf414b785998" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1207-1"&gt;Joule&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Datasphere/pd-p/73555000100800002141" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="16-1"&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/exploring-sap-joule-integration-options-with-sap-datasphere/qaq-p/14075462"/>
    <published>2025-04-14T15:07:03.690000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/questions-about-sap-joule/qaq-p/14076048</id>
    <title>Questions about SAP Joule</title>
    <updated>2025-04-15T07:07:51.942000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Karthik_Murugan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2080683</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Community,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We are planning to enable SAP Joule. But before we proceed, we wanted to understand the capabilities of Joule with respect to SAP Sales Cloud Version 2. I had a few questions regarding it, please read through them and provide your insights.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I understand that SAP Joule currently has 3 Interaction Patterns: Transactional, Navigational and Informational. But I would like to know more about the following:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;1. What are the Business Objects supported in Joule with respect to SAP Sales Cloud Version 2?&lt;BR /&gt;2. What are the use-cases that are supported in Joule with respect to SAP Sales Cloud Version 2?&lt;BR /&gt;3. What are the current limitations of Joule?&lt;BR /&gt;4. Is there a way to customize navigation capabilities of Joule from SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 to SAP ECC?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If there are any online sources that I could reference for the questions above, please provide those to me as well.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks in advance,&lt;BR /&gt;Karthik C M.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-q-a/questions-about-sap-joule/qaq-p/14076048"/>
    <published>2025-04-15T07:07:51.942000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/ai-agent/qaq-p/14089059</id>
    <title>AI Agent</title>
    <updated>2025-04-29T08:42:17.144000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>darma1212</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/854918</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Dear SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I would like to inquire regarding the availability and usage of AI Agents within SAP environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Are AI Agents available for both SAP Public Cloud and SAP Private Cloud editions?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Could you kindly provide guidance on the prerequisites, activation process, and how to utilize AI Agents in both cloud models?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I appreciate your support and look forward to your insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Darma&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/ai-agent/qaq-p/14089059"/>
    <published>2025-04-29T08:42:17.144000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-business-ai-where-to-start/qaq-p/14093763</id>
    <title>SAP Business AI - Where to start?</title>
    <updated>2025-05-05T20:35:02.409000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>geronasso</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15080</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1581051406"&gt;SAP Discovery Center: Your Gateway to AI-Powered Innovation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In today's rapidly evolving digital landscape, organizations need a centralized platform to discover, evaluate, and implement innovative technologies. The &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/A&gt; serves this purpose, functioning as a comprehensive gateway to SAP's vast ecosystem of solutions, with a particular emphasis on artificial intelligence capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1513620620"&gt;What is SAP Discovery Center?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Discovery Center is a dynamic online platform that serves as your primary resource for exploring and implementing SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) services and &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AI features&lt;/A&gt;. It provides structured guidance for creating tailored business solutions that address specific organizational challenges.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;As stated on the platform itself, SAP Discovery Center positions itself as "Your Gateway to Innovation," helping users to "Discover, evaluate, and adopt SAP Business Technology Platform services and AI features to create tailored business solutions."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1317107115"&gt;Key Components of SAP Discovery Center&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The Discovery Center is organized around three core pillars:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1249676329"&gt;1. Discover&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Browse comprehensive catalogs of:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AI Features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/viewServices" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Services&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/refArchCatalog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Reference Architectures&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Customer Stories&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/search/solution%20diagram" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Solution Diagrams&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Roadmaps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1053162824"&gt;2. Evaluate&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Identify and assess the most suitable solutions with tools like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/estimator" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Service Estimator&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-estimator" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AI Estimator&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Price and Value Estimates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-856649319"&gt;3. Adopt&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Implement solutions with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quick Account Setup&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Proof of Concept Creation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Expert Collaboration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Initial Setup Guidance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Guided Project Board&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-531053095"&gt;Featured Content in SAP Discovery Center&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The Discovery Center showcases innovation highlights designed to accelerate business transformation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-463622309"&gt;Missions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Step-by-step guidance for implementing specific use cases, with support from topic experts and the SAP Community. AI Missions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://use-case-repository-proxy.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/public/resources/UC00004338/N9ECFBTGXFECWBNPMZR5UKG5IRW2FXV1WGL7RKPFS" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Get Started with SAP Business AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://use-case-repository-proxy.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/public/resources/UC10000234/VPUZ7JKG3GOIU6XDIURIAS2HTOAAK6WROTVMLUOTNO" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Activate Joule for SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://use-case-repository-proxy.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/public/resources/UC10000014/IOMAXZHHGLSBYOPT8DQEDA7VSWT8OEDOQZJS4T2HFQS" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GenAI Mail Insights: Develop a CAP application using GenAI and Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://use-case-repository-proxy.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/public/resources/UC10000365/UMINIXFJBRJTLLYYJXZ4PZNL6G8ICVWXXB9YOTGNHA" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Establish a Unified Joule Instance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://use-case-repository-proxy.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/public/resources/UC10000246/NZB2V8X7UHN1EUAHBBKSGLFQWHQMZYEWW4DGXL6XBE" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Activate Joule with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://digitalmarketplace-sapcpprd.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/dMfEj03RjuturYw-NJ7ACbBsxs3CC9qN9BgouB6VVw-S0Y6-13fqHdQvqrBOr6Cu.svg" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Digitizing Criticality Assessments using SAP AI Core and SAP AI Launchpad&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://use-case-repository-proxy.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/public/resources/UC10000253/4Y9RCP2HWKRBMQWQH96AKJACLCVH9C8LOUMA1TVT8S" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Facilitate Invoice Validation - Leveraging Document Information Extraction&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://use-case-repository-proxy.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/public/resources/UC10000228/KQWYXXY6OJQSWZ9FYPTM4WN4SYGHBSRBVGQGVBDIM" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Get Started with SAP Build Code and Joule using Generative AI (Trial and Enterprise Account)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://proxybridgesdck5a4a61ad17b8dc3.hana.ondemand.com/proxybridge-sdc-k5a4a6-1.0.0/readonly/cmis/json/5e5fd7b197b6556fa80bc826/root?objectId=Ye3oi3FnLiTyZyTxo4k4_RqhxAYOSqZceyE0j3BRdcQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Process and approve your invoices with SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://use-case-repository-proxy.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/public/resources/UC10000102/PTPL3MI0XGUQCS9FAYOCY53V06UTG66LXRHS3XVXYE" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Leveraging SAC visualizations with the power of GenAI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://use-case-repository-proxy.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/public/resources/UC10000396/B9FYKEYKPWJW99JKBBPFQBHE5NNOXOJAWMP6MSYIBFM" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Automate Agency Recruiting Process with SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://use-case-repository-proxy.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/public/resources/UC00004330/KKNR8VQVFHDCRZTHZABSXJ0VVXHJYWIORZSBGV3EK" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Make your Experience Management Survey More Intelligent with ChatGPT&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-267108804"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-70595299"&gt;Reference Architectures&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Explore and understand different architecture patterns implementable using SAP Business Technology Platform services, such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/refArchDetail/ref-arch-open-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Retrieval Augmented Generation with GenAI on SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Retrieval-Augmented-Generation-and-Generative-AI-on-SAP-BTP-single_diagram.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/257842i3792D7EB247A8E67/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Retrieval-Augmented-Generation-and-Generative-AI-on-SAP-BTP-single_diagram.png" alt="Retrieval-Augmented-Generation-and-Generative-AI-on-SAP-BTP-single_diagram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--201149575"&gt;SAP BTP Services&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Discover services that help integrate, extend, and build solutions, including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration Suite: An industry-leading integration platform-as-a-service&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--397663080"&gt;AI Features Catalog&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A comprehensive catalog of the 210 &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AI capabilities&lt;/A&gt; to optimize productivity, drive innovation, and personalize experiences across SAP's product portfolio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/?category=pp.2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Customer Relationship Management:&lt;/A&gt; 55 items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/?category=pp.1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Enterprise Management (Corporate)&lt;/A&gt;: 36 items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/?category=pp.3" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Human Capital Management&lt;/A&gt;: 23 items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/?category=pp.6" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Product Lifecycle Management&lt;/A&gt;: 3 items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/?category=pp.5" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Spend Management&lt;/A&gt;: 33 items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/?category=pp.8" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Management&lt;/A&gt;: 31 items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/?category=pp.4" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt;: 30 items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--300773578"&gt;The AI Feature Estimator&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;One of the most valuable tools within the Discovery Center is the AI Feature Estimator. This tool helps organizations:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Generate estimates for AI features&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Modify estimates as requirements evolve&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Share estimates with stakeholders&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Understand the potential business impact of AI implementation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--497287083"&gt;Related Resources&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Discovery Center connects users to a broader ecosystem of resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Content&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer References&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tutorials&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Communities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Road Map Explorer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Partner Applications&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--693800588"&gt;Why SAP Discovery Center Matters for AI Implementation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;For organizations interested in implementing AI within their SAP landscape, the Discovery Center provides several unique advantages:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Centralized Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A single source of truth for all available AI features across the SAP portfolio&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Guided Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Step-by-step missions for specific AI use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Estimation Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Resources to calculate potential costs and value&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-world Examples&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Customer stories demonstrating successful implementations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expert Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Access to topic experts and community resources&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;By leveraging the SAP Discovery Center, organizations can accelerate their AI adoption journey, reduce implementation risks, and maximize the business value of their investments in SAP's AI capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--596911086"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--793424591"&gt;The Importance of Artificial Intelligence Training for SAP Solutions&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI) is transforming how companies operate, enabling greater efficiency, process automation, and more accurate predictive analytics. Within the SAP ecosystem, AI plays a fundamental role in optimizing business processes, from financial management to customer experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Building AI expertise within the SAP context is not just a competitive advantage but a necessity for professionals who wish to drive innovation and extract maximum value from technological solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Whether through predictive modeling, robotic process automation (RPA), or virtual assistants, AI in the SAP universe is opening new business possibilities. Therefore, investing in continuous learning and exploring specific training can be decisive for standing out in the market.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1283341103"&gt;Exploring the SAP Discovery Center: Strategic Positioning in Artificial Intelligence&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/STRONG&gt; is an essential resource for any professional seeking to understand and implement Artificial Intelligence solutions in the SAP ecosystem. It offers a comprehensive view of use cases, integrations, and best practices, helping companies accelerate their digital journey with AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Through the Discovery Center, it's possible to access reference projects, explore services, and gain valuable insights on how to leverage AI capabilities within SAP solutions. This way, professionals and organizations can make more informed decisions and improve their innovation strategy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1479854608"&gt;List of Artificial Intelligence Training for SAP&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Here is an organized list of essential training programs on Artificial Intelligence in SAP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/introducing-sap-business-ai-strategy-and-partner-opportunity?userlogin=true" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exploring the SAP Business AI Portfolio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/introducing-sap-business-ai-commercial-model" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing SAP Business AI Commercial Model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/introducing-sap-business-ai-for-cloud-erp" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing SAP Business AI for Cloud ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-new-ai-capabilities-for-sap-finance" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discovering SAP Business AI Capabilities for SAP Finance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/introducing-sap-business-ai-for-sap-successfactors" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing SAP Business AI for SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/introducing-sap-business-ai-for-customer-experience" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing SAP Business AI for Customer Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/positioning-the-capabilities-and-benefits-of-the-sap-hana-cloud-vector-engine" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Positioning the Capabilities and Benefits of the SAP HANA Cloud Vector Engine&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/introducing-sap-business-ai-for-sap-digital-supply-chain" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing SAP Business AI for SAP Digital Supply Chain&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/introducing-sap-business-ai-for-spend-management?userlogin=true" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing SAP Business AI for Spend Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/applying-a-human-centered-approach-to-identify-and-define-business-ai-use-cases" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Applying a Human-Centered Approach to Identify and Define Business AI Use Cases&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/navigating-large-language-models-fundamentals-and-techniques-for-your-use-case" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Navigating Large Language Models Fundamentals and Techniques for Your Use Case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/boosting-your-cloud-transformation-journey-with-sap-business-ai-and-generative-ai" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Boosting Your Cloud Transformation Journey with SAP Business AI and Generative AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/solving-your-business-problems-using-prompts-and-llms-in-sap-s-generative-ai-hub" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solving Your Business Problems Using Prompts and LLMs in SAP's Generative AI Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/provisioning-and-implementing-joule" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Provisioning and Implementing Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/creating-applications-and-extensions-using-sap-build-code" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creating Applications and Extensions Using SAP Build Code&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://content-discovery.int.sap/assets/demo-store/19234?referer=%2F%3FassetTypeIds%3De042b329-9f58-4fe0-ab4d-12f2ce8cdd17" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Code - Generative AI-powered Development with Joule Copilot&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://content-discovery.int.sap/assets/demo-store/19273?referer=%2F%3FassetTypeIds%3De042b329-9f58-4fe0-ab4d-12f2ce8cdd17" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generative AI with SAP AI Launchpad&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://content-discovery.int.sap/assets/demo-store/19270" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud with Vector Engine and GenAI Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;These training programs are fundamental for any professional who wants to master Artificial Intelligence in the SAP ecosystem and enhance their business solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Send your doubts!&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-business-ai-where-to-start/qaq-p/14093763"/>
    <published>2025-05-05T20:35:02.409000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/detecting-handwritten-vs-digital-docs-in-sap-cap-dox/qaq-p/14096930</id>
    <title>Detecting Handwritten vs. Digital Docs in SAP CAP + DOX</title>
    <updated>2025-05-09T08:46:00.939000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sundar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1393233</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I'm working on a solution using&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP CAP (Cloud Application Programming) with Node.js&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, integrated with&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Document Information Extraction (DOX)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. This project sends documents via API to the DOX service to extract relevant information from files such as invoices and receipts. My requirement here is to check whether the document is&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;handwritten or computer-generated&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. This distinction could significantly enhance data accuracy and processing logic. If anyone has insights on integrating handwriting detection with SAP DOX or using pre-processing techniques for document classification, I’d love to connect and learn more.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/detecting-handwritten-vs-digital-docs-in-sap-cap-dox/qaq-p/14096930"/>
    <published>2025-05-09T08:46:00.939000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-bdc-demo-environment/qaq-p/14107492</id>
    <title>SAP BDC Demo Environment</title>
    <updated>2025-05-21T10:07:19.202000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SANA11</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1696282</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello All,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since the BDC trial version is now available, I’d like to create a demo using it. Could you please guide me on how to enable or build the content? Also, is it possible to showcase a demo using standard content, considering that the source systems are not properly maintained? I’m looking for any way to effectively pitch it to clients. I’m exploring options to work exclusively within BDC AI/ML part. The practice source systems are not properly maintained, making it impractical to establish connections with them. However, intelligent applications or insight apps require both source and target systems to be connected in order to enable the content. Are there any materials or documents available that can guide the implementation of Databricks AI/ML on raw data within an SAP BDC environment?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-bdc-demo-environment/qaq-p/14107492"/>
    <published>2025-05-21T10:07:19.202000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/need-information-on-different-sap-ai-modules-resources/qaq-p/14148414</id>
    <title>Need information on different SAP AI modules/Resources</title>
    <updated>2025-07-09T15:44:37.948000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Narasimha</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14917</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I am preparing for the SAP AI certification and went through all the relevant course material.&amp;nbsp; I still need clarification on some concepts.&amp;nbsp; I have put my understanding of different SAP AI resources with an example. Could someone clarify if my understanding is correct ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP AI Module Primary Role What It Does Examples&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Core&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Manages end-to-end lifecycle of &lt;STRONG&gt;any ML model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;- Train, deploy, monitor containerized models- Define YAML pipelines, executables, secrets&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Train an MRP delay prediction model using TensorFlow&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Monitor PO exception forecasting&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Generative AI Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Connects to &lt;STRONG&gt;external LLMs&lt;/STRONG&gt; via an &lt;STRONG&gt;abstraction layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;- Prompt execution- Orchestration- Safety filters- Document grounding&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Ask GPT-4 to summarize blocked invoices in S/4HANA&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Use Claude to explain a supply issue&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Launchpad&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Central UI&lt;/STRONG&gt; for managing all AI assets (Core + GenAI)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;- Deployment dashboard- Manage pipelines, prompts, templates, secrets&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; See status of ML model runs&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Manage GenAI Hub prompts and results in one place&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Foundation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Infrastructure layer&lt;/STRONG&gt; that powers Core &amp;amp; GenAI&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;- Resource orchestration (e.g., CPU, GPU)- Security, observability, scaling&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Supports storage access to datasets in Azure blob&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Enables auth and runtime allocation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Business Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pre-built APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt; for common AI tasks&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;- Pre-trained services like: ▪ Document Information Extraction ▪ Service Ticket Intelligence&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Auto-extract invoice fields from PDF&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Categorize helpdesk ticket based on past text data&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Vector Engine&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Embedding &amp;amp; vector search for &lt;STRONG&gt;RAG&lt;/STRONG&gt; or semantic search&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;- Stores embeddings- Enables Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) pipelines&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Query internal policies grounded to document embeddings&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Match customer queries to SOPs&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP SDK for Generative AI (Python)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;SDK to call GenAI Hub/Orchestration APIs from code&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;- Define LLM, prompt, and deployment in Python- Access orchestration APIs&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Call GPT from a script to validate MRP output&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Automate prompt evaluation over vendor data&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/need-information-on-different-sap-ai-modules-resources/qaq-p/14148414"/>
    <published>2025-07-09T15:44:37.948000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/can-joule-ai-make-sap-readiness-check-amp-process-insights-smarter/qaq-p/14178894</id>
    <title>Can Joule AI Make SAP Readiness Check &amp; Process Insights Smarter?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-12T18:20:14.608000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TommyB65</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2003338</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m Tommy, an intern at SAP. As part of my internship, I’ve been given the research topic:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "&lt;EM&gt;How to utilise Joule to interpret SAP tools such as Readiness Check and Signavio Process Insights&lt;/EM&gt;"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After discussions with the original topic proposer, I’ve refined this to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "&lt;EM&gt;Leveraging Joule AI for immediate, context-aware interpretation of SAP tools such as Readiness Check and Process&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Insights outputs through integrated or standalone models.&lt;/EM&gt;"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current ideas under exploration:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential role of AI (Joule):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Integrated approach – Joule embedded directly in tools for live Q&amp;amp;A and guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Standalone approach – Central Joule portal where exported tool data is uploaded for AI-generated summaries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Industry &amp;amp; process-specific insights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Could Joule be trained using Signavio Process Explorer as a knowledge source?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer-specific process learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Could Joule learn a customer’s business processes over time to adjust tool benchmark thresholds?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;For example, if a process is flagged as problematic by a benchmark but is actually fine for a specific customer, could&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Joule adapt to avoid false alarms?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m not looking to start a conversation and see if this direction aligns with others’ perspectives and see if anyone has experience in the topic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Would love to hear your thoughts!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/can-joule-ai-make-sap-readiness-check-amp-process-insights-smarter/qaq-p/14178894"/>
    <published>2025-08-12T18:20:14.608000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-business-ai-driving-the-next-wave-of-enterprise-innovation/qaq-p/14182239</id>
    <title>SAP Business AI – Driving the Next Wave of Enterprise Innovation</title>
    <updated>2025-08-17T04:48:19.355000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chandra_reddy1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/271052</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737805072"&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI is no longer a distant concept—it’s transforming how businesses operate today. Generative AI alone is projected to add up to &lt;STRONG&gt;$4.4 trillion&lt;/STRONG&gt; in global productivity within the next five years. For SAP customers, who generate 87% of the world’s commerce, the impact of embedding AI directly into core business processes is both immediate and profound.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Highlights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule – The AI Copilot&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Acts as SAP’s &lt;STRONG&gt;unified front end&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling users to work in natural language.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Delivers context-aware insights, transaction execution, and navigation across SAP apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Boosts efficiency by &lt;STRONG&gt;up to 80%&lt;/STRONG&gt; for employees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Coordinates specialized AI agents for complex tasks (e.g., dispute resolution, sustainability planning).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrates with &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Copilot for Office 365&lt;/STRONG&gt; for seamless cross-platform experiences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded AI – Innovation at Scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI features are built directly into SAP’s cloud solutions (ERP, Supply Chain, HCM, CRM, Procurement, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use cases already improving business outcomes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Henkel&lt;/STRONG&gt; → Faster, data-driven decisions with AI in SAP Analytics Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FC Bayern Munich&lt;/STRONG&gt; → Accelerated recruiting with generative AI in SAP SuccessFactors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gibson&lt;/STRONG&gt; → Boosted email revenue by 50% through AI-powered customer engagement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Over &lt;STRONG&gt;100+ new AI features released in 2024&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with continuous quarterly rollouts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Foundation – Building Custom Solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Part of SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provides developers with reusable AI services, lifecycle management, and access to leading LLMs (OpenAI, Google, AWS, Meta, etc.).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Offers deep integration with SAP HANA Cloud Vector Engine and SAP Knowledge Graph for contextualized business data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enables low-data AI innovation, such as invoice due date predictions or sales order auto-filling .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Responsible AI at SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Commitment to &lt;STRONG&gt;ethics, privacy, and security&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;No partner or third-party models are trained on customer data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI ethics embedded in governance via SAP’s AI Ethics Steering Committee.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Guardrails against misuse, bias, and security risks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alignment with &lt;STRONG&gt;UNESCO AI ethics standards&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;EU AI Act compliance&lt;/STRONG&gt; .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s vision is &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-first and suite-first&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI copilots like Joule will become hyper-personalized.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;More AI-driven automation across finance, HR, supply chain, and sustainability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The future is already here. With SAP Business AI, organizations can run better, innovate faster, and empower people to focus on what truly matters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore more:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/" target="_new" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business AI Feature Catalog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys?page=1&amp;amp;query=artificial+intelligence" target="_new" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learning Journeys&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/sap-business-ai-driving-the-next-wave-of-enterprise-innovation/qaq-p/14182239"/>
    <published>2025-08-17T04:48:19.355000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error/qaq-p/14209413</id>
    <title>Error</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T09:38:22.178000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thakurp</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2252326</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;error&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/error/qaq-p/14209413"/>
    <published>2025-09-06T09:38:22.178000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/finding-sap-note-using-ai/qaq-p/14209415</id>
    <title>Finding SAP Note using AI</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T09:48:14.448000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thakurp</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2252326</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1888339165" id="toc-hId-1888339167"&gt;The Challenge Every Basis Administrator Knows&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’ve worked in SAP Basis, you know the scenario well:&lt;BR /&gt;A transport fails, a short dump appears in ST22, or a background job terminates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The next step?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Hunting through SAP Notes in the Launchpad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This process is often:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Time-consuming, with hundreds of possible Notes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keyword-driven, meaning you need to guess the right search terms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Trial-and-error, as many Notes don’t exactly match the error in your system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result is hours of lost productivity, delayed fixes, and frustrated teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today’s SAP Notes search is powerful, but it depends heavily on manual filtering. Notes can be technical, fragmented, or reference outdated versions of components. Even experienced Basis administrators often spend too much time narrowing down the “right” Note.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, SAP landscapes are becoming more complex, spanning&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA, cloud integrations, DB migrations, and hybrid infrastructures&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This complexity only increases the challenge of quickly mapping system errors to the correct Note.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1691825660" id="toc-hId-1691825662"&gt;Where AI Can Make a Difference&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Natural Language Processing (NLP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;can transform the way we work with SAP Notes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine a system that could:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read your error log automatically&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(from ST22, SM21, STMS, or job logs).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understand the context&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;of the error beyond keywords (e.g., system version, module, DB type).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommend the top 3 SAP Notes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;most relevant to fixing that exact error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learn from history. I&lt;/STRONG&gt;f a Note solved the issue for your team in the past, it would prioritize that next time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This would save Basis teams valuable hours, reduce downtime, and make troubleshooting far more efficient.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1495312155" id="toc-hId-1495312157"&gt;How It Could Work in Practice&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Log Capture&lt;/STRONG&gt;: System errors, dumps, or transport logs are collected (e.g., via Solution Manager or Focused Run).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI/NLP Engine&lt;/STRONG&gt;: An AI model trained on historical SAP error messages and Notes embeddings interprets the log text.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Notes Recommendation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The system suggests a short, ranked list of relevant Notes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feedback Loop&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Administrators confirm whether the suggested Note fixed the issue, improving recommendations over time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach transforms troubleshooting from&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;manual search&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered recommendation&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI-powered Note recommendation is just the beginning. Over time, such a system could evolve into&amp;nbsp;an intelligent assistant that:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Correlates&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP + OS + DB logs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for cross-layer analysis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Validates system refreshes and upgrades by comparing logs before and after.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predicts risks in transports or background jobs before they fail.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This vision aligns with SAP’s own push toward intelligent operations and embedded AI, but with a strong focus on the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Basis layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where today much of the work is still manual.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1298798650" id="toc-hId-1298798652"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;By applying AI and NLP to SAP Notes, Basis teams can move from reactive troubleshooting to proactive, intelligent support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is an area where I believe there is huge potential for innovation, research, and where every Basis professional can benefit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;I’m exploring this further and would love to connect with others interested in AI + Basis.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/finding-sap-note-using-ai/qaq-p/14209415"/>
    <published>2025-09-06T09:48:14.448000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
