<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Artificial-Intelligence-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Artificial Intelligence</title>
  <updated>2025-12-08T12:10:08.826645+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Artificial Intelligence/pd-p/c3c3a408-33ea-4c2a-ae6f-05461e76982d" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Artificial Intelligence blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447</id>
    <title>Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:00:38.750000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndreasKunz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565995"&gt;Flashback: the feature&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a &lt;EM&gt;"making of"&lt;/EM&gt; article about the implementation of the new&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; slash command available within Joule in SAP Build Code. In short, this new feature enables a conversation between AI assistant and application developer about a new freestyle UI5 application to build, with a full-fledged best-practice application starting point as result.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To see screenshots of this feature in action and understand it better, feel invited to read &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445" target="_self"&gt;my previous blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are just here for the background and AI-related learnings—go ahead!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439052490"&gt;General considerations&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;With open‑ended prompting, users aren’t restricted to predefined interactions. The user could ask for &lt;EM&gt;anything&lt;/EM&gt;. In contrast to traditional programming, a prompt input field can’t be handled with a sprawling web of if/else logic trying to cover all possible use-cases. Attempting this will lead to a frustrating user experience where the user often gets an "I do not understand your request".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some developers try to mimic this traditional programming pattern when crafting prompts and contexts for LLMs, telling an LLM "&lt;EM&gt;if the user asks for x, then answer y&lt;/EM&gt;". Instead, as demonstrated below, tell the LLM what it &lt;EM&gt;can&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;cannot&lt;/EM&gt; do and give it a goal to achieve. It's "smart" enough to figure out a suitable response to whatever the user will throw at it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538985"&gt;A fundamental choice&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking at this specific feature in the specific environment, the implementation options on the table were (for a variety of reasons) these two:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Either just provide a system prompt (a prompt that is added behind the scenes in addition to what the user typed) without interfering with the specific prompts and replies entered during the conversation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Or adopt a new way of creating an "agentic" multi-step execution plan. Similar to a guided activity, this would allow phases of data collection, possibly in different steps for different data, then an app creation step and so forth.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Surely "agentic" and "well-defined steps" sound good for app creation from a template, no? In fact, the initial implementation started like this, but it was soon apparent that this would neither provide the expected flexibility nor allow for a truly intelligent app creation experience. Defining phases in which to acquire specific information and having the application code created at a specific stage in this process did not feel right. The user would still feel like clicking through a traditional template creation process, as something specific was expected from the user at every stage, instead of giving the user the freedom to tweak every aspect at every stage. The true power of AI, on the other hand, would be totally underused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But then again... just a system prompt and that's it? No file read access to explore the environment, no dynamically updated instructions? Is this enough for an intelligent coding assistant?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046025480"&gt;Creating an "AI agent" out of nothing&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consider the now common definition of an "AI agent" which has settled over the course of this year: it's nothing more than "&lt;A href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/395657404_An_LLM_Agent_Runs_Tools_in_a_Loop_to_Achieve_a_Goal_A_Comprehensive_Semantic_Framework_for_Defining_AI_Agents_and_Agentic_Systems_by_Simon_Willison_and_Leading_Research_Laboratories" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;an LLM with tools, called in a loop to achieve a goal&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;". The chat conversation provided by Joule can be our loop, an application template with its parameters is the tool and the goal of assisting the developer to create an app can be stated in the system prompt. Of course a real &lt;EM&gt;autonomous&lt;/EM&gt; agent would require the loop to run without user interaction, but for this feature a loop involving the user is just right.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system prompt used for this feature literally includes: "&lt;EM&gt;Y&lt;SPAN&gt;ou help users create new UI5 applications by analyzing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;their requirements and filling the project template parameters. [...]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your goal is to gather all necessary information to create a new UI5 application.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The application will be generated from a template which&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;has only one page and a hardcoded UI, but can optionally display data from an OData V4 service. [...]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You cannot create the application yourself, but the user will see a preview...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;". There you have it: the goal and the tool!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It then goes on with some behavioral hints and of course a detailed description of what exactly the template parameters do. Finally, it requests &lt;EM&gt;each reply&lt;/EM&gt; to contain a JSON object with the best choice of template parameters according to the current understanding of the user request. The JSON object could look like this example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;{&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "appNamespace": "com.myorg.myapp",&lt;/SPAN&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "basePath": "/path/to/workspace",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
   "createAppDirectory": true,&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "framework": "SAPUI5",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "frameworkVersion": "1.136.0",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "author": "John Doe",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "oDataV4Url": "https://services.odata.org/TripPinRESTierService/(S(s5xrj1t51r41s3ooztsynysq))/",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "oDataEntitySet": "Airports",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "entityProperties": ["Name", "Address"],&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "runNpmInstall": true,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "initializeGitRepository": true,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "typescript": true&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;}&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This JSON object is removed from the LLM response before displaying it, then the application is generated with these parameters, so the user can accept it or request changes. In an environment where tools with a well-defined interface like MCP servers are not enabled, this JSON object as part of the conversation is how the integration with the templating tool is achieved. It's basically a use-case-tailored alternative to MCP.&amp;nbsp; A note to make this very clear: this environment is &lt;EM&gt;not&lt;/EM&gt; the official SAP Joule assistant running inside end-user applications, as it is now also being enabled for development by customers. Instead, it is a sort of predecessor implementation specifically available in SAP Build Code since spring 2024 and about to be replaced by advanced solutions. So do not draw conclusions about SAP Joule based on this article.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some of these parameters in the JSON object are more important than others with regards to the user explicitly influencing them or having to accept them. Whether the app code is generated as TypeScript or JavaScript is something the user should not be surprised with &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; accepting the app! On the other hand, the author name, which is only written into package.json, can be reliably defaulted to the logged-in user name and also very easily changed later on if needed. Hence, the parameter descriptions explain not only &lt;EM&gt;what&lt;/EM&gt; they do, but also how much the user should be bothered with them. As result, Joule usually does not even mention half of the parameters, thus keeping the conversation focused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" style="width: 455px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339533i8B53DC0B3A50E913/image-dimensions/455x912/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="455" height="912" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849511975"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to stop the agent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regarding the state &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; the app was accepted, the prompt explains "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AFTER the user has generated the application, you **MUST NOT** continue discussing parameters for generation, but rather [...] i&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;n particular by referring the user to the '/ui5' command for most requests or '/ui5-create-page'&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for adding pages to the app, because they are much better than you in developing features, as they have the capability to automatically select a suitable context of files.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This means the transition in the overall process between refining parameters and "no more changes possible" is not a hardcoded step or denoted by changing the system prompt, but rather explained up-front. That's enough. Can you talk Joule into proposing another set of parameters after the app was accepted? Maybe. But its &lt;EM&gt;normal&lt;/EM&gt; behavior is just right: it will explain that the app can not be created again without restarting the conversation. Nevertheless, there are also non-AI guardrails in place to prevent the app from being generated again, thus causing trouble.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All in all, we shape Joule’s behavior by explaining the templating tool and its limits, by stating the goal and desired behavior towards this goal, and by explaining the general flow, in particular the state after app acceptance. This is enough to guide it to a suitable reaction for whatever the user requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Even if the user insists like this:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" style="width: 457px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339649i5AAFEF728BB75C51/image-dimensions/457x620/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="457" height="620" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-652998470"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Context, context, context!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To make the entire feature really user-friendly, however, it is not sufficient to write a good prompt, but the context must also provide enough information to the LLM to allow for informed decisions. Hence, information like the list of project root files and folders, whether a Git repository is present, plus CAP service/entity/property info, and more, are gathered (e.g. using the &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap-ux/project-access" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@sap-ux/project-access&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;package). This knowledge is provided as prompt context behind the scenes or used in another way (like as content of the suggested prompts). This makes Joule aware of the environment it acts in, leading to better responses, like automatically avoiding app names that would conflict with existing folder names.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agentic coding assistants like Cline, GitHub Copilot, Cursor etc. usually have the ability to read files and execute shell commands as needed to understand their environment. In this pure user request + LLM response environment this might have been a bit harder to build. Basically, more tools could have been defined, e.g. by describing other JSON object structures for invoking them. But control would not so easily return to the LLM until after the user has entered another prompt. Or, there could have been one "preprocessor" LLM request asking for needed files, like it is done for the other&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5*&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;commands.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But for a narrow scenario like app creation this wasn't necessary. Collecting the most relevant information up front not only provides sufficient context, but also improves performance and reliability by avoiding repeated tool calls and unpredictable LLM loops.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-456484965"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In-response prompting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The real-world context, however, changes over time. Specifically, once the app is created and accepted, there are new additional files present.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When developing the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt;, we observed that the agentic AI tool (e.g. Cline) using the MCP server often decided to inspect the new app directory tree after creation, causing several LLM roundtrips which cost time and tokens. Or it would run "npm install" again, even though it had already been executed. Or it would make specific coding errors very often in subsequent modifications. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To avoid this, we extended the response of the MCP server after creating the app. Normally, it contains just the success message. &lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server/blob/a5a06382e0b3b8b39beaf1f40e95f2d887b3b50b/src/tools/create_ui5_app/createSuccessMessage.ts#L30-L66" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;But now it includes&lt;/A&gt; a full list of generated files, it states that "npm install" was already executed and it instructs how to prevent those coding errors. Basically, the MCP server response added further updated instructions to the conversation context. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Exactly the same principle was applied in this new Joule feature. While there is no autonomous agent loop in this case which would inspect the new files, the knowledge &lt;EM&gt;which&lt;/EM&gt; files were created can be valuable for the conversation with the user. And while the&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; command doesn't modify any code after app creation (thus avoiding the coding issues), facts like whether "npm install" was already executed, or whether the created UI5 Table in the MainView is lacking any columns, are useful for giving the user hints how to continue. Therefore, the context is extended by adding a hidden message to the conversation history.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-259971460"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Traditional coding has its place(s)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition to the process of context collection, deterministic coding is also used &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; the app has been accepted by the user for making the app consumption as smooth as possible. When inside a CAP project, it for example ensures that the &lt;EM&gt;cds-plugin-ui5&lt;/EM&gt; is added as dependency. This allows the UI5 tooling, including TypeScript transpilation of the UI5 app when needed, to run as part of the "cds watch" or "npm start" script of the CAP project itself.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Also, this dependency and all the UI5 app dependencies need to be installed. Unfortunately, there is a wide range of options and specific setups which might be used for dependency management in the already existing app. Probably&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;npm&lt;/EM&gt;? With or without workspaces? &lt;EM&gt;yarn&lt;/EM&gt;? &lt;EM&gt;pnpm&lt;/EM&gt;? Others? The code detects what is used and tries to cover the 95% case. The initial setup might not be complete in &lt;EM&gt;every&lt;/EM&gt; scenario, but for most users it will “just work,” providing a good developer experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is fine and all, but sometimes one has to go the extra mile and do some coding.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-63457955"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use deterministic code where reasonable (because the space of possibilities is bounded and a deterministic and quick result is beneficial) .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use LLMs for language understanding or dealing with an unpredictable range of possible requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don't try to "program" the LLM with an if/else prompt, but treat it like an intelligent human: state the goal, options and boundaries—and let it decide on its own.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Provide solid pre-collected context so the LLM can make good decisions reliably.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--133055550"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;P.S.:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For those who prefer graphics over text to gain an understanding of something, here is a depiction of the overall information flow inside this feature.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" style="width: 931px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340805i5BAE698E5DCD6369/image-dimensions/931x498/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="931" height="498" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:00:38.750000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-rpt-1-a-revolutionary-tabular-ml-model-and-owasp-ml-top-10-compliance/ba-p/14270750</id>
    <title>SAP-RPT-1: A Revolutionary Tabular ML Model and OWASP ML Top 10 Compliance</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T09:01:48.703000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AlexDevassy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2158816</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Note: This blog discusses &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;model, the enterprise version of the ConTextTab / SAP-RPT-1-OSS model architecture. The underlying technology is detailed in the &lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.10707" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ConTextTab research paper&lt;/A&gt; published by SAP, with an open-source implementation available as ConTextTab on &lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/SAP/contexttab" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Hugging Face&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/contexttab/tree/main" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765455978"&gt;The Challenge: Traditional Tabular ML's Security Dilemma&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the world of enterprise machine learning, tabular data represents the backbone of business intelligence from customer analytics to financial forecasting. However, traditional tabular ML approaches have long faced a fundamental security challenge: the need for extensive fine-tuning on customer data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When organisations deploy conventional ML models, they must:&lt;BR /&gt;- Fine-tune models using sensitive customer data, permanently modifying model weights&lt;BR /&gt;- Store customer information within model parameters, creating privacy risks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Manage complex security frameworks to protect against data poisoning, model inversion, and membership inference attacks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Navigate compliance requirements while maintaining model performance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This creates a paradox: the more effective the model becomes through fine-tuning, the greater the security risks it introduces.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568942473"&gt;Enter SAP-RPT-1: Redefining Tabular Machine Learning&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501511687"&gt;The Breakthrough: In-Context Learning for Tabular Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1&lt;/A&gt; represents a paradigm shift in tabular machine learning, introducing a revolutionary approach that eliminates the security-performance trade-off entirely. Built on the principle of In-Context Learning (ICL), SAP-RPT-1 achieves state-of-the-art performance without ever modifying its core model weights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304998182"&gt;How SAP-RPT-1 Works: A Security-First Architecture&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unlike traditional models that require fine-tuning, SAP-RPT-1 operates through a fundamentally different mechanism:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer provides data (tables) examples as context&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Model processes examples in real-time without storing or learning from them&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Predictions are made based on patterns identified in the provided context&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer data is immediately discarded after prediction completion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach delivers two critical advantages:&lt;BR /&gt;- Superior performance through semantic understanding of tabular relationships&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Inherent security advantages through its ephemeral processing approach, addressing several traditional ML vulnerability categories. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979401958"&gt;The Technical Innovation: Seven Pillars of Security-by-Design&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 revolutionary approach is built on seven fundamental characteristics that naturally eliminate most machine learning security risks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911971172"&gt;1. Specialized Architecture for Tabular Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 is fundamentally a classification and regression model designed specifically for structured data, not a Large Language Model. This focus makes it subject to the OWASP ML Top 10 security framework rather than LLM-specific vulnerabilities, providing a clearer security assessment pathway.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715457667"&gt;2. In-Context Learning vs. Traditional Fine-Tuning&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The core innovation lies in SAP-RPT-1 learning approach:&lt;BR /&gt;- Traditional Fine-tuning: Permanently modifies model weights using customer data, creating persistent security risks&lt;BR /&gt;- SAP-RPT-1 ICL: Uses customer data as contextual examples within the input, without modifying any model parameters&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Security Advantage: Eliminates risks associated with model weight manipulation and data persistence&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518944162"&gt;3. Enterprise API-First Security Model&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Fully managed API service: SAP handles all infrastructure, security, and model management while customers interact exclusively through secure, authenticated API endpoints&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Enterprise-grade security: Leverages SAP's proven security frameworks and compliance standards to safeguard SAP-RPT-1, while the base architecture remains transparently published through the open-source SAP-RPT-1-OSS version&lt;BR /&gt;- Controlled environment: All predictions occur within SAP's secure infrastructure&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-322430657"&gt;4. Customer Data Dependency as a Security Feature&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 ICL architecture creates an inherent security advantage:&lt;BR /&gt;- No standalone inference: Model requires customer-provided historical examples for every prediction&lt;BR /&gt;- Customer data control: Prediction quality directly depends on customer-provided context&lt;BR /&gt;- Reduced poisoning risk: Traditional attacks like model poisoning and data poisoning become significantly limited&lt;BR /&gt;- Contextual relevance: Model can only make predictions within the scope of provided examples&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-125917152"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;5. Ephemeral Processing Architecture&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every SAP-RPT-1 inference follows a secure, temporary processing model:&lt;BR /&gt;- Memory-only processing: Customer data exists solely during the inference request&lt;BR /&gt;- No weight updates: Model parameters remain completely unchanged throughout operation&lt;BR /&gt;- Zero persistence: No traces of customer information remain in the model&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--145827722"&gt;6. Enterprise-Grade SAP Management&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a SAP-provided service, SAP-RPT-1 &lt;/SPAN&gt;benefits from comprehensive enterprise security controls:&lt;BR /&gt;- Supply chain security: Direct SAP control over model development, training, and distribution&lt;BR /&gt;- Model integrity: Protection against unauthorised modifications and tampering&lt;BR /&gt;- Data governance &amp;amp; compliance: &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt; SAP ensures that all data used to train its Foundation Model follows strict regulations to protect privacy and meet legal standards. SAP has robust security policies to manage data safely when developing its applications.&lt;BR /&gt;- Quality assurance: Professional model validation and continuous security testing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--342341227"&gt;7. Secure Semantic Processing Pipeline&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-RPT-1 employs a mathematically based data processing approach that eliminates code execution risks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All inputs (strings, numbers, dates, etc.) are transformed into embeddings (vector representations of the data), and these embeddings undergo pure mathematical transformations within the model with no code execution occurring during data processing, only mathematical operations on numerical vectors: Inputs (e.g., strings, numbers, dates) → Vector Embeddings → Mathematical Operations → Prediction Result.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Security guarantees:&lt;BR /&gt;- No code execution pathways in data processing&lt;BR /&gt;- Pure mathematical tensor operations throughout the pipeline&lt;BR /&gt;- Semantic understanding without security vulnerabilities&lt;BR /&gt;- Input sanitization through numerical conversion&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--245451725"&gt;SAP-RPT-1 &amp;amp; OWASP ML Top 10 Compliance&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With SAP-RPT-1 architecture established, we can now examine how these design principles address the industry-standard OWASP ML Top 10 security framework. This assessment demonstrates that SAP-RPT-1 innovative approach doesn't just match traditional security measures, it fundamentally eliminates most attack vectors entirely.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--735368237"&gt;SAP RPT-1 &amp;amp; OWASP ML Top 10 Compliance Overview&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;OWASP ML Top 10&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Risk &lt;SPAN&gt;Applicability&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to SAP RPT-1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;Risk Assessment&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;Technical Rationale&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Security Status&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML01: Input Manipulation Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="212px"&gt;Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Minimal exposure due to customer-controlled data model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers provide their own contextual examples, significantly reducing adversarial input scenarios. Risk limited to compromised customer environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="212px"&gt;Customer Managed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML02: Data Poisoning Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="212px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Architecture prevents traditional data poisoning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="212px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;In-Context Learning does not modify model weights. Customer data serves only as contextual input during inference, with no persistent model updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="212px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="165px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML03: Model Inversion Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="165px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="165px"&gt;No sensitive training data to extract&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="165px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer data is ephemeral and not embedded in model weights. No gradient information exposed through API.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="165px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="111px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML04: Membership Inference Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="111px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="111px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP regulated training data eliminates attack vector&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="111px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;No customer data persists in model, eliminating membership inference opportunities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="111px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML05: Model Theft&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP-managed infrastructure prevents model parameter access&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP-RPT-1 is provided and managed within SAP's secure infrastructure. Customers access only the API endpoint, never the model parameters &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Further since customer provided context is not saved in model due to ICL, model theft has no impact on customers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML06: AI Supply Chain Attacks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP as trusted model provider eliminates supply chain risk&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is the official model provider with direct control over development, training, and distribution. No third-party supply chain vulnerabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML07: Transfer Learning Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;No transfer learning in deployment architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In-Context Learning eliminates transfer learning attack vectors entirely..&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML08: Model Skewing &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer data quality responsibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Potential for unintentional bias in customer-provided data. Model leverages &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;patterns present in contextual examples, requiring customer awareness and data curation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Customer Managed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML09: Output Integrity Attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%" height="30px"&gt;Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Standard API security controls apply&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Risk can be mitigated through conventional authentication and authorization mechanisms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%" height="30px"&gt;Customer Managed&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="17.145877378435518%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ML10: Model Poisoning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="13.234672304439746%"&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.025369978858357%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Immutable model architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="32.26215644820296%"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pre-trained model weights remain completely unchanged during operation. Customer data cannot modify base model behaviour or parameters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="11.331923890063425%"&gt;Inherently Protected&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--638478735"&gt;The Results: A New Standard for Secure ML&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1128395247"&gt;SAP-RPT-1 Security Achievement&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The OWASP ML Top 10 compliance reveals SAP-RPT-1 remarkable security profile:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Inherent Protection Against 7 out of 10 Major Threats&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP-RPT-1 In-Context Learning architecture provides built-in protection against most ML security risks. Unlike traditional systems that require extensive security hardening, SAP-RPT-1 design reduces the likelihood of most attack vectors by default.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Standard Controls for Remaining Risks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The three-remaining low-risk areas (Input Manipulation, Model Skewing, and Output Integrity) are addressed through conventional security measures that organisations typically already have in place:&lt;BR /&gt;- Input validation and API security controls&lt;BR /&gt;- Customer data governance&lt;BR /&gt;- Standard authentication and authorization mechanisms&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Empowerment Through Data Control&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Rather than creating security burdens, SAP-RPT-1 empowers customers by giving them direct control over model behaviour through their own data, while eliminating the risks associated with traditional model training.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://owasp.org/www-project-machine-learning-security-top-10/)" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;OWASP ML Security Top 10&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.10707" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1-OSS / ConTextTab Paper&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/SAP/contexttab" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1-OSS / ConTextTab Model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/contexttab/tree/main" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1-OSS / ConTextTab Github&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/tuH8Fj5?h=&amp;amp;ltr=a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP-RPT-1 Model FAQ&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/sap-rpt.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;- Know more on SAP-RPT-1 Model&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-rpt-1-a-revolutionary-tabular-ml-model-and-owasp-ml-top-10-compliance/ba-p/14270750"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T09:01:48.703000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/afsug-amp-sap-a-new-era-of-support-join-our-executive-series-and-onsite/ba-p/14271334</id>
    <title>AFSUG &amp; SAP: A New Era of Support — Join Our Executive Series and Onsite Event in Cape Town</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:53:14.999000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>oliverhuschke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35096</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636399148"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Bildschirmfoto 2025-11-17 um 18.50.41.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342021iCCD8EBA93D8F8328/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Bildschirmfoto 2025-11-17 um 18.50.41.png" alt="Bildschirmfoto 2025-11-17 um 18.50.41.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439885643"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AFSUG &amp;amp; SAP: A New Era of Support — Join Our Executive Series and Onsite Event in Cape Town&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together with AFSUG, the African SAP User Group, SAP’s Customer Support organization is launching a series of high-impact remote sessions — all leading up to an exclusive onsite event in Cape Town in March 2026. This program gives customers a unique opportunity to learn directly from SAP executives and experts, discover the future of support, and experience how AI, automation, and preventative practices are reshaping SAP’s entire support landscape. Whether you want to understand SAP’s proactive support strategy, get hands-on with the latest digital experiences, or explore agentic AI in real customer scenarios — this series is built for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372454857"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Series Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Support has evolved far beyond “break/fix.” Today, it is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A strategic advantage, not an insurance policy&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP customers choose us because we help them run better, scale smarter, and stay ahead.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Preventive and predictive by design&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Programs like Black Friday / Cyber Monday Readiness demonstrate how SAP reduces risk before issues arise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered, human-backed&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agentic AI, prescriptive guidance, and intelligent digital entry points give customers immediate access to insights and the right expertise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded across the entire lifecycle&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support is now a built-in value multiplier — from onboarding to transformation to continuous optimization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer outcomes at the center&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stability, performance, resilience, and continuous improvement aren’t extras — they’re expectations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A blueprint for operationalizing AI&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Customer Support is the frontrunner in adopting agentic AI inside SAP — and showing customers how to scale AI safely and practically in their own environments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join our experts as they unpack these themes in four remote sessions — each one providing unique insights and previews of what awaits at the onsite event in Cape Town.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046858633"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Remote Session Series&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108510566"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. November 27, 2025 — 3–4 PM CET / 4-5 PM SAST&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782914342"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From Reactive to Proactive: How SAP’s Support Strategy &amp;amp; Agentic AI Are Reshaping the Future&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Stefan Steinle, EVP &amp;amp; Head of Customer Support &amp;amp; Cloud Lifecycle Management, SAP SE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Support is shifting from reactive problem-solving to strategic enablement. Stefan Steinle will walk attendees through SAP’s future support strategy — one that is predictive, preventative, and deeply infused with agentic AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;You’ll learn:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How SAP is moving toward proactive and preventative support models&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How agentic AI analyzes telemetry, detects risks, and takes safe autonomous action&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How disciplines from BF/CM Readiness are expanding into daily operations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A live demo on proactive support identifying “Go-Live endangered” situations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A first look at what awaits at the Cape Town onsite event — including Support Accreditation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://afsug.com/product/afsug-sap-vs-from-reactive-to-proactive-how-saps-support-strategy-agentic-ai-are-reshaping-the-future/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt; now to secure your place.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715483556"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. December 11, 2025 — 3–4 PM CET / 4-5 PM SAST&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-389887332"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reinventing Support – Self-Services, Real-Time Assistance &amp;amp; the Power of AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Mohammed Ajouz, SVP &amp;amp; Global Head of Technical Support, SAP Americas&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditional support is being reinvented. Mohammed Ajouz will showcase how SAP delivers intelligent, connected, and customer-centric services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In this session, you’ll explore:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Smarter, always-available self-services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Live channels for real-time engagement&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agentic AI that supports — and acts — on your behalf&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How AI and LLMs transform knowledge, case resolution, and insights&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ll also get a preview of the onsite workshops and simulations — and how to earn the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Support Accreditation Certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Cape Town.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://afsug.com/product/afsug-sap-vs-reinventing-support-self-services-real-time-assistance-the-power-of-ai/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt; now&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;to secure your place&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-322456546"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. January 21, 2026 — 3–4 PM CET / 4-5 PM SAST&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--3139678"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ALM as Your Transformation Execution Platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Sören Ruder, SVP &amp;amp; CPO, Global Head of Customer Experience &amp;amp; Solutions, SAP SE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Transformation succeeds when tools work together — not in silos. This session shows how SAP Cloud ALM unifies processes, architecture, testing, and operations into a single AI-infused orchestration layer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn how Cloud ALM:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Aligns Signavio processes directly with project scope&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Synchronizes landscape models from SAP LeanIX&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Coordinates manual and automated testing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Orchestrates ABAP and non-ABAP change processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uses intelligent event processing to reduce noise and automate remediation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Delivers real-time dashboards with embedded analytics&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sören Ruder will also preview deep-dive workshops happening onsite in Cape Town.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://afsug.com/product/afsug-sap-vs-sap-cloud-alm-as-your-transformation-execution-platform/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt; now for the January session.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--145801833"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. February 26, 2026 — 3–4 PM CET / 4-5 PM SAST&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--48912331"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Front Door Thinking&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Michelle Lewis-Miller, Head of SAP Support Digital Experience &amp;amp; Voice of Customer, SAP SE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every customer journey starts with a digital front door — and SAP is reinventing it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This session includes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Live demos of SAP for Me, the Get Support App, and the SAP Support Portal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Insights into personalization, streamlined access, mobility, and new navigation patterns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The debut of the SAP Support Accreditation Program&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is your best opportunity to get ready for certification onsite in Cape Town.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://afsug.com/product/afsug-sap-vs-intelligent-front-door-thinking-empowering-users-with-sap-for-me-get-support-app-accreditation/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register&lt;/A&gt; now for the February session.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-47977171"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_showing_europe_africa:"&gt;🌍&lt;/span&gt;March 26, 2026 — Onsite in Cape Town, South Africa&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--148536334"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AFSUG &amp;amp; SAP: From Insights to Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;All remote sessions lead to this highly interactive onsite event — bringing together SAP executives, experts, and customers for a full day of hands-on learning, networking, and certification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Onsite Highlights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keynote by Stefan Steinle&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;EM&gt;The Future of Support — Intelligent, Preventive, and Built for the Cloud Era&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multiple expert deep-dives&lt;/STRONG&gt; on:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP for Me &amp;amp; Built-In Support&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Self-Services, Live Channels &amp;amp; AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Preventive Support &amp;amp; Agentic AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Cloud ALM and the Integrated Toolchain&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet-the-Expert stations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct networking with SAP executives&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Support Accreditation — completed onsite with printed certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the moment where everything comes together — strategy, demos, hands-on labs, customer stories, and the opportunity to connect directly with the people shaping the future of support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Registration opens soon — reserve the date now.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--345049839"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Join Us for the Full Journey&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;These remote sessions and the Cape Town onsite event offer an exceptional opportunity to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learn from SAP’s top executives&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See agentic AI in action&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Strengthen your SAP expertise&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Network with industry peers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Earn your official SAP Support Accreditation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Don’t miss your chance to be part of this evolution.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Register for the sessions, mark your calendar for Cape Town — and join us as we shape the next era of SAP Support together.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/afsug-amp-sap-a-new-era-of-support-join-our-executive-series-and-onsite/ba-p/14271334"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:53:14.999000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-2-of-6/ba-p/14271554</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 2 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T09:09:46.257000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>bereitw</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/713212</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" style="width: 760px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342097iB3F1A04EBC22CFFD/image-dimensions/760x208/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="760" height="208" role="button" title="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" alt="bereitw_0-1763451389398.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: How Data, AI, and Agents are Changing Supply Chain Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the discussion about the future of supply chain management, one area is increasingly at the center: planning. Supply chain planning not only affects operational efficiency, but directly influences a company’s service quality, fixed capital and responsiveness. Our joint study from SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University clearly shows that companies that are already planning proactively today can avoid bottlenecks, optimize costs, and exploit potential in a targeted manner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain planning is the central lever for anticipating problems before they arise. Companies that anticipate bottlenecks and proactively manage capacity, inventory and resources avoid hectic “fire fighting” in day-to-day operations. Planning thus acts as an early warning system that not only enables stable service, but also more efficient use of resources and proactive action. Effective planning also requires seamless integration and evaluation of a variety of internal and external data sources – from granular sales data to basic economic data, to production, procurement, and distribution plans. Different planning levels and horizons need to be connected, and this is where there are huge opportunities for artificial intelligence that can process data volumes, identify patterns, and improve predictions. Advanced planning processes will become a matter of course over the next ten years. If you do not achieve at least a modern, integrated planning level by 2035, you risk not only a competitive disadvantage, but also the loss of operational control capability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our survey of supply chain decision-makers (see figure) provides a clear picture of the future. Many expect planning to be much simpler and more intuitive in 2035 than today. More than half expect generative AI and GPT models to have a significant impact on planning processes, and much of it sees data quality as a critical factor in planning decisions. In addition, many expect the breakthrough of new AI-powered forecasting tools that incorporate additional data sources and significantly improve demand planning. Around a quarter expect advanced risk analysis to provide the ability to proactively detect and mitigate disruptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, the status quo shows how big the gap between aspirations and reality is. Only a small number of companies rated their planning as mature in our survey. Similarly, few are actively experimenting with GenAI or GPT applications in the planning environment. Only a minority has very accurate planning data harmonized from different sources. Highly automated demand planning with minimal human intervention is the exception, as are planning systems that provide clear recommendations for action in the event of disruptions. This discrepancy shows that the path to truly modern, intelligent planning is still long and requires targeted investment, clear priorities and structured action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to close this gap, different approaches must be pursued. Companies where planning is a strategic core process or requires very individual processes can realize enormous potential with agent-based AI. With the advent of new agency tools, most repetitive, error-prone work is automated, allowing planners to focus on value-added analytics and decisions. Companies with standardized processes and a low strategic relevance of planning will be able to procure their planning function more as a service in the future. Technology and platform models could enable true end-to-end planning across company boundaries for the first time. Simulations and digital twins will also play a growing role. Although these often fail today due to complexity, modeling effort, and scalability, AI-powered modeling agents could significantly accelerate and improve the accuracy of simulation creation and updates in the future, making their use more practical in larger networks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless of the individual target image, there are measures that every company should tackle immediately (“no-regret moves”). This includes building robust data governance and harmonizing master data as the foundation for any data-driven planning. Unfortunately, the principle of “garbage in, garbage out” also applies with AI: without high-quality data, even the best AI system cannot deliver meaningful value. A consistent, company-wide IBP system enabling a S&amp;amp;OP process provides the basis for a common planning goal. Initial pilot projects with agent-based sales forecasting help gather experience with AI-powered planning approaches. Finally, it is important to actively link existing planning platforms, such as SAP IBP, with AI services to unlock integration potential early on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supply chain planning is now more important than ever and will become a key differentiator between successful companies and those left behind by 2035. The technologies to make planning smarter, faster, and more resilient already exist – but they must be combined with clear goals, a resilient data foundation, and organizational readiness for change. Those who lay the foundations today will not only be able to plan faster and more precisely tomorrow but can also act strategically before others can even react.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342098i554F3BCC37F9CF93/image-dimensions/592x285/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="592" height="285" role="button" title="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" alt="bereitw_1-1763451389405.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure: Results of an online survey of 119 SC managers with people responsibility, conducted on 01/2025 as part of a joint SAP KLU study&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-2-of-6/ba-p/14271554"/>
    <published>2025-11-18T09:09:46.257000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/pioneering-work-on-enhancing-code-reasoning-with-search-and-self-correction/ba-p/14272703</id>
    <title>Pioneering Work on Enhancing Code Reasoning with Search and Self-Correction</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T17:16:23.842000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GraceQin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1465342</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Large language models (LLMs) for code generation and understanding can be boosted by training on search-like reasoning traces and by self-correction mechanisms. Recent work has framed code tasks as iterative decision processes, using fine-tuning or reinforcement learning (RL) to teach models to identify errors and explore alternative solutions. For example, &lt;STRONG&gt;Stream-of-Search (SoS)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tree-of-Thoughts (ToT)&lt;/STRONG&gt; reasoning organizes intermediate “thoughts” into a search tree, allowing LMs to branch on different solution paths and backtrack when needed&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2305.10601v2#:~:text=framework%20for%20language%20model%20inference%2C,or%20search%3A%20Game%20of%2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[1]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03683" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[4]&lt;/A&gt;. As shown in the ToT schematic design, multiple partial solution “thoughts” are generated and evaluated, greatly improving performance on tasks requiring planning or search. Similarly, code models can be trained on annotated search traces, e.g. execution logs or error-flagged drafts, to internalize debugging strategies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765515408"&gt;Our Work&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our team, &lt;STRONG&gt;the Research &amp;amp; Innovation team at Palo Alto led by Yaad Oren and Alexander Schaefer&lt;/STRONG&gt;, collaborate with Dr. Noah Goodman's CoCoLab from &lt;STRONG&gt;Stanford HAI institution&lt;/STRONG&gt;, exploring and bringing the pioneering work on the foundational reasoning capability enhancement of LLMs to SAP. Recently we got one paper accepted by NeurIPS 2025 Foundations of Reasoning workshop, titled by &lt;STRONG&gt;"Smaller Models, Smarter Rewards: A Two-Sided Approach to Process and Outcome Rewards"&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;(&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.23083" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;arxiv link&lt;/A&gt;). The following is our abstract as a teaser:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;Generating high-quality code remains a challenge for Large Language Models (LLMs). For the evolution of reasoning models on this task, reward models are a necessary intermediate step. These models judge outcomes or intermediate steps. Decoder-only transformer models can be turned into reward models by introducing a regression layer and supervised fine-tuning. While it is known that reflection capabilities generally increase with the size of a model, we want to investigate whether state-of-the-art small language models like the Phi-4 family can be turned into usable reward models blending the consideration of process rewards and outcome rewards.&lt;BR /&gt;Targeting this goal, we construct a dataset of code samples with correctness labels derived from the APPS coding challenge benchmark. We then train a value-head model to estimate the success probability of intermediate outputs. Our evaluation shows that small LLMs are capable of serving as effective reward models or code evaluation critics, successfully identifying correct solutions among multiple candidates. Using this critic, we achieve over a 20% improvement in the search capability of the most accurate code out of multiple generations.&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569001903"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372488398"&gt;Supervised Fine-Tuning on Search Traces&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A key idea is to &lt;STRONG&gt;supervise models on entire search trajectories&lt;/STRONG&gt; instead of only correct solutions. For example, Qin et al. train a backtracking model on DFS-generated reasoning traces and a direct model on final solutions&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=strategies%2C%20we%20train%20,outperforms%20the%20direct%20solution%20model" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;. They find this trace-based SFT can bias models into particular strategies: on CountDown puzzles the backtracking model overfits the training search path and underperforms, while on Sudoku it generalizes better. In general, learning from explicit annotated chains-of-thought (CoT) can encourage rich reasoning, but may also lock in suboptimal habits (e.g. verbosity or fixed search biases). Qin et al. show two pitfalls: (1) Prescribed search bias – fixed traces can constrain exploration, and (2) Excessive verbosity – writing out every step can discourage internal reasoning&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=Through%20controlled%20experiments%2C%20we%20identify,Beyond%20these%20factors%2C%20we%20demonstrate" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;. Notably, they observe that reinforcement learning fine-tuning can overcome these issues: a backtracking model fine-tuned with RL discovers new strategies and improves substantially, whereas a direct model improves one-shot accuracy but fares worse under parallel sampling&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=Extending%20beyond%20supervised%20learning%2C%20we,term%20reasoning%20capabilities" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other supervised approaches include synthetically augmenting data with error annotations or ‘hints’. For instance, Sahni et al. train models with error-infused examples (marking lines with potential bugs) to improve debugging&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19055v1#:~:text=manifest%20as%20bugs%20that%20we,describe%20each%20component%20in%20detail" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[3]&lt;/A&gt;. In code repair tasks, models have been fine-tuned on (input, buggy code, fix) triplets to internalize common corrections. However, most of these rely on proprietary data or strong verifiers. Self-contained supervised traces for code are still scarce; researchers often generate them on-the-fly (e.g. solving puzzles to get traces) or use execution feedback.&lt;STRONG&gt; In our work, we also used Claude and Phi to generate similar reasoning hints to augment our training data.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175974893"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-979461388"&gt;Reinforcement Learning for Self-Correction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To leverage dynamic feedback, many recent works use &lt;STRONG&gt;reinforcement learning&lt;/STRONG&gt; on self-generated data. One line of work (e.g. &lt;STRONG&gt;Stream-of-Search&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03683" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[4],&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SCoRe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.12917#:~:text=behavior%20that%20is%20often%20not,model%20to%20generate%20a%20policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[5]&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;CoCoS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.23060v1#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20we%20propose%20an%20online,implementation%20can%20be%20accessed%20at" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[6]&lt;/A&gt;) explicitly frames code generation as a multi-turn Markov decision process where the model can iteratively revise its code. These methods train the code model end-to-end using rewards that encourage fixing mistakes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stream-of-Search (Kanishk et al. 2024)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;proposes a unified search trace design, demonstrated through the game of Countdown. The streams of search logs the state transitions, actions and reward scores when making each computation step in the game. The highlight is that this scoring always considers the impact from different branching choices through &lt;STRONG&gt;backtracking.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Through pre-training a transformer-based language model on streams of search, and then applying further fine-tuning with policy improvement methods led to a significant improvement of correct solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SCoRe (Kumar et al. 2024)&lt;/STRONG&gt; introduces a two-stage RL process for code and math. A base LLM first learns to produce correction traces by iterative self-evaluation (often in multiple turns) and then undergoes &lt;STRONG&gt;policy optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt; using its own feedback. Simply fine-tuning on offline “correction” traces does not work well, so SCoRe employs online PPO with shaped rewards for partial correctness&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.12917#:~:text=first%20show%20that%20variants%20of,correction%20on%20test%20problems.%20SCoRe" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[5]&lt;/A&gt;. They report substantial gains on MATH and HumanEval pass@1 after RL. This shows small LMs can learn to “self-correct” if trained under their own error distribution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CoCoS (Cho et al. 2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt; focuses on small open-source models. They propose an RL fine-tuning objective where each turn’s reward reflects cumulative progress: the model is encouraged to maintain correct outputs and also to improve any incorrect outputs incrementally&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.23060v1#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20we%20propose%20an%20online,implementation%20can%20be%20accessed%20at" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[6]&lt;/A&gt;. Specifically, CoCoS uses an &lt;STRONG&gt;accumulated reward (discounted sum over turns) and a progressive reward&lt;/STRONG&gt; for fine-grained improvements, rather than just binary success. In experiments on MBPP and HumanEval with 1B models, CoCoS yields large improvements over baselines. The authors release code and RL data (on GitHub) enabling reproducibility&lt;A href="https://github.com/jeonghun3572/CoCoS#:~:text=Download%20the%20datasets%3A" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[7]&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RLEF (Gehring et al. 2024)&lt;/STRONG&gt; frames code synthesis as an interactive RL problem. The model repeatedly proposes code, receives &lt;STRONG&gt;execution feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt; (unit test results) as the environment response, and is updated via PPO to maximize passing tests. This end-to-end RL causes models to ground in test feedback rather than ignore it&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2410.02089v2#:~:text=Large%20language%20models%20,time%20behavior" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[8]&lt;/A&gt;. RLEF training on the CodeContests benchmark produces state-of-the-art solve rates with 8B and 70B models, while drastically reducing the number of samplings needed. Critically, RLEF models learn to adapt code based on errors – e.g. using caches or fixing off-by-one errors – without human hints. The gains generalize: after RLEF, models also improve on HumanEval+ and MBPP+ by leveraging feedback.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Satori (Shen et al. 2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt; combines supervised format-tuning with RL. It first imitates a “Chain-of-Action-Thought” (COAT) format by training on synthetic multi-agent demonstrations, teaching the model to use special tokens like &amp;lt;|reflect|&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;|explore|&amp;gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori#:~:text=%2A%20Chain,action%20tokens%20to%20guide%20reasoning" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[9]&lt;/A&gt;. Then it applies RL with a &lt;STRONG&gt;Restart-and-Explore (RAE)&lt;/STRONG&gt; strategy: the model is periodically reset to intermediate states (including failed ones) and trained to explore new branches, with rewards for eventual correctness and penalties for repeating mistakes&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori#:~:text=2.%20Self,RL" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[9]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.18458v2#:~:text=Similarly%2C%20Satori%C2%A0%5B351%5D%20introduces%20Chain,Llama8B" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[10]&lt;/A&gt;. The final 7B Satori model (based on Qwen) achieves SOTA on challenging math reasoning tasks, showing that an LLM can “internalize search”&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori#:~:text=1,Imitation%20Learning" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[9]&lt;/A&gt;. The full Satori code, model checkpoints, and RL data (including rollouts from RAE) are publicly released for community use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These RL methods set examples for online self-improvement: the model generates its own traces (code attempts, feedback, or self-reflections), evaluates them via an automatic reward (tests or proxy reward models), and uses that to update its policy. In all cases, models get reward signals across multiple turns – for example, RLEF only awards a final reward but uses intermediate test feedback as observations, while CoCoS and SCoRe explicitly shape rewards at each revision step. This multi-turn RL contrasts with one-off prompting: the model learns that reflecting on errors and branching can yield higher expected reward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782947883"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-586434378"&gt;Empirical Gains and Benchmarks&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Overall, trace-based training and self-correction in the mentioned work yield significant empirical improvements across diverse benchmarks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Coding tasks&lt;/STRONG&gt;: HumanEval/HumanEval+&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.03374" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[11]&lt;/A&gt;, APPS[&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09938" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;12&lt;/A&gt;], TACO&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14852" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[13]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mathematical reasoning&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Sudoku&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=strategies%2C%20we%20train%20,outperforms%20the%20direct%20solution%20model" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;. MATH-500&lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/datasets/HuggingFaceH4/MATH-500" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[15],&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;GSM8K&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.14168" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[16]&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, results also reveal nuances and limitations. The “backtracking vs direct” study shows that task structure matters: on some problems (CountDown) naive backtracking hurt performance&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=Through%20controlled%20experiments%2C%20we%20identify,Beyond%20these%20factors%2C%20we%20demonstrate" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;. Many methods still rely on test or verifier oracles (e.g. to score branches), which will invalid this whole method when such oracles don’t exist. Also, RL training can be sample-inefficient and sensitive to reward hacking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-389920873"&gt;Discussion and Outlook&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Annotating search and correction steps enables deep reasoning in code LMs, but challenges remain. Key gaps include robust reward design, scaling to very large models, and generalizing for tasks with unclear oracles. Most existing methods focus on code generation. We hope future work in the community would apply more effort on code understanding (e.g. program analysis, code review, translation, documentation). It is also important to study the trade-offs: extensive backtracking can be quadratically expensive, and some tasks favor direct answering. Moreover, as the “when to backtrack” analysis shows&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=Through%20controlled%20experiments%2C%20we%20identify,Beyond%20these%20factors%2C%20we%20demonstrate" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&lt;/A&gt;, blindly encouraging self-correction is not always beneficial.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nonetheless, models that learn from their own mistakes via annotated traces or RL often outperform “single shot” models. By combining supervision with tree-based reasoning traces through RL, systems can achieve autoregressive search capabilities without human prompts&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori#:~:text=%2A%20Chain,action%20tokens%20to%20guide%20reasoning" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[9]&lt;/A&gt;. Overall, these advances point toward autonomous code agents that can plan, check, and correct – closing the gap toward human-like programming workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-193407368"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2305.10601v2#:~:text=framework%20for%20language%20model%20inference%2C,or%20search%3A%20Game%20of%2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[1]&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Tree of Thoughts: Deliberate Problem Solving with Large Language Models&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2305.10601v2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2305.10601v2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1#:~:text=strategies%2C%20we%20train%20,outperforms%20the%20direct%20solution%20model" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[2]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;To Backtrack or Not to Backtrack: When Sequential Search Limits Model Reasoning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/html/2504.07052v1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19055v1#:~:text=manifest%20as%20bugs%20that%20we,describe%20each%20component%20in%20detail" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[3]&lt;/A&gt; Effective Large Language Model Debugging with Best-first Tree Search&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19055v1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19055v1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03683" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[4]&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Stream of Search (SoS): Learning to Search in Language&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03683" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03683&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.12917" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[5]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;Training Language Models to Self-Correct via Reinforcement Learning&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.12917" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.12917&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.23060v1#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20we%20propose%20an%20online,implementation%20can%20be%20accessed%20at" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[6]&lt;/A&gt; Self-Correcting Code Generation Using Small Language Models&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.23060v1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/html/2505.23060v1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/jeonghun3572/CoCoS#:~:text=Download%20the%20datasets%3A" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[7]&lt;/A&gt; GitHub - jeonghun3572/CoCoS: This is the official implementation of the paper "Self-Correcting Code Generation Using Small Language Models"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/jeonghun3572/CoCoS" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/jeonghun3572/CoCoS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2410.02089v2#:~:text=Large%20language%20models%20,time%20behavior" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[8]&lt;/A&gt; [2410.02089] RLEF: Grounding Code LLMs in Execution Feedback with Reinforcement Learning&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2410.02089v2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://ar5iv.labs.arxiv.org/html/2410.02089v2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori#:~:text=%2A%20Chain,action%20tokens%20to%20guide%20reasoning" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[9]&lt;/A&gt; GitHub - satori-reasoning/Satori: [ICML 2025] Satori: Reinforcement Learning with Chain-of-Action-Thought Enhances LLM Reasoning via Autoregressive Search&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://github.com/satori-reasoning/Satori&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.18458v2#:~:text=Similarly%2C%20Satori%C2%A0%5B351%5D%20introduces%20Chain,Llama8B" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[10]&lt;/A&gt; Data × LLM: From Principles to Practices&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2505.18458v2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/html/2505.18458v2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.03374" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[11]&lt;/A&gt; Evaluating Large Language Models Trained on Code&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.03374" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.03374&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09938" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;12&lt;/A&gt;]&amp;nbsp;Measuring Coding Challenge Competence With APPS&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09938" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09938&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14852" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[13]&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;TACO: Topics in Algorithmic COde generation dataset&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14852" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14852&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.06770" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[14]&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;SWE-bench: Can Language Models Resolve Real-World GitHub Issues?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.06770" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.06770&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/datasets/HuggingFaceH4/MATH-500" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[15]&lt;/A&gt; MATH-500&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/datasets/HuggingFaceH4/MATH-500" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://huggingface.co/datasets/HuggingFaceH4/MATH-500&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.14168" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;[16]&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Training Verifiers to Solve Math Word Problems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.14168" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.14168&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/pioneering-work-on-enhancing-code-reasoning-with-search-and-self-correction/ba-p/14272703"/>
    <published>2025-11-19T17:16:23.842000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-rpt-1-context-model-vs-training-classical-models-the-models-battle/ba-p/14268507</id>
    <title>SAP RPT-1 Context Model vs. Training Classical Models: The Models Battle (Python Hands-on)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T07:50:27.670000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nicolasestevan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1198632</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764768715"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":collision:"&gt;💥&lt;/span&gt;The Models Battle&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_5-1763206328497.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341535i2A2C9A98D24BF43B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_5-1763206328497.png" alt="nicolasestevan_5-1763206328497.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predictive modeling is becoming a built-in capability across SAP, improving how teams handle forecasting, pricing, and planning. &lt;STRONG&gt;Many SAP professionals, however, aren’t machine-learning specialists&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and traditional models often demand extensive setup, tuning, and repeated training, which slows down new ideas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; offers a simpler path. It’s a pretrained model from SAP, also available in an OSS version, that lets developers and consultants produce predictions with far less technical effort, no deep ML background required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've explored SAP RPT-1 hands-on, comparing it with traditional regressors using Python and a real public vehicles price dataset.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goal:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To see (as a non Data Scientist) how &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; behaves in practice, what advantages and limits it shows, and when it could make sense in a predictive scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Usually for real-world scenario, the right approach would be consume the SAP RPT-1 though the available and simplified API, but for studies proposal and fair comparision over othe traditional ML models, the &lt;STRONG&gt;OSS&lt;/STRONG&gt; fits perfectly for it:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568255210"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thinking_face:"&gt;🤔&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP RPT-1 vs Traditional Machine Learning - Core Differences&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into the code, let’s quickly revisit how&lt;STRONG&gt; traditional ML&lt;/STRONG&gt; models work:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Training-based models like Random Forest, LightGBM, and Linear Regression learn patterns directly from data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;They require hundreds or thousands of examples to tune their internal parameters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Their performance depends heavily on data quantity and quality.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The more relevant examples they see, the smarter they get.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the other hand, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 f&lt;/STRONG&gt;ollows a different philosophy. It’s part of the RPT (Representational Predictive Transformer) family, pretrained on a wide variety of business and contextual data. This means:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You don’t "train" it in the traditional sense. Instead, it uses context embeddings to predict outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It can be used immediately, even with smaller datasets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The OSS version allows developers to experiment directly in Python.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No special SAP backend required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Outcome:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Traditional ML models learn from high amount of data. SAP RPT-1 already knows how to deal with small context amount of data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371741705"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":desktop_computer:"&gt;🖥&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;The Experiment - Setup &amp;amp; Dataset&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-container"&gt;&lt;a class="lia-spoiler-link" href="#" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Spoiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;noscript&gt; (Highlight to read)&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-border"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-content"&gt;Don't worry on "playing puzzles" copying + pasting code below. The full version is available for download at end!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-container"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-content"&gt;Don't worry on "playing puzzles" copying + pasting code below. The full version is available for download at end!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make this comparison tangible, I built a simple yet realistic Python experiment to predict vehicle selling prices using a public dataset containing car attributes like make, model, year, transmission, and mileage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why vehicle pricing? Because it’s an intuitive example where both traditional machine learning and pretrained AI models can be applie, and it helps visualize how prediction quality evolves as the sample size grows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This entire analysis runs on a local Python environment&amp;nbsp;with the following stack:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import os
import gc
import warnings
import pandas as pd
import numpy as np
import matplotlib.pyplot as plt
from datetime import datetime
from sklearn.model_selection import train_test_split
from sklearn.metrics import r2_score
from sklearn.ensemble import RandomForestRegressor
from sklearn.preprocessing import LabelEncoder
from sklearn.linear_model import LinearRegression
from sap_rpt_oss import SAP_RPT_OSS_Regressor
import lightgbm as lgb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;pandas&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;numpy&lt;/STRONG&gt; for data manipulation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/STRONG&gt; for classical ML regressors (R&lt;STRONG&gt;andom Forest, Linear Regression&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;LightGBM&lt;/STRONG&gt; for gradient &lt;STRONG&gt;boosting&lt;/STRONG&gt; comparison&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;sap_rpt_oss&lt;/STRONG&gt; — the open-source Python version of &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP’s RPT-1 model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;matplotlib&lt;/STRONG&gt; for all &lt;STRONG&gt;visualizations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 OSS &lt;/STRONG&gt;can be downloaded installed following official Hugging Face:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://huggingface.co/SAP/sap-rpt-1-oss?library=sap-rpt-1-oss" href="https://huggingface.co/SAP/sap-rpt-1-oss?library=sap-rpt-1-oss" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://huggingface.co/SAP/sap-rpt-1-oss?library=sap-rpt-1-oss&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;. Python can be installed with executable download on Windows, or via &lt;STRONG&gt;Home Brew&lt;/STRONG&gt; for Mac and &lt;STRONG&gt;apt&lt;/STRONG&gt; commands for Linux. Libraries dependencies can be downloaded with &lt;STRONG&gt;pip&lt;/STRONG&gt; commands. Googling it may not be a road blocker.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;We use a sample&amp;nbsp;vehicle sales dataset. The complete file is about to 88Mb but for such experiment a restricted sample of 20k as it's more than enough to prove our the concept, still it's faster and consuming less computing resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="498px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;year&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Vehicle model year&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;make&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Brand (e.g., Toyota, Ford, BMW)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;model&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Specific model name&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;body&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Type (SUV, Sedan, etc.)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;transmission&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Gear type&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;odometer&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Vehicle mileage&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;color&lt;/CODE&gt;, &lt;CODE&gt;interior&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Visual attributes&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;sellingprice&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;The target variable to predict&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Dataset Download:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/syedanwarafridi/vehicle-sales-data?resource=download" href="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/syedanwarafridi/vehicle-sales-data?resource=download" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/syedanwarafridi/vehicle-sales-data?resource=download&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The dataset is loaded and preprocessed in a few simple steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;df = pd.read_csv("car_prices.csv").sample(n=20000, random_state=42)

# Fill missing values for categorical columns
fill_defaults = {
    'make': 'Other', 'model': 'Other', 'color': 'Other',
    'interior': 'Unknown', 'body': 'Unknown', 'transmission': 'Unknown'
}
for col, val in fill_defaults.items():
    df[col] = df[col].fillna(val)

X = df[["year", "make", "model", "body", "transmission", "odometer", "color", "interior"]]
y = df["sellingprice"]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this point, the stage is set:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The data is clean.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The environment is ready.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All models, traditionals and SAP RPT-1, are ready to be tested under identical conditions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175228200"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Training the Models - Three different ones&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the dataset ready, the &lt;STRONG&gt;next step&lt;/STRONG&gt; is to run each model under the same conditions: &lt;STRONG&gt;same features, same target, same train/test split and same random seed&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This ensures the comparison is fair and repeatable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We evaluate prediction performance using &lt;STRONG&gt;R² (coefficient of determination)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which indicates how much of the price variation the model can explain (1.0 = perfect prediction).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107797414"&gt;Training Model #1 - Random Forest&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Random Forest is often the first model used in tabular ML. It works by creating &lt;STRONG&gt;many decision trees&lt;/STRONG&gt; and averaging their predictions. Before training, categorical variables need to be &lt;STRONG&gt;label-encoded&lt;/STRONG&gt; into numbers, a common requirement for classical ML models:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_random_forest(X, y):
    X = X.copy()
    cat_cols = ["make", "model", "body", "transmission", "color", "interior"]
    le = LabelEncoder()

    for col in cat_cols:
        X[col] = le.fit_transform(X[col].astype(str).fillna("Unknown"))

    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = RandomForestRegressor(
        n_estimators=150, max_depth=20, random_state=42, n_jobs=-1
    )

    try:
        model.fit(X_train, y_train)
        preds = model.predict(X_test)
        r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)
    except Exception as e:
        preds, r2 = np.zeros_like(y_test), 0

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911283909"&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_3-1763206176248.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341502i82216AA724092E03/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_3-1763206176248.png" alt="nicolasestevan_3-1763206176248.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714770404"&gt;Up to 7067 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_8-1763206511155.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341538iF2A25E0C0EBE0612/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_8-1763206511155.png" alt="nicolasestevan_8-1763206511155.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518256899"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="RandomForest_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341551i3A2C874AFAF47388/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="RandomForest_20251115_092355.gif" alt="RandomForest_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-321743394"&gt;Training Model #2 - LightGBM&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;LightGBM is one of the most powerful models for tabular data. Unlike Random Forest (many independent trees), LightGBM builds trees &lt;STRONG&gt;sequentially&lt;/STRONG&gt;, each correcting the errors of the previous one. It supports categorical features natively, which simplifies preprocessing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_lightgbm(X, y):
    X = X.copy()
    cat_cols = ["make", "model", "body", "transmission", "color", "interior"]
    for col in cat_cols:
        X[col] = X[col].astype(str).fillna("Unknown").astype("category")

    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = lgb.LGBMRegressor(
        n_estimators=500, learning_rate=0.05, num_leaves=31,
        subsample=0.8, colsample_bytree=0.8, random_state=42
    )

    try:
        model.fit(X_train, y_train, categorical_feature=cat_cols)
        preds = model.predict(X_test)
        r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)
    except Exception:
        preds, r2 = np.zeros_like(y_test), 0

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-125229889"&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_2-1763205951324.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341474i1AAB214E2D01C2B2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_2-1763205951324.png" alt="nicolasestevan_2-1763205951324.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--146514985"&gt;Up to 7067 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_7-1763206474860.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341537i0ACD453B96C87ADF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_7-1763206474860.png" alt="nicolasestevan_7-1763206474860.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--343028490"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="LightGBM_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341552i30BC4DE94C4988F6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="LightGBM_20251115_092355.gif" alt="LightGBM_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--539541995"&gt;Training Model #3 - Linear Regression&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not fancy and even not complex, Linear Regression provides a baseline that shows:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;“If the relationship between attributes and price is roughly linear, how well can a simple model perform?”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_linear_model(X, y):
    X = X.copy()
    cat_cols = ["make", "model", "body", "transmission", "color", "interior"]
    for col in cat_cols:
        X[col] = LabelEncoder().fit_transform(X[col].astype(str).fillna("Unknown"))

    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = LinearRegression()
    X_train = X_train.fillna(X_train.mean(numeric_only=True))
    X_test = X_test.fillna(X_test.mean(numeric_only=True))

    try:
        model.fit(X_train, y_train)
        preds = model.predict(X_test)
        r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)
    except Exception:
        preds, r2 = np.zeros_like(y_test), 0

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--736055500"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_1-1763205857765.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341472i81AFB2D0BE770F90/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_1-1763205857765.png" alt="nicolasestevan_1-1763205857765.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--932569005"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 7067 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_6-1763206428099.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341536iC708165AEAE11D46/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_6-1763206428099.png" alt="nicolasestevan_6-1763206428099.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1129082510"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="LinearModel_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341553i0849B4C842A417EE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="LinearModel_20251115_092355.gif" alt="LinearModel_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1032193008"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chequered_flag:"&gt;🏁&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP RPT-1 OSS: Context Model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where things get interesting. SAP RPT-1 does &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; rely on learning patterns from the dataset. Instead, it uses a pretrained transformer architecture to infer relationships directly through &lt;STRONG&gt;context embeddings&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Lean and simple, "for non-Data Science PhD":&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_sap_rpt1(X, y):
    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = SAP_RPT_OSS_Regressor(max_context_size=8192, bagging=8)
    model.fit(X_train, y_train)

    preds = model.predict(X_test)
    r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1522109520"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_0-1763205729558.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341471i4AC7007DCA5A0F76/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_0-1763205729558.png" alt="nicolasestevan_0-1763205729558.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1718623025"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 2055 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_4-1763206228416.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341505i9ADE9D2D2B38C363/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_4-1763206228416.png" alt="nicolasestevan_4-1763206228416.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1915136530"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SAP_RPT1_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341566i0BE0E0D666836951/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP_RPT1_20251115_092355.gif" alt="SAP_RPT1_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1650063337"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Running Experiments at Multiple Sample Sizes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section breaks down how the iterative experiment loop works, why the SAP RPT-1 OSS model has a max-context limit, and how performance changes as we scale up the dataset. By running the same models across several sample sizes, we can see where traditional ML shines, where RPT-1 stays competitive, and how both behave as the data grows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;sample_sizes = np.linspace(50, len(X), 200, dtype=int)
results, max_r2_rpt1, max_sample_rpt1 = [], 0, 0

for n in sample_sizes:
    idx = np.random.choice(len(X), n, replace=False)
    X_sample, y_sample = X.iloc[idx], y.iloc[idx]


    # SAP RPT-1 OSS (limited sample size)
    if n &amp;lt;= rpt1_limit:
        rpt_res = train_sap_rpt1(X_sample, y_sample)
        fn = plot_predictions(rpt_res[2], rpt_res[0], rpt_res[1], "SAP_RPT1", n)
        video_frames["SAP_RPT1"].append(fn)
        r2_rpt1 = rpt_res[1]
        max_r2_rpt1 = max(max_r2_rpt1, r2_rpt1)
    else:
        r2_rpt1 = max_r2_rpt1
        if max_sample_rpt1 == 0:
            max_sample_rpt1 = n

    # Train and plot models
    rf_res = train_random_forest(X_sample, y_sample)
    fn = plot_predictions(rf_res[2], rf_res[0], rf_res[1], "RandomForest", n)
    video_frames["RandomForest"].append(fn)

    lgb_res = train_lightgbm(X_sample, y_sample)
    fn = plot_predictions(lgb_res[2], lgb_res[0], lgb_res[1], "LightGBM", n)
    video_frames["LightGBM"].append(fn)

    lin_res = train_linear_model(X_sample, y_sample)
    fn = plot_predictions(lin_res[2], lin_res[0], lin_res[1], "LinearModel", n)
    video_frames["LinearModel"].append(fn)

    results.append((n, rf_res[1], r2_rpt1, lgb_res[1], lin_res[1]))

    # Early stop if traditional model reaches SAP RPT-1
    if rf_res[1] &amp;gt;= max_r2_rpt1 or lgb_res[1] &amp;gt;= max_r2_rpt1 or lin_res[1] &amp;gt;= max_r2_rpt1:
        break
    gc.collect()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This loop compares SAP RPT-1 OSS with traditional ML models as sample sizes increase. Each iteration randomly selects a subset of the data and trains all models on the same slice for a fair comparison. SAP RPT-1 can only run up to its max-context limit, so once the sample size exceeds that threshold, it stops retraining and simply carries forward its best R². The traditional models continue training at every step. The loop ends early when any traditional model matches or surpasses RPT-1’s best score, making the experiment efficient while showing how performance evolves as data grows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1846576842"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":end_arrow:"&gt;🔚&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Conclusion and Final Thoughts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP RPT-1 OSS stands out because it performs well with small datasets, requires minimal code, and can generate useful predictions with just an API call and a bit of context. This makes it ideal for jump-starting predictive use cases early on, delivering fast business value without a full ML pipeline. Traditional models, however, still shine when projects mature, data grows, and fine-tuned control becomes important. It’s not about choosing one over the other, but understanding where each approach brings the most value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aspect&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 OSS&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Traditional ML (RF, LGBM, Linear)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Data Requirements&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Low (performs well with small samples)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Medium/High (performance scales with data&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Setup Effort&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Minimal (API call + context)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Higher (preprocessing, encoding, tuning)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Training Process&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;None (pretrained context model)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Full training pipeline required&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Speed to Insights&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Very fast&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Moderate to slow&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Best Use Case&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Early-stage predictive cases, quick baselines&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Mature pipelines, high control and customization&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Flexibility&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Limited tuning / plug-and-play&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Highly customizable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Business Value&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Immediate, fast, accessible&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Strong when optimized and scaled&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;This experiment highlights a simple truth: &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 isn’t here to replace traditional ML, it jump-starts it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;With a pretrained, context-driven approach, RPT-1 delivers fast, reliable insights with very little data and almost no setup. Traditional models still excel in mature, data-rich scenarios, but RPT-1 shines as a rapid accelerator and early-value generator inside SAP landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1958473942"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt;Open for Exchange&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you're testing RPT-1, exploring predictive cases, or want the full code, feel free to reach out.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Happy to connect, compare experiences, and push this topic forward together.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-rpt-1-context-model-vs-training-classical-models-the-models-battle/ba-p/14268507"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T07:50:27.670000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/keep-the-blue-side-up-building-trust-in-ai-through-transparency-responsible/ba-p/14269929</id>
    <title>Keep the blue side up: Building trust in AI through transparency (Responsible AI blogpost series)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T16:01:34.302000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BettinaLaugwitz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/176876</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764802414"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="277483_277483_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341246i23A9003A522ED815/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="277483_277483_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" alt="277483_277483_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568288909"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flying has been a dream of humankind&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for ages, and how it can be achieved has tickled the minds of many visionaries and engineers. Part of the fascination is the possibility that humans push boundaries of what is physically possible. But physical laws are still in place, and accidents end fatally when something goes wrong, due to heights of dozens or thousands of meters or speeds needed for starts and landings. How much risk is the dream worth taking?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On December 17, 1903, Orville Wright conducted his historic flight with an airplane successfully. Just a few days earlier, Orville and his brother Wilbur had crashed in a test flight – one of the first documented aviation accidents in history.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today, many decades later, &lt;STRONG&gt;using aircrafts is considered one of the safest travel options&lt;/STRONG&gt; (measured by distance traveled &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aviation_safety" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aviation_safety&lt;/A&gt;) – thanks to curious engineers, learnings from accidents and incidents, scientific progress, publication of relevant regulations and industry standards, and of course an ever-attentive approach to safety and security checks and improvements. We can trust planes to be safe – not per se (the owl Archimedes has a point here &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KLI46yMdtmU" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KLI46yMdtmU&lt;/A&gt;) but because we have found ways to make them safe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;fascination for machines that work similarly to the human mind&lt;/STRONG&gt; has been around for ages. The potential of Artificial Intelligence (AI) for adding efficiency, creativity, and inspiration to persons’ lives is immense. The nature of the technology brings also specific risks and can be scary: machines that reason and learn imply a loss of human control – a challenge that is not only (science) fiction (&lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HAL_9000" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;HAL 9000&lt;/A&gt; being just one example; for more see e. g. &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence_in_fiction" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence_in_fiction&lt;/A&gt;) but reality (e. g. &lt;A href="https://www.aiaaic.org/aiaaic-repository" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AIAAIC Incident Repository&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://github.com/daviddao/awful-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Awful AI List&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://incidentdatabase.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://incidentdatabase.ai/&lt;/A&gt; ).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Artificial intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; has still a long way until it can be considered a matured technology which is as safe as air traffic has become. When it comes to AI today and going forward, we definitely want to &lt;STRONG&gt;trust, but verify&lt;/STRONG&gt;: what are the implications when implementing a specific AI system; what is the system doing and why; in case of incidents: what was causing the issue; etc. Iteratively improving technical standards and procedural governance, considering ethical and legal requirements, will enhance safety for people, environment, and society going forward. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every framework that discusses how to make AI systems safe for usage includes a section that has to do with &lt;STRONG&gt;transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt;, including the &lt;A href="https://www.unesco.org/en/artificial-intelligence/recommendation-ethics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UNESCO Recommendation&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the Ethics of AI&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html?pdf-asset=940c6047-1c7d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff&amp;amp;page=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP’s Guiding Principles&lt;/STRONG&gt; for Artificial Intelligence&lt;/A&gt;, or the &lt;A href="https://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/dae/document.cfm?doc_id=60419" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Ethics Guidelines for Trustworthy AI by the High Level Expert Group on Artificial Intelligence set up by the &lt;STRONG&gt;European Commission&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; (HLEG AI Ethics Guidelines). &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to the HLEG AI Ethics Guidelines, “[t]rustworthy AI has &lt;STRONG&gt;three components&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which should be met throughout the system's entire life cycle: (1) it should be &lt;STRONG&gt;lawful&lt;/STRONG&gt;, complying with all applicable laws and regulations (2) it should be &lt;STRONG&gt;ethical&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring adherence to ethical principles and values, and (3) it should be &lt;STRONG&gt;robust&lt;/STRONG&gt;, both from a technical and social perspective.” Transparency requirements play a role in all three components, so let’s use these angles to have a closer look.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371775404"&gt;Lawful: Transparency requirements in regulatory and legal areas&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the 1920s, barnstorming and so-called flying circuses were very popular: stunt shows with daredevil pilots and acrobats executing spectacular and risky maneuvers with the plane (loopings etc.) and on the plane (wing walking). Early legislation related to civil air transportation addressed the most common causes of fatal accidents, including lack of pilot qualification and stunt practices that put the spectators’ lives at risk. Over the years, laws were passed, updated, and complemented which intended to improve aviation safety and with that, the trust of the public in the technology, with the &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_government_role_in_civil_aviation#Air_Commerce_Act" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Air Commerce Act&lt;/A&gt;, issued in 1926, as an early example, and the &lt;A href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/reg_impl/2025/920/oj" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) 2025/920&lt;/A&gt; for sure not the last.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Defining and implementing regulation for technologies is inherently slower than the subject it is supposed to regulate. In the context of AI, luckily some laws that provide important guardrails to protect individuals have been in place for some time, &lt;SPAN&gt;or &lt;A href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB853" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The California AI Transparency Act AB 853&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; are examples of regulation which targets the specific risks and challenges related to AI. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Individuals and legal entities have a need and partly also (will have) a &lt;STRONG&gt;right to transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt; when it comes to decisions and AI; valid questions of stakeholders include: Which role does AI play in a decision that may &lt;STRONG&gt;affect my life&lt;/STRONG&gt; going forward, and am I okay with that? Can I make an informed decision when I give &lt;STRONG&gt;consent&lt;/STRONG&gt; to using an AI system as an individual? Do I have the transparency I need to &lt;STRONG&gt;diagnose&lt;/STRONG&gt; the functioning / malfunctioning of an AI system, so that we can &lt;STRONG&gt;learn from issues&lt;/STRONG&gt; and fix them going forward? How can &lt;STRONG&gt;Terms &amp;amp; Conditions&lt;/STRONG&gt; help understand scope and limitations of AI systems?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175261899"&gt;Robust: Making AI systems secure and robust&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Aircrafts are subject to thorough inspection based on sophisticated protocols that prove their respective &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Airworthiness" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;airworthiness&lt;/A&gt; before they are permitted to operate. Insights from past incidents, e. g. through &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flight_recorder" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Flight Recorder&lt;/A&gt; data, are an important resource of input for improvements of hardware, software, or procedures, to help prevent future damage and harm.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Software systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; need to be reliable in the sense that they work as designed and the potential risks related to their usage are minimized. &lt;STRONG&gt;Quality management&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;software&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;security &lt;/STRONG&gt;efforts and &lt;STRONG&gt;governance&lt;/STRONG&gt; in general play a critical role when creating robust software. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The same applies to the development of&lt;STRONG&gt; AI systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;, plus some extra aspects that have to do with the specific nature of those systems, in particular when they involve &lt;STRONG&gt;machine learning&lt;/STRONG&gt; capabilities or are generating output &lt;STRONG&gt;autonomously&lt;/STRONG&gt; (for definitions / distinctions of AI / ML / genAI / Agentic AI see e. g. the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/03/7211ee96-647e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI Ethics Handbook&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What role does transparency play? For example, without transparency, testing AI system robustness and reliability are a critical challenge. At the same time, we are speaking of &lt;STRONG&gt;‘black box’ systems&lt;/STRONG&gt; – how can we even understand what is going on in the system and if that is what we expect in terms of reliability, security and safety?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security testing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; of AI systems should not only look at the outcome or effect, but ideally have a certain level of insight in the processes and methods inside the system to identify root causes and potential &lt;STRONG&gt;systematic threats&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &lt;STRONG&gt;Benchmarking&lt;/STRONG&gt; of models or AI systems help understand / ‘diagnose’ the quality and reliability and trigger mitigation as needed, runtime &lt;STRONG&gt;monitoring and traceability&lt;/STRONG&gt; help prevent unintended and unwanted shifts in an AI system’s performance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Software companies can leverage guidelines and recommendations (e. g. &lt;A href="https://owasp.org/www-project-ai-testing-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OWASP AI Testing Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;), applicable industry standards (i.e &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso:9001:ed-5:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ISO 9001 Quality Management System&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso-iec:27001:ed-3:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ISO/IEC 27001 Security Management System&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;), and adjust and complement according to the specifics of e. g. the industry or the regional context. Documenting the &lt;STRONG&gt;compliance&lt;/STRONG&gt; with relevant standards, including &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;NIST AI Risk Management Framework RMF&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso-iec:42001:ed-1:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ISO/IEC 42001 AI Management Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, helps build trust in the responsible development of AI systems in customers (see e. g. the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Trust Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) and the general public. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978748394"&gt;Ethical: Human oversight&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;How come airplane engineers invent seatbelts for pilots and passengers, and why was there an affordance to adjust law and regulation to reduce accidents and harm related to air traffic? Costs related to damages and injuries may have played a role, but without doubt also: empathy and ethical considerations. Situations where people lose loved ones, suffer from severe injury or face damages to their property are something to be avoided, and there is a strong motivation to reduce risks leading to them and to strengthen the public’s &lt;STRONG&gt;trust in the technology and its operation&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, there are AI-related legal requirements for transparency, and technical robustness is a prerequisite for AI systems that can be trusted. Relying on current or upcoming (known) regulation only when working on AI safety is not a sustainable approach: Technology is evolving too fast to allow regulatory processes to keep up and put legal boundaries in place. Thinking only in terms of current rules and potential gaps between them will turn legally compliant innovation into a ‘jigsaw puzzle with moving parts’: Legal gaps you designed for may be closing in due course, and every new regulation poses a threat to the products in the portfolio or on the roadmap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The ethical perspective on the other hand changes the focus from legal texts and fear of being sued, towards the vision to what we want the technology to do and what needs to be avoided. AI Ethics principles help &lt;STRONG&gt;inform legislation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but also provide &lt;STRONG&gt;guidance for technical innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Not just do what is feasible, but think what is acceptable and desirable going forward&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, for us as individuals, for us as a company, and for us as a society. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One example: The &lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HLEG AI Ethics Guidelines&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; name &lt;STRONG&gt;fairness&lt;/STRONG&gt; as an &lt;STRONG&gt;ethical imperative for trustworthy AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; as early as&lt;STRONG&gt; 2016&lt;/STRONG&gt;. SAP committed to fairness in the Guiding Principles for the Ethics of AI in &lt;STRONG&gt;2018&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The &lt;STRONG&gt;EU AI Act&lt;/STRONG&gt; entered into force in 2024, with certain provisions applying immediately and others phased in over time, reaching full applicability by &lt;STRONG&gt;2027&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Given the risks related to AI, we want to ensure that &lt;STRONG&gt;humans&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;control AI systems as needed, and not the other way around&lt;/STRONG&gt;. A prerequisite to ensure human agency and oversight: Transparency. You can’t control what you don’t know or understand. Measures like &lt;STRONG&gt;explainability&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;interpretability&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;traceability&lt;/STRONG&gt; are required to allow humans in their respective capacity and interaction with AI systems to stay in control, acquire knowledge, and gain &lt;STRONG&gt;trust&lt;/STRONG&gt; and confidence that the AI is &lt;STRONG&gt;not creating any harm&lt;/STRONG&gt;, neither to the &lt;STRONG&gt;individual&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;society&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;,&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; nor &lt;STRONG&gt;environment&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782234889"&gt;Different perspectives on transparency for responsible AI&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The blogpost series will take the perspective of &lt;STRONG&gt;different stakeholders in the lifecycle of AI systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;, including those who are “designing, developing, deploying, implementing, using or being affected by AI” (&lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;HLEG AI Ethics Guidelines&lt;/A&gt;). SAP experts will shed light on different aspects and approaches, from a &lt;STRONG&gt;legal&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a&lt;STRONG&gt; technical&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or an&lt;STRONG&gt; ethical &lt;/STRONG&gt;viewpoint, providing insights into challenges and solutions, considering &lt;STRONG&gt;organizational practices&lt;/STRONG&gt; as well as &lt;STRONG&gt;user needs &lt;/STRONG&gt;and &lt;STRONG&gt;customer expectations&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Examples from &lt;STRONG&gt;real SAP use cases&lt;/STRONG&gt; will illustrate the practical relevance and the efforts SAP is taking to build AI systems responsibly and create transparency so that stakeholders are enabled and empowered to understand risks and benefits, and execute on human oversight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blogpost will be updated with references whenever a new post is available to make it easy to get notified and find the information you are interested in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-585721384"&gt;Closing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When on an airplane, in most situations you would want to know that the skies are above you and the ground is beneath you (exceptions include flying circuses, see above). In any case, at least the pilot should know about the current orientation of the aircraft, even if weather conditions are blocking the sight of the actual surroundings. If the physical horizon is not visible, the attitude indicator, an instrument mimicking the blue skies above an artificial horizon and a brown ground below, will help adjust the plane’s orientation. &lt;STRONG&gt;Blue side up&lt;/STRONG&gt;, brown side down means that the plane is not going astray, neither upwards nor downwards – a means to keep orientation and an &lt;STRONG&gt;indicator of aviation safety&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We trust airplanes not because they are perfect and unbreakable. But because we know about their challenges, weaknesses, what to check, what to look at, how to optimize human-machine collaboration. And we have found ways to surface the information that is needed – by pilots, by engineers, by passengers, or in other words: leverage transparency to foster safety.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Meaningful transparency is ‘in the eye of the beholder’. Its design needs a human-centered approach to provide just the right angle, level, and amount of information that is relevant and helpful for individuals to interpret the situation, to “&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;make sense, or derive meaning, from a given stimulus […] so that the human can make a decision”&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; (&lt;A href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2021/NIST.IR.8367.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Broniatowski, 2021&lt;/A&gt;) – a prerequisite for human oversight and trustworthy AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="295087_GettyImages-95757310_medium_jpg.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/343645i5F0DF1C8D73EB027/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="295087_GettyImages-95757310_medium_jpg.jpg" alt="295087_GettyImages-95757310_medium_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let us share how &lt;STRONG&gt;AI transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt; helps &lt;STRONG&gt;keep_the_blue_side_up&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned for the next post of the series about&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Engineering AI Transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-260125160"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-63611655"&gt;References and further readings&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--3819131"&gt;Responsible AI challenges&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.aiaaic.org/aiaaic-repository" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AIAAIC Incident Repository&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/daviddao/awful-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Awful AI List&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://incidentdatabase.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://incidentdatabase.ai/&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence_in_fiction" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence_in_fiction&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-146921721"&gt;Responsible AI guidelines&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;UNESCO Recommendation on the Ethics of AI: &lt;A href="https://www.unesco.org/en/articles/recommendation-ethics-artificial-intelligence" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.unesco.org/en/articles/recommendation-ethics-artificial-intelligence&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Guiding Principles for AI Ethics / Policy / Handbook: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;HLEG on Artificial Intelligence (European Commission) – Ethics Guidelines for Trustworthy AI: &lt;A href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/ethics-guidelines-trustworthy-ai&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--49591784"&gt;Lawful&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;General Data Protection Regulation GDPR &lt;A href="https://gdpr.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://gdpr.eu/&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;European Union Artificial Intelligence Act (EU AI Act): &lt;A href="https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/ai-act-explorer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/ai-act-explorer/&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AB-853 California AI Transparency Act: &lt;A href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB853" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB853&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--246105289"&gt;Robust&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso:9001:ed-5:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ISO 9001 Quality Management System&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso-iec:27001:ed-3:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ISO/IEC 27001 Security Management System&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#iso:std:iso-iec:42001:ed-1:v1:en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ISO/IEC 42001 AI Management Systems&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OWASP &lt;A href="https://owasp.org/www-project-ai-testing-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://owasp.org/www-project-ai-testing-guide/&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://owaspai.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://owaspai.org/&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;NIST AI RMF &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Trust Center: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--442618794"&gt;Ethical&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Guiding Principles for AI Ethics / Policy / Handbook: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Understandability blog post: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/trustworthy-ai-how-to-make-artificial-intelligence-understandable/ba-p/13576857" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/trustworthy-ai-how-to-make-artificial-intelligence-understandable/ba-p/13576857&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Broniatowski, D. A. (2021): Psychology of Explainability and Interpretability. &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2021/NIST.IR.8367.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt;https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2021/NIST.IR.8367.pdf&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/keep-the-blue-side-up-building-trust-in-ai-through-transparency-responsible/ba-p/14269929"/>
    <published>2025-11-21T16:01:34.302000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-industrial-manufacturing-blog-posts/sap-cloud-erp-as-fundamental-part-of-sap-business-suite-for-industrial/ba-p/14258161</id>
    <title>SAP Cloud ERP as fundamental part of SAP Business Suite for Industrial Manufacturing (2508 Release)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-25T04:05:50.160000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nico_Dahl</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1433541</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763841530"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introduction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Industrial manufacturing is at a crossroads. The industry faces mounting pressures from global market shifts, technological advancements, and the imperative to operate more sustainably. At the same time, new opportunities are emerging for those ready to embrace change. As the industry evolves, the ability to adapt quickly, innovate continuously, and build resilient operations has become essential. This post explores how SAP Cloud ERP as part of SAP Business Suite is enabling industrial manufacturers navigate this transformation, drawing on the latest insights from our industry update with the 2508 release.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Watch the full recording here: &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/industrial-manufacturing-industry-update-pet-h2-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Industrial Manufacturing Industry Update - PET H2 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567328025"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Evolving Landscape of Industrial Manufacturing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Industrial manufacturing companies are defined by their ability to transform raw materials into finished goods at scale, serving a wide range of markets from household appliances to heavy equipment. Many organizations operate across several industry subsegments, often as a result of mergers and acquisitions, which adds complexity to their operations and increases the demands placed on their ERP systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today’s manufacturers are not only expected to deliver high-quality products efficiently but also to manage increasingly complex supply chains, comply with evolving regulations, and respond to rapid changes in customer demand. The need for robust, flexible, and integrated business systems has never been greater.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370814520"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Challenges and Industry Trends&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recent industry studies and ongoing engagement with customers have highlighted several persistent challenges. Business growth remains a top priority, with manufacturers seeking to attract new customers and enter new markets. However, legacy systems often lack the capabilities needed to support new business models or the localization required for global expansion. Supply chain resilience is another critical concern. Manufacturers are striving to build closer relationships with suppliers and gain deeper visibility into their supply chains, but many lack the systems to enable real-time insights or to streamline the onboarding of new partners.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Operational efficiency is also under pressure. Companies are looking to maximize the effectiveness of both machines and workforce, often through automation and upskilling. Yet, manual processes and limited visibility into production capacity can hinder progress. Finally, technology adoption remains a challenge. Many manufacturers are still reliant on inflexible legacy systems, with data locked away in silos and not easily accessible for business decision-making. The transition to cloud-based, data-driven operations is essential for unlocking new value and staying competitive with the help of AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174301015"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP’s Approach: Building the Intelligent, Sustainable Enterprise&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Cloud ERP is designed to address these challenges head-on. The solution provides a strong foundation for industrial manufacturers, offering pre-configured, ready-to-run, end-to-end scenarios that can be deployed quickly and adapted as business needs evolve. Integration with SAP Business Technology Platform and a broad ecosystem of SAP and Partner solutions ensures that customers can support their unique processes while benefiting from continuous innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A key strength of SAP’s approach is its support for both headquarter scenarios and subsidiaries through two-tier ERP models. This enables organizations to maintain strict governance and standardization at the corporate level while allowing subsidiaries the flexibility to operate in ways that best suit their local markets or distinct business models.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977787510"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;End-to-End Scenarios for Modern Manufacturing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Cloud ERP supports a wide range of manufacturing archetypes, each tailored to the specific needs of different industry segments. E.g. for component manufacturers, make-to-stock scenarios enable efficient production planning, procurement, and sales from inventory. Machinery manufacturers benefit from assemble-to-order and configure-to-order processes, which provide the flexibility to meet individual customer requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;End-to-end scenarios are designed to span the entire industrial manufacturing value chain, from idea to market, source to pay, plan to fulfill, and lead to cash. By connecting every part of the business, manufacturers gain greater visibility, control, and the ability to respond quickly to changing conditions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781274005"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Innovations in the SAP Cloud ERP 2508 Release&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The latest release of SAP Cloud ERP brings several important enhancements for industrial manufacturers. In production planning and execution, the capacity scheduling board introduces activity coloring, allowing production planners to distinguish between setup, production, and teardown times at a glance. This provides clearer insights into operations and helps optimize resource utilization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_1cb6ppu9" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Component availability checks have also been added to the capacity scheduling table, enabling planners to verify that all necessary parts are on stock before scheduling production orders, thus reducing the risk of costly delays.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_k3t51ak9" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-Assisted Processing of Incoming Quality Certificates with SAP Document AI automatically processes incoming quality certificate documents. By leveraging SAP Document AI on BTP, the data extraction and automatic attachment of certificates to relevant receipts become a hassle-free reality. This allows to handle certificates more efficiently and helps ensure that nothing is lost or overlooked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_8iqjpmzs" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In sales management, SAP’s AI copilot, Joule, can now handle expiring prices, automate renewals, and identify fulfillment issues in sales orders, helping sales teams work more efficiently and proactively.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_hobyopp3" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Advanced Variant Configuration capabilities have also been enhanced. Multi-level bills of materials can now be downloaded for easier comparison, and configurations can be imported from sales documents for reuse, streamlining the process of managing complex product variants.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_y3oac71z" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_y14d5m35" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584760500"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer Success Stories: Real-World Impact&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The value of SAP Cloud ERP is best illustrated through the experiences of leading industrial manufacturers. &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/07/8ecec030-147f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DINE Inc.&lt;/A&gt;, a South Korean manufacturer specializing in high-precision machining tools, faced challenges with an outdated ERP system that hindered digital transformation and data reliability. By implementing SAP Cloud ERP, DINE achieved unified accounting management across global operations, standardized workflows, and enhanced data visibility. The results included a doubling of profit and loss analysis accuracy, a 1.5-fold increase in inventory turnover rate, and a 10% reduction in spare parts inventory value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2025/09/0cb9afb9-1f7f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Tetra Pak eBeam Systems AG&lt;/A&gt;, headquartered in Switzerland, sought to modernize operations after being acquired by Tetra Pak in 2020. By adopting SAP Cloud ERP and leveraging the SAP Activate methodology, the company reduced upgrade preparation time from eight hours to two, improved user experience, and enabled IT resources to focus on strategic initiatives.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Other customers, such as &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/H1GJdct?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=68&amp;amp;doi=SAP1117756" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Acceleron&lt;/A&gt; and Ferrotec, have also realized significant benefits. Acceleron consolidated more than 20 ERP systems into a single global business foundation in the cloud, enabling unified processes across 40 countries. &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2024/10/f0cffe1d-e07e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Ferrotec Manufacturing Malaysia Sdn. Bhd.&lt;/A&gt; improved finance team productivity by 40%, procurement efficiency by 90%, and reduced supply chain costs by half.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-388246995"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Takeaways for Industrial Manufacturers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The journey to becoming an agile, intelligent, and sustainable enterprise is both challenging and rewarding. SAP Cloud ERP serves as a catalyst for transformation, enabling manufacturers to adapt quickly, streamline operations, and unlock new business models. Artificial intelligence and automation are driving efficiency and resilience, reducing manual effort and empowering teams to make better decisions. Integrated, end-to-end processes ensure that every part of the business is connected, delivering greater visibility and control.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Perhaps most importantly, the experiences of leading manufacturers demonstrate real world impact and measurable value. From improved operational efficiency to enhanced compliance and accelerated growth, SAP Cloud ERP is helping organizations to future-proof their businesses for continuous growth and thrive in a rapidly changing world.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-191733490"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conclusion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Industrial manufacturing is evolving at an unprecedented pace. The path to sustainable growth and long-term success lies in embracing digital transformation and building resilient, data-driven operations. SAP Cloud ERP and the entire SAP Business Suite continues to evolve with innovations which empowers manufacturers to meet today’s challenges and seize tomorrow’s opportunities. By working together with SAP, we can deliver exceptional value and shape the future of industrial manufacturing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information on how SAP can support your transformation journey, we invite you to connect with our team or visit our website: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/industries/industrial-manufacturing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Industrial Manufacturing Industry Software | SAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4780015"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Want to know more?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bert Schulze shared the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/highlights-of-the-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-release/ba-p/14163726" target="_blank"&gt;Highlights of the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release&lt;/A&gt;, my colleague Markus Oertelt shared what’s new in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/manufacturing-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14161093" target="_blank"&gt;Manufacturing in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508&lt;/A&gt; and my colleague Leonie Peterka has written the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/quality-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14167949" target="_blank"&gt;Quality Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;blog post. Here you will find even more innovations for industrial manufacturers and other businesses.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-industrial-manufacturing-blog-posts/sap-cloud-erp-as-fundamental-part-of-sap-business-suite-for-industrial/ba-p/14258161"/>
    <published>2025-11-25T04:05:50.160000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-3-of-6/ba-p/14277803</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 3 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T09:13:17.706000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marcus_mock</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/304566</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345278i64BEF6314EEBDD8F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" alt="marcus_mock_0-1764144277642.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: Is Artificial Intelligence Determining Future Purchasing?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The third part of the joint study by SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University on the supply chain of the future deals with purchasing. We do not assume the future of purchasing looks the same for all companies. Rather, key trends and key technologies play a big role. Their impact varies greatly depending on the industry and business model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The shaping trends for purchasing (as well as for the other parts of the supply chain) include the global economic situation and geopolitical tensions, the growing importance of sustainability, the scarcity of raw materials, and the changes for the people involved. These issues are not new, but they will play a major role in the coming years and will sometimes become even bigger.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key technologies are in the focus, e.g. integrated transactional purchasing applications with new semantic data models, AI agents, AI-based data analyses, and insights from the evaluation of information from business networks. Artificial intelligence is not the only driving technology but will become increasingly relevant in the coming years. No process in modern purchasing organizations will remain unaffected by its influence. Against this background, purchasing organizations have to work out which trends and technologies are particularly important for their company to plan the path to a successful future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The study conducted an online survey of 174 supply chain managers with people responsibility (April 2025). There was a clear discrepancy between ambitious visions for the future and the sad reality. On the one hand, 28% of respondents expected purchasing managers to play an important role in shaping corporate strategy and security of supply in 2035, while 31% expected buying organizations to achieve significantly better AI-driven outcomes with high quality data. On the other hand, only 12% say that procurement in their organization is now fully integrated into C-level decision-making, and only 3% think AI-powered purchasing analytics are great today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How should this discrepancy be dealt with? And how to deal with the uncertainty of every look into the future? The clear recommendation for all purchasing organizations is to do their homework first, to take decisions and to perform a couple of no-regret moves. It is clear that only purchasing organizations following these five important points are optimally positioned for the coming years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Firstly, clearly defined strategies and responsible people are in place for the most important categories and sub-categories. These category strategies must be kept up to date in suitable applications instead of gathering dust in presentations stored on shared drives. The strategies will be the trigger for activities, and the focal point for monitoring the progress of the activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Secondly, the operating model of the purchasing organization must be optimized by shifting personnel capacities from administrative activities to value-adding tasks. The goal is to work with a small but highly skilled workforce.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Third, clearly defined and standardized processes are required that exist in Business Process Model and Notation (BPMN) notation and are mapped in a process management solution, not a drawing tool. On this basis, simulations and comparisons of as-is and to-be can be carried out. Also, the processes can be linked to business requirements, test cases, application documentation, driving AI based automation in these related activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fourth, modern purchasing applications should be used to support end-to-end processes, without media breaks and with a steadily growing degree of automation. An end-to-end flow of data and information is essential. Specifications and prices belong into the apps themselves, not in file attachments. These pieces of information are critical parts of the data that drives AI. Similarly, the apps must be integrated so data is not transferred manually or via bots.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fifth, all relevant data from various procurement apps and third-party data must be available for analysis. The key is that this data is available on an appropriate platform and mapped to a semantic model. This is the only way to get an overview of the entire purchasing process, to derive in-depth insights and to drive more AI use cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The last point is of particular importance. Only if data on purchasing processes is available in structured form, across all purchasing processes, in good quality, will the purchasing organization have a solid basis for using AI functionalities of any kind, especially AI-driven analytics and AI agents, which can take on complex tasks on their own.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI agents sound a bit like science fiction for many persons in the procurement space – that is why the figure below outlines an agentic AI scenario in strategic procurement. The CPO sets a task for a procurement orchestration agent which in turn sets tasks for other, more specialized procurement agents (e.g. spend analysis, sourcing activities, contract creation) to achieve an overall goal, the optimization of a specific sub-category.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly, all other parties involved in the purchasing processes can be supported. Requestors can interact with an operational purchasing agents to quickly and clearly describe their needs. That operational purchasing agent reaches out to other agents leveraging existing contracts or catalogs, adhering to all purchasing guidelines, and covering topics such as account assignment, tax determination, and transportation costs. With the help of their own agents, suppliers will find it easy to participate in complex tenders, bid in Dutch or Japanese auctions, negotiate and sign contracts, and provide price lists and catalogs in specific formats to the purchasing organization. Since suppliers will use their own AI agents, there will be an increasing frequency of interaction between multiple agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, it can be said that those purchasing organizations will be optimally positioned for the future, who correctly classify the relevance of future trends and technologies to their own business, and who conclude the five no-regret moves mentioned above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345277iDB02DA211AADEFBC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" alt="marcus_mock_1-1764144277645.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure: AI agents implement a complex task in purchasing&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-3-of-6/ba-p/14277803"/>
    <published>2025-11-26T09:13:17.706000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/proactive-monitoring-that-integrates-retail-operations-in-a-data-driven/ba-p/14278750</id>
    <title>Proactive Monitoring that Integrates Retail Operations in a Data-driven World</title>
    <updated>2025-11-27T10:02:09.087000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JeaneFerreira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1759223</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Imagine a global retailer preparing for the holiday season, a time when system stability is paramount. In previous years, unexpected disruptions caused delays and customer dissatisfaction. This year, things are different. By implementing proactive monitoring powered by AI and Collective Intelligence, the retailer identified early signals of potential issues weeks before peak demand. This story exemplifies how proactive monitoring transforms support from reactive firefighting to predictive prevention.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2023859744"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Proactive Monitoring Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Proactive monitoring reduces escalations, improves customer confidence, and optimizes operations. Instead of waiting for incidents to occur, we anticipate them, ensuring uninterrupted business continuity. For example, during the Holiday Season Readiness Program, proactive monitoring helped SAP support teams detect anomalies in critical systems, preventing potential outages for major e-commerce customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1827346239"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How It Works&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The process begins with comprehensive data collection—telemetry from cloud systems, business process data, and historical case patterns. AI-driven algorithms then analyze these inputs to recognize patterns and correlate events. When anomalies are detected, automated workflows trigger alerts and initiate Preventive Customer Risk Mitigation actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1630832734"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Breaking Data Silos&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Success depends on breaking down data silos. Only by building a Collective Intelligence framework—where insights from global case data, configuration logs, and usage analytics converge—can this model be scaled across the entire customer base. As data needs to be used collaboratively, data sharing enables an environment where information is accessible in a timely manner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1434319229"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Among the benefits of proactive monitoring, they can range from faster root cause analysis to reduced mean time to resolution. The first refers to the process of identification of causes and reasons for an issue taking place, and the latter concerns the measurement of how quickly a system responds to a failure once it is recognized. Both play a part in refining the customer experience through invisible, but automated support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="JeaneFerreira_0-1764233626580.png" style="width: 706px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345763i03DC1DFD8A84FD58/image-dimensions/706x381/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="706" height="381" role="button" title="JeaneFerreira_0-1764233626580.png" alt="JeaneFerreira_0-1764233626580.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the proactive monitoring strategy anchored in AI, retailers can turn their peak shopping seasons from difficult periods into opportunities for improving customer engagement and operational resilience. A continued adoption of AI-driven capabilities is what will enable smarter planning and sustainable data-driven growth. strategic AI adoption and thoughtful implementation will drive retail excellence in an increasingly digital and data-driven world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;A special thanks to SAP experts Bharath Ramamurthy, Vice President of Strategic Initiatives, Customer Support, and Kartikaye Gomber, AI Solution Architect, for their contributions to this article.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/proactive-monitoring-that-integrates-retail-operations-in-a-data-driven/ba-p/14278750"/>
    <published>2025-11-27T10:02:09.087000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/to-the-left-to-the-left-setting-businesses-up-for-irreplaceable-success/ba-p/14278775</id>
    <title>To the Left, To the Left: Setting Businesses Up for Irreplaceable Success</title>
    <updated>2025-11-27T10:19:37.439000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JeaneFerreira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1759223</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Consider a scenario where a critical update is scheduled for a financial services customer ahead of a major fiscal event. Traditionally, risks would surface post-deployment, leading to costly escalations. That is where a shift to the left walks into the stage: as the testing and detection steps are moved earlier into the lifecycle, an eventual delay in release is avoided, as well as the increase in costs associated with fixings issues. In other words, shifting to left is like reserving the seat in the first rows for testing!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At first glance, it may appear that risks are put in the spotlight, much like nominees at an award show. However, in reality, this approach aims at reducing them. Early recognition of potential issues enables development teams to allocate more time to data cleansing and preparation, tasks that typically consume a significant part of their efforts. This proactive approach allows for more focus on generating valuable insights rather than dealing with escalations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2023859811"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Does Shift Left Mean?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shift Left involves moving risk detection and mitigation earlier in the lifecycle. This approach reduces downstream support costs and enhances customer satisfaction. During the Holiday Season Readiness Program, Shift Left strategies ensured that preventive controls were in place well before peak transaction periods. These strategies included:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementing Preventive Customer Risk Mitigation workflows for early alerts and automated case creation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrating with Cloud ALM for lifecycle event monitoring&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Defining governance models for clear ownership of risk mitigation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1827346306"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Predictive Intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predictive intelligence uses Collective Intelligence to aggregate insights from global case data and apply AI models for event-to-issue correlation. This enables proactive actions that prevent disruptions before they impact customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1630832801"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Breaking Data Silos for Scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Scaling this model requires dismantling data silos. By pooling insights across teams and regions, we create a unified intelligence network capable of supporting our entire customer base efficiently. With reliable data through the software deployment process, customers can make well-informed decisions at all stages of their businesses, that could lead to better budget management likewise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1434319296"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This method is aligned with SAP’s vision for an effortless customer experience. It reduces escalations and downtime while improving operational efficiency. By incorporating recurrent tests at every step of the development process, the system is continuously reviewed and adjusted as needed. Just as filming involves many behind-the-scenes teams, a shift to the left ensures that the backstage engines are aware and constantly prepared for the result that customers witness.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In conclusion, the Shift Left approach changes traditional development and deployment processes by proactively addressing risks and issues earlier in the lifecycle. When customers operate their businesses smoothly and stay well-prepared, we join forces to lay the foundation for lasting success and sustained trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;A sincere thank you to SAP experts Bharath Ramamurthy, Vice President of Strategic Initiatives, Customer Support, and Kartikaye Gomber, AI Solution Architect, for their contributions to this article&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/to-the-left-to-the-left-setting-businesses-up-for-irreplaceable-success/ba-p/14278775"/>
    <published>2025-11-27T10:19:37.439000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/skills-architecture-playbook-10-design-decisions-with-talent-intelligence/ba-p/14275531</id>
    <title>Skills Architecture Playbook: 10 Design Decisions with Talent Intelligence Hub that Define Success !</title>
    <updated>2025-11-30T03:13:30.857000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RinkyKarthik</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/19490</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The shift towards a skills-based workforce is picking up speed, and this transformation lives or dies on one thing: your skills architecture, the foundation that defines:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;how skills are structured,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;how they are governed,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;how they flow through your HRtech landscape, and&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;how employees, managers, and admins actually experience them.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s happening -&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;Most organizations jump straight into “skills projects” without stopping to define the design decisions that truly matter!&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;I have seen SAP SuccessFactors customers engaging with different HRTech or Skills vendors separately, rather than as a coherent group. The result? Duplicate skills across systems, messy job profiles, confused employees, frustrated managers, and governance models held together with duct tape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think of this blog as your Skills Architecture Playbook: the 10 decisions every company must get right to build a clean, future-proof foundation with &lt;STRONG&gt;Talent Intelligence Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;. These decisions will shape everything from AI models and inference reliability to employee growth journeys and manager adoption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re implementing TIH, planning a Skills Transformation, or just trying to bring order to the skills chaos, this guide is for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s get into the decisions that define your success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765602950"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;Leading Practice Skills Architecture with Talent Intelligence Hub&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s a leading practice approach for designing a Skills Architecture with TIH at its core. Open Skills Ecosystem (OSE) partners help augment and complement customers' internal data, creating a high-quality skills foundation that brings together market skills data, job and work insights, and people attributes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once standardized in Talent Intelligence Hub and enriched with employee and organizational master data from SuccessFactors, this unified skills intelligence can be delivered through Career and Talent Development (CTD) as the experience layer for every persona -employees, managers, HR, recruiters, and leaders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1827254883"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;I had shared this diagram in my session at SuccessConnect and have further explained it in my podcast. Give it a listen -&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;&lt;A title="Art of the Possible - Episode 1 - Skills-based Transformation - Talent Alchemy Podcast series" href="http://&amp;nbsp;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z7yFfZXGwec&amp;amp;t=864s&amp;nbsp;" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Art of the Possible - Episode 1 - Skills-based Transformation - Talent Alchemy Podcast series&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;This is how you bring a skills-based transformation concept to life.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Skills Arch diagram.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344662i61D058FDAC04F584/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Skills Arch diagram.png" alt="Skills Arch diagram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1372575940"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Choose Your System of Record: Where Does Job &amp;amp; Skills Truth Live?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Everything starts with a single question:&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where does the truth sit?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For job architecture and skills governance, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Talent Intelligence Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; should be your system of record and governance layer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s how it breaks down:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TIH + JPB = Your Master Foundation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Job Families&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Job Roles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Job Profiles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Skills Library&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Skills tagged to roles and profiles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;JPB&lt;/STRONG&gt; holds your job architecture.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Open Skills Ecosystem partners&lt;/STRONG&gt; enrich your skills library.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TIH&lt;/STRONG&gt; governs and standardizes everything.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get this foundation right, and the rest of your skills strategy becomes infinitely easier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176062435"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Standardize Skills in the Attributes Library with AI Skills Standardization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you know where the truth lives, the next step is: &lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What does that truth look like?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Attributes Library&lt;/STRONG&gt; in TIH is your governance layer for all skills master data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It helps you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintain a clean, unified skills library.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Standardizes the Skills data into one common language.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manage lifecycle states (active, deprecated, standardized)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Standardize proficiency scales&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your Open Skills Ecosystem partner sends business- and industry-relevant skill data &lt;EM&gt;into&lt;/EM&gt; TIH, where you standardize it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This avoids:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Duplicate skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confusing naming conventions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Skill inflation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Random “HR-created” one-off skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is your quality control engine.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1237714368"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;Check out my&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/rinkykarthik_new-segment-alchemy-bits-bytes-2h-activity-7397488637870874624-Y0Vg?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;amp;rcm=ACoAAADZ4I8Bk_dQ_vToHYD2zCLPIpLudIp9MQU" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Talent Alchemy Bits and Bytes&lt;/A&gt; &lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;segment, where I talked about Skills Standardization.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-783035425"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Decide How Skills Will Be Validated&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If there’s one thing employees love, it’s adding skills. If there’s one thing managers love… It’s being skeptical of those skills.&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validation matters!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You need to decide:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who validates the skills?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Employee?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manager?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Or does it depend on the skill type?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s the sequence?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Employee declares → Manager approves&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manager nominates → Employee confirms&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;System infers → Employee validates → Manager approves&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consistency is key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Which system is the system of record for validation?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;TIH/Growth Portfolio or your OSE partner?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Either works—just don’t let both do it independently.&amp;nbsp;That’s how data chaos is born.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-586521920"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Define Your Skills Signals Strategy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Skills come from everywhere. Projects, learning, bots, assessments… even legacy tools that are somehow still alive.&amp;nbsp;Your rule of survival:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Growth Portfolio should be the master system of record for all employee skill interactions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That means:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Employees view and update skills here&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Managers make decisions here&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HR governs here&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Partners feed into here&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other systems can contribute, but they can’t own the truth&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-390008415"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Choose What Skills You will Infer and from Where?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Skill inferencing is magical… unless it pulls the wrong signals.&amp;nbsp;You need to define:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What external sources can infer skills?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Project systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Legacy HR/LMS tools&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;External learning platforms&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gig/mobility platforms&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assessment vendors&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How will you judge quality?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Set thresholds such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Evidence required&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confidence level&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Relevance to job or industry&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Duplication rules&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Which SF processes continuously infer skills?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learning completions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Internal gigs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Performance achievements&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Career development activities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;A thoughtful inferencing strategy prevents “noise skills” and keeps your profiles trustworthy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-193494910"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;6. Decide Where Employee Skills Data Should Flow&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once an employee’s skills are updated and validated, &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;where does that data go?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Typical downstream consumers include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recruiting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Opportunity Marketplace&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Workforce planning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Career &amp;amp; succession tools&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assessment vendors&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-384229562"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;Important:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;"&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;If you have multiple skills-enabled vendors (LMS, recruiting, assessment tools), &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;Growth Portfolio remains the master.&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Application partners consume standardized data; they don’t manage it. This keeps your ecosystem clean and consistent."&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-147722257"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7. Define How the Skills Taxonomy Will Be Propagated&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your &lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;skills taxonomy flows &lt;EM&gt;outward&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;from TIH into the rest of the ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;TIH is your:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Skills system of record&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Job architecture governance tool&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Standardization engine&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Master metadata source&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If you use multiple Open Skills Ecosystem (OSE) partners:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pick &lt;STRONG&gt;ONE&lt;/STRONG&gt; to be your skills architecture provider.&amp;nbsp;Why?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because multiple skills dictionaries = chaos.&lt;BR /&gt;One dictionary + TIH governance = sanity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--48791248"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8. Design the Employee Experience (Growth Portfolio and..)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Employees are the heart of your skills ecosystem.&amp;nbsp;Decide:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How much ownership do they have?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Full self-declaration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Only inferred skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Only validated skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Only view or able to manage skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A blended model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What should they see?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validated skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inferred skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Critical or core skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Skill gaps&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How guided should their experience be?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Single entry inside SuccessFactors&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Some interactions inside partner tools&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Or a completely unified Growth Portfolio experience&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The goal?&lt;BR /&gt;Keep it simple, intuitive, and aligned to growth, not admin work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--245304753"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9. Design the Manager Experience (Teams View and...)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Managers are where skills turn into results, development, mobility, and readiness.&amp;nbsp;You need to define:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How much oversight managers have:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;Do they validate? Approve? Only for critical skills?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How deeply do skills feed talent decisions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Should they use skills to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recommend learning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Suggest gigs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Nominate for roles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Support succession plans&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Plan team capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What feedback loops they own&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Projects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assignments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reskilling initiatives&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manager feedback becomes key evidence for skill proficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--441818258"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10. Design the Admin Experience (Governance, Analytics, and ...)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#800080"&gt;Admins run the heartbeat of your skills ecosystem&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Define:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who owns the skills library?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HR COE?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Talent?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learning?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A cross-functional governance team?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How partners integrate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;External vendors must feed &lt;EM&gt;into&lt;/EM&gt; Growth Portfolio without duplicating or reinventing your skills.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What KPIs HR will track&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some examples:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;% validated critical skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Internal fill rate&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mobility rate&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Skills coverage vs. demand&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Time-to-proficiency&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learning-to-skills conversion&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--931734770"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion: Your Skills Architecture Is Your Future&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Building a skills-based organization is not about collecting skills, it’s about creating a &lt;STRONG&gt;system of truth&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a &lt;STRONG&gt;system of intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and most importantly, a &lt;STRONG&gt;system of experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; that employees and managers trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Talent Intelligence Hub gives you the governance layer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Growth Portfolio with CTD (Career &amp;amp; Talent Development solution) provides the experience layer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Your open ecosystem partners give you the enrichment layer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;But &lt;STRONG&gt;your design decisions&lt;/STRONG&gt; tie it all together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;Get these decisions right, and skills become the engine behind: talent mobility, workforce agility, learning personalization, internal career growth, and more.&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get them wrong, and you’ll spend months reconciling data, chasing inconsistencies, and wondering why adoption is low.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Talent Intelligence Hub at the center and these 10 decisions guiding your journey, you can build not only an architecture, but a future-ready, human-centered skills ecosystem that actually works.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/skills-architecture-playbook-10-design-decisions-with-talent-intelligence/ba-p/14275531"/>
    <published>2025-11-30T03:13:30.857000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/where-is-my-stuff-joule-s-first-industry-release-brings-ai-driven-insight/ba-p/14280802</id>
    <title>Where Is My Stuff? — Joule’s First Industry Release Brings AI-Driven Insight to Oil and Gas Upstream</title>
    <updated>2025-12-01T08:56:31.229000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SrinivasaMural</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1412113</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The oil and gas domain has historically been one of the most stable but also conservative areas of enterprise architecture. Over multiple decades, SAP customers have evolved from custom ABAP solutions to standardized S/4HANA objects, Fiori applications, and integrated complex logistics planning and processes. While this has driven consistency and transactional efficiency, the &lt;STRONG&gt;core decision-making mechanisms in field logistics remained predominantly human-driven&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;with, manual validation, and the experience of field and personnel&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Field Logistics is a solution built on SAP S/4HANA. It is available on both S/4HANA private cloud and public cloud.&amp;nbsp; This solution enables customers leverage best in class industry practices to manage the logistics movement of their own- and third-party items between their supply and demand plants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are happy to announce that in &lt;STRONG&gt;May 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we at SAP introduced a landmark innovation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;the very first Joule-enabled capability across all industries, delivered specifically within SAP Upstream Field Logistics.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This early release is subtle in scope but monumental in strategic significance. It marks the beginning of Field Logistics evolution from traditional business processes to a future where core FL operations become deeply AI-driven through Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Strategic First Step: Joule’s Inventory Insights for FL&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The initial capability released in May focuses on a &lt;STRONG&gt;read-only non-stock inventory scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;, allowing users to retrieve consolidated product and equipment visibility through natural language and gives the latest milestone of its lifecycle to help to know where the equipment is located. Even though this first use case is intentionally controlled, it is designed as the &lt;STRONG&gt;foundation for a multi-release future where Joule will perform full field logistics (FL) transactions end-to-end&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP’s intention is clear:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Start small, prove value, ensure reliability, and then scale AI-driven operations across the entire upstream lifecycle.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This first release demonstrates Joule’s ability to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Understand Field Logistics terminology in 50 different languages&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Interpret users queries through Natural Language Processing and provide contextual answers instantly&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Display list of products along with relevant information’s like plant, Purchase order, different quantities etc&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to Manage logistics application from Joule to get a wholistic view&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;While simple on the surface, the underlying architecture sets the stage for powerful, future-ready logistics automation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What This Means for Customers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Faster, simpler access to operational intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Users can ask Joule questions in natural language — no need to navigate complex screens or interpret multiple reports.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immediate visibility where it matters most&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inventory and material readiness have direct impact on non-productive time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A future-proof foundation for autonomous logistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This first release is intentionally scoped — but designed for expansion into item receival, returns process, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A clear step toward an “AI co-pilot” for upstream operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule is not just a search tool. It is the beginning of a more intelligent, proactive, and predictive logistics environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Highlights Behind the Scenes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While the customer experience focuses on simplicity, the technical implementation is sophisticated:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SrinivasaMural_0-1764575303042.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346883i4874BCB8FAF73DFB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SrinivasaMural_0-1764575303042.png" alt="SrinivasaMural_0-1764575303042.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flow Diagram&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SrinivasaMural_1-1764575303045.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346882iFEFF45DEE8079013/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SrinivasaMural_1-1764575303045.jpeg" alt="SrinivasaMural_1-1764575303045.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Semantic Understanding of FL and S/4HANA Operational Objects&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule interprets upstream-specific structures such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Field Logistics items&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PO, GR, Open and Return quantity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Latest Milestone&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Non-stock Inventory availability data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This domain-awareness is what enables Joule to deliver precise, contextual answers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Natural Language → CDS Query Generation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule automatically translates plain language into data retrieval operations using:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CDS consumption views&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;FL OData APIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This eliminates the need for custom queries or separate analytical tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Functionality&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do follow the below link to understand about Joule and how to access the same in a Private Cloud system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-a-comprehensive-setup-guide/ba-p/13786453" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-a-comprehensive-setup-guide/ba-p/13786453&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you login to your Fiori system as a Supply Chain Analyst persona and click on the Joule icon at the top, all the capabilities that are part of your user role will be available. Users also can click on helpful conversation starters instead of asking a question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SrinivasaMural_2-1764575303054.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346884i76CE0445FF451CF0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SrinivasaMural_2-1764575303054.png" alt="SrinivasaMural_2-1764575303054.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Certain mandatory parameters are needed to process the user utterance, for our capability the item number/ description must be provided. Additionally, optional parameters like plant could also be provided to narrow down the search results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SrinivasaMural_3-1764575303061.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346886i65229D4E405754C3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SrinivasaMural_3-1764575303061.png" alt="SrinivasaMural_3-1764575303061.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule displays a list of items that are relevant for your search along with some important fields such as PO and item, Latest Milestone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SrinivasaMural_4-1764575303073.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346887i753E5B98441923FD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SrinivasaMural_4-1764575303073.png" alt="SrinivasaMural_4-1764575303073.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can click on each entry which would take you to a detail view wherein additional fields such as Order and various quantities can be viewed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SrinivasaMural_5-1764575303079.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346885i23AEAED06173E85F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SrinivasaMural_5-1764575303079.png" alt="SrinivasaMural_5-1764575303079.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, there is a button at the bottom which can be used to Navigate to Manage Logistics application that filters the data already entered by the user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SrinivasaMural_6-1764575303091.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346888iAB2B2AACEB80985D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SrinivasaMural_6-1764575303091.png" alt="SrinivasaMural_6-1764575303091.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer-Focused Future Roadmap&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has already signalled a &lt;STRONG&gt;multi-release roadmap&lt;/STRONG&gt; to expand Joule’s Oil and Gas capabilities beyond visibility into actionable intelligence and automated logistics execution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Future Vision&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This progression reflects SAP’s commitment to &lt;STRONG&gt;controlled, safe, value-driven rollout of Joule capabilities to field logistics operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion: A Small Release with a Massive Strategic Horizon&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The May 2025 Joule capability for FL may be limited to inventory visibility, but it represents:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;first-ever Joule release across industries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The foundation of AI-enriched S/4HANA FL operations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The beginning of SAP’s broader AI transformation across line-of-business functions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customers leveraging this early capability are not just gaining a new feature—they are positioning themselves at the &lt;STRONG&gt;frontline of an industry-wide shift&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where SAP systems evolve from transactional engines to &lt;STRONG&gt;intelligent co-pilots for complex field logistics operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/where-is-my-stuff-joule-s-first-industry-release-brings-ai-driven-insight/ba-p/14280802"/>
    <published>2025-12-01T08:56:31.229000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/research-community-spotlight-sap-kd-lab-karlsruhe/ba-p/14267055</id>
    <title>🔎 Research Community Spotlight: SAP @ KD²lab Karlsruhe</title>
    <updated>2025-12-01T13:25:36.464000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hannahsperling</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/42396</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1893816991"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP and KIT Expand Research Partnership&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="Prof. Dr. Alexander Mädche, head of the Human-centered Systems Lab." style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/346913iE7C4E1FE0633B09C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="8D919F97-88C1-4F56-89A8-CDCDBD05F78D_1_201_a.jpeg" alt="Prof. Dr. Alexander Mädche, head of the Human-centered Systems Lab." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Prof. Dr. Alexander Mädche, head of the Human-centered Systems Lab.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP and the Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) are longstanding partners in academic and res&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;earch endeavors. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In 2019, this partnership was further institutionalized through a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;comprehensive framework contract&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for joint research initiatives, paving the way for further collaboration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A recent initiative exemplifies the growing partnership between SAP and one of Germany's most prestigious technical universities: the research collaboration with&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;the &lt;A href="https://h-lab.win.kit.edu/index.php" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Human-Centered Systems Lab&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(h-lab).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Led by &lt;A href="https://h-lab.win.kit.edu/team_maedche.php" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Prof. Dr. Alexander Mädche&lt;/A&gt;, the h-lab research group organized its first "&lt;STRONG&gt;Research and Innovation Symposium on Human-centered AI for Sustainable Business&lt;/STRONG&gt;" in November 2025, in collaboration with Dr. Norbert Frech-Koppenhagen and Christian Boos from SAP. T&lt;/SPAN&gt;he event took place at &lt;A href="https://www.kd2lab.kit.edu/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Karlsruhe Decision &amp;amp; Design Lab&lt;/A&gt; (KD²lab), a DFG-funded experimental lab located in the heart of Karlsruhe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697303486"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Software meets Behavioral Science&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Dr. Julia Seitz registering a study participant at KD2lab (copyright: KIT/Amadeus Bramsiepe)." style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345973i280D6B6588291CBE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="KD2Lab_smallest.jpeg" alt="Dr. Julia Seitz registering a study participant at KD2lab (copyright: KIT/Amadeus Bramsiepe)." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Dr. Julia Seitz registering a study participant at KD2lab (copyright: KIT/Amadeus Bramsiepe).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;KD²lab at KIT&lt;/STRONG&gt; is one of the world's largest computer-based behavioral science experimental laboratories.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;40 soundproof computer cubicles, climate-controlled experimental rooms, and high-resolution biosignal measu&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;rement equipment (including eye tracking, ECG, and EEG) enable researchers to capture neuro- and psychophysiological processe&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;s under controlled conditions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://h-lab.win.kit.edu/2236_2287.php" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Dr. Julia Seitz&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;is Research Team Lead for two research streams at h-lab: &lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic Enterprise Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Biosignal-Adaptive Collaboration Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;. She&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;combines psychological theories and behavioral economics approaches in her experimental research on human-centered information systems design.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Focusing on collaboration in teams of humans and AI&amp;nbsp;agents, Dr. Seitz is particularly interested in how adaptive and agentic information systems in the workplace impact users. In her research, she combines qualitative and quantitative empirical methods with real-time processing of biosignal data to explore how agentic software design can improve outcomes and collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1500789981"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI for Sustainability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the collaborative project "&lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic Information Systems for Sustainability&lt;/STRONG&gt;" with SAP, Dr. Seitz is working alongside &lt;A href="https://h-lab.win.kit.edu/team_3404.php" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Anna Sommer&lt;/A&gt;, SAP PhD student at KIT, to explore a crucial question: How can generative AI agents and humans work together optimally to drive sustainable business practices?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="SAP PhD student Anna Sommer." style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345967iD54E797635D1D7CD/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Anna_sommer.jpeg" alt="SAP PhD student Anna Sommer." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP PhD student Anna Sommer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Using human-centered AI design approaches and hands-on experimental research, the team is investigating the dynamic interplay between humans and generative agents, identifying which forms of interaction deliver the most impactful results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;"The project's ambition is to develop AI systems that truly complement human expertise rather than replace it: Systems that enhance rather than diminish critical thinking, enable more efficient resource management, and strengthen both ecological and social sustainability," says Anna Sommer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In her current study, she is investigating how the use of AI agents influences cognitive processes—particularly critical thinking—and whether these effects differ between different AI agents. To do this, participants first complete a critical thinking test with the help of an AI agent. In a second part of the study, this test is replaced with a realistic task from the field of sustainability management requiring critical thinking. This part takes place in the KD²lab and is supplemented by additional measurement methods such as eye tracking.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ultimately, Anna Sommer's goal is to develop guidelines for AI agents that actively foster critical thinking rather than hinder it—an ability that is becoming increasingly vital for businesses striving for sustainable success.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1304276476"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Get in Touch with the SAP Research Community&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Want to participate or know more about the partnership between SAP and KIT? Feel free to reach out to &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1678067" target="_self"&gt;Dr. Philipp Hoffmann,&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Senior Data Scientist and Lead Researcher for Developer Experience at SAP,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;who coordinates the strategic collaboration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/research-community-spotlight-sap-kd-lab-karlsruhe/ba-p/14267055"/>
    <published>2025-12-01T13:25:36.464000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-4-of-6/ba-p/14282736</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 4 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T10:22:29.612000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Oliver_K2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1728860</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Oliver_K2_0-1764752655665.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347868i703ED71619D1B4FA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Oliver_K2_0-1764752655665.png" alt="Oliver_K2_0-1764752655665.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: The Factory of the Future: Production in the Age of AI, Circular Economy, and Autonomous Systems &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the debate around the supply chain of the future, one aspect is taking center stage: production as the core of modern value creation for many companies. In times of global change, digital disruption, and growing demands for sustainability, it has a key role to play.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The production of the future is networked, flexible, and data driven. Leveraging technologies such as robotics, artificial intelligence, and the Internet of Things, it is increasingly growing together with other areas of the supply chain. This development is giving rise to a digital ecosystem in which real-time data availability enables faster and more accurate decision-making across the entire supply chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, production is gaining strategic importance: Companies are relocating manufacturing processes closer to sales markets to reduce their dependency on global disruptions – a trend that has been further amplified by the pandemic, energy crisis, and geopolitical tensions. In addition, there is increasing regulatory pressure and simultaneous efforts to produce more sustainably and to use resources more efficiently. All of this must be achieved while maintaining the lowest possible production costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, production is not merely one element of the supply chain, but the driving force behind its future. It determines how resilient, climate-friendly, and innovative businesses can operate tomorrow. The fourth part of the study by SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University on “Supply Chain 2035” therefore focuses on production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result of the study clearly highlights that the vision of a connected, AI-powered, and sustainable factory has long since arrived in the minds of many manufacturing managers – yet its implementation is still at the beginning in many places. There is a noticeable gap in maturity between the ambitions for 2035 and today's reality. While many organizations have already formulated a clear vision for the future, operational execution often remains fragmented and experimental.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The gap in sustainability and the circular economy is particularly striking. Circular production models and closed-loop material cycles are seen as key pillars of future value creation but are currently only implemented sporadically. Product designs that facilitate recycling, reuse, and modular construction are often still in the early stages of development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Achieving digital continuity represents another major challenge. While connected, data-driven control is considered a prerequisite for the smart factory; data landscapes are often fragmented. The lack of interoperability and inconsistent standards makes it difficult to leverage production and supply chain information end-to-end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similarly, the deployment of artificial intelligence falls short of expectations. Many companies are experimenting with AI-powered applications, but the leap from pilot projects to widespread deployment is still pending. In addition, data quality and availability remain critical bottlenecks. Without clean, consistent, and connected data, every digital initiative remains piecemeal. It is only on this basis that intelligent systems can be scaled, and factories can be managed holistically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, organizational structures are undergoing transformation. Many companies are moving from experimentation to scaling – a process that requires not only new technologies, but also new skills, structures, and leadership approaches. Transforming production therefore entails not just digitalization but a fundamental shift in the interaction between people, machines, and data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The study underscores that while the path towards the factory of the future is charted, many pillars are still under construction. Success will depend on consistently linking technological and organizational building blocks. The factory of the future will not emerge from isolated innovations, but from the integrated interplay of data, technologies, and resource-efficient processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347872i420615AEBF98885F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="Picture1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Figure 1: What the Data Really Shows – Current Studies briefly&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The factory of 2035 will differ fundamentally from what we are used to today. It is no longer a production system of siloed processes, but part of an intelligent, globally connected value-creating ecosystem. Data forms its central raw material – flowing through all systems in real time, connecting design, manufacturing, logistics, and recycling to a dynamic and adaptive cycle. The decisions are increasingly taken by artificial intelligence. It controls material flows, optimizes production plans, and detects deviations and disruptions early and preventively. Human expertise will thus shift toward strategic, creative, and monitoring tasks – AI becomes the central instance of production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The physical factory itself becomes autonomous and modular. Production lines adapt in real time to changing orders, materials, or energy availability. Mobile robots, self-learning systems, and digital platforms orchestrate processes largely independently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the paradigm shifts from linear to circular production. Closed loops are emerging; products are designed in a modular manner and optimized for reuse or remanufacturing. Digital twins and IoT data connect the physical and digital worlds. Each manufacturing step, component, and usage generates data that makes the life cycle of a product fully traceable. This digital memory not only enables precise traceability, but also predictive maintenance, accurate material returns, and the continuous improvement of future product designs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary: Industrial transformation is more than technological modernization – it is a cultural change. The factory of 2035 becomes a reality where data intelligence and circular thinking become part of the company’s DNA – not as an isolated project, but as a foundational principle. Those who actively shape this change not only strengthen their efficiency, but also their ability to reinvent themselves in an increasingly interconnected and dynamic industry.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-4-of-6/ba-p/14282736"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T10:22:29.612000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-far-will-ai-go-and-what-will-it-mean-for-your-job/ba-p/14282106</id>
    <title>How far will AI go... and what will it mean for your job?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T13:50:18.535000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Pierre_Col</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/63</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In April this year, I decided to voluntarily&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/so-this-is-it-i-m-verped/ba-p/14068989" target="_self"&gt;retire early from SAP&lt;/A&gt; after 6 years of a very interesting journey. Indeed, I've lived from the inside the infusion of powerful Artificial Intelligence capabilities in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Build/pd-p/73555000100700001491" target="_self"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;, for &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-sap-build-code-when-generative-ai-comes-to-help/ba-p/13584227" target="_self"&gt;application development&lt;/A&gt; and for &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/generative-ai-boosting-process-automation-come-see-our-the-results-at-sap/ba-p/13709057" target="_self"&gt;process automation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since then, I've spent 8 months observing the IT industry evolution, particularly around AI. And now, I have very mixed feelings:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;On one hand, I'm impressed how well SAP is positioned on the market and how SAP AI is powerful&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":question_mark:"&gt;❓&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;On the other hand, I'm more and more worried by the impact humanoid robots and AI, from SAP and all vendors, will have on so many jobs everywhere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So I decided to share my views with you in this blog post.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766433166"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP is amazingly well positioned with Business AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A month ago I watched SAP &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X9qHsLmPMk4" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;TechEd Keynote&lt;/A&gt; and also a few sessions, and I have to say that I'm impressed. By the way, in case you missed it, watch the replay of the keynote:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FX9qHsLmPMk4%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DX9qHsLmPMk4&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FX9qHsLmPMk4%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="Keynote: How SAP is Supercharging Developers for What's Next | AI &amp;amp; Agents | SAP TechEd 2025" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;I discovered AI &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/blog-it-forward-pierre-col/ba-p/13449598" target="_self"&gt;more than 40 years ago&lt;/A&gt;,&lt;/STRONG&gt; when I was studying to graduate in 1986 as an engineer in computing science, and 10 years ago I was working for &lt;A href="https://www.fluidtopics.com/antidot-company/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Antidot&lt;/A&gt;, a french startup involved in knowledge graphs, where I wrote this &lt;A href="https://bit.ly/LED-Antidot-2012" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;white paper on Business Knowledge Graphs&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;in 2014.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, from my humble point of view, &lt;STRONG&gt;putting together&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#00CCFF"&gt;SAP ERP&lt;/FONT&gt; +&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#00CCFF"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/FONT&gt; + &lt;FONT color="#00CCFF"&gt;SAP&amp;nbsp;Knowledge Graphs&lt;/FONT&gt; + &lt;FONT color="#00CCFF"&gt;SAP&amp;nbsp;Business AI with Joule&lt;/FONT&gt; creates a winning combo. It puts SAP in a unique position , better than any competitor, to bring the best of AI to the customers.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SAP announcements at TechEd.jpeg" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347605i3BDAD036538092B6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP announcements at TechEd.jpeg" alt="SAP announcements at TechEd.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And what has been presented and announced at SAP TechEd makes SAP even stronger:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP-ABAP-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a new model allowing to handle ABAP language: trained on more than 250 million lines of ABAP code, 30 million lines of CDS code, and extensive technical documentation, it is purpose-built to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;explain&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;generate&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-the-next-era-of-abap-development/ba-p/14260522" target="_self"&gt;modern ABAP code&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP-RPT-1 (&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Relational Pre-trained Transformer Model-1&lt;/EM&gt;) is a &lt;STRONG&gt;brand new &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-is-sap-rpt-1-a-table-specialized-model-explained-through-the-original/ba-p/14277618" target="_self"&gt;classification and regression model&lt;/A&gt;,&lt;/STRONG&gt; allowing to &lt;STRONG&gt;better handle &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-rpt-1-a-revolutionary-tabular-ml-model-and-owasp-ml-top-10-compliance/ba-p/14270750" target="_self"&gt;structured, tabular business data&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt; It is a paradigm shift in machine learning, introducing a revolutionary approach that eliminates the security-performance trade-off entirely. SAP-RPT-1 achieves state-of-the-art performance and&amp;nbsp;already outperforms regular text-based LLMs&amp;nbsp;through semantic understanding of tabular relationships.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Knowledge Graph in SAP HANA &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cloud&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;an RDF graph built from system catalog, capturing tables, columns, relationships, and annotations. It provides&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-becomes-agentic-introducing-discovery-agent-amp-data-agent/ba-p/14257394" target="_self"&gt;the semantic layer&lt;/A&gt; needed for exploration, AI grounding, and graph-based reasoning.&lt;/STRONG&gt; It&amp;nbsp;allows agents to reason about data, to understand entities relationships, and which attributes are relevant.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A2A and MCP protocols &lt;/STRONG&gt;foster Agentic AI&amp;nbsp;by allowing&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-agentic-ai-system-with-agent2agent-a2a-and-mcp-tools-on-sap-btp/ba-p/14093412" target="_self"&gt;autonomous agents collaboration&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP is providing&amp;nbsp;out-of-the-box Joule agents and alllowing customers to create custom agents with Agent Builder in Joule Studio. Beyond that, agentic protocols such as&amp;nbsp;A2A - &lt;EM&gt;Agent to Agent&lt;/EM&gt; - and MCP - &lt;EM&gt;Model Context Protocol&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;- with SAP Lean IX &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749118636333001o3gW" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Agent Hub&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/agent-mining-in-sap-signavio-understand-agent-behavior/ba-p/14279314" target="_self"&gt;Agent Mining&lt;/A&gt; in SAP Signavio&amp;nbsp;allow to &lt;STRONG&gt;standardize, deploy and monitor AI agents collaboration.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To dig deeper on these topics, follow the links I've put in the text above, watch the replay of the SAP TechEd sessions and also refer to&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/topics/innovation-guide/h2" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Innovation Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Guide&amp;nbsp;"&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/serviceguide/what-is-joule?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What is Joule?&lt;/A&gt;"&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569919661"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What impact will AI have on human employment?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, we all agree, SAP is doing very well with Business AI for empowering companies to do better and faster. And this is very good for SAP and its entire ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But when it comes to employees working in these companies, things could be different. Indeed, some news popping up in mainstream media are a bit worrying. For instance, according to &lt;A href="https://fortune.com/2025/11/25/why-ai-wont-take-your-job-partnership-agents-robots-mckinsey/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;McKinsey &amp;amp; Company&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://fortune.com/2025/11/25/why-ai-wont-take-your-job-partnership-agents-robots-mckinsey/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;,&lt;/A&gt; AI can already do almost 60% of all the work:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://fortune.com/2025/11/25/why-ai-wont-take-your-job-partnership-agents-robots-mckinsey/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Fortune McKinsey AI.jpeg" style="width: 700px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347585i0A89D332BF7783EC/image-dimensions/700x639/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="700" height="639" role="button" title="Fortune McKinsey AI.jpeg" alt="Fortune McKinsey AI.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Their research “&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/mgi/our-research/agents-robots-and-us-skill-partnerships-in-the-age-of-ai" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Agents, robots, and us: Skill partnerships in the age of AI&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;” says that the future of work will be basically shaped by partnerships among people, agents, and robots - all powered by AI. The research emphasizes that capturing AI’s massive potential economic value - about $2.9 trillion by 2023 in the US only! -&amp;nbsp;depends entirely on how organizations will reorganize.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Pierre_Col_1-1764761106700.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347986i1CF8ED90C196E1FB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pierre_Col_1-1764761106700.png" alt="Pierre_Col_1-1764761106700.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Indeed, be it for business users, for consultants, for developers, AI agents will be everywhere... and they will do a lot of tasks done by human employees today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And we have already seen this year how big tech firms have "reorganized" to embrace AI benefits:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Amazon -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.reuters.com/business/world-at-work/amazon-targets-many-30000-corporate-job-cuts-sources-say-2025-10-27/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;30,000 layoffs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Accenture -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/company-just-laid-off-11-123000530.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;11,000 layoffs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Microsoft -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/13/microsoft-is-cutting-3percent-of-workers-across-the-software-company.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;6,000 layoffs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;HP - &lt;A href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/11/25/tech/hp-layoffs-ai-efforts" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;4,000-6000 layoffs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;So in total more than 50,000 jobs have been erased in a few months only. And SAP as well is shrinking its workforce: “I&lt;EM&gt;n one year, it could be one or sometimes two percent of jobs that are eliminated&lt;/EM&gt;” said Christian Klein, and&amp;nbsp;Dominik Asam&amp;nbsp; added “&lt;EM&gt;There are certain tasks which are automated and for the same volume of output we can afford to have less people&lt;/EM&gt;". He&amp;nbsp;admits to be "brutal",&amp;nbsp; comparing this program to routines such as brushing teeth...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Meanwhile, it seems everyone is trying to reassure the public that everything will be fine… perhaps to prevent tens of millions of workers from becoming upset about the prospect of losing their jobs?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Should not a part of the value created by all the AI software and humanoid robots be used to compentiate this massive loss of jobs?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today, in many countries, health insurance, unemployment insurance, and pensions are financed by contributions paid by employers and employees on human work. If the number of employees is decreasing, shouldn't social security contributions be levied on the work performed by AI agents and humanoid robots?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="workers of the world unite.jpg" style="width: 480px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347612i5102A5D408955909/image-dimensions/480x480/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="480" height="480" role="button" title="workers of the world unite.jpg" alt="workers of the world unite.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Will robots embrace &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Workers_of_the_world,_unite!" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Karl Marx slogan&lt;/A&gt;? &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":upside_down_face:"&gt;🙃&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What do you think? How do you envision the impact AI and robots will have on your job in 3, 5 or 10 years?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your feedback will be highly appreciated, so feel free to share your own views in the comments!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-far-will-ai-go-and-what-will-it-mean-for-your-job/ba-p/14282106"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T13:50:18.535000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/prompt-engineering-unlocking-hidden-power-for-enterprise-ai-success/ba-p/14283344</id>
    <title>Prompt Engineering: Unlocking Hidden Power for Enterprise AI Success</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T22:02:03.423000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RichDBlumberg</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44933</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="People.at.top.of.Blog.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348234i1A7588599FA9A392/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="People.at.top.of.Blog.jpg" alt="People.at.top.of.Blog.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766465001"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;Gaps in Prompt Design Derail the User Experience&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;What happens when gaps in prompt design or user intent recognition turns everyday AI interactions into a dead‑end waste of time?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Have you ever experienced this type of situation?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, I recently tried to claim a rebate for a kitchen appliance, but the company’s AI assistant misinterpreted my request and left me stuck with irrelevant FAQs. The issue was poor prompt design. With proper prompt engineering, the assistant could have recognized my rebate request and guided me to the correct, enabled form. A smarter workflow would have turned a dead end into a faster way to get my rebate money.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What fun!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This experience underscores a critical truth:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;EM&gt;when prompts fail to capture real&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;‑&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;world users’ intent, the customer experience collapses.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For business and IT users working with AI, this isn’t just a consumer inconvenience, it’s a wake‑up call. Prompt engineering is more than a technical capability; it’s the discipline of shaping interactions so that AI systems understand nuance, adapt to context, and deliver meaningful results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether in customer service troubleshooting, enterprise workflows (agentic AI), or customer engagement, the quality of prompts directly determines the quality of the user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this age of AI agents and assistants, refining prompts is no longer optional; it is essential for building trust, driving efficiency, enabling scalable automation, and achieving successful outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569951496"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reducing AI Project Failures - Understanding Prompt Engineering&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prompt engineering is the art and science of designing inputs that guide AI models to produce desired outputs. By framing instructions accurately, organizations can harness AI to generate relevant, high-quality responses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to a RAND report, 80% of AI project failures stem from poor human to AI communication. Misunderstandings between business and IT teams about goals, data, and capabilities are the most common cause of failure. Companies that master prompt engineering achieve significantly higher ROI compared to those relying on basic or ad hoc prompting (1).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In short:&lt;/STRONG&gt; success doesn’t come from the technology alone; it comes from how we communicate with it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="People.at.Conference.jpg" style="width: 402px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348237iE8CAF4B250712171/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="People.at.Conference.jpg" alt="People.at.Conference.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1373437991"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prompt engineering is no longer a fringe capability and skill. It is becoming a critical organizational capability embedded into everyday business functions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to Market Research Future (MRFR), the prompt engineering market was valued at $2.195 billion in 2024 and is projected to grow to $32.78 billion by 2035, with a staggering 27.86% CAGR (2).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176924486"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Prompt Engineering Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prompt engineering transforms vague queries into precise instructions, guiding AI toward accurate, consistent, and actionable outputs. With AI agents and assistants like SAP’s Joule, Microsoft Copilot, Google Gemini, and OpenAI’s ChatGPT, organizations recognize that prompt engineering is essential to maximize AI’s potential and align outcomes with business goals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has embedded prompt engineering into Joule, powered by the Generative AI Hub in &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-ai-core/sap-ai-core-service-guide/what-is-sap-ai-core" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI Core&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/codejam-ai-prompt-engineering-and-orchestration/blob/main/exercises/00-prompt-engineering-with-ai-launchpad/readme.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Launchpad&lt;/A&gt; (part of the SAP Business Technology Platform) and supported by SAP’s &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-foundation-os.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Foundation&lt;/A&gt;, delivering enterprise‑grade accuracy and trust with Large Language Models (LLMs).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP Sapphire 2025, SAP announced a proprietary &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/ai-core-genaihub-prompt-optimization..html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Prompt Optimizer&lt;/A&gt; built with the company, Not Diamond. This optimizer enables enterprises to migrate and adapt prompts across multiple LLMs, supporting consistency, accelerating adoption, and improving the user experience across diverse AI systems (3).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not Diamond envisions “a multi‑model AI future, with thousands of foundation models, millions of fine‑tuned variants, and billions &lt;SPAN&gt;of custom inference engines running on top of them&lt;/SPAN&gt;.” Their infrastructure routes, governs, and scales prompts across these systems, ensuring flexibility and trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This partnership confirms prompt engineering as an important, core enterprise requirement, bridging business strategy with technology capabilities for responsible AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-980410981"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best of Prompt Engineering Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prompt engineering serves as the strategic layer that transforms raw AI capabilities into business value, delivering a range of benefits including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clarifies Intent – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Ensures AI understands user goals, reducing miscommunication and aligning outputs with business needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Engagement &amp;amp; Personalization – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Crafts prompts that drive tailored chatbot interactions, outreach, and recommendations, fostering loyalty and satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Structures Outputs – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Guides AI to deliver usable formats (tables, lists, reports, narratives) for clarity and consistency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improves Efficiency &amp;amp; Operational Automation –&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Minimizes unnecessary token usage, accelerates turnaround, and empowers agentic AI to automate repetitive workflows such as reporting, summarization, and FAQ handling.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adds Domain Context – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Embeds industry‑specific language, governance and compliance rules, approved product names, synonyms, and brand tone for relevance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supports Scalability Across Teams – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Builds reusable prompt libraries and frameworks that allow consistent enterprise‑wide adoption without reinventing workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content Quality &amp;amp; Consistency – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Ensures outputs are brand‑aligned, accurate, and emotionally resonant across all channels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Optimizes Across Models – &lt;/STRONG&gt;With tools like Not Diamond’s Prompt Optimizer, prompts can be migrated and adapted across Copilot, Gemini, ChatGPT, Joule, and other LLMs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Accuracy &amp;amp; Decision‑Making – &lt;/STRONG&gt;Produces precise, consistent outputs and extracts actionable intelligence quickly to support better business decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By uniting these capabilities, prompt engineering becomes the foundation for trustworthy, scalable, and business‑aligned AI success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AdobeStock_558703749_Young.Professionals.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348242i10BE48643376C73E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AdobeStock_558703749_Young.Professionals.jpeg" alt="AdobeStock_558703749_Young.Professionals.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-783897476"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Short on Time? Who Manages Prompt Engineering&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prompt engineering isn’t just the domain of IT or developers; business roles like product managers, business analysts, marketing, communications, operations, UX/CX designers, content strategists, and other lines of business are equally critical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, product managers align prompts with business goals, analysts map workflows, designers ensure intuitive user experiences, and strategists refine language and tone. Together, they make AI outputs reliable and customer‑centric.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, a dedicated, focused part‑time prompt engineering consultant can help jumpstart this process by auditing the current status, delivering best practices, and establishing governance standards in collaboration with IT and key stakeholders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In a fast paced, short-handed, busy work environment, these prompt optimization specialists can provide support by providing focus and discipline, coaching key stakeholders with standard operation procedures (SOPs), monitoring performance, and refining prompts as business needs evolve to help ensure AI systems remain accurate, consistent, and trusted across the enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-587383971"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prompt engineering is no longer a niche skill or technical curiosity; it has become a core business capability that drives efficiency, compliance, and innovation. Organizations that embrace it gain a competitive edge, while those that neglect it risk wasted investments and inconsistent results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By embedding prompt engineering as a business standard, integrated into workflows through enterprise‑wide libraries, governance, and automated refinement, companies can optimize AI strategies to keep pace with evolving models, regulations, and customer expectations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The future of enterprise AI will not be defined by those who merely explore prompts, but by those who master them, transforming raw model potential into trusted, scalable business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And as a result, users can save time by getting answers versus &lt;U&gt;gaps and dead ends&lt;/U&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-390870466"&gt;---&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;Your Comments are Appreciated!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FFFFFF"&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;Interested to hear your experiences when prompting works and doesn't work from a business and IT perspective!!!&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;If you are new to prompt engineering, what are your impressions as a result of reading this blog?&lt;BR /&gt;Please take a moment to post them below...&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks!!!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-194356961"&gt;---&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;About the Author&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rich Blumberg is a long time SAP Community member and contributor. For 20+ years he's been an SAP consultant working with SAP ecosystem organizations around the globe. He's the President of &lt;A href="https://www.worldsalessolutions.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;World Sales Solutions, LLC&lt;/A&gt;, (WSS) a business development and low-code no-code services company. He has published two acclaimed Amazon books, &lt;A href="https://worldsalessolutions.com/job-seeking-warriors-acclaimed-amazon-book/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Job Seeking Warriors – A Mentors Guide to Winning&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FXPT33R4" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Novi’s Journey to the Magic Garden&lt;/A&gt;. In his spare time, he is a Drexel University Alumni Board of Governors Emeritus volunteer, &lt;A href="https://www.enginprogram.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ENGin&lt;/A&gt; English tutor for Ukrainian citizens, and an aspiring guitar player.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;---&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Footnotes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;RAND Corporation, “The Root Causes of Failure for Artificial Intelligence Projects and How They Can Succeed: Avoiding the Anti‑Patterns of AI,” (August 2024)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Market Research Future, “Prompt Engineering Market Size, Share, Trends, Analysis 2035.” Published (October 2025)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Press Release, “Not Diamond Launches Prompt Adaptation, an Agentic System for Multi-Model Enterprise AI” (May 2025)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/prompt-engineering-unlocking-hidden-power-for-enterprise-ai-success/ba-p/14283344"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T22:02:03.423000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/defining-safe-ai-transparency-within-ideation-and-validation/ba-p/14283700</id>
    <title>Defining Safe AI: Transparency within ideation and validation</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T15:44:19.695000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Abhishek_Pant01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/852345</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Aviation safety became non-negotiable because stakeholders agreed on a clear definition: keeping humans alive and systems operational. For AI, the definition is less obvious and varies by use case. We define &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI safety&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; as systems operating within intended boundaries without causing harm: technical, ethical, or societal, as beautifully explained by Bettina Laugwitz in her introductory blogpost of this series (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/keep-the-blue-side-up-building-trust-in-ai-through-transparency-responsible/ba-p/14269929" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keep the blue side up: Building trust in AI throug... - SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;). This means being &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;lawful, ethical, and robust&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, echoing the principles outlined in global AI governance frameworks such as ISO/IEC 42001 and related regulations such as the EU AI Act. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/standard/42001" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ISO/IEC 42001:2023 - AI management systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;EU Artificial Intelligence Act | Up-to-date developments and analyses of the EU AI Act&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s43681-025-00661-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Standards, frameworks, and legislation for artificial intelligence (AI) transparency | AI and Ethics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For “Transparency &amp;amp; Explainability” in AI systems to progress beyond aspirational slogans; they must be &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;engineered into the product, the pipeline, and day-to-day operations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, with clear roles for every stakeholder. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/data-and-policy/article/overview-of-transparency-and-inspectability-mechanisms-to-achieve-accountability-of-artificial-intelligence-systems/C9E75DB736CAAEA00158D8F0ACD595D6" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Overview of transparency and inspectability mechanisms to achieve accountability of artificial intelligence systems | Data &amp;amp; Policy | Cambridge Core&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://thesai.org/Downloads/Volume16No10/Paper_102-Evaluating_Transparency_in_the_Development_of_Artificial_Intelligence_Systems.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Evaluating Transparency in the Development of Artificial Intelligence Systems: A Systematic Literature Review.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;Let's look at how.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI's Captain and the crew: Stakeholder Requirement Mapping&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In aviation, roles are clearly defined: pilots, air traffic controllers, maintenance crew, and cabin staff, each have specific responsibilities and access to information. Pilots see cockpit instruments not the engineering schematics; maintenance teams get technical manuals, not passenger safety cards. This layered approach ensures clarity without unnecessary information overload. Similarly, transparency must be tailored to the different roles. Engineers need deep technical details while end users need simple actionable explanations of the system they are interacting with.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What does it include: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A persona mapping exercise should be conducted in the early ideation stage for the AI feature to identify stakeholders including engineers, product owners, compliance teams, end users, etc. and their transparency needs should be detailed out. Role-based access to information should follow the least privilege principle. Further to this mapping exercise, there should be a clear assignment of accountabilities related to transparency checkpoints(decided on a case to case basis). Questions like: who approves product updates, who updates the documentation, who monitors compliance, etc. Should be answered by the use case team and related mapping should be embedded into the design documents and backlog items early in the lifecycle.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;practice:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; An established approach to identify user roles, users’ objectives, and their (information) needs is conducting early-stage design workshops (e. g. following the SAP AppHaus’ &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://apphaus.sap.com/resource/business-ai-explore-workshop" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business AI Explore&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; or &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://apphaus.sap.com/resource/business-ai-design-workshop" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Design workshop&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; methodology).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Navigating tough terrains: Classifying use cases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For planning appropriate contingency measures, scenarios within aviation sector are classified into different categories, based on weather conditions, passenger load, aircraft readiness, etc. Similarly, it is important to classify AI use cases into different categories early on to decide the extent of transparency measures to be implemented within the use case to mitigate the associated risks appropriately.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What does it include: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This would include classification based on low, medium, high impact (on individuals for e.g.), critically of the sector in which the use case is operationalized (HR, Finance being on the higher criticality side), automation levels (fully automated decision-making being highly critical), tool access (especially for agent use cases, in order to avoid cascading harms), regulatory exposure (For e.g. healthcare being highly regulated), etc. Considering this classification, for appropriate transparency:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Human oversight mechanisms should be appropriately adjusted.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Retention period for the audit logs should be proportional to the impact.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;High impact use cases should have rollback mechanisms and hence related documentation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Impact should be linked to internal responsible AI policies around transparency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In practice: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At SAP, every AI use case goes through the AI Ethics Review process that categorizes them into different categories according to the respective ethical impact. A detailed blogpost around the AI ethics governance process at SAP will be published soon as part of this blogpost series around AI transparency. For now,&amp;nbsp;to learn more about how the process works, please refer to the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/03/7211ee96-647e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP AI Ethics Handbook&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (chapter “Principles into action”) in which categorization criteria and governance setup are described in more details (or watch the “Governing AI Ethics at SAP” lesson of the SAP Learning Journey &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/putting-ai-ethics-into-practice-at-sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Putting AI Ethics into Practice at SAP”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI's Pre‑flight checklists: Transparency &amp;amp; explainability prerequisites&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Airplanes are never shipped without a complete ticked off checklist. Similarly, AI features should never be shipped without passing a Transparency &amp;amp; explainability checklist. This list should also be passed down the chain to relevant stakeholders who can then use this at different checkpoints and keep an eye out for deviations and document these parameters. This not only includes architectural transparency, but also other components of overall engineering side of AI development related quality checks focusing on transparency and explainability which should be provided to relevant stakeholders within the enterprise and to the system admins at the customer/user side.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What does it include: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A pre-flight checklist for AI transparency should mandate architectural transparency by documenting system purpose, data sources, model type, and limitations; confirm explainability readiness&amp;nbsp;wherever AI influences outcomes; and verify compliance hooks aligned with regulatory anchors like the EU AI Act. This checklist must integrate into the development workflow by linking items to backlog tools and making transparency a release gate item. No feature ships without proof of appropriate transparency and explainability. It should also be distributed across stakeholders including architects, QA, product owners, and system admins, with checkpoints for deviations during lifecycle changes (something on the lines of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/fiori-design-web/v1-136/discover/get-started" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Design System Guidelines&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;). Alongside this, evidence packs should be stored in a central repository linked to project management tools for auditability. Finally, for high-risk AI systems, add enhanced monitoring and troubleshooting documentation for deployment and operations to ensure resilience and compliance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In practic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;e:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Transparency and explainability requirements are very different for different application contexts, situations and user personas (as explained in this blogpost: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/trustworthy-ai-how-to-make-artificial-intelligence-understandable/ba-p/13576857" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trustworthy AI: How to make artificial intelligenc... - SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;). The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/fiori-design-web/v1-120/foundations/ai-and-joule-design/guidelines/explainable-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Fiori Design Guidelines for explainable AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; take this variety of expectations into account by differentiating between L1/L2/L3 explanations: Level 1: Minimum explanation level for quick overview; Level 2: Condensed view of the relevant properties, amounts and contextual information; Level 3: Extended report specifically for advanced users covering details around the AI performance, further context and conditions for monitoring AI operations). Applied to an SAP use case, the need for end-user transparency is very obvious when it comes to HR related contexts, e. g. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Fieldglass/d90e4d56084b4540b73e72fc822b8fc9/312e889200ba4abb82a3a64a530595e4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;candidate analysis in recruiting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. In the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/putting-ai-ethics-into-practice-at-sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learning Journey&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; lesson “Ensuring Explainability in HR AI Systems”, our experts share how the team addressed the requirements during implementation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Closing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transparency isn’t a checklist you tick once, it’s a culture that starts at ideation and validation and continues through every stage of the AI lifecycle. By embedding stakeholder mapping, risk classification, and compliance gates early, we create a foundation where trust is engineered, not promised. These steps ensure that transparency is not an afterthought but a design principle that shapes every decision.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the next blog post, we’ll move beyond planning and delve deeper into practice, exploring how transparency can be operationalized during realization, productization, and operations stages, with concrete engineering patterns. Together, these two parts outline key engineering practices for integrating transparency into AI systems aligned with the principles of lawfulness, ethics, and robustness.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="abhishek_pant01_0-1764838167771.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348424i5F7FE3DCB12CEB35/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="abhishek_pant01_0-1764838167771.png" alt="abhishek_pant01_0-1764838167771.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's keep sharing how &lt;STRONG&gt;AI transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt; helps &lt;STRONG&gt;keep_the_blue_side_up&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned for the next part of this blogpost with further deep dive into the &lt;STRONG&gt;engineering practices&lt;/STRONG&gt; around AI transparency!!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References and further readings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI Transparency Blogpost Series&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introductory Blogpost:&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/keep-the-blue-side-up-building-trust-in-ai-through-transparency-responsible/ba-p/14269929" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keep the blue side up: Building trust in AI throug... - SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explainability Blogpost: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/trustworthy-ai-how-to-make-artificial-intelligence-understandable/ba-p/13576857" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trustworthy AI: How to make artificial intelligenc... - SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI Transparency &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Design workshops: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://apphaus.sap.com/resource/business-ai-design-workshop,;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://apphaus.sap.com/resource/business-ai-design-workshop;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A href="https://apphaus.sap.com/resource/business-ai-explore-workshop" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://apphaus.sap.com/resource/business-ai-explore-workshop&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Testing and Monitoring Features within Agent Builder: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-studio/product-tour.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule Studio | AI Agent Builder | Product tour&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explainable AI Design Guidelines: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/design-system/fiori-design-web/v1-120/foundations/ai-and-joule-design/guidelines/explainable-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.sap.com/design-system/fiori-design-web/v1-120/foundations/ai-and-joule-design/guidelines/explainable-ai&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Responsible AI Assets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Blogpost explaining Trustworthy AI: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/trustworthy-ai-how-to-make-artificial-intelligence-understandable/ba-p/13576857" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trustworthy AI: How to make artificial intelligenc... - SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP AI Ethics Policy and Handbook: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-ethics.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Responsible AI | SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learning Journey: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/putting-ai-ethics-into-practice-at-sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/putting-ai-ethics-into-practice-at-sap&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Compliance &amp;amp; certification information-SAP Trust Center:&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Aviation Safety Research&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mdpi.com/2313-576X/11/2/56" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrated Framework for Implementing Safety-I and Safety-II Principles in Aviation Safety Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://ijsra.net/sites/default/files/IJSRA-2024-2588.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhancing modern aviation systems through systems engineering principles and emerging technologies&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regulations and governance frameworks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iso.org/standard/42001" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ISO/IEC 42001:2023 - AI management systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;EU Artificial Intelligence Act | Up-to-date developments and analyses of the EU AI Act&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence-blogs-posts/defining-safe-ai-transparency-within-ideation-and-validation/ba-p/14283700"/>
    <published>2025-12-04T15:44:19.695000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/explore-sap-business-ai-innovations-on-sap-roadmap-explorer-today/ba-p/14278752</id>
    <title>Explore SAP Business AI Innovations on SAP Roadmap Explorer Today</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T16:07:04.245000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Paul_P</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/64</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At SAP, we are committed to embedding AI capabilities directly into our core applications and processes with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business AI,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; designed to deliver tangible, real-world business outcomes across the enterprise.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Navigating this dynamic landscape is key: understanding what’s coming next, when features or agents are available, and how they could improve end-to-end business processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That’s why we are thrilled to announce a new and dedicated roadmap experience for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/business-views/A39622A5AFE542D1A81FC4B6DF4DABDC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business AI on the SAP Roadmap Explorer website&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; available today.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This new experience encompasses:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A new banner on the SAP Roadmap Explorer home page&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A new ‘Strategic Topics’ menu where SAP Business AI is featured&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A new business view page for SAP Business AI that offers the transparency you need into SAP’s AI product strategy, development priorities, and upcoming innovations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/business-views/A39622A5AFE542D1A81FC4B6DF4DABDC" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Capture d’écran 2025-12-04 à 16.05.02.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348601i8C18ACD13DC987A3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Capture d’écran 2025-12-04 à 16.05.02.png" alt="Capture d’écran 2025-12-04 à 16.05.02.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let's focus on the new business view page, which is a perfect asset to move from high-level announcements to access granular details about specific AI features and agents and their anticipated release timelines.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This allows you to deep dive into the different road map priorities per Line of Business (LoB), such as Spend Management or Human Capital Management, giving you deeper insights to make informed, timely decisions that drive tangible business outcomes. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can rapidly evaluate SAP’s AI offerings against your unique business requirements, thereby accelerating your innovation cycles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/business-views/A39622A5AFE542D1A81FC4B6DF4DABDC" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Capture d’écran 2025-12-04 à 16.06.28.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348606iBFB7C5C7089013BA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Capture d’écran 2025-12-04 à 16.06.28.png" alt="Capture d’écran 2025-12-04 à 16.06.28.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The roadmap acts as a living document, reducing the risk of making uninformed decisions based on outdated or incomplete information. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can also leverage the latest ‘notification’ feature available on SAP Roadmap Explorer by clicking on the ‘subscribe’ button on the right-hand side of the page to get notified as soon as it’s updated by SAP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By providing transparency and ability to deep dive into LoB-specific innovations across time, it empowers everyone to confidently embark on their AI journey, maximize investments, and harness the transformative power of SAP Business AI. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We encourage all SAP Community members, customers, and partners to regularly visit &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/welcome" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;roadmap.sap.com&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and explore the future of SAP Business AI.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/explore-sap-business-ai-innovations-on-sap-roadmap-explorer-today/ba-p/14278752"/>
    <published>2025-12-04T16:07:04.245000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-hidden-behavior-of-llms-prompt-caching-and-determinism/ba-p/14285663</id>
    <title>The Hidden Behavior of LLMs - Prompt Caching and Determinism</title>
    <updated>2025-12-08T08:17:36.779000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>santhosini_K</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/138505</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="7"&gt;The Hidden Behavior of LLMs - The LLM Prompt Caching and Determinism&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Are LLMs Really Stateless?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="3"&gt;A Developer’s Deep Dive Into the &lt;STRONG&gt;Hidden Behavior of LLMs&lt;/STRONG&gt; (with code-gen as the use case)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction: The "Wait, What?" Moment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;I recently started building a code generation tool using Large Language Models (LLMs) via API calls. Like many of you, I learned the golden rule of LLM development early on: &lt;STRONG&gt;LLMs are stateless.&lt;/STRONG&gt; They don’t "remember" past requests; every API call is a fresh start.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;But as I tested my tool, I noticed something that confused me.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Whenever I made changes in my prompt instructions:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The output was perfect!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;When I changed &lt;EM&gt;nothing&lt;/EM&gt; and sent the exact same request:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The output still changed!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;I expected that if the inputs were identical (and the model is stateless), the result should be consistent. This inconsistency led me down a rabbit hole of research where I landed on a feature that completely changed how I optimize my workflows: &lt;STRONG&gt;Prompt Caching.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;If you are building AI Agents or Code Gen tools on SAP BTP (using SAP Generative AI Hub) or directly via provider APIs, this is a mechanism you need to understand—not just for speed, but to clear up the "caching" misconception.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Myth Buster: "Prompt Cache" NE "Response Cache"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Here is the inference I made during my research, which might clear up your confusion too:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Reality:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Prompt Caching does not cache the answer.&lt;/STRONG&gt; It caches the &lt;STRONG&gt;question.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;When we hear "Cache" in software development (like SAP ABAP or SAP HANA), we think of storing the &lt;EM&gt;result&lt;/EM&gt; to serve it instantly next time. &lt;STRONG&gt;Prompt Caching is different.&lt;/STRONG&gt; It caches the &lt;STRONG&gt;pre-computation of your input context&lt;/STRONG&gt; (the Key-Value states of the attention mechanism). It essentially "pre-loads" the model's brain with your long documents, codebases, or instructions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;However, the &lt;STRONG&gt;generation&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the response is still calculated fresh, token by token. This brings us to the second major realization—why your output changes even when the prompt doesn't.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The "Temperature=0" Trap: Why It’s Still Not Deterministic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;You might think, &lt;EM&gt;"If the prompt is cached and I set Temperature to 0, shouldn't the output be identical every time?"&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;The short answer: No.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;The technical answer: Modern LLMs are only "mostly" deterministic, even at Temperature=0.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;While setting the temperature to 0 forces &lt;STRONG&gt;greedy decoding&lt;/STRONG&gt; (always picking the highest-probability next token), real-world infrastructure introduces subtle variations:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) Architecture:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Models like GPT-4 are believed to use a "Sparse MoE" design. Different "expert" subnetworks handle different parts of your input. Parallel routing and slight gating differences can introduce non-determinism in the path your data takes.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GPU "Fuzziness":&lt;/STRONG&gt; Modern GPUs perform massive parallel operations. Because floating-point arithmetic is non-associative, the order of operations can shift slightly based on thread scheduling. A microscopic rounding error can flip a token choice when two words have nearly identical probabilities.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System Variance:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Your request might hit a different backend instance or hardware generation (indicated by the system_fingerprint in OpenAI responses).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Takeaway:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Even with a cached prompt and zero temperature, expect minor "drift" in your outputs. The prompt cache speeds up the &lt;EM&gt;input&lt;/EM&gt; processing, but the &lt;EM&gt;output&lt;/EM&gt; generation remains subject to the complex physics of AI hardware.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How It Works: Implicit vs. Explicit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Different vendors handle this differently. If you are using models via SAP Generative AI Hub, it's crucial to know how the underlying models behave.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Implicit Caching (The "It Just Works" Approach)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vendors:&lt;/STRONG&gt; OpenAI (GPT-4.1), Google (Gemini)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mechanism:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You don't need to change your code. If the API detects that the first 1,024+ tokens of your prompt match a previous request sent recently, it automatically uses the cached processing.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pros:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Zero developer effort.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cons:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Less control over what stays in the cache.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Explicit Caching (The "Precision" Approach)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vendor:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Anthropic (Claude 3.5 and &amp;gt; Sonnet/Haiku)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mechanism:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You must explicitly tell the API where to stop caching. You insert a cache_control parameter at a specific "checkpoint" in your message history.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pros:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You guarantee that your heavy context (like a full ABAP codebase or API specification) is cached.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cons:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Requires a small code change.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Common Practice for Agentic AI &amp;amp; Code Gen&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;In my code generation use case, I send the entire project context (libraries, style guides, and current code) with every request. Without caching, this is slow and expensive.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;The Strategy:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Organize your prompt so the static content is at the top.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System Prompt&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Static: "You are an ABAP Expert...")&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Context/Documentation&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Static: "Here is the SAP Cloud SDK documentation...") -&amp;gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;[CACHE CHECKPOINT]&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Query&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Dynamic: "Write a method to fetch Business Partners.")&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;By placing the checkpoint after the documentation, the model "reads" the docs once. For every subsequent user query, it skips the heavy lifting and jumps straight to generating code.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Verifying the Speed Up: Analyze Your Logs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;How do you know it's working? You won't see "same output," but you will see "faster time-to-first-token."&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Look at the usage metadata in your API response.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OpenAI:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Look for cached_tokens in the usage object.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Anthropic:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Look for cache_read_input_tokens.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Google Gemini:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Look for cachedContentTokenCount.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example Analysis:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Request 1 (Cold):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Input Tokens: 10,000 | Processing Time: 4.5s&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Request 2 (Warm):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Input Tokens: 10,000 (9,900 Cached!) | Processing Time: &lt;STRONG&gt;0.8s&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why could this be a game-changer?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Latency:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The model doesn't have to "read" your 5,000-line code file every time. It "remembers" the reading process.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cost:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You pay significantly less (often ~90% less) for the cached tokens.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;If you see the processing time drop drastically while the output remains high-quality (and slightly varied), you have successfully implemented Prompt Caching.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Personal Inference: The "Bad Roll" &amp;amp; The Butterfly Effect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;During my testing, I encountered a frustrating scenario that I believe many developers will face.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Scenario:&lt;/STRONG&gt; I used OpenAI for code generation. When the prompt was cached (no changes), the code quality was consistently "not perfect"—it had minor bugs or incomplete logic.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Fix:&lt;/STRONG&gt; When I added just &lt;STRONG&gt;one single word&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the prompt, the code generation suddenly became perfect.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Contrast:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Switching to Anthropic (without caching) gave me complete code every time.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why did adding one word fix the OpenAI output?&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is what I call the &lt;STRONG&gt;"Deterministic Trap."&lt;/STRONG&gt; When you use a cached prompt with a low temperature (which we usually do for code), the model is mathematically locked into a specific "reasoning path." If the model generates a suboptimal solution (a "bad roll") on the first try, the cached state ensures it starts from the &lt;EM&gt;exact same mathematical position&lt;/EM&gt; next time. It essentially "remembers" the path to the bad answer.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;By adding a single word, I forced a &lt;STRONG&gt;"Cache Miss"&lt;/STRONG&gt; (or at least a perturbation in the attention mechanism). This acted like the "Butterfly Effect"—it shifted the token probabilities just enough to force the model to calculate a fresh path, allowing it to escape the "bad roll" and find the correct solution.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Lesson:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Prompt Caching is powerful for speed, but if you notice your model is "stuck" giving you the same bad code repeatedly, don't just retry. &lt;STRONG&gt;Change the prompt.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Even a single extra adjective can shake the model out of a local minimum and produce the perfect result.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;LLMs are stateless, but Prompt Caching gives them a "short-term memory" for processing inputs. While it won't force your outputs to be bit-for-bit identical (due to MoE and GPU nuances), it &lt;STRONG&gt;will&lt;/STRONG&gt; make your applications significantly faster and cheaper to run.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next Step:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Check your current API logs. If you are sending long contexts (&amp;gt;1024 tokens) repeatedly, you might already be benefiting from implicit caching, or you may need to add cache_control headers for Anthropic models to unlock these savings.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References &amp;amp; Further Reading&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Anthropic Prompt Caching:&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/build-with-claude/prompt-caching" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/build-with-claude/prompt-caching&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OpenAI Prompt Caching:&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://platform.openai.com/docs/guides/prompt-caching" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://platform.openai.com/docs/guides/prompt-caching&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Google Gemini Context Caching:&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://ai.google.dev/gemini-api/docs/caching" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://ai.google.dev/gemini-api/docs/caching&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Generative AI Hub:&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://www.google.com/search?q=https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-ai-core/generative-ai-hub" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-ai-core/generative-ai-hub&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-hidden-behavior-of-llms-prompt-caching-and-determinism/ba-p/14285663"/>
    <published>2025-12-08T08:17:36.779000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
