<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Artificial-Intelligence-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Artificial Intelligence</title>
  <updated>2025-11-15T00:10:05.937009+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Artificial Intelligence/pd-p/c3c3a408-33ea-4c2a-ae6f-05461e76982d" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Artificial Intelligence blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-kpmg-firms-are-helping-to-build-next-generation-ai-agents-with-joule/ba-p/14258178</id>
    <title>How KPMG firms are helping to build next-generation AI agents with Joule Studio</title>
    <updated>2025-11-03T13:55:47.589000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vkoester</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5691</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1634758849"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;As enterprises increasingly shift toward intelligent automation and generative AI-driven workflows, the ability to embed purpose-built AI agents into the enterprise landscape is fast becoming a competitive differentiator. KPMG firms are proudly participating in the early adopter program with SAP, leveraging our role as an alliance partner to explore the capabilities of the Joule Studio’s AI Agent Builder. Together, we are focused on developing next-generation AI agents specifically designed for enterprise operations. This collaboration allows KPMG firms to co-create and pilot innovative solutions, addressing real-world use cases with cutting-edge technology.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;In the sections that follow, we cover why KPMG chose Joule Studio, the portfolio of agents we are building, how the building works (including a deeper dive on two selected use cases), and what this means for enterprise AI going forward.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1438245344"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why KPMG chose Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;The enterprise AI agenda is no longer about isolated pilots or theatrical proofs-of-concept: it is about embedding intelligence into core business processes, at scale, with trust and governance in place. With Joule Studio’s Agent Builder (part of SAP Build), KPMG saw an opportunity to use a purpose-built platform for creating agents that integrate seamlessly into SAP’s cloud ecosystem (such as Cloud ERP and LoB solutions) with components such as the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) and generative AI capabilities.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;As a selected alliance partner, KPMG firms were able to access early program capabilities, shape the program scope and roadmap, and bring a use case portfolio into a scalable architecture. Our goal was to deliver tangible business value, enable faster time to market, and ensure the resulting solutions are aligned with business needs and not just technical capabilities.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1241731839"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What KPMG has built using Joule Studio’s AI Agent Builder:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Here is an overview of the first wave of agent-use-cases KPMG has developed using Joule Studio’s AI Agent Builder:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Inventory Exposure Analyzer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Industry: Cross-Industry | LoB: Supply Chain | Business Process: Inventory Management&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;This AI agent detects aging or obsolete inventory across SAP S/4HANA, classifies risks, and recommends actions like redistribution or markdowns. It simulates financial impacts before execution, enabling supply chain teams to reduce working capital, free up cash, and respond faster to demand or supply shifts.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tariff Control-Tower &amp;amp; Real-Time Alerting for Re-Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Industry: Cross-Industry | LoB: Supply Chain | Business Process: Global Trade and Planning&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;This AI agent tracks global tariff and duty changes, alerting planners to impacts from trade policies or currency shifts. It triggers re-planning recommendations in SAP IBP or SAP S/4HANA, enabling proactive responses to market volatility and helping businesses protect margins and maintain profitability in dynamic global conditions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Agentic Approach on Inefficient and Inaccurate Returns Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Industry: Retail &amp;amp; Fashion | LoB: Supply Chain | Business Process: Order-to-Cash (Return Mgmt.)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;This Joule Agent analyzes return data from SAP S/4HANA and external sources to detect high-return products, repeat customers, or fraud. It identifies root causes like listing errors or quality issues and recommends corrective actions - reducing return rates, minimizing fraud, and improving customer satisfaction for retailers.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Warehouse Operation Joule Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Industry: Cross-Industry | LoB: Supply Chain | Business Process: Warehouse Management&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;This agent integrates with SAP EWM to optimize warehouse tasks, slotting, and workload balance in real time. It detects bottlenecks, reallocates tasks dynamically, and uses predictive analytics via Joule Studio to help logistics teams boost throughput, reduce idle time, and achieve more responsive, efficient warehouse operations.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart eCommerce Fulfillment Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;Industry: Retail &amp;amp; Consumer Goods | LoB: Supply Chain | Business Process: Fulfillment &amp;amp; Order Mgmt. &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;This agent connects SAP S/4HANA, SAP Commerce Cloud, and logistics providers to orchestrate real-time fulfillment. It optimizes order routing based on priority, carrier, and stock availability, and triggers automated recovery for delays or stockouts - ensuring on-time delivery, reduced logistics costs, and an enhanced customer experience.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;Supplier Risk Monitoring &amp;amp; Dynamic Sourcing&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Industry: Cross-Industry | LoB: Spend Management | Business Process: Risk &amp;amp; Sourcing&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;This solution uses AI agents in SAP Joule to monitor high-risk suppliers, find alternatives, estimate onboarding timelines, and trigger sourcing events in SAP Ariba via natural language prompts. Built on SAP BTP, it automates workflows, reduces manual effort, and enhances supply chain resilience and profitability.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Field Service Scheduling Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Industry: Field Service | LoB: Supply Chain &amp;amp; Service | Business Process: Service &amp;amp; Maintenance Scheduling &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;This agent automates field service scheduling by matching technician skills, routes, and part availability across SAP S/4HANA and calendars. It proposes optimal timeslots, notifies technicians, and updates systems automatically - enabling faster dispatch, higher first-time-fix rates, and fewer SLA breaches through an intuitive Joule Agent workflow.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Together, this portfolio demonstrates the breadth and depth of what can be achieved when Joule Studio is applied through a KPMG lens of business relevance, process alignment and rapid value creation.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1045218334"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How: The KPMG approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977787548"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Approach &amp;amp; methodology&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Our build methodology follows the guiding principles from our whitepaper: holistic, human, business-led (&lt;A href="https://kpmg.com/xx/en/what-we-do/alliances/kpmg-and-sap/harness-the-power-of-ai-with-kpmg-and-sap.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;KPMG and SAP AI whitepaper&lt;/A&gt;). Starting with business value-discovery workshops, we can identify high-impact agent-use-cases, evaluate fit for Joule Studio, define target operating models, and align with governance, trust and human oversight frameworks. From there we move into agile development, prototyping with Joule Studio AI Agent Builder, integration via SAP BTP services, embedding into SAP application processes, and finally producing a roadmap for scaling, monitoring and continuous improvement.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781274043"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role of SAP Joule for Consultants&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;An important enabler of the build is &lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/03/kpmg-sap-joule-for-consultants-ai-driven-consulting/?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Joule for Consultants&lt;/A&gt;. While Joule Studio allows us to build customer-facing agents, SAP Joule for Consultants empowers KPMG consultants with internal copilot capabilities accelerating discovery, design and deployment by surfacing expert-level SAP knowledge and best practices. This dual capability of internal acceleration plus external solution delivery creates a multiplier effect: faster build times, stronger alignment with SAP landscape, and deeper value for clients.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584760538"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From Concept to impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;The next two deep dive use cases illustrate how KPMG firms are leveraging Joule Studio to help tackle real-world challenges with AI solutions.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000080"&gt;Use case one: Inventory Exposure Analyzer&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Business challenge:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Manufacturers and retailers lose millions each year from aging and obsolete inventory. Traditional manual processes identify risks too late, leading to high carrying costs, write-offs, and missed sales caused by stockouts.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Solution overview:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;The Inventory Exposure Analyzer, built with Joule Studio’s AI Agent Builder, transforms inventory management into a proactive, data-driven process. The agent continuously scans SAP S/4HANA data, detects early signs of obsolescence, classifies risks, and recommends actions such as redistribution or markdowns. Users can simulate financial-impact scenarios before execution, freeing up working capital and improving responsiveness.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Architecture diagram:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="vkoester_0-1761938301942.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334836i3069BA6F6CA9F72F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="vkoester_0-1761938301942.png" alt="vkoester_0-1761938301942.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;SAP component stack:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;SAP BTP Build Work Zone • SAP CAP Application • SAP S/4HANA Cloud • Joule Studio (Custom Skills + Agent Builder) • SAP BTP AI Foundation – Generative AI Hub&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;The outcome and observations:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;An approximate 20% reduction in write-offs and approximately15% decrease in working capital, which helps drive faster decision-making via real-time visibility and automated recommendations.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Help maintain task-specific agent focused, integrate historical data to help enable predictive intelligence, and control AI instruction limits through external logic.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000080"&gt;Use case two: Tariff Control-Tower &amp;amp; Real-Time Alerting for Re-Planning&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Business challenge:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Manufacturers face constant shifts in tariffs and trade regulations that disrupt sourcing, cost forecasts, and profitability. Existing monitoring processes are reactive, time-consuming, and prone to compliance errors.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Solution overview:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;The Tariff Control Tower agent, built in Joule Studio, continuously tracks global tariff and duty changes, analyzes the impact on sourcing and logistics, and issues real-time replanning alerts. By integrating external trade data with SAP S/4HANA and the KPMG Signals Repository, it enables proactive, data-driven decision-making for supply chain and procurement teams.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Architecture diagram:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="vkoester_1-1761938372418.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334837i5DFBAE2834694647/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="vkoester_1-1761938372418.png" alt="vkoester_1-1761938372418.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;SAP component stack:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;SAP BTP Build Work Zone • SAP S/4HANA Cloud • Joule Studio AI Agent Builder • SAP BTP AI Foundation – Generative AI Hub • SAP S/4HANA • SAP IBP • KPMG Signal Repository&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;The outcome and observations:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Help to deliver faster tariff-impact response, reduced compliance risk, optimized sourcing decisions, and improved profitability through cost re-planning.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Modular skill design improves scalability; integrating historical and external data enhances predictive value; externalizing logic mitigates instruction limits.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-259164314"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-62650809"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technology &amp;amp; Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Full technical details are shown in the architecture diagrams above; key elements of the build include:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Build agents in Joule Studio using natural-language workflows, integrating SAP and non-SAP data services&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Deploy within SAP’s cloud-native stack (SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), Data &amp;amp; Analytics, Integration Services) for secure, scalable operation&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Apply human-in-the-loop governance and trust frameworks aligned to the KPMG Trusted AI principles&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Embed the agent in core business processes (e.g., supply chain orchestration, inbound/outbound logistics, returns management) rather than as stand-alone bots&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Provide developers and architects with tooling, accelerators, and reference libraries (via KPMG and SAP) to help speed up delivery and enhance reuse&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--133862696"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-439363882"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion &amp;amp; Outlook&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;In a world where generative AI hype abounds, the differentiator will likely be those organizations that embed intelligence into day-to-day operations, aligned with business value, trusted frameworks and enterprise-grade platform architecture. Through our alliance with SAP and early adoption of Joule Studio, KPMG firms are proud to help shape that future.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;We have delivered a portfolio of AI agents spanning inventory analytics, trade tariffs, fulfilment orchestration, field service scheduling and supplier risk monitoring each architected to drive measurable business outcomes. As we scale these agents into larger client engagements, our focus remains on delivering &lt;STRONG&gt;trusted, value-centric, business-led AI solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Looking ahead to 2026 and beyond, the pace of change will likely accelerate: more real-time data, more autonomous decisions, more domain-specific agents. KPMG and SAP are ready to help clients move beyond pilots into full-scale, embedded AI agent deployment.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-242850377"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-46336872"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Call to Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Learn more about how KPMG and SAP are unlocking AI-powered transformation to help transform your business with confidence: &lt;A href="https://kpmg.com/xx/en/what-we-do/alliances/kpmg-and-sap/unleash-the-power-of-ai-with-kpmg-and-sap.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Unleash the power of AI with KPMG and SAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-kpmg-firms-are-helping-to-build-next-generation-ai-agents-with-joule/ba-p/14258178"/>
    <published>2025-11-03T13:55:47.589000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management-blog-posts/ki-agenten-bei-sap-%C3%BCberblick-beispiele-umsetzung-und-adoption-mit-jochen/ba-p/14259318</id>
    <title>KI-Agenten bei SAP: Überblick, Beispiele, Umsetzung und Adoption mit Jochen Schneider</title>
    <updated>2025-11-03T15:17:12.245000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ThomasJenewein</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/594</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Stell Dir vor, du gibst deinem zehnjährigen Kind morgens die Anweisung: "In zehn Minuten fahren wir zur Schule." Was passiert? Im Idealfall zieht es sich selbstständig an – Hose, Schuhe, Jacke – und steht bereit. Genau so funktionieren KI-Agenten. Diese Metapher nutzt &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sjochen/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Jochen Schneider&lt;/A&gt;, verantwortlich für AI Capabilities auf der SAP Business Technology Platform, um zu erklären, was Agentic AI von herkömmlichen Gen-AI-Lösungen unterscheidet. Im aktuellen &lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/education-newscast/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;EducationNewscast&lt;/A&gt; gibt er einen umfassenden Einblick in die Welt der KI-Agenten bei SAP – von den Grundlagen über praktische Beispiele bis hin zu konkreten Tipps für den Einstieg.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Hier eine Zusammenfassung des fast einstündigen Interviews und Gespräch - reinhören könnt ihr hier auf &lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/education-newscast/2025/10/27/enc374-ki-agenten-bei-sap-uberblick-beispiele-nutzung-und-adoption-mit-jochen-schneider/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;SAP-Podcasts -&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://podcasts.apple.com/de/podcast/enc374-ki-agenten-bei-sap-%C3%BCberblick-beispiele-nutzung/id1352307529?i=1000733653247" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Apple&lt;/A&gt; - oder &lt;A class="" href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5hsuELMNmsySwkMeZDcC4d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Spotify.&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Da das Thema so wichtig und spannend ist, denke ich, dass eine Zusammenfassung des Talks auch hier in der Gruppe von Interesse ist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AIAgenten.png" style="width: 869px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335427i2D75D43AB018E67F/image-dimensions/869x739/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="869" height="739" role="button" title="AIAgenten.png" alt="AIAgenten.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763873095"&gt;Was KI-Agenten wirklich ausmacht&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Der Unterschied zwischen einem klassischen Chatbot oder Assistenten und einem KI-Agenten ist fundamental. Während du bei ChatGPT einen Prompt eingibst und eine Antwort erhältst, arbeiten Agenten deutlich komplexer und autonomer. Jochen erklärt das Prinzip anhand seiner Kinder: Du gibst nicht jeden einzelnen Schritt vor ("Zieh die Hose an, dann die Schuhe"), sondern beschreibst das gewünschte Ergebnis. Der Agent findet dann selbst heraus, welche Schritte nötig sind, um dieses Ziel zu erreichen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Damit ein Agent funktioniert, braucht er drei zentrale Komponenten: &lt;STRONG&gt;Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt; (die "Hände", um Aktionen auszuführen), &lt;STRONG&gt;Reasoning-Fähigkeiten&lt;/STRONG&gt; (den "Kopf", um Entscheidungen zu treffen) und &lt;STRONG&gt;Memory&lt;/STRONG&gt; (das "Gedächtnis", um Kontext zu behalten und aus Erfahrungen zu lernen). Diese Kombination ermöglicht es Agenten, komplexe Aufgaben eigenständig zu bewältigen, ohne dass du jeden Zwischenschritt vorgeben musst.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ein wichtiger Punkt, den Jochen betont: Nicht alles sollte oder muss zum Agenten werden. Es gibt aktuell viel "Agent-Washing" – Workflows, die als Agenten verkauft werden, obwohl sie deterministisch ablaufen. Seine Empfehlung ist klar: Wenn du einen Prozess mit einem klassischen Workflow abbilden kannst, solltest du das tun. Das ist kostengünstiger und effizienter. Agenten zeigen ihre Stärke dort, wo Prozesse dynamisch, komplex und von äußeren Faktoren beeinflusst sind.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567359590"&gt;Wichtige Begriffe einfach erklärt&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Im Dialog mit Claude über den Podcast habe ich festgestellt, dass doch einige Fachbegriffe im Podcast vorkamen. Bevor wir in die Details eintauchen, hier die wichtigsten Fachbegriffe, die im Podcast und in dieser Zusammenfassung vorkommen – verständlich erklärt. (War kein Teil des Podcasts, KI Experten können das einfach überspringen).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic AI / KI-Agenten&lt;/STRONG&gt; Softwaresysteme, die eigenständig Ziele verfolgen und dabei selbst entscheiden, welche Schritte nötig sind. Anders als klassische Programme, die Schritt für Schritt Anweisungen befolgen, bekommen Agenten nur das Ziel vorgegeben und finden den Weg dorthin selbst. Wie ein Mitarbeiter, dem du sagst "Organisiere das Meeting", statt "Schreibe eine E-Mail an Person X, buche Raum Y, bestelle Catering Z".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tokens&lt;/STRONG&gt; Die "Währung" von KI-Modellen. Texte werden in kleine Einheiten (Tokens) zerlegt – ungefähr 4 Zeichen pro Token. Jede Anfrage an ein KI-Modell und jede Antwort kostet Tokens, und damit Geld. "Tokens verbrennen" bedeutet: unnötig viele (teure) Anfragen an die KI stellen, z.B. wenn ein Agent in einer Endlosschleife hängt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deterministic vs. Non-Deterministic&lt;/STRONG&gt; Deterministisch = vorhersagbar. Bei einem klassischen Workflow weißt du genau: Bei Input A kommt immer Output B raus. Non-deterministisch = nicht vorhersagbar. Ein Agent kann bei derselben Aufgabe verschiedene Lösungswege wählen – wie ein Mensch, der kreativ an Probleme herangeht. Das macht Agenten flexibel, aber auch weniger kontrollierbar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reasoning&lt;/STRONG&gt; Die Fähigkeit eines KI-Modells, logisch zu denken, Schlussfolgerungen zu ziehen und Probleme zu lösen. Statt nur Muster aus Trainingsdaten zu wiederholen, können moderne Reasoning-Modelle mehrschrittige Überlegungen anstellen – ähnlich wie du bei einer komplexen Entscheidung Pro und Contra abwägst.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tools (im Agent-Kontext)&lt;/STRONG&gt; Die "Werkzeuge", die ein Agent nutzen kann, um Aufgaben zu erledigen. Das können APIs sein (um Daten abzurufen), Datenbanken (um Informationen zu suchen), oder Funktionen (um E-Mails zu versenden, Kalendereinträge zu erstellen etc.). Ohne Tools ist ein Agent wie ein Handwerker ohne Werkzeugkasten – er kann denken, aber nichts umsetzen. #Hände &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Memory (Short-Term &amp;amp; Long-Term)&lt;/STRONG&gt; Das "Gedächtnis" eines Agenten. Short-Term Memory = er erinnert sich an die aktuelle Konversation ("Du hast vorhin gesagt, dass..."). Long-Term Memory = er speichert Informationen über längere Zeit ("Letzten Monat hattest du nach X gefragt"). Ohne Memory müsstest du einem Agenten jedes Mal alles neu erklären.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Human in the Loop&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ein Kontrollmechanismus, bei dem ein Mensch an kritischen Punkten eingebunden wird, bevor der Agent eine Aktion ausführt. Wie ein Vier-Augen-Prinzip: Der Agent schlägt vor, der Mensch entscheidet. Besonders wichtig bei sensiblen Aufgaben oder am Anfang, wenn du dem Agenten noch nicht voll vertraust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Evals (Evaluations)&lt;/STRONG&gt; Automatisierte Tests, die kontinuierlich prüfen, ob ein Agent die gewünschte Qualität liefert. Ähnlich wie Qualitätskontrollen in der Produktion: Du definierst Kriterien (z.B. "Antworten müssen faktisch korrekt sein", "Prozess darf max. 5 Minuten dauern") und der Eval prüft regelmäßig, ob diese eingehalten werden.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Model Context Protocol (MCP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ein Standard von Androphic, der definiert, wie KI-Modelle auf externe Tools und Datenquellen zugreifen können. Stell dir vor, jedes Tool hätte einen anderen Stecker – MCP ist wie ein Universal-Adapter, der alles kompatibel macht. Das ermöglicht Agenten, flexibel verschiedene Werkzeuge zu nutzen, ohne dass für jedes eine spezielle Integration nötig ist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agent-to-Agent (A2A)&lt;/STRONG&gt; Kommunikation zwischen verschiedenen Agenten. Statt dass ein Agent alles alleine macht, können mehrere Agenten zusammenarbeiten – wie Kollegen in verschiedenen Abteilungen. Ein Agent analysiert ein Problem, ein anderer setzt die Lösung um, ein dritter überwacht das Ergebnis. A2A-Protokolle regeln, wie diese Zusammenarbeit funktioniert.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Edge Models&lt;/STRONG&gt; KI-Modelle, die direkt auf deinem Gerät (Smartphone, Laptop, IoT-Device) laufen, statt in der Cloud. "Edge" bedeutet "am Rand des Netzwerks", also bei dir vor Ort. Vorteil: Deine Daten bleiben auf deinem Gerät (Datenschutz!), und du brauchst keine Internetverbindung. Wird möglich, weil Modelle immer kleiner und Geräte immer leistungsfähiger werden.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;World Models&lt;/STRONG&gt; KI-Modelle, die nicht nur Sprache verstehen, sondern ein Verständnis der physischen Welt entwickeln – 3D-Raum, Bewegung, Ursache-Wirkung. Wie ein Kind, das durch Interaktion mit der Umwelt lernt. World Models können vorhersagen, was passiert, wenn ein Ball rollt oder ein Objekt fällt. Wichtig für Robotik und komplexere KI-Anwendungen, die in der realen Welt agieren.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Knowledge Graph&lt;/STRONG&gt; Eine strukturierte Datenbank, die Informationen als Netzwerk von Beziehungen speichert. Statt isolierter Datenpunkte siehst du Zusammenhänge: "Person A arbeitet bei Firma B", "Firma B hat Produkt C", "Produkt C wird in Land D verkauft". Hilft Agenten, Kontext zu verstehen und intelligentere Entscheidungen zu treffen. (Sehr spannend als Wissensmanagement Enthusiast, dazu muss ich noch ein Podcast mal machen).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TCO (Total Cost of Ownership)&lt;/STRONG&gt; Die Gesamtkosten, die eine Lösung über ihre gesamte Lebensdauer verursacht – nicht nur die Anschaffung, sondern auch Betrieb, Wartung, Schulung etc. Bei Agenten: Token-Kosten, Entwicklungsaufwand, Monitoring, Fehlerkorrektur. Manchmal ist ein einfacher Workflow TCO-mäßig besser als ein Agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow vs. Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; Der zentrale Unterschied: Ein &lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow&lt;/STRONG&gt; ist wie ein Rezept – du gibst jeden Schritt vor (wenn X, dann Y, sonst Z). Ein &lt;STRONG&gt;Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; ist wie ein Koch – du sagst "Mach ein leckeres Abendessen für 4 Personen", und er entscheidet selbst, welche Zutaten und Schritte nötig sind. Workflows sind günstiger und zuverlässiger für klar definierte Prozesse. Agenten sind besser für komplexe, dynamische Situationen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BTP (Business Technology Platform)&lt;/STRONG&gt; Die technologische Grundlage von SAP für Cloud-Anwendungen, Integrationen und – jetzt neu – KI-Agenten. Hier laufen die Modelle, hier werden Agenten entwickelt (im Joule Studio), hier greifen sie auf Unternehmensdaten zu. Die Plattform bietet Enterprise-Features wie Security, Skalierbarkeit und Compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAPs KI-Assistent, conversational Interface und gleichzeitig die zentrale Schnittstelle für Agenten. Joule ist mehr als ein Chatbot – es ist die Orchestrierungsebene, über die du mit Agenten interagierst, sie startest, überwachst und Feedback gibst. Denk an Joule als "Kontrollzentrum" für deine digitalen Mitarbeiter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;So - jetzt geht es weiter mit der Zusammenfassung des Podcast.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370846085"&gt;Züge auf Gleisen versus autonome Autos als Metaphern&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Um die Rolle von Agenten im Unternehmenskontext zu verdeutlichen, nutzt Jochen eine zweite einprägsame Metapher: Stell dir einen alten Zug auf Gleisen vor, daneben hochmoderne, vollautonome Autos auf einer Straße. Der Zug repräsentiert klassische, klar definierte Prozesse – sie laufen zuverlässig, transportieren viel und brauchen keine Änderung. Solange die Gleise frei sind, ist das perfekt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Problematisch wird es, wenn Unvorhergesehenes passiert: eine Baustelle, ein Hindernis auf den Gleisen, eine notwendige Routenänderung. Hier kommen die autonomen Autos ins Spiel – die KI-Agenten. Sie finden flexibel ihren Weg zum Ziel, auch wenn die Ideallinie blockiert ist. Sie transportieren zwar weniger als ein Zug, dafür kannst du viele gleichzeitig losschicken und sie passen sich dynamisch an veränderte Bedingungen an.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Diese Analogie macht deutlich: In der Unternehmenswelt der Zukunft werden beide Systeme koexistieren. Stabile, wenig änderungsbedürftige Prozesse bleiben bestehen. Agenten kommen dort zum Einsatz, wo Flexibilität, Anpassungsfähigkeit und komplexe Entscheidungsfindung gefragt sind – etwa bei sich ändernden Zollbestimmungen, individuellen Kundenanfragen oder komplexen Analyseaufgaben.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174332580"&gt;SAP Joule und die Rolle von Agenten&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Bei SAP läuft die Agent-Strategie über mehrere Ebenen zusammen. &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt; ist dabei weit mehr als nur ein Conversational Interface – es ist die zentrale Klammer, die Agenten zugänglich macht, sie orchestriert und dem Nutzer eine einheitliche Interaktionsfläche bietet. Jochen beschreibt Joule als das "Surface", hinter dem eine komplexe technologische Infrastruktur arbeitet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Agenten können auf verschiedene Arten getriggert werden: Entweder durch eine Konversation mit Joule ("Wie sieht mein Abverkauf diese Woche aus und was kann ich optimieren?") oder durch System-Trigger im Hintergrund, wenn sich bestimmte Daten ändern oder Ereignisse eintreten. Wenn ein Agent im Hintergrund auf ein Problem stößt und eskalieren muss, ist Joule die Instanz, die den Menschen einbindet – ähnlich wie ein Mitarbeiter zu seinem Manager geht, wenn er nicht weiterkommt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Die technologische Basis bildet die &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; mit dem AI Core für Model Access. Ein großer Vorteil: Du hast dort Zugriff auf über 40 verschiedene Modelle von allen großen Anbietern. Das ist wichtig, weil verschiedene Aufgaben unterschiedliche Modelle erfordern – für einfache Tasks nutzt man besser kostengünstige, kleine Modelle, für komplexe Reasoning-Aufgaben greifst du am besten auf leistungsstarke Modelle zurück.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977819075"&gt;Konkrete Beispiele aus der Praxis von KI-Agenten&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Jochen teilt mehrere spannende Use Cases, die zeigen, wo Agenten bereits heute Mehrwert schaffen. Ein offensichtliches Beispiel sind &lt;STRONG&gt;Service-Ticket-Agenten&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ein Ticket kommt rein, der Agent analysiert, ob der Claim gerechtfertigt ist, identifiziert die Fehlerquelle (eigene Seite, Supplier, Kunde) und schlägt eine Lösung vor. Bevor er diese umsetzt, bindet er den Menschen ein – der klassische "Human in the Loop".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Besonders interessant ist ein Beispiel aus Jochens eigenem Team: ein &lt;STRONG&gt;Pipeline-Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; für die Software-Entwicklung. Wenn bei einem Deployment Fehler auftreten, analysiert der Agent automatisch Logs mit zehntausenden Zeilen, identifiziert das Problem und schlägt eine Lösung vor. Ein zweiter Agent kann dann direkt den Code anpassen. Das spart nicht nur Zeit, sondern macht auch weniger erfahrene Entwickler produktiver, die früher auf Senior-Kollegen angewiesen waren.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Im &lt;STRONG&gt;HR-Bereich&lt;/STRONG&gt; gibt es Agenten für Karriereplanung und Zielentwicklung, im &lt;STRONG&gt;Finance-Bereich&lt;/STRONG&gt; unterstützen sie Power-User bei komplexen Analysen. Die Bandbreite reicht vom hochspezialisierten Tech-Experten bis zum Endnutzer, der seine persönliche Entwicklung plant. Jochen selbst nutzt privat einen Agenten, der seine E-Mails von der Schule zusammenfasst, wichtige Termine in den Kalender einträgt und ihn an Dinge erinnert, die sonst untergehen würden – gebaut mit &lt;A class="" href="http://lindy.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Lindy.ai&lt;/A&gt;, einem visuellen Low-Code-Framework. (Steht auf meiner To-Learn Liste).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781305570"&gt;Agenten bauen mit dem Joule Studio&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Die gute Nachricht: Einen Agenten im &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt; zu erstellen ist überraschend einfach – auch wenn technischer Sachverstand wichtig bleibt. Die Grundschritte sind überschaubar: Du gibst dem Agenten einen Namen, eine Rolle (z.B. Finance-Experte oder Service-Experte) und eine klare Instruction, die den gewünschten Outcome beschreibt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Dann stattest du ihn mit den nötigen &lt;STRONG&gt;Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt; aus – das umfasst Datenzugriffe, API-Schnittstellen und MCP-Tools (Model Context Protocol). Du entscheidest, auf welche Systeme der Agent zugreifen darf und welche Daten relevant sind. Anschließend wählst du das passende Modell: ein starkes Reasoning-Modell für komplexe Aufgaben, ein kleineres für einfache Tasks. Danach kannst du den Agenten bereits testen – die "Magic" passiert auf der Runtime im Framework.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Der Agent zerlegt den Auftrag selbstständig in Tasks, arbeitet diese ab und nutzt die verfügbaren Tools, um fehlende Informationen zu beschaffen. Jochen beschreibt einen Agenten als "LLM-Zugriff im Loop", der kontinuierlich durch neue Informationen von außen ergänzt wird. Das Joule Studio bietet dabei Enterprise-Grade-Features wie Security, Data Privacy, Scalability und Audit-Logs – Anforderungen, die viele andere Frameworks noch nicht erfüllen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ein wichtiger Aspekt ist die &lt;STRONG&gt;Granularität&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Wie komplex sollte ein Agent sein? Die Antwort hängt vom Business-Prozess ab. Viele Unternehmensprozesse sind sequenziell getaktet, weshalb Agent-to-Agent-Kommunikation (A2A) seltener nötig ist als zunächst gedacht. Oft reicht ein komplexer Agent oder eine sequenzielle Abfolge mehrerer Agenten – wie beim Pipeline-Beispiel, wo ein Agent analysiert und ein zweiter die Lösung umsetzt. Das ermöglicht auch, den Menschen zwischen den Schritten einzubinden.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584792065"&gt;Daten als Fundament von AI-Agents&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Agenten sind nur so gut wie die Daten, auf die sie zugreifen können. Dabei gilt nicht einfach "je mehr, desto besser", sondern: &lt;STRONG&gt;die richtigen Daten zur richtigen Zeit&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Zu viele Daten können einen Agenten sogar verwirren und die Qualität verschlechtern. Hier kommen Lösungen wie &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt; und &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; ins Spiel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;BDC bietet Data Products mit semantischer Beschreibung von Daten, spezifisch auf den Business-Kontext zugeschnitten. Das ist ein Riesenasset von SAP: Das Unternehmen kennt den Business-Kontext, weiß, wo sich der User bewegt, und kann über Joule und BDC genau die Informationen bereitstellen, die der Agent für seine Aufgabe braucht. Knowledge Graphs helfen dabei, Daten zu sortieren und Zusammenhänge zu verstehen – die Ontologie, also das Verständnis, wie Daten zusammengehören, ist entscheidend für die Qualität der Agent-Outputs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Diese tiefe Integration in die SAP-Systemlandschaft ermöglicht es Agenten, nicht nur E-Mails zu verschicken oder Zusammenfassungen zu erstellen, sondern wirklich datengetrieben auf Business-Daten zu arbeiten und komplexe Prozesse effizient durchzulaufen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-388278560"&gt;Der Weg zur Adoption von AI-Agents: Experimentieren, lernen, skalieren&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Wo stehen Unternehmen heute mit KI-Agenten? Jochen beobachtet zwei parallele Entwicklungen: Zum einen experimentieren alle Kunden, mit denen er spricht, auf verschiedenen Plattformen – von der BTP bis zu anderen Frameworks. Das ist wichtig, denn ein theoretisches Verständnis reicht nicht. Du musst einen Agenten gebaut und genutzt haben, um zu begreifen, was möglich ist – und was noch nicht.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Zum anderen starten viele mit &lt;STRONG&gt;Standard-Agenten&lt;/STRONG&gt;, um zu sehen, wie sich diese von klassischen Workflows unterscheiden und wie schnell sie im eigenen Unternehmen akzeptiert werden. Niemand wird 200 Agenten auf einmal ausrollen. Der Ansatz ist phasenweise: Wo habe ich gerade ein Problem? Welche Prozesse eignen sich für Agenten? Gibt es einen Standard-Agent, der passt, oder muss ich einen eigenen bauen?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ein interessanter Tipp von Jochen: Schau dir dein &lt;STRONG&gt;Backlog&lt;/STRONG&gt; an. Gibt es geplante Features oder Prozesse, die du mit einem Agenten komplett neu denken könntest? Intern bei SAP wird genau das gemacht – Teams prüfen, ob geplante Entwicklungen mit Agenten besser oder effizienter umgesetzt werden können.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Auch sprechen wir kurz über die &lt;STRONG&gt;"Pilot-Falle"&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Es ist heute relativ einfach, einen Wow-Effekt zu erzeugen und einen experimentellen Agenten zu bauen. Die eigentliche Arbeit beginnt danach – beim Produktisieren, beim Enterprise-Ready-Machen. Wie gehst du damit um, wenn der Agent in einen Fehler läuft? Wie verhinderst du Endless-Loops, die Tokens und damit Geld verbrennen? Was passiert, wenn der Agent faktisch etwas Falsches macht (wie falsche Verbuchungen oder Meldungen), ohne dass ein technischer Fehler auftritt? Themen wie Traceability, Monitoring, Observability und Governance werden zentral.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-191765055"&gt;Kontrolle und Autonomie: Der Mensch bleibt im Loop&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Gerade am Anfang solltest du vorsichtig sein mit der Autonomie von Agenten. Jochen vergleicht es mit der Einstellung neuer Mitarbeiter: Du würdest auch nicht am ersten Tag sagen "Schreib mal das Unternehmens-Balance-Sheet und gib es raus, ohne dass ich draufschaue." Stattdessen bewegst du dich schrittweise vorwärts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Seine Entwickler machen das mit Coding-Agenten (Cursor, Cline) genauso: Am Anfang wollen sie jeden Code-Snippet sehen und bestätigen. Aber das Tool schreibt schneller Code, als sie lesen können. Nach sechs, sieben, acht erfolgreichen Durchläufen kommt der Punkt, wo sie sagen: "Okay, mach es automatisch, frag nicht mehr." Dann brauchen sie aber einen neuen Mechanismus zur Qualitätssicherung – &lt;STRONG&gt;Evals&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Evaluations).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Evals sind datenunterstützte Tests der Agenten, die kontinuierlich laufen und prüfen, ob die Qualität und wichtige Attribute eingehalten werden. Das sind im Prinzip Unit-Tests in Dauerschleife, mit komplexeren Datasets. Und hier zeigt sich wieder: Je mehr gute Daten du hast, desto präziser werden die Evals und desto höher die Output-Qualität des Agenten.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Der Ansatz ist also: Viele kleine Checks am Anfang, die sukzessive weniger werden. Wenn es weniger menschliche Checks werden, brauchst du mehr technische Checks im Hintergrund. Agenten sind nie 100% deterministisch – Fehler können passieren, und du brauchst immer irgendwo einen Checkpoint.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4748450"&gt;Offene Standards und Zukunftsfähigkeit von KI Agenten&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP setzt stark auf &lt;STRONG&gt;offene Standards&lt;/STRONG&gt; wie das &lt;STRONG&gt;Agent-to-Agent-Protokoll (A2A)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, bei dem SAP im Gründungskonsortium mit Google und anderen großen Unternehmen sitzt. Aktuell wird ausgelotet, was in so ein Protokoll gehört: Autorisierung, Kontextaustausch, welcher Agent darf welchen Agent rufen – besonders wichtig, wenn Agenten über Unternehmensgrenzen hinweg kommunizieren sollen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Auch das &lt;STRONG&gt;Model Context Protocol (MCP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; ist in aller Munde. Jochen beschreibt es als semantischen Layer über eine API mit beeindruckend schneller Community-Adoption. Trotzdem gibt es noch offene Fragen zu Autorisierung, Governance, Discovery und Registry. Anthropic hat gerade eine Lösung für die Frage gelauncht, wo man die richtigen Tools findet, die zugänglich sind.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Die Philosophie bei SAP: &lt;STRONG&gt;Adaptivität&lt;/STRONG&gt; ist entscheidend. Genau wie beim Model Access, wo SAP von Anfang an auf mehrere Modelle statt auf eines gesetzt hat, gilt das auch für Agent-Frameworks und Protokolle. Es wird nicht das eine Framework geben, sondern mehrere – und du solltest in der Lage sein, flexibel zu wechseln und neue Entwicklungen komplementär mitzunehmen, ohne alles wegschmeißen zu müssen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-145992402"&gt;Praktische Tipps für den Einstieg&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Jochens wichtigster Rat: &lt;STRONG&gt;Anfangen ist wichtig&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Du musst nicht selbst coden können, aber du solltest verstehen, wie ein Agent aufgebaut ist. Für technisch Interessierte empfiehlt er, einen Agenten auf einem Low-Code-Framework zu bauen oder sich zumindest eine Schulung anzuschauen. Wichtig ist, die Traces zu verstehen – wie zerlegt der Agent ein Problem in Tasks? Wie kommt er zu seinen Lösungswegen?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Für Business-orientierte Personen ist es entscheidend, den &lt;STRONG&gt;Unterschied zwischen Workflow und Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; zu begreifen: Bei einem Workflow kennst du den Weg zum Ziel genau (auch wenn es 100 If-Else-Verzweigungen sind). Bei einem Agent beschreibst du nur den Outcome – der Agent findet selbst heraus, wie er dahin kommt. Wenn du diesen Unterschied verstehst, entwickelst du ein Auge dafür, welche Business-Probleme sich für Agenten eignen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Konkrete Empfehlungen:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Probiere bestehende Standard-Agenten aus und beobachte, was sie machen, wo sie stolpern&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Nutze den &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Innovation Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt; für Beispiele und Inspiration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Schau dir das &lt;STRONG&gt;App House Toolkit für Agent Design&lt;/STRONG&gt; an&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Absolviere Learning Journeys auf der SAP-Plattform (s. Shownotes unten)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Für Deep Dives: Der Kurs zu &lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic AI von &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" href="http://deeplearning.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DeepLearning.AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; (von KI OG Andrew Ng) oder der SAP-Kurs zu &lt;STRONG&gt;Knowledge Graphs&lt;/STRONG&gt; auf &lt;A class="" href="http://deeplearning.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;DeepLearning.AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Und vergiss nicht: Wenn ein Problem mit einem klassischen Workflow lösbar ist, solltest du das tun. Nicht alles muss ein Agent werden – das ist auch eine Frage des TCO (Total Cost of Ownership). Lass dich nicht vom "Agent-Washing" täuschen, wo Workflows als Agenten verkauft werden, nur weil eine Konversation davor geschaltet ist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--50521103"&gt;Verantwortung und Ethik im Rahmen von KI Agenten&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Bei aller Begeisterung für die Technologie: Das Thema &lt;STRONG&gt;Responsible AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; bleibt zentral. Viele Mechanismen sind bereits technologisch eingebaut – Content-Filter gegen Hate Speech, Security-Features, Data Privacy. Aber bei Agenten musst du dir immer wieder die Frage stellen: Kann ich verantworten, was der Agent macht? Würde ich diese Aufgabe so auch an mein Team geben?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Besonders beim Umgang mit persönlichen Daten oder wenn Agenten Menschen beeinflussen, sind klare ethische Grenzen wichtig. Bei SAP gibt es dafür interne Prozesse und Governance-Strukturen. Der "Human in the Loop" ist nicht nur eine technische Notwendigkeit, sondern auch eine ethische – Menschen müssen an den richtigen Checkpoints eingebunden werden, um Kontrolle und Verantwortung zu behalten.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--247034608"&gt;Blick in die Zukunft von KI Agenten&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Wohin geht die Reise? Jochen sieht mehrere spannende Entwicklungen: Die &lt;STRONG&gt;Capabilities verschieben sich immer mehr in die Modelle&lt;/STRONG&gt; selbst – OpenAI hat gerade ein Agent Kit angekündigt, die Modelle werden von reinen LLMs zu echten Problemlösern. Das macht es umso wichtiger, sich nicht von einem Modell abhängig zu machen und flexibel zu bleiben.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Edge-Modelle&lt;/STRONG&gt; treiben Jochen besonders um: Die Modelle werden kleiner und brauchen weniger Rechenpower, während Devices immer leistungsfähiger werden. Was kann auf deinem Edge-Device passieren, ohne dass Daten ins Netz gehen müssen? Aus Data-Privacy-Sicht ist das mega spannend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Die Interaktion zwischen Foundation-Modellen und der &lt;STRONG&gt;physischen Welt&lt;/STRONG&gt; wird relevant – Robotics ist ein Thema, auch wenn es noch dauert. Und dann gibt es die philosophische Frage: Wird es einen &lt;STRONG&gt;Super-Orchestrator&lt;/STRONG&gt; für alle Agenten geben oder eher ein intelligentes Netzwerk basierend auf offenen Standards? Jochen ist großer Fan der Netzwerk-Ökonomie – auch auf der technischen und Agent-Ebene.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Besonders faszinierend sind auch &lt;STRONG&gt;World Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;, wie sie Fei-Fei Li beschreibt. Wenn du dir anschaust, wie schnell Kinder in der realen Welt lernen, wird klar: Ein LLM, das sich nur der Sprache bedient, lässt vieles vermissen. Ein Verständnis des ganzen Raums – 3D, 4D mit Zeitachse – ermöglicht schnelleres Begreifen. Und das gilt auch im Business (und für Agenten): Teams mit mehr Kontextinformationen treffen bessere Entscheidungen. Je mehr verschiedene Informationen du in die Modelle einbringen kannst, desto besser die Prediction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--443548113"&gt;Inspirierende Aussagen aus dem Podcast&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;"Ein Agent ist im Prinzip wie meine zehnjährigen Kinder: Ich sage ihnen, was ich erreichen will, und hoffe, dass sie rausfinden, wie sie dahin kommen – ohne dass ich jeden Schritt vorgeben muss."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;"Es gibt momentan sehr viel Agent-Washing. Nicht alles, was als Agent verkauft wird, ist wirklich agentic. Wenn du es mit einem Workflow lösen kannst, solltest du das tun."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;"Wir steuern in eine Welt, in der Code schreiben schneller geht als Code lesen. Das stellt uns vor fundamental andere Probleme."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;"Der Wow-Effekt mit Agenten ist heute schnell erreicht. Die eigentliche Arbeit beginnt danach – beim Produktisieren und Enterprise-Ready-Machen."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;"Kontext ist key – nicht nur für LLMs und Agenten, sondern auch für uns Menschen. Zu verstehen, was drumherum abgeht, ist die Grundlage für Adaptability."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;"Bei Agenten musst du dir immer fragen: Würde ich diese Aufgabe so auch an mein Team geben? Wenn nicht, solltest du es auch keinem Agenten überlassen."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;"Je mehr verschiedene Informationen du in die Modelle einbringen kannst, desto besser die Prediction. Deshalb sind World Models so spannend."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--640061618"&gt;Konkrete Tipps für die Praxis&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Für den Start:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Beginne mit Experimenten – baue oder nutze einen Agenten, um ein Gefühl für die Technologie zu bekommen&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Probiere Standard-Agenten aus, um zu sehen, was möglich ist und wie schnell sie in deinem Unternehmen akzeptiert werden&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Schaue dir dein Backlog an: Welche geplanten Features könntest du mit Agenten neu denken?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Für die Entwicklung:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Nutze das Joule Studio für schnelle Prototypen mit Enterprise-Grade-Features&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Denke in Outcomes, nicht in Schritten – beschreibe, was erreicht werden soll, nicht wie&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Statte Agenten mit den richtigen Tools aus, aber überfrachte sie nicht – zu viele Tools verschlechtern die Qualität&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Wähle das passende Modell: klein und günstig für einfache Tasks, leistungsstark für komplexe Reasoning-Aufgaben&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Für die Skalierung:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Starte mit vielen kleinen Human-in-the-Loop-Checkpoints und reduziere sie schrittweise&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Baue technische Checks (Evals) auf, wenn menschliche Checks weniger werden&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Implementiere Monitoring, Observability und Audit-Logs von Anfang an&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Denke an Governance: Was passiert bei Fehlern? Wie verhinderst du Endless-Loops?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Für die Strategie:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Priorisiere Use Cases nach Business Value, nicht nach technischer Coolness&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Unterscheide klar: Workflow oder Agent? Nutze Agenten nur dort, wo Flexibilität und Dynamik nötig sind&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Bleibe adaptiv und unabhängig von einzelnen Modellen oder Frameworks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Investiere in gute Datengrundlagen – die richtigen Daten zur richtigen Zeit sind entscheidend&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--836575123"&gt;Resümee: Die Zukunft ist agentic – aber mit Augenmaß&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;KI-Agenten sind keine Science-Fiction mehr, sondern Realität im Enterprise-Kontext. Bei SAP sind sie bereits in allen möglichen Lösungen announced, von Finance über HR bis zu technischen Use Cases. Die Technologie ist beeindruckend einfach von der Bedienung aber sehr mächtig: Agenten können komplexe Aufgaben eigenständig lösen, sich dynamisch an veränderte Bedingungen anpassen und Prozesse augmentieren, die früher viel manuelle Arbeit erforderten.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Aber – und das ist die zentrale Botschaft von Jochen Schneider – nicht alles sollte oder muss zum Agenten werden. Die Kunst liegt darin, zu erkennen, wo Agenten echten Mehrwert schaffen und wo klassische Workflows effizienter sind. Es geht nicht darum, dem Hype zu verfallen, sondern Business Value zu schaffen und Probleme zu lösen, die heute nicht oder nicht so gut lösbar sind.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Und was man sieht: viele Inhalte der vergangene Gespräche im Podcast von KI Ethik, humanzetrierten Design oder KI Strategie sind auch im Kontext von Agenten zentral. BTW: Lernangebote speziell für den &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management-blog-posts/sap-ai-training-und-sap-ai-skills-self-assessment/ba-p/14220337" target="_blank"&gt;SAP AI Bereich haben hier im Blog&lt;/A&gt; gesammelt.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ich habe mich auf diesen Podcast mit Recherche und einem E-Learning von &lt;A class="" href="http://deeplearning.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;deeplearning.ai&lt;/A&gt; zu AgenticAI vorbereit. Der nächste Schritt ist, dass ich mir eigene Agenten bastele. Mir fällt es noch einfacher, Business Use Cases zu sehen anstatt für den persönlichen Gebrauch - denn mir reichen oft GPTs oder eben das Nutzen von verschiedenen LLMs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Oder wie seht Ihr das?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1033088628"&gt;Ressourcen und weiterführende Links&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sjochen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Jochen Schneider auf LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-agents.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Überblick: Joule Agents&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/germany/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-foundation-os/knowledge-graph.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Infos zu SAP Knowledge Graph&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/germany/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-assistant.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Website zu Joule-KI-Agenten&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-studio.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Infos zu Joule Studio&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/boosting-ai-driven-business-transformation-with-joule-agents" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Kostenfreies E-Learning: Boost...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/podcast" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Lennys Podcast&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learn.deeplearning.ai/courses/agentic-ai/lesson/pu5xbv/welcome!" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;E-Learning zu Agentic AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.deeplearning.ai/short-courses/knowledge-graphs-for-ai-agent-api-discovery/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;Short course: Knowledge Graphs...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://apphaus.sap.com/resource/ai-innovation-toolkit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Apphaus AI Innovation Tool...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/topics/innovation-guide/h2#business-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Innovation Guide HJ2 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management-blog-posts/sap-ai-training-und-sap-ai-skills-self-assessment/ba-p/14220337" target="_blank"&gt;Sammlung von AI Lernangeboten&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management-blog-posts/ki-agenten-bei-sap-%C3%BCberblick-beispiele-umsetzung-und-adoption-mit-jochen/ba-p/14259318"/>
    <published>2025-11-03T15:17:12.245000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-joule-studio-learning-series-lead-agentic-development-with-confidence/ba-p/14258233</id>
    <title>The Joule Studio Learning Series: Lead Agentic Development with Confidence</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T16:00:00.072000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kvidit</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1631981</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Organizations are adopting agentic AI to transform how work gets done. Joule Studio offers developers a low code, no code environment to design and deploy secure, scalable, and interoperable &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Joule &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;agents&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; that plan and execute workflows in a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;heterogenous&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; landscape&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To help you get started, I’ve created a four-part enablement video series that walks you through everything: from understanding what Joule Studio is to building Joule agents.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whether you’re just getting started or an experienced developer, this series will help you transform business workflows with the power agentic AI and Joule Studio.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By the end of this enablement series, you’ll have an understanding of:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule Studio: its marketecture and capabilities&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule agents and skills: definition, characteristics, and use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to build, test, and deploy your own Joule agents&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and skills&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;What is Joule Studio?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start your learning journey with an introduction to Joule Studio, underlying components, and how it enables the creation of adaptive, intelligent agents for business workflows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You’ll learn:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Joule Studio is and what problems it solves&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key capabilities and components&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The value Joule Studio delivers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_94hgmrdz" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Are AI Agents and Joule Skills?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dive into the fundamentals. Understand the building blocks of Joule Studio: AI agents and Joule skills, how they work together, their characteristics, and use cases.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You’ll learn:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Difference between Joule skills and AI agents&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How AI agents work&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Common use cases for both&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_f6a5oab2" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Creating a Joule Skill in Joule Studio&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this hands-on demo, learn how to create a Joule skill within SAP Build using Joule Studio for predictable execution of&amp;nbsp;rule-based, repetitive tasks. The example walks through creating an ID badge in a third-party system after performing a preliminary check in SAP. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You’ll learn:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to configure inputs and outputs for a Joule skill&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to connect SAP and external systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to configure messages to Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_2ps4lo36" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Creating Joule Agents in Joule Studio&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See the agent builder capability in Joule Studio in action. This video shows how to create and configure a Joule agent end-to-end, equipping it with tools, models, and other configurations for adaptive execution in a business scenario.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You’ll learn:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to create and test Joule agent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to configure tools, models, and skills&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_f136yizu" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get Started with Joule Studio&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to build your first agent? Check out additional documentation and resources to get started:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/how-to-get-started-with-joule-studio/ba-p/14152855" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to get started with Joule Studio&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-complete-joule-studio-resource-hub-everything-you-need-to-get-started/ba-p/14183113" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Complete Joule Studio Resource Hub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-joule-studio-learning-series-lead-agentic-development-with-confidence/ba-p/14258233"/>
    <published>2025-11-04T16:00:00.072000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/build-business-grounded-ai-agents-faster/ba-p/14258166</id>
    <title>Build Business-Grounded AI Agents, Faster</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T16:00:00.076000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BharatSandhu82</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/43599</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At Sapphire 2025, SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/build-deploy-and-extend-ai-agents-with-joule-studio/ba-p/14105964" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;announced&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Joule Studio, a capability in SAP Build that enables developers to create Joule agents and skills. Deeply grounded in business data, these agents orchestrate workflows across heterogenous landscapes to deliver accurate outcomes. Joule Studio delivers an agent runtime with built-in data protection guardrails, multi-LLM support, and context retention across tasks for scalable, secure execution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today, we are announcing additional capabilities that will equip developers with a comprehensive development tool kit to build scalable agentic AI for their business. We are introducing vibe coding experience to create not only conversational but also system-triggered AI agents. Instead of building from scratch, developers can also extend ready-to-use Joule agents as per their business needs. Joule Studio will also support open standards such as Model Context Protocol (MCP) and Agent2Agent (A2A) protocol. These advances empower developers to deliver end-to-end agentic automation with greater speed, flexibility, and control. See what our customers and partners from the beta program (Q3 2025) have to say:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#808080"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“With Joule Studio, we could build powerful agents in three weeks. It is an intuitive, no‑code environment that enables system connectivity across SAP and non‑SAP critical environments, for a hybrid landscapes where data resides in multiple modules.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;Gianluca Simeone, VP - Global SAP CTIO and Gen-AI Leader at Capgemini&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#808080"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Nestle, SAP, and IBM worked together on a supply chain Agentic AI PoC. With the agent builder capability in Joule Studio, we created this POC bringing in data from SAP and non-SAP sources to create an agent that will automate our complex Order fulfillment processes”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;- Pablo Nill, Sr Product Group Manager, Nestle&amp;nbsp;&lt;/I&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“&lt;FONT color="#808080"&gt;With Joule Studio, agentic innovation moves closer to the heart of operations. At KPMG, we’re helping to shape trusted solutions that transform business context into measurable value by building specialized AI agents for fulfillment orchestration, supply chain management, and more”.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;FONT color="#808080"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;Valentino Köster, Global Head of SAP360 Program &amp;amp; AI, KPMG AG WPG, Germany&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Fast‑Tracking Ideas into Agents: Empowering Developers with AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;To lower the barrier to AI adoption, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Joule Studio provides AI &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;assistance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; in the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; design-time experience of creating agents. Developers can use natural language to share their requirements with Joule copilot and get contextual recommendations for agent definition, tools, and other configurations, tailored to their specific needs. For example, Joule may suggest and add relevant Joule skills to custom Joule agents. This makes agent creation more accessible and accelerates time-to-value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Image 1: AI-assistance in Joule Studio" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335644iF76BF32073888545/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Vibe coding_agent builder (1).png" alt="Image 1: AI-assistance in Joule Studio" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Image 1: AI-assistance in Joule Studio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Cross-Ecosystem Integration with Model Context Protocol (MCP)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One of the most significant updates is Joule Studio’s support for MCP, an open standard that provides a unified way to connect AI agents with external systems. This breaks down traditional application silos and enables cross-platform agent execution. In Joule Studio, you can configure connectivity to external MCP servers, allowing agents to use third-party tools and applications. For example, a support agent that you built in Joule Studio can retrieve ticket information from a third-party IT service platform exposed via MCP. This open integration empowers AI agents to act as central, intelligent orchestrators, managing complex workflows across diverse systems without the need for custom integrations. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Image 2: Configuration of tools, MCP servers, and models for agent design" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335645i946D84D0AC265003/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MCP Servers and tools (1).png" alt="Image 2: Configuration of tools, MCP servers, and models for agent design" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Image 2: Configuration of tools, MCP servers, and models for agent design&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Proactive Agentic Automation with System-Triggered Agents&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule Studio will support the creation of system-triggered AI agents that operate autonomously with no human input. Triggers such as business events, APIs, and schedules will be supported for agents to be initiated. This elevates agents from being reactive to proactive collaborators, capable of initiating actions like inventory monitoring and initiating purchase orders for low stock items or incident response. That enables true end-to-end automation of business processes with minimal human intervention.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Image 3: Add triggers for custom agents" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335646i0D727232784347EE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="System Triggers (1).png" alt="Image 3: Add triggers for custom agents" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Image 3: Add triggers for custom agents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Adapt Pre-Built, SAP-Delivered Agents to Your Enterprise&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In Joule Studio, developers will be able to extend ready-to-use Joule agents by adding additional tools and custom skills as pre- and post-processing steps. For example, extend an Accounts Receivable Agent, which analyzes overdue receivables and follows up with customers, by grounding it in your order handling policy for informed decision making. This allows you to tailor ready-to-use Joule agents to your unique business requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Image 4: Extending ready-to-use Joule agents" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335647i37FA4B3929E54169/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Act I - 29.png" alt="Image 4: Extending ready-to-use Joule agents" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Image 4: Extending ready-to-use Joule agents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Getting Started with agent builder in Joule Studio&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The agent builder will be generally available in December 2025 with support for MCP, agent as a tool, vibe coding, and document grounding part of first release. Later in 2026, we will release support for agent extensibility, system-triggered agents, A2A, and agent observability.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are interested in learning more:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Register for the webinar for a closer look at agent builder experience: &lt;A href="https://url.sap/hhbka2" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visit the Joule Studio webpage: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-studio.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Checkout demo on building Joule agents in Joule Studio: &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/3R64qaH?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1251723" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Demo&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/build-business-grounded-ai-agents-faster/ba-p/14258166"/>
    <published>2025-11-04T16:00:00.076000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-thevaluechain-transforms-multitenant-solutions-with-q-amp-a-joule-agent/ba-p/14249033</id>
    <title>How TheValueChain transforms multitenant solutions with Q&amp;A Joule Agent Built in Joule Studio</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T17:04:17.676000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>geert-janklaps</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/868</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762946748"&gt;A quick introduction to TheValueChain&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://thevaluechain.eu/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;TheValueChain&lt;/A&gt; is an SAP Partner founded in 2011 and has over 400 consultants across Belgium, The Netherlands, Switzerland, Luxembourg and France. Over the years, TheValueChain has primarily been active in providing consulting services (end-to-end projects, SLA's, ad-hoc assignments). Since a few years we have adapted our strategy to also provide our own in-house developed products, built on top of SAP Business Technology Platform with a primary focus on multitenant (SaaS) solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="geertjanklaps_0-1761028970107.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330081i3AD532CB8002519B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="geertjanklaps_0-1761028970107.png" alt="geertjanklaps_0-1761028970107.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today, I'm the lead technical architect for the multitenant solutions, ensuring our solutions are built using the latest SAP best-practices, are scalable, resilient and stable. We currently have 3 multitenant solutions live in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/search?query=:relevance:publisher:TheValueChain%20NV" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Store&lt;/A&gt;, GoBeyond Supplier Invoicing (which is SAP Business AI certified!), GoBeyond Integration Monitoring and GoBeyond Customer Portal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566433243"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Providing instant access to our solution documentation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are strong believers in leveraging AI in all our solutions to improve process efficiency &amp;amp; user experience. With our solutions already being AI-infused using SAP Business AI services like SAP AI Core and SAP Document AI, mainly focusing on process efficiency. A next logical step was to focus on AI-assisted user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We wanted to start with enriching the user experience of our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/partners/thevaluechain-nv-gobeyond-supplier-invoicing.html?countryCode=BE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;GoBeyond Supplier Invoicing&lt;/A&gt; solution, by creating two Joule Agents. Our primary use-case being a Q&amp;amp;A agent, which, based on document grounding our online notion documentation website can answer any general or how-to questions a user could have about our solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why did we see the Q&amp;amp;A agent as our primary use-case? The answer is easy, even though we have a full-blown documentation website we still see support tickets being logged with general questions, even with a well-maintained website, critical answers get buried among large volumes of content, leading to increased support ticket submissions seeking answers to general questions. That demonstrated the need to surface precise, contextual information instantly, reducing support workload. and improving user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, the advantage of our Q&amp;amp;A agent is twofold, our customers get instant answers to their questions by simply asking Joule instead of logging a support ticket and we from a support perspective get less tickets, freeing up our time to focus on what really matters: constantly improving and including new innovations in our solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joule Agent answering a general question about one of our apps in the Supplier Invoice Management Solution" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330119i86E4B40EED6A41A7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="geertjanklaps_0-1761032589427.png" alt="Joule Agent answering a general question about one of our apps in the Supplier Invoice Management Solution" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Joule Agent answering a general question about one of our apps in the Supplier Invoice Management Solution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1369919738"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How we created and deployed a Q&amp;amp;A agent in a matter of hours&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For our Q&amp;amp;A agent, we are leveraging four main components:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Notion (which holds our live documentation)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GitHub actions (as a data ingestion pipeline)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Core AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule Studio&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The idea behind this setup is that whenever we release new features or bugfixes to production, a GitHub action automatically crunches our online documentation, updating the vector storage in SAP AI Core with the latest documentation. (we can manually trigger this pipeline, if we improve documentation based on user feedback without an actual release)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GitHub Action as a data ingestion pipeline" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330134iF1D44B3D8E9DE8C9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="geertjanklaps_0-1761034470723.png" alt="GitHub Action as a data ingestion pipeline" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;GitHub Action as a data ingestion pipeline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Under the hood of our data ingestion pipeline, we are leveraging a custom script that uses the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/ai-sdk/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud SDK for AI&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to fill a data repository in a document grounding-enabled resource group in SAP Core AI. Since this is a full custom scenario as we can't link e.g. an S3 Object Store, we are also in charge of properly applying document chunking to get the best results and not overload the AI Agents with unnecessary context.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For chunking the documents, we leveraged LangChain's RecursiveCharacterTextSplitter in markdown mode (with a maximum chunk size of 10K tokens and an overlap of 1K tokens).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Data repository view in SAP Core AI, showing the chunked documentation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330138iC60E52AB7FB62D48/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="geertjanklaps_0-1761035444878.png" alt="Data repository view in SAP Core AI, showing the chunked documentation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Data repository view in SAP Core AI, showing the chunked documentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In a last step, we assigned our SAP Core AI resource group to our Joule Agent as tool, providing clear instructions on how and when to use this tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joule Studio Agent Builder, documentation tool maintenance" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330144i087B810863067F07/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="geertjanklaps_1-1761036029657.png" alt="Joule Studio Agent Builder, documentation tool maintenance" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Joule Studio Agent Builder, documentation tool maintenance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For informational purposes, the full solution architecture looks like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Supplier Invoice Management Solution architecture" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330080i4FFDB42DD2F28E43/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Supplier Invoice Management.drawio.png" alt="Supplier Invoice Management Solution architecture" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Supplier Invoice Management Solution architecture&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1173406233"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;We are only getting started&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;From our point of view, the Q&amp;amp;A agent implementation was a big success. We are able to cover the full scope of what we had in mind for our Q&amp;amp;A agent. As per our estimates, this will decrease the number of documentation related support tickets by 25%.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For us, this is only the beginning, we plan to implement a Q&amp;amp;A agent for our other solutions as well in a first phase. In a next phase, we're planning on creating additional agents interacting with the solutions and guiding the user through the processes in an AI-assisted way, always keeping a human in the loop.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What stood out for us in Joule Studio was that it’s very intuitive and well-integrated no-code environment, especially if you are used to working with SAP Build Process Automation, the experience is the same. Even better, you can easily re-use existing artifacts like e.g. action projects, automations and processes by integrating them in Joule Skills and assigning these skills to your agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even though SAP AI Core requires some more technical knowledge, integration with Joule Studio is so easy and straight forward, your SAP AI Core data repository is assigned to your AI agent in a matter of minutes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All-in-all we really like the experience and were able to deliver our Q&amp;amp;A agent in a matter of hours. We’re already looking forward to building our next use-cases!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-thevaluechain-transforms-multitenant-solutions-with-q-amp-a-joule-agent/ba-p/14249033"/>
    <published>2025-11-04T17:04:17.676000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-new-paradigm-for-enterprise-ai-in-context-learning-for-relational-data/ba-p/14260221</id>
    <title>A New Paradigm for Enterprise AI: In-Context Learning for Relational Data</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T17:30:00.514000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>philipp_herzig</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/195453</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Businesses run on structured data. From financial ledgers to supply chain logistics, tables and relational data are the backbone of the global economy. And for years, we’ve applied artificial intelligence (AI) to this data, but with a fundamental limitation: we had to build a custom AI model for every single prediction task.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Until now organizations needed one model to forecast demand; another one to predict late payments; a third one for identifying sales opportunities; and so on. Each model required a time-consuming and expensive investment with dedicated teams, lengthy training cycles, and constant maintenance. This fragmented approach, while powerful in isolation, has created a complex and slow-moving AI landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What if we could change that? What if, instead of a huge amount of narrow AI specialist models, you had a single, universal AI engine that could understand your relational business data and address virtually any predictive task?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is exactly the gap that &lt;STRONG&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; closes for SAP’s customers and partners. At SAP TechEd this year, we launched our table-native foundation model, pre-trained to understand your table-based business data out-of-the-box across a vast range of predictive tasks, without the need for task-specific training or fine-tuning. It’s designed to elevate predictions in enterprises to a new level. Let’s take a closer look!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Paradigm Shift: In-Context Learning for Business Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The concept of a foundation model, a large-scale model pretrained on huge amounts of data, has already transformed how we interact with text and images. We now bring this same paradigm to the unique domain of relational business data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The abbreviation ‘rpt’ in&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;stands for&amp;nbsp;Relational Pretrained Transformer. This model is a natural evolution of SAP's decades-long leadership in managing the world's most critical business data. It is table-native, which means that from ground up, it was designed with a deep understanding of the relationships, structures, and semantics inherent in tabular enterprise data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But its true power lies in a capability called&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;in-context learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine you have a brilliant new consultant. Instead of sending them to a six-month training course for every new project, you can simply sit down with them, show them a few examples of what you need – &lt;EM&gt;“Here are some customers who paid on time, and here are some who paid late”&lt;/EM&gt; – and they immediately recognize the pattern and can predict the outcome for the next thousand customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is exactly how&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;works. It doesn't require task-specific training or fine-tuning. You provide labeled table row examples of your predictive task&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;in-context&lt;/EM&gt;, and the model delivers a highly accurate prediction instantly. One single model, serving a huge variety of enterprise prediction tasks, across finance, supply chain, HR, and more, simply by each time seeing examples from a different domain in its context.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Engine: From Scientific Breakthrough to Real-World Application&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The science behind&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1,&lt;/FONT&gt; developed by our world-class AI researchers, was recently &lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.10707" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;published&lt;/A&gt; to this year’s NeurIPS conference, one of the most prestigious AI conferences. The key here is the table-native design. This is where &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;is breaking new ground: it is a transformer-based architecture (remember the T in RPT?), just as LLMs are; but whereas LLMs are optimized to deal with text that comes in a linear sequence, our table-native model is designed to detect connections and dependencies across rows and columns in large enterprise tables, with optimized processing for the unique semantics and datatypes found in business data.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 1: High-level schematic of the relational pretrained transformer architecture, including semantic embeddings, table-native 2D attention scheme and classification/regression heads for output generation" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336161i5BF75518D1BEEDB6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture4.png" alt="Figure 1: High-level schematic of the relational pretrained transformer architecture, including semantic embeddings, table-native 2D attention scheme and classification/regression heads for output generation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1: High-level schematic of the relational pretrained transformer architecture, including semantic embeddings, table-native 2D attention scheme and classification/regression heads for output generation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If that all got a little too technical for your taste, what matters is that we see best-in-class performance. On public scientific benchmarks, the open-source variant&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1-oss&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;performs on par with the very best AI systems, even when these have been carefully tuned for each individual task. The results are covered in more detail in the &lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.10707" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;paper&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More impressive still, on SAP-specific benchmarking problems that mirror the real business complexity our customers face, the commercial model variants of&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;outperform task-specific models substantially, as can be seen in the following benchmark:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Figure 2: Relative improvement (error reduction factor) of sap-rpt-1-large over narrow AI predictions, per SAP domain" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336061i86C4CA3AEA216EFE/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="Figure 2: Relative improvement (error reduction factor) of sap-rpt-1-large over narrow AI predictions, per SAP domain" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 2: Relative improvement (error reduction factor) of sap-rpt-1-large over narrow AI predictions, per SAP domain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Up to two times fewer prediction errors than optimized, task-specific narrow AI models – cutting downstream costs from every incorrect prediction. Plus, far greater flexibility, zero effort for re-training and updating the model. Plain and simple!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Elephant in the Room: sap-rpt-1 vs. State-of-the-Art LLMs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, the big question you might have is, why not just use an LLM? These models are extremely versatile, out-of-the-box knowledgeable, and become more powerful with every new release. So why not just do a bit of prompt engineering, and let your enterprise prediction task be solved by an LLM?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While generally it’s not very difficult to get an LLM to solve all kinds of enterprise predictive tasks (we’ve tested it!), there are two caveats:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;LLMs are flexible, but not always that accurate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;LLMs need to process relational data as plain text strings, which are much more error-prone and ineffective compared to a table-native processing. For a good reason, tabular and relational data processing have manifested themselves – probably no human would think that doing a financial close for a multi-national corporation in prose is a good idea.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This effect also shows when benchmarking &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt; against leading LLMs on tabular prediction tasks from the enterprise domain: we found the prediction quality of &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt; to be substantially ahead of LLMs, with a much lower error rate – see Figure 3, and by its design a much lower risk for hallucinations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Figure 3: Relative improvement (error reduction factor) of sap-rpt-1-large over state-of-the-art LLM predictions, per SAP domain" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336062i36EF25E9121AFBED/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Picture2.png" alt="Figure 3: Relative improvement (error reduction factor) of sap-rpt-1-large over state-of-the-art LLM predictions, per SAP domain" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 3: Relative improvement (error reduction factor) of sap-rpt-1-large over state-of-the-art LLM predictions, per SAP domain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;LLMs are neither fast, nor efficient&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Compared to LLMs, which are typically much larger in model size and computational complexity due to their versatility, &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt; is dramatically more efficient. Using an LLM to perform the same prediction task requires up to&amp;nbsp;100,000 times more floating point operations (FLOPs) and takes up to&amp;nbsp;50 times longer (despite running on substantially larger hardware). This level of efficiency not only reduces computational costs but also makes &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt; ideal for time-sensitive scenarios and environments with large context data at scale.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For these reasons, we have built &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt; from the ground up as a table-native model. We think it opens a new chapter in enterprise AI that extends the capabilities for foundation models towards relational data. While general-purpose LLMs exemplify most versatile natural language capabilities, &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt; excels in the important domain of predictions on tabular enterprise data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What This Means for Your Business: Getting Insights in Minutes, not Months&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By moving from a fragmented to a universal model, the benefits are clear:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Radical Agility &amp;amp; Speed:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Customers can go from a new business question to a live prediction in a fraction of the time. There is no need to iterate over hours-long model-training jobs, and companies can adapt to market changes with AI that learns on the fly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dramatically Lower Operations Effort:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Instead of building, deploying, and maintaining hundreds of separate models, customers and partners benefit from a single, centrally managed foundation model embedded within the SAP ecosystem they trust.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Superior Performance Where It Counts:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Our customers can achieve higher accuracy on their own complex business problems, leading to better decisions and outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Democratization of AI:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Business experts and analysts are empowered to generate their own predictions without needing deep data science expertise. Users benefit from interactive predictions instead of weeks of feature engineering and slow-moving development cycles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consider the possibilities:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;An accountant needs to assign cost centers, general ledger accounts and tax codes to invoices. Instead of commissioning a new AI project, the accountant can simply provide&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;with a few examples from the last quarter – delivering the prediction in almost no time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;A logistics manager is facing a new, unexpected disruption. They can immediately leverage &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt; to predict which shipments are most likely to be impacted, using real-time data and a handful of historical examples.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;A sales manager wants to identify which leads are most likely to convert based on a new marketing campaign and can map the business question to the company’s data, provide examples of past successes and failures to &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt;, and get the answer straight away.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a shift from often multi-month development cycles to near-instantaneous business insight.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;See For Yourself: The SAP-RPT Playground&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The introduction of&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;marks a major step forward in our mission to embed powerful, accessible AI across the enterprise. It represents a move towards a more unified and efficient AI architecture for business applications. &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt; is planned for general availability on the generative AI hub of SAP’s AI Foundation in Q4 2025. And of course, we will leverage this new technology to supercharge our own applications, delivering even greater value and innovation to our customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can’t wait? Try a preview version of &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1&lt;/FONT&gt; now for free – via no-code UI or via API at &lt;A href="https://rpt.cloud.sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://rpt.cloud.sap&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also don’t miss to check out the open source variant &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;sap-rpt-1-oss&lt;/FONT&gt;, available on &lt;A href="https://huggingface.co/sap/sap-rpt-1-oss" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;HuggingFace&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/sap-rpt-1-oss" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Co-authored by Dr. Janick Zaehringer-Frasch, Dr. Sam Thelin, Dr. Johannes Höhne, Dr. Markus Kohler, Oscar Cediel, Dr. Christiane Kubach, Dr. Johannes Hoffart, Mayank Shrivastava, Walter Sun, PhD, and Dr. Philipp Herzig.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-new-paradigm-for-enterprise-ai-in-context-learning-for-relational-data/ba-p/14260221"/>
    <published>2025-11-04T17:30:00.514000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/pioneer-ai-innovation-sap-customer-engagement-initiative-registration-open/ba-p/14260634</id>
    <title>Pioneer AI Innovation: SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Registration Open Until Nov 14, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T18:49:57.007000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nadine_p</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/762608</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AI.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336148iAB82F0FDF9C70973/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AI.png" alt="AI.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you prepared to unlock AI’s full potential and revolutionize your industry? With SAP’s advanced AI technology, you can optimize operations, enhance decision-making, and boost efficiency like never before.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now's your chance to go beyond adoption - and become a pioneer of innovation. By participating in our SAP Customer Engagement Initiative projects, you’ll actively shape the next generation of AI solutions. Your input won’t just be considered: it will directly influence the design of smarter tools tailored to your real-world needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t miss this chance to lead the digital transformation with AI - &lt;STRONG&gt;Registration is open only until November 14, 2025.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check out the full list&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/880" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;or follow the links below to discover the exciting opportunities:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4066" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI-assisted message monitoring agent for SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4041" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The impact of AI on SAP BTP users&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4030" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI- Assisted Summaries in SAP Analytics Cloud Stories&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Digital Supply Chain Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4047" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Identify un-assessed assets and auto propose draft risk assessments using AI Agent&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Public Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4024" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Agent for Accrual Postings SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4059" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Agent for Debt Collection&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Assistant for Manual Postings in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4051" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business AI for Product Cost Controlling&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4053" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule as Project Assistant: Optimizing Project Execution and Reducing Manual Processes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4029" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Let’s Create the Future of US Sales and Use Tax with AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4046" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Risk and Assurance Management - Exploring Joule use cases and AI features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lifecycle Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4037" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Automation and AI in Private Cloud Workspace&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s build the future together!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation thrives through collaboration. By participating in the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative projects, you help SAP develop more effective and relevant solutions for businesses like yours. This is your chance to impact the future of enterprise technology.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t miss out - sign up today at&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://influence.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;influence.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and be a part of the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Cycle 3 in 2025!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Warm regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your SAP Customer Engagement Initiative Team&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Follow-up after registration: When you register for a project, you will be invited to an introductory call with the SAP project lead. Participation beyond this point is optional and typically governed by the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/MvteHxp/Public%20Info%20on%20FBA_09_2024.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Feedback Agreement with SAP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/pioneer-ai-innovation-sap-customer-engagement-initiative-registration-open/ba-p/14260634"/>
    <published>2025-11-04T18:49:57.007000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/beyond-poc-how-sovanta-detects-purchasing-anomalies-with-a-custom-joule/ba-p/14257926</id>
    <title>Beyond PoC: How sovanta Detects Purchasing Anomalies with a Custom Joule Agent built in Joule Studio</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T13:48:48.870000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DanielJckl</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1855603</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Agents are the future of intelligent enterprise automation. They can understand context, enhance workflows, and interact autonomously within business systems. With the new &lt;STRONG&gt;agent builder capability in Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP is providing the tools to get closer to that future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an early adopter of Joule Studio, we at &lt;STRONG&gt;sovanta&lt;/STRONG&gt; explored how it can be used to solve real-world problems with custom AI agents. For more than 15 years, sovanta has been supporting SAP customers with Extensions, Integrations, and AI solutions in the cloud, forming into a specialized SAP BTP partner.&amp;nbsp; Using this experience in SAP BTP and AI, we have successfully implemented a real-world use case with the agent builder that goes beyond a proof-of-concept.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, we will explore this use case that we have adopted together with one of our most innovative customers &lt;STRONG&gt;Endress+Hauser&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Detecting anomalies in customers’ purchasing behavior.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763819308"&gt;Why we chose Agent Builder in Joule Studio&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before exploring the agent builder, we already gained hands-on experience &lt;A title="How sovanta uses Joule Studio to take ticketing systems to the next level" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/how-sovanta-uses-joule-studio-to-take-ticketing-systems-to-the-next-level/ba-p/14102612" target="_blank"&gt;creating Joule Skills in Joule Studio&lt;/A&gt;. This gave us an early glimpse into the potential of integrating AI more deeply into SAP business processes, and we were excited to take it to the next level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When SAP introduced the agent builder, we immediately saw its potential. It provides a &lt;STRONG&gt;low-code environment&lt;/STRONG&gt; that allows users &lt;STRONG&gt;to design, configure, and deploy AI agents&lt;/STRONG&gt; with minimal technical effort. By combining skills, data connections, and prompt logic, it enables teams to create powerful agents that can understand business context directly within the SAP ecosystem and scale in a heterogeneous landscape efficiently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For us, it was the perfect opportunity to explore how AI agents could become a natural part of everyday business processes. Our goal was clear: to validate whether the agent builder could support real business-critical scenarios beyond just prototypes and evaluate its potential for large-scale customer adoption.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567305803"&gt;The Business Challenge: Identifying Anomalies in Purchasing Behavior&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together with our long-time customer Endress+Hauser, a global process and laboratory instrumentation and automation supplier, we decided to focus on a challenge faced by sales representatives: identifying anomalies in customers’ purchasing behavior to be better prepared for sales meetings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently, it’s almost impossible for sales representatives to quickly recognize if a customer’s purchasing patterns have changed significantly across Endress+Hauser’s extensive product portfolio. Such anomalies could include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sudden increases or decreases&lt;/STRONG&gt; in a specific product area&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Shifts&lt;/STRONG&gt; towards unexpected measuring principles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Recent orders of products that are soon to be &lt;STRONG&gt;discontinued&lt;/STRONG&gt; or put on &lt;STRONG&gt;order stop&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Detecting these changes manually would require searching through multiple systems, analyzing past purchases, checking order stop lists – a process that is extremely time-consuming and not really feasible in practice. As a result, these insights could be overlooked, leading to slower reactions in the sales process, missed opportunities, and lower customer satisfaction. This made it a perfect challenge to be solved by an agent and the ideal case for the agent builder.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370792298"&gt;Our Solution: Detecting Anomalies and More&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our idea was simple: &lt;STRONG&gt;let sales representatives interact with their data conversationally&lt;/STRONG&gt;. To identify anomalies, they should be able to simply ask:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“Are there any anomalies in purchasing behavior for my customer?”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“Did my customer purchase any products recently that are running in order stop over the next year?”.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The agent would extract the needed data, detect anomalies, and provide a clear explanation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We did not want to be limited to anomaly detection, which is why we decided to &lt;STRONG&gt;connect the agent directly to the database&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This would allow users to go beyond anomaly detection and explore additional insights about customers and products. For example, instead of just identifying products running in order stop, the agent would also be able to identify successor products that should be recommended instead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And it doesn’t stop there: by additionally connecting the agent to the product documentation, we were able to further extend its capabilities. This allows sales representatives to instantly compare the ordered product with its successor and understand what has changed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174278793"&gt;How our Agent can detect Anomalies&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To be able to answer questions to prepare for sales meetings, we identified several data sources we needed to connect:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BDIH – Business Data and Integration Hub: &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud containing all types of operational data, including technical details of millions of sold devices.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product Knowledge Base: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Contains Product Documentation that is reachable via an internal RAG System.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The exact technical setup can be seen in the architecture below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-848682569"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Unbenanntes Diagramm-1744361461953.drawio (12).png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334732i98BE673AE97CF39C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Unbenanntes Diagramm-1744361461953.drawio (12).png" alt="Unbenanntes Diagramm-1744361461953.drawio (12).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since we wanted the agent to handle a wide range of questions from the BDIH, we decided to implement a &lt;STRONG&gt;Text-to-SQL approach&lt;/STRONG&gt; with Joule Studio. This enabled the agent to transform natural language questions into structured queries, allowing it to directly extract data from the database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To achieve this, we created a Text-to-SQL pipeline in Joule Studio. This involved grounding the agent with the following documents:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The database schema of all relevant tables&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Example SQL queries&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;General documentation about the database structure and business context&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These documents were added via &lt;STRONG&gt;document grounding&lt;/STRONG&gt;, allowing the agent to better understand how to map natural language questions to actual database queries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the actual data extraction from the BDIH, we included a custom Joule Skill that takes a SQL query as input and retrieves the corresponding data through a proxy endpoint to the database. Because SAP Build Actions currently do not fully support dynamic outputs, we applied a workaround to handle the dynamically changing query results coming from the database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition to the Text-to-SQL pipeline, we also connected the Product Knowledge Base with a separate Joule Skill. With these two integrated data sources connected to the agent through separate Joule Skills, the agent can flexibly retrieve and combine relevant information depending on the type of question.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781251783"&gt;The Agent Flow and its Business Impact&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The interaction flow is simple and powerful:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The sales representative &lt;STRONG&gt;asks a question&lt;/STRONG&gt; in natural language.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;agent interprets&lt;/STRONG&gt; the intent and decides which data source to use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It will &lt;STRONG&gt;extract information&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the DB schema and example queries before &lt;STRONG&gt;formulating&lt;/STRONG&gt; an appropriate &lt;STRONG&gt;SQL query&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;query result is retrieved&lt;/STRONG&gt; and enriched with additional knowledge from the Product Knowledge Base.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The agent &lt;STRONG&gt;summarizes the findings&lt;/STRONG&gt; in plain language and is available for follow-up questions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following two examples demonstrate how this flow can help find anomalies in purchasing behavior for certain measuring principles, find products in order stop and their successor products:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog Post Examples.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334735iFE1F88A2A2E67A03/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog Post Examples.png" alt="Blog Post Examples.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This conversational and data-driven approach significantly &lt;STRONG&gt;improves efficiency and empowers sales teams to prepare more effectively for customer meetings&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It also allows sales representatives to identify opportunities and gaps earlier and provide recommendations for the customer, demonstrating how Joule Studio can create measurable business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584738278"&gt;Our Final Thoughts on Agent Builder in Joule Studio&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our experience as an early adopter has shown that the agent builder is more than just a proof-of-concept. It’s a promising addition to the SAP ecosystem, fully native to SAP Build, which allows us to leverage existing components such as actions, automations, and workflows directly within Joule Studio. It also proved to be highly open and interoperable by seamlessly connecting agents and skills with third-party systems. Combined with its built-in business understanding and grounding, it enables enterprise-ready AI Agents to reliably interact with real business data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking ahead, we plan to further explore capabilities such as Agent-to-Agent collaboration and additional agent tools coming to the agent builder. For example, a native database tool could eliminate the need for our current Text-to-SQL pipeline and even further simplify the agent development process. At sovanta, we are excited to continue exploring how Joule Studio can empower our customers with AI Agents that can seamlessly and autonomously interact within their business systems.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/beyond-poc-how-sovanta-detects-purchasing-anomalies-with-a-custom-joule/ba-p/14257926"/>
    <published>2025-11-05T13:48:48.870000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/from-days-to-minutes-how-epi-use-labs-custom-joule-agent-automates-payroll/ba-p/14254271</id>
    <title>From Days to Minutes: How EPI-USE Labs’ Custom Joule Agent Automates Payroll Variance Analysis with</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T14:10:11.733000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JACoetzee</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8679</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As a global company, EPI-USE Labs provides software solutions and services to over 1,800 large enterprises worldwide, with a core focus on SAP Human Capital Management (HCM) and Payroll. We have over 40 years of experience in SAP HCM projects and are one of the world's largest independent SAP HR/Payroll specialists. Our solutions, such as Query Manager and Variance Monitor, are key to how our clients manage their SAP Payroll data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our expertise extends into AI and developing custom solutions for SAP and SuccessFactors. We are always looking for ways to leverage new technologies (such as Joule) to enhance the efficiency and employee experience for our clients.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892806077"&gt;Why and What?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our specific use case was to dramatically reduce the time and effort payroll administrators and employees spend on payroll variance queries. Currently, when an employee's pay changes, the reason for the variance often requires manual investigation, leading to numerous queries, data checking in different systems and delays, that could impact employees. Days can be spent on these investigations and payroll needs to run before a specific date and time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are an early adopter of Joule Studio because we recognize that the future of enterprise software is intelligent, driven by agentic AI, and improving user experience. SAP's decision to embed AI and the Joule digital assistant directly into core business operations, aligns perfectly with our strategic focus.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To solve this, we set out to create a custom Joule agent using Joule Studio - AI Payroll Variance Agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696292572"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule Studio enabled us to deliver agents that are powered with human-like reasoning, grounded in business data, and connect disparate systems to solve complex, goal-oriented business processes and provide reliable outcomes. Payroll, which is highly complex and rule-based, is an ideal workflow for this type of agentic AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We built our custom Joule AI agent was designed to understand and explain complex pay discrepancies in natural language. It's a prime example of utilizing Joule skills and the agent builder capability in Joule Studio to connect disparate data systems and provide immediate, contextual answers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="JACoetzee_0-1762198528258.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335618i007F3D5E3EA3DA0C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="JACoetzee_0-1762198528258.png" alt="JACoetzee_0-1762198528258.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Payroll Variance Joule Agent consists of two parts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Joule skill creation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We leveraged our expertise with SAP Payroll data and our Query Manager solution to create Joule skills that can access real-time, live payroll results from SAP ECC On-premises Payroll or SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central Payroll. These skills were the "tools" the Joule agent could use for more rule-based, deterministic execution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Joule agent creation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The agent was configured in the agent builder capability of Joule Studio with the goal of "explaining payroll variances". We grounded the agent in the business context by linking it to the payroll data retrieved by our custom skills.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The agent enables payroll administrators to instantly understand the reason for pay changes, such as a decrease in regular working time, a full week absence, or the elimination of overtime, by simply asking a question. This transforms the HR administrator experience by providing the necessary context for follow-up, which ultimately streamlines operations. This capability moves beyond standard deliveries, allowing for custom SAP Payroll automation that dramatically improves transparency and cuts down on investigation time. In a POC with a client of ours, it was estimated that our Payroll Variance Agent saves them three days per Payroll Analyst, per region.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="joule_agent_diagram-Copy of Page-1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335402i2CC294B436BAA918/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="joule_agent_diagram-Copy of Page-1.png" alt="joule_agent_diagram-Copy of Page-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499779067"&gt;What's next?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our early-stage experience working with Joule Studio in SAP Build was overwhelmingly positive. The capability was very intuitive to use, allowing us to quickly develop an agent and skills solution that delivered measurable value and scaled across SAP and non-SAP systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We see immense value in SAP Build's environment coupled with Joule Studio's AI capabilities, which empower partners like us to bring sophisticated, business-specific solutions to market rapidly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward, we plan on building AI Agents for more complex, multi-step scenarios that require dynamic planning and reasoning across a wider array of SAP and non-SAP systems. Our next steps will focus on integrating Joule with our own Payroll Expert Agent once A2A capabilities are available and build out several use-cases to achieve new levels of efficiency and user experience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/from-days-to-minutes-how-epi-use-labs-custom-joule-agent-automates-payroll/ba-p/14254271"/>
    <published>2025-11-05T14:10:11.733000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-beta-ai-assisted-incoming-bills-of-exchange-posting/ba-p/14261781</id>
    <title>Join the Beta: AI-Assisted Incoming Bills of Exchange Posting</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T07:28:45.644000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shivendra25</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1551668</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1893645061"&gt;Are you ready to transform your Bill of Exchange processes in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’re excited to invite you to participate in the beta testing program for an innovative new capability: &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Assisted Incoming Bills of Exchange Posting&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shivendra25_0-1762407697899.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336724i71995855D0EE3227/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shivendra25_0-1762407697899.jpeg" alt="Shivendra25_0-1762407697899.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This feature, set to be available for early access with the February 14, 2026 release(2602), leverages AI to simplify and streamline the handling of incoming Bills of Exchange (BoE). The current focus is on key regions such as &lt;STRONG&gt;Japan, China, France, Turkey, and the United Arab Emirates.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Managing Bills of Exchange can be a time-consuming task that involves extracting and interpreting large amounts of data. This new AI-powered capability aims to make your life easier by automating the extraction, mapping, and posting of BoE information directly within the application. The result: faster processing, reduced errors, and enhanced efficiency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a beta participant, you’ll have the opportunity to test this feature in your own SAP S/4HANA Cloud system. Your feedback will be invaluable in shaping the future of this tool. We will also organize regular meetings to share updates and collect your insights, ensuring that the tool evolves in a way that truly benefits your business processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1697131556"&gt;Key Dates&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Registration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; October 21, 2025 - January 15, 2026&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Program Start:&lt;/STRONG&gt; February 14, 2026&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Duration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 90 days&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Seats are limited, so act fast! To participate, you must be an SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition customer or partner and sign a Test Evaluation Agreement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to get involved? Visit the &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/4069" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;BETA Campaign&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;and click the Register button at the top left to secure your spot. Together, let's make handling Bills of Exchange more efficient and straightforward!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-beta-ai-assisted-incoming-bills-of-exchange-posting/ba-p/14261781"/>
    <published>2025-11-06T07:28:45.644000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/predicting-cycling-performance-sap-rpt-1-vs-ai-chat-models-and-strava/ba-p/14263679</id>
    <title>Predicting Cycling Performance: SAP RPT-1 vs AI Chat Models and Strava</title>
    <updated>2025-11-09T18:19:18.957000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VictorSevilla</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15643</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This study compares the prediction accuracy of SAP RPT-1, Strava, and leading AI chat models (Copilot, ChatGPT, Gemini) for a real cycling route. Using historical data from 85 rides, each model predicted time and average speed for the next session. Results show that &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 delivered highly accurate, deterministic forecasts&lt;/STRONG&gt;, outperforming general-purpose LLMs and coming close to Strava’s specialized algorithm. These findings highlight SAP RPT-1’s potential for precise forecasting in structured data scenarios. Once the model reaches &lt;STRONG&gt;General Availability&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we will extend this analysis to real business datasets for even more impactful insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_2-1762709039472.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337641i327FE9B3F078E3CD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_2-1762709039472.png" alt="VictorSevilla_2-1762709039472.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This article was created with the support of Microsoft Copilot, but the results are based on a real-world experience.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Introduction&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predicting performance in cycling is not just a sports challenge - it’s a fascinating analogy for forecasting in business. Just like companies predict production or maintenance needs, cyclists can try to anticipate their next ride’s time and average speed. In this study, we explored how different prediction models perform when estimating these metrics for a real cycling route.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We compared five approaches:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Strava’s prediction engine, widely trusted by athletes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP RPT-1, a tabular model designed for structured data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Three popular AI chat models: Microsoft Copilot, ChatGPT, and Gemini.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The actual ride result, serving as the baseline.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The goal was simple: predict the route time and average speed as accurately as possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Methodology&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The dataset included 85 cycling routes recorded over four months, covering distances, times, speeds, and elevation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_3-1762707650344.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337631i61AE018FFF4014E5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_3-1762707650344.png" alt="VictorSevilla_3-1762707650344.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each model received the same prompt:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“I will give you a CSV file with all the data about my last 4 months with the bike. You should predict my route time and average speed during the route on the next Sunday. Label [PREDICT] identifies which data need to be predicted by you. Analyse and give me your expectations for this Sunday.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We then compared:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Predicted time (in seconds)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Average speed (in km/h)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Response time (how fast the model delivered its prediction)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, we benchmarked these predictions against the real ride, which covered 53.6 km with 765 m elevation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Results&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;The predictions from each model were compared against the actual ride, which covered 53.6 km with 765 m elevation. The key metrics analyzed were time (in seconds) and average speed (in km/h).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_4-1762707799840.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337632i20BE265FAA225038/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_4-1762707799840.png" alt="VictorSevilla_4-1762707799840.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The simplified comparison shows clear differences in accuracy:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strava&lt;/STRONG&gt; delivered the closest prediction to reality, with only minor deviations in time and speed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; performed impressively, producing deterministic results and staying very close to the real values.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gemini&lt;/STRONG&gt; was fast and understood units correctly, but its speed prediction deviated more than others.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Copilot&lt;/STRONG&gt; struggled with consistency and unit interpretation, leading to larger errors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/STRONG&gt; showed the biggest gap, especially in time prediction, due to misinterpretation of units.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These results underline the importance of structured models like SAP RPT-1 for numeric predictions and reveal the limitations of general-purpose LLMs when handling precise, unit-based data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Conclusions&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The comparison highlights clear patterns:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strava&lt;/STRONG&gt; remains the most accurate overall, with minimal deviation in both time and speed. Its specialized algorithm and access to large datasets give it a strong advantage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; stands out as a powerful alternative. It delivered deterministic predictions, handled structured data effectively, and achieved results very close to reality. This shows its potential for numeric forecasting beyond sports—think production planning or predictive maintenance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gemini&lt;/STRONG&gt; produced fast responses and understood units correctly, but its speed prediction was less precise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Copilot&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/STRONG&gt; struggled with numeric interpretation. Copilot showed inconsistent outputs, while ChatGPT had the largest error in time prediction, likely due to misunderstanding units.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The charts you will include (bar chart, dispersion plot, and error chart) reinforce these insights, showing how SAP RPT-1 consistently outperforms general-purpose LLMs in accuracy and stability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bar charts&lt;/STRONG&gt; reveal how predicted times and speeds compare to actual values.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_0-1762707354122.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337628i8B644837E098FA58/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_0-1762707354122.png" alt="VictorSevilla_0-1762707354122.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dispersion plots&lt;/STRONG&gt; show the spread of speed predictions across models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_1-1762707360892.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337629iC68FC11C79AA113A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_1-1762707360892.png" alt="VictorSevilla_1-1762707360892.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Error charts&lt;/STRONG&gt; make deviations in time and speed crystal clear.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_2-1762707379644.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337630i3641C96914E5FB53/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_2-1762707379644.png" alt="VictorSevilla_2-1762707379644.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key takeaway:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP RPT-1 has demonstrated a clear advantage over current LLM models by effectively leveraging structured data to deliver more accurate forecasts. Once the model reaches General Availability, we will be able to perform even more precise comparisons using real business datasets, unlocking its full potential for enterprise forecasting scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Annexes&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;To provide full transparency and context, this section includes screenshots of the responses&amp;nbsp;generated by each model during the experiment. These captures show the raw outputs based on the same prompt and dataset, highlighting differences in interpretation, numeric handling, and prediction logic.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;SAP RPT-1 output:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_11-1762708606838.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337639i1157CF5DA2D14298/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_11-1762708606838.png" alt="VictorSevilla_11-1762708606838.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Strava Forecast:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_5-1762708366431.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337633i8DD98DACD3CD4C8B/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_5-1762708366431.png" alt="VictorSevilla_5-1762708366431.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Microsoft Copilot output:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_10-1762708576612.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337638i6D2FFBD68206E617/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_10-1762708576612.png" alt="VictorSevilla_10-1762708576612.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Chat GPT output:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_9-1762708560976.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337637i6D6A1481E65303E7/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_9-1762708560976.png" alt="VictorSevilla_9-1762708560976.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Gemini output:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_8-1762708548724.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337636iF8C3822B419E4A83/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_8-1762708548724.png" alt="VictorSevilla_8-1762708548724.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Actual ride data from Strava:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorSevilla_7-1762708533884.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337635iF2FC37CE18F60C7E/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="VictorSevilla_7-1762708533884.png" alt="VictorSevilla_7-1762708533884.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/predicting-cycling-performance-sap-rpt-1-vs-ai-chat-models-and-strava/ba-p/14263679"/>
    <published>2025-11-09T18:19:18.957000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-machines-learn-the-science-behind-model-training/ba-p/14261378</id>
    <title>How Machines Learn: The Science Behind Model Training</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T05:43:17.151000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ashishsingh1987</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/589094</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635475755"&gt;Understanding Model Training — A Step-by-Step Explanation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;One must have heard the buzzwords &lt;STRONG&gt;“Model Training”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;“Machine Learning"&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;"Model Learning”&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or &lt;STRONG&gt;“AI Model”&lt;/STRONG&gt; quite often — whether in tech discussions, product demos, or data science talks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, when it comes to explaining what actually happens during this “training” process — in plain English or even in technical terms — most people are left guessing. Is the model memorizing data? Is it adjusting something inside? What exactly is it learning?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, let’s peel back the layers and understand what truly happens when a model is trained — step by step. We’ll start from a simple analogy and then gradually move into the math behind the learning process. The goal is to make the idea of “model training” not just familiar, but intuitively clear.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568044969"&gt;Analogy: A Child Learning to Throw a Basketball&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To understand the model learning process in a simple, non-technical way, imagine a child learning to throw a basketball into a hoop.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Initially, the child doesn’t know how much force to use. On the first try, the ball falls too short or goes too far. Depending on the outcome, the child adjusts slightly and tries again. After a few attempts, the child improves and starts hitting the target consistently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s exactly how a machine learning model gets trained — it starts with random guesses, measures how wrong it was, adjusts itself, and improves over many repetitions. It learns not because someone told it what’s right, but by learning from its own mistakes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371531464"&gt;Before We Begin Few Important Notes:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1433183397"&gt;Data as Numbers&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;To train any model — whether for image classification, prediction, or generative AI — data must be represented numerically (as integers, decimals, or vectors). In this blog, we’ll skip the mathematical details of data conversion to numeric format. As part of this blog we will take an example of data which is already in numerical form.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1236669892"&gt;Loss Function&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;A loss function is like a report card for a machine learning model. It tells the model how well or how poorly it performed on the training data by comparing its predictions with the actual answers. In simple terms, the loss function calculates the difference between what the model's predicted and what it should have predicted. The bigger the difference, the higher the loss — meaning the model is doing poorly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The whole idea of model training is to minimize the loss — that is, to reduce the gap between what the model predicted and what it should have predicted with every iteration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911073668"&gt;Optimizer&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;An optimizer is the part of the training process that helps the model to&amp;nbsp;learn from its mistakes. Once the loss function tells the model how wrong it was, the optimizer decides how to adjust the model’s &lt;STRONG&gt;internal parameters (like weights and biases)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to reduce that error in the next round.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Think of it like the model’s coach or guide — after every attempt, it reviews the model’s performance (using the loss value) and gives it small, calculated corrections to move it closer to the right answer. Technically, an optimizer updates the model’s parameters ensuring that with every step, the model’s predictions improve.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Popular optimizers include &lt;STRONG&gt;Gradient Descent, Adam, RMSProp, and SGD&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-843642882"&gt;Optimization step &amp;amp; Learning rate&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-905294815"&gt;Optimization step&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;P&gt;An &lt;STRONG&gt;optimization step&lt;/STRONG&gt; is the actual moment when the model &lt;STRONG&gt;updates its internal parameters&lt;/STRONG&gt; (like weights and biases) based on what it learned from the loss function. The optimization step applies the gradients calculated in previous steps to make the model slightly better than before.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can think of it as the model taking one step forward in the right direction toward minimizing the loss.&lt;BR /&gt;Over many such steps (iterations or epochs), the model gradually “learns” the best parameter values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-708781310"&gt;Learning Rate&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;P&gt;The learning rate, often denoted by the Greek letter η (eta), controls how big each optimization step should be. It’s a small numerical value that determines how quickly or slowly the model updates its parameters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If the learning rate is too high, the model might overshoot the optimal point and fail to converge.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If it’s too low, the model will learn very slowly and take a long time to reach good performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In simple terms —&lt;BR /&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;learning rate is like the step size&lt;/STRONG&gt; the model takes while learning.&lt;BR /&gt;A good learning rate ensures the model moves steadily&lt;STRONG&gt; toward lower loss&lt;/STRONG&gt; without jumping past the goal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mathematically:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;wnew = wold − η × (∂L/∂w)&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Now let's dive into the actual model training part.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--4063071"&gt;Introduction — What Happens When a Model Trains&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we call below code in python:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;model.fit()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;we are asking the model to learn patterns that map inputs to outputs. Behind this simple command lies a mathematical cycle of prediction, error measurement, and gradual improvement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In essence:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Model training is about minimizing mistakes — by repeatedly predicting, comparing, and correcting.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To truly understand what “learning” means, let’s dive one level down in the layers with a simple example: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;linear regression&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, where a line is fit to the provided data points using &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;gradient descent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--146725226"&gt;Step 1: Getting the Historical Data and Understanding the Business Ask&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To begin any model training process, we need historical records which holds the input and output values required for model training.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s consider the below data points as our historical records, where x is the input and y is the output for our model training. It means that whenever x happened, what was the value of y.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;x&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;y&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business problem:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Build a model that predicts &lt;EM&gt;y&lt;/EM&gt; for any given &lt;EM&gt;x&lt;/EM&gt;, based on the historical data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--343238731"&gt;Step 2: Making Predictions (Forward Pass)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Making predictions in world of model training is also referred to as “Forward Pass”, where both true input and the true outputs (i.e. historical record samples) are provided to the model for it to start learning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since we are considering a linear regression as our example, we use the simple model equation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;ŷ = w·x + b&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ll start with random model parameters: &lt;STRONG&gt;w = 0&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;b = 0&lt;/STRONG&gt;, predictions for all (x, y) pairs are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For three training data points values i.e. in the pairing of (x,y) as per above mentioned historical records:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;(1,2), (2,4), (3,6)&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;x&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;y (Actual)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ŷ (Predicted)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;0&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;0&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;0&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The model predicts nothing correctly yet — it hasn’t learned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s break down one prediction for better understanding.&lt;BR /&gt;For example let us consider the pair (x,y) --&amp;gt; (1,2), where x is the input to the model equation and y is the expected output.&lt;BR /&gt;We have our parameters w and b both having value as “0”.&lt;BR /&gt;If we substitute values of w, x and b in above equation, since both w and b are “0”, the result will be “0”.&lt;BR /&gt;Same thing happens with other paired values of (x,y). Hence all the predicted values are “0”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--539752236"&gt;Step 3: Measuring the Error (Loss Function)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We measure how wrong the predictions are using &lt;STRONG&gt;Mean Squared Error (MSE),&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;which is given by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;L = (1/n) Σ(yᵢ − ŷᵢ)²&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Substituting the numbers:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;L = (1/3)[(2−0)² + (4−0)² + (6−0)²] = 18.67&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;So, the &lt;STRONG&gt;loss = 18.67&lt;/STRONG&gt; — quite high.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;The model now knows &lt;EM&gt;how bad&lt;/EM&gt; it is doing, but not &lt;EM&gt;how to improve&lt;/EM&gt;. That’s where gradients come in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--736265741"&gt;Step 4: Learning from Mistakes (Gradient Computation)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To improve, the model must figure out &lt;STRONG&gt;how changing each parameter (w, b)&lt;/STRONG&gt; affects the loss.&lt;BR /&gt;This is done using &lt;STRONG&gt;gradients&lt;/STRONG&gt; — the partial derivatives of the loss with respect to each parameter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;∂L/∂w = −(2/n) Σ xᵢ(yᵢ − ŷᵢ)&lt;BR /&gt;∂L/∂b = −(2/n) Σ (yᵢ − ŷᵢ)&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;At our current statue (w=0, b=0):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;∂L/∂w = - (2/3) × [(1)(2) + (2)(4) + (3)(6)] = - (2/3) × 28 = -18.67&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;∂L/∂b = - (2/3) × (2 + 4 + 6) = -8&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;This tells the model to &lt;EM&gt;increase&lt;/EM&gt; w and b to reduce the loss.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--932779246"&gt;Step 5: Updating the Model (Optimization Step)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now comes the &lt;STRONG&gt;optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt; step — where we update parameters in the opposite direction of the gradient, scaled by the &lt;STRONG&gt;learning rate (η)&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lets take&amp;nbsp;η = 0.1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We update parameters using the learning rate (η):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;wnew = w − η(∂L/∂w)&lt;BR /&gt;bnew = b − η(∂L/∂b)&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Plugging in the values:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;w = 0 − 0.1(−18.67) = 1.867&lt;BR /&gt;b = 0 − 0.1(−8) = 0.8&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;After iteration 1: &lt;STRONG&gt;w = 1.867, b = 0.8&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Training doesn’t stop after one update.&lt;BR /&gt;We repeat the process (forward pass → loss → gradient → update) for several &lt;STRONG&gt;epochs&lt;/STRONG&gt;, each time bringing the model closer to the true pattern.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s perform one more iteration to see the progression.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1422695758"&gt;Iteration 2&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-2088952019"&gt;Forward Pass&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;ŷ = 1.867x + 0.8&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;x&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;y&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ŷ (Predicted)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2.667&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;4.534&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;6.401&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Loss after iteration 2:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;L = (1/3)[(2−2.667)² + (4−4.534)² + (6−6.401)²] ≈ 0.34&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Loss dropped from 18.67 → 0.34 in just one iteration!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1892438514"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compute Gradients&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;∂L/∂w = - (2/3) × [(1)(2−2.667) + (2)(4−4.534) + (3)(6−6.401)] = - (2/3) × [−0.667 − 1.068 − 1.203] = 1.86&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;∂L/∂b = - (2/3) × [(2−2.667) + (4−4.534) + (6−6.401)] = 1.73&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1695925009"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update Parameters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;w = 1.867 − 0.1 × (1.86) = &lt;STRONG&gt;1.681&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;b = 0.8 − 0.1 × (1.73) = &lt;STRONG&gt;0.627&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;After iteration 2: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;w=1.681, b = 0.627&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Loss has dropped sharply — the model is learning!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Loss Summary Table:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Iterations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;w&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;b&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Loss&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;1.867&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;0.800&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;18.67&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;1.681&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;0.627&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;0.34&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;If we finish the training process after two iterations, the model for the given data would be represented by the equation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ŷ = 1.681x + 0.627&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, the values &lt;STRONG&gt;1.681&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;0.627&lt;/STRONG&gt; are the learned parameters (weight and bias) that the model has adjusted during training to best fit the data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The animation attached shows how the regression line gradually adjusts during training for 10 iterations. With each iteration, the model updates its weight (w) and bias (b) to better fit the data points — moving closer to the true relationship between x and y.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId-1499411504"&gt;Additional Note:&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;For ease of explanation, we considered an example with just one input variable (x).&lt;BR /&gt;However, in real-world scenarios, models usually work with multiple input features, represented as x₁, x₂, x₃, …, where each represents a different attribute or factor influencing the prediction.&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1650273578"&gt;Intuitive Summary&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Model training is guided trial and error mechanism. Each iteration:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The model guesses (&lt;EM&gt;forward pass&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It checks how wrong it was (&lt;EM&gt;loss&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It learns from the error (&lt;EM&gt;gradient&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It updates itself slightly (&lt;EM&gt;optimization&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It repeats until mistakes are minimal.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;And that’s how a simple mathematical routine turns into a “&lt;STRONG&gt;learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;” machine or what we proudly call today a “&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Machine Learning Model.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-machines-learn-the-science-behind-model-training/ba-p/14261378"/>
    <published>2025-11-10T05:43:17.151000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307</id>
    <title>The Future of Supply Chain Management | Part 1 of 6</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T13:28:03.217000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Joerg_Wilke1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/880183</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337983iB92DCD9ECB4F908E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1762776972060.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain 2035: How&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Future Supply Chain Management Works &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More and more companies have recognized the critical power of supply chain management for business success – without viable supply chains, there are no satisfied customers, no successful product launches, and no stable value creation. Supply chains need to continuously evolve to meet these needs. Today, digital technologies open up numerous opportunities, which you could only dream of a few years ago: more accurate forecasts, fully connected partner networks, and near-autonomous operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, the economic environment is changing at a rapid pace: geopolitical tensions, changing customer needs, and climate change pose additional challenges for companies. In ten years’ time, supply chain management will look different than today – more connected, data-driven, and more adaptable than ever before. But what exactly will change, and how can companies prepare for it today? To answer these questions, SAP Business Consulting and Kühne Logistics University conducted a comprehensive study last year, the results of which we present in today’s and the next five issues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are building on a previous study in which we analyzed the visions of the future of companies in the middle of the “Digital SC Hypes” ten years ago. The mood was euphoric: From numerous conversations with supply chain managers, over 120 potential use cases arose – from 3D printed Lego stones to the use of social media data in sales forecasting to mini factories, ultra-fast BOM resolution, and last mile drone delivery. Companies were ready to invest and experiment with new technologies. Much was visionary, some sounded like science fiction – and yet the digital revolution in supply chains seemed tangibly close.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our follow-up study shows a significantly changed picture. Pragmatic realism has given way to the great euphoria. Over the last 10 years, many technologies have been introduced slower and to a lesser extent than expected. The reasons for this include underestimated complexity and misconceptions about the performance of digital solutions (e.g. augmented reality, 3D printing or IoT), as well as an often inadequate technological state of development in the companies. Often, immature technologies, talent shortages, and inconsistent data quality slowed down execution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course, there were also some pioneers – often from industries with high pressure to innovate – who secure an advantage with targeted investments and know-how. Success often correlated with a focus on clearly outlined use cases with rapid return on investment: better delivery reliability, fewer disruptions, quickly tangible value for the user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This has been further reinforced by the recent years of pandemic, geopolitical tensions and economic weaknesses. Digital solutions for increasing automation, building integrated planning platforms, or tools to improve the customer experience are now only introduced if their value is clearly demonstrated. Successful projects usually start small and are not scaled until they have a proven effect. Lack of data quality, talent shortages, and lack of system integration are some of the biggest hurdles. Consistent data and change management is indispensable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Between 2015 and 2025, the view of digital technologies has changed significantly: away from technology-driven euphoria, towards a use-oriented deployment. The potential to achieve true competitive advantage with new technologies in supply chain management is enormous. However, many companies are still lagging behind technology leaders today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of our study, several surveys were conducted with a total of approximately 660 supply chain experts to understand today’s situation and expectations for 2035. In a multitude of in-depth discussions on Plan, Source, Make, Deliver, and People, we identified measures that companies should implement immediately, regardless of the scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are some exciting insights for the 2035 supply chains. First, the foundation of any successful digital transformation is a significant improvement in data quality. Companies also need appropriate tools to leverage this data and not remain “data-rich but insights poor.” People will continue to be important in the future, but their roles are changing. When AI takes on most of the operational work, and employees primarily monitor and develop, they are responsible for tasks that they have never practically performed themselves. Value chain silos will disappear, and technology-driven planning enables seamless end-to-end control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Few innovation leaders like Amazon, Apple or Procter &amp;amp; Gamble will be able to set new standards on their own. Most organizations do not have comparable budgets, skills, or talents. They will make technological leaps, especially if they can use market-based standard solutions and thus participate in developments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regardless of the individual level of maturity, it is possible to record: If you want to play at the front in 2035, you must already start implementing “no-regret moves”: for example, establish robust data governance, standardize processes, and introduce employees specifically to AI tools. Companies that lay these foundations today will not only use technologies in 2035, but will use them strategically. Or, to say it with the words of Wayne Gretzky, “Good players skate to the puck. Great players skate to where the puck is going to be.“&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the second part of the series, we will show in the next issue why supply chain planning is becoming the decisive success factor, what gaps exist here today between ambition and reality, and how companies can prepare for 2035 with data, AI, and agents. In the subsequent expenditures, we will examine the key findings of our research in the areas of purchasing, production, distribution, and employees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340454iFD3D03812DA7B84A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" alt="Joerg_Wilke1_0-1763108934112.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article was written in collaboration with Prof. Kai Hoberg (Kühne Logistics University) and Florian Diehlmann (SAP) in the context of the SAP-KLU study "The Supply Chain of the Future”.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-future-of-supply-chain-management-part-1-of-6/ba-p/14264307"/>
    <published>2025-11-10T13:28:03.217000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-document-ai-accelerates-document-centric-business-processes-with/ba-p/14264358</id>
    <title>SAP Document AI accelerates document-centric business processes with Generative AI</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T13:54:41.812000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jacobahtan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2758</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Authors:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7024"&gt;@amagnani37&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16662"&gt;@merza&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you to everyone who joined our recent partner webinar, &lt;STRONG&gt;"Streamline document processing with SAP Document AI"&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This session was part of our ongoing partner webinar series, "&lt;A href="https://url.sap/crvdej" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Talk to your business with Generative AI&lt;/A&gt;", and the turnout and engagement were fantastic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For those who couldn't make it, or for anyone who wants a recap, we—&lt;STRONG&gt;Merza Klaghstan&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Alice Magnani&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Jacob Tan&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the BTP &amp;amp; AI Solution Architects team —wanted to share the key takeaways, demos, and technical insights from the session.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our goal was to go beyond a simple feature list and show you how SAP Document AI can be the centerpiece of a complete, end-to-end business solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s what we covered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565066"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 1: What is SAP Document AI and Why Does it Matter?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We kicked off by tackling the core business problem: a staggering &lt;STRONG&gt;70-80% of all enterprise information is unstructured&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Manually processing this data from documents, emails, and scans is not only slow but also expensive and prone to errors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Document AI, formerly known as Document Information Extraction (DOX), is SAP's AI-powered solution on the Business Technology Platform (BTP) designed to solve this. It goes far beyond simple Optical Character Recognition (OCR) to &lt;STRONG&gt;extract, classify, and validate data&lt;/STRONG&gt; with high precision.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568134280"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We highlighted several key features:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multiple Editions:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The service is available in &lt;STRONG&gt;Base AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Premium AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; (which includes Generative AI capabilities), and &lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded&lt;/STRONG&gt; editions to fit different use cases. We also want to highlight for our &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Partners&lt;/STRONG&gt; that the Premium AI edition is part of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Test, Demo, and Development (TDD) license&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which provides a much more convenient model for your non-productive and internal development purposes.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_0-1762748655159.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337670iAC7B14D2EA3F5CEC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_0-1762748655159.png" alt="jacobahtan_0-1762748655159.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The New "Workspace" UI:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We compared the classic "Basic" UI with the new, full-featured "Workspace," which is the future of the service and includes capabilities like email channel configuration and workflow management.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;It's the new, full-featured environment for all document processing tasks . We want to emphasize that &lt;STRONG&gt;from now on, all the latest SAP Document AI features will be available in the Workspace UI only&lt;/STRONG&gt;, so we strongly advise using it for all new projects.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_2-1762778617735.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338002i32C51D71B4CCA784/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_2-1762778617735.png" alt="jacobahtan_2-1762778617735.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pre-Configured &amp;amp; Custom Content (Schemas):&lt;/STRONG&gt; The service provides many pre-trained models (called "Schemas") for standard documents like invoices and purchase orders. The real power, however, comes from creating &lt;STRONG&gt;custom schemas&lt;/STRONG&gt; for any document type your business needs—from specialized licenses to internal forms.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_2-1762748655205.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337672iFABDFFF3FF0DDE1F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_2-1762748655205.png" alt="jacobahtan_2-1762748655205.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generative AI &amp;amp; Instant Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; For custom schemas, SAP Document AI leverages Generative AI and Large Language Models (LLMs) to understand and extract information. We also demonstrated &lt;STRONG&gt;"Instant Learning,"&lt;/STRONG&gt; where the model learns from your manual corrections &lt;EM&gt;immediately&lt;/EM&gt;. After one correction, it knows how to handle that document layout correctly the next time.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In our demo, we showed how the model initially struggled with a name containing a middle name and extracted the wrong federation name (full name vs. acronym) . After one manual correction and confirmation, it learned immediately. Technically, this feature uses &lt;STRONG&gt;few-shots prompting&lt;/STRONG&gt; to make the underlying LLM aware of your previously reviewed documents to improve accuracy on the next run.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2Fb3ZP-2bAqK0%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3Db3ZP-2bAqK0&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2Fb3ZP-2bAqK0%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="Instant Learning in SAP Document AI for Streamline document processing with SAP Document AI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538056"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 2: A Real-World Use Case: "Vertigo Travels"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make this real, we introduced &lt;STRONG&gt;"Vertigo Travels,"&lt;/STRONG&gt; a fictional travel agency specializing in sports and adventure holidays. Their key challenge is managing the various kind of documents required for subscriptions, such as ID cards, medical certificates, and diving licenses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_3-1762748655218.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337673i4B1770A465F5332A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_3-1762748655218.png" alt="jacobahtan_3-1762748655218.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175107270"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The solution architecture includes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Vertigo Travels website&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a frontend application,&amp;nbsp; deployed in Cloud Foundry, serving as entry point for Travelers to select travel packages and upload the necessary documents, such as ID cards or medical certificates. The backend logic is a &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP (Node.js)&lt;/STRONG&gt; application also deployed in a cloud Foundry.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Document AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;, for all document intelligence operations, communicating via &lt;STRONG&gt;API&lt;/STRONG&gt; with our backend application.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as a persistence layer for our application, to store all the entities involved in the subscription process.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Work Zone standard edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as the entry point for Vertigo Travels employees to supervise the process. From Work Zone, business users can access the Vertigo Travel website for admin operations, or the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Document AI workspace&lt;/STRONG&gt;, for instance to review documents. SAP Build Work Zone also allows business users to use SAP Document AI via mobile.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, to define business rules to automate some document validation checks. Although this could also be implemented as part of the &amp;nbsp;Vertigo Travels backend application, SAP Build Process Automation enables citizen developers to modify easily the business logics when required.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as the core SAP Cloud solution. The Vertigo Travels backend is integrated with modules such as Business Partners, Products, Sales Orders/Invoice, Customer Return for refund.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107676484"&gt;For the source code, you may refer &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-generative-ai-hub-use-cases/tree/main/53-vertigo-travels-documentai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here for reference&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;P.S. if you're planning to work on this prototype, please give us a shout out~! So at least we know somebody is trying our repository out!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_0-1762777602698.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337997i11A82F6B49B135F4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_0-1762777602698.png" alt="jacobahtan_0-1762777602698.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911162979"&gt;We demonstrated three end-to-end scenarios:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The E2E Flow:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A traveler, Mary, subscribes on the website and uploads her documents. A back-office employee, Barry, reviews and corrects one document in the Document AI Workspace. Once confirmed, a Sales Order is automatically created in S/4HANA Cloud.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multi-Channel Ingestion:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A traveler, Luca, visits an office. The employee uses &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Mobile Start&lt;/STRONG&gt; to scan his ID and medical certificate. The system then automatically emails Luca about a missing document. He simply replies to the email with his license attached, which is automatically ingested via the &lt;STRONG&gt;Inbound Channel&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A traveler, Claire, uploads an income statement to apply for a discount. &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt; runs a rule to check her eligibility. When she submits her final documents, they have a high confidence score and are &lt;STRONG&gt;auto-confirmed&lt;/STRONG&gt; without any manual review.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FfaKqdkL1UmI%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DfaKqdkL1UmI&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FfaKqdkL1UmI%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="113" scrolling="no" title="Use Case end to end demo for Streamline document processing with SAP Document AI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-456484036"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 3: How We Built It (The Technical Deep Dive)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518135969"&gt;For our developer community, we walked through the "how-to" for the key components.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-450705183"&gt;For the source code, you may refer &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-generative-ai-hub-use-cases/tree/main/53-vertigo-travels-documentai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here for reference&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;P.S. if you're planning to work on this prototype, please give us a shout out~! So at least we know somebody is trying our repository out!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Setup and Schema Management:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We started with the BTP setup, which involves managing entitlements, creating the service instance, and, critically, &lt;STRONG&gt;establishing trust with SAP Cloud Identity Service (IAS)&lt;/STRONG&gt; for user authorization. We then showed how to create the custom schemas that power the application.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;When you set up your entitlements, make sure to use the application subscription ending in &lt;STRONG&gt;-ias (Identity Authentication Service)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as this is the one that provisions the new Workspace interface.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. API-Driven Development:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Our CAP application's backend communicates directly with Document AI's APIs. We showed code snippets for uploading a file (using the FileService) and processing it against a schema (using the SchemaService).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to retrieve specific extracted values:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;While our demo UI showed a simple text extraction, your application will likely need specific, structured data (like "gross_family_income" or "number_of_kids"). The API makes this straightforward:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After processing the document, you get a Document ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can use this Document ID to retrieve the Document Version ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Using the Version ID, you can then query the Entities for that document. 4. Finally, you can retrieve the specific value by using the Entity ID (e.g., the ID for your "number_of_kids" field) .&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is how our automation process, for example, was able to pull only the family income and number of kids to pass to the rules engine.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Configuring Email Ingestion:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We configured the "Channels" feature to monitor an email inbox. This required registering an app in Microsoft Azure, granting Mail.ReadWrite permissions , and then using the Document AI Workspace to map a specific email folder to our target schema.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F2CFz59M6QkE%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D2CFz59M6QkE&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F2CFz59M6QkE%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="113" scrolling="no" title="Email Ingestion by SAP Document AI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Enabling SAP Mobile Start:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This was a key integration for the in-office scenario. It involved three steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adding the Document AI dependency to SAP Build Work Zone within the IAS console.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Creating a specific BTP destination (sapdocumentaimobilestartintegration).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configuring the app tile in the Work Zone Site Manager with the correct navigation and visualization parameters (e.g., mobilestart.type = documentAi).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F6zSnSLFhono%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D6zSnSLFhono&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F6zSnSLFhono%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="113" scrolling="no" title="Document Scanning with SAP Mobile Start integrated with SAP Document AI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Automating Logic with SAP Build Process Automation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To keep our application logic flexible, we externalized our validation rules. We created a process in SAP Build Process Automation with a &lt;STRONG&gt;Decision Table (Rule)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to calculate the family discount based on income and number of kids. This process is exposed as an API and triggered by our CAP application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FULpiT681ooQ%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DULpiT681ooQ&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FULpiT681ooQ%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="113" scrolling="no" title="Decision Rules in Build Process Automation for Streamline document processing with SAP Document AI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jacobahtan_5-1762748655258.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/337675iDE3C9EE786CF3B6B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jacobahtan_5-1762748655258.png" alt="jacobahtan_5-1762748655258.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-125108959"&gt;For the source code, you may refer &lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-generative-ai-hub-use-cases/tree/main/53-vertigo-travels-documentai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here for reference&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;P.S. if you're planning to work on this prototype, please give us a shout out~! So at least we know somebody is trying our repository out!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-440170099"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 4: Conclusion, Best Practices, and What's Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We concluded with some key advice and a look ahead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--49746413"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best Practices &amp;amp; Responsible AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quality In, Quality Out:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The accuracy of extraction heavily depends on the quality of your scans.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Human in the Loop:&lt;/STRONG&gt; While automation is powerful, always design your processes with a "human in the loop" for validation, especially for critical data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Responsible AI:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We reiterated SAP's commitment to AI ethics. External LLM providers are carefully selected and are &lt;STRONG&gt;not permitted to store or retrain their models on customer data&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Features like continuous data sharing for model improvement are strictly opt-in and should not be used for sensitive personal data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--246259918"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started and Look Ahead&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are committed to helping our partners build on this platform. Here are the resources to get you started:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Document AI Official Help Page:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://url.sap/imohkv" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://url.sap/imohkv&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vertigo Travels GitHub Repository:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://url.sap/pi5vwn" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://url.sap/pi5vwn&lt;/A&gt; (The code for our demo app will be available here!)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Community for AI/ML:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://url.sap/ai-ml-grp" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://url.sap/ai-ml-grp&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The roadmap for SAP Document AI is packed with features, including more pre-built schemas, document workflows, custom LLM prompting, and deeper integration with Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, don't miss &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual&lt;/STRONG&gt;! Be sure to check out sessions &lt;STRONG&gt;AI821v&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;AI102v&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the latest roadmap and deep-dive innovations from the product team.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please feel free to leave any questions or feedback in the comments below!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-document-ai-accelerates-document-centric-business-processes-with/ba-p/14264358"/>
    <published>2025-11-10T13:54:41.812000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-handle-posting-issues-for-billing-documents-using-joule/ba-p/14258903</id>
    <title>How to Handle Posting Issues for Billing Documents Using Joule</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T07:47:22.168000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>emilyshi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/809418</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763849034"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Background Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a billing clerk, managing billing documents with posting issues can be frustrating sometime. Fortunately, Joule can streamline the process, making it more efficient and less stressful to resolves the posting issues.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Posting issues often arise when billing documents cannot be posted to the financial account due to errors like closed posting periods. Common errors include accounting errors (F5/286 and F5/903), which occur when the billing date falls outside the open period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule is an AI copilot designed to enhance interaction with SAP business systems. Joule delivers a unified user experience across SAP's solutions, offering conversational interactions to streamline information access, automate business processes, and improve both employee and customer satisfaction. For more information, see &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/joule-guide/what-is-joule" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What Is Joule&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567335529"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure you have the &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales - Billing Documents&lt;/STRONG&gt; business catalog (&lt;EM&gt;SAP_SD_BC_BIL_DOC_PC&lt;/EM&gt;) assigned. The &lt;STRONG&gt;Billing Clerk&lt;/STRONG&gt; role template (&lt;EM&gt;SAP_BR_BILLING_CLERK&lt;/EM&gt;) includes this catalog by default.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set up Joule in your environment. For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule/initial-setup" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Initial Setup.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1370822024"&gt;Implementation Details&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow the steps below to try out this feature:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in to your Fiori Launchpad as a &lt;STRONG&gt;Billing Clerk&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Launch Joule. The method for launching Joule differs depending on your platform. See&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/serviceguide/using-joule?state=DRAFT&amp;amp;version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using Joule | SAP Help Portal.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ask Joule to find out billing documents with posting issues. You can narrow down your searching results by specifying criteria such as document type, issue type, or sales organization. Note that only the billing documents with accounting access error will be listed here.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;Post&lt;/STRONG&gt; button or chat commands to post a document. Only one document can be posted at a time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review the error message for more details.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;As an alternative solution, you can adjust the billing date to a valid date using the quick buttons. When the posting error is resolved, the document will be automatically posted. You can open the billing document to confirm the changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By following these steps, you can efficiently manage and resolve posting issues, ensuring a smooth billing process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watch the following video for step-by-step instruction:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_t2lq0d80" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-handle-posting-issues-for-billing-documents-using-joule/ba-p/14258903"/>
    <published>2025-11-11T07:47:22.168000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/vibe-coding-when-ai-writes-the-code-benefits-challenges-and-guardrails/ba-p/14266237</id>
    <title>Vibe Coding: When AI Writes the Code — Benefits, Challenges, and Guardrails</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T07:46:04.669000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>da_radix</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/703241</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From my experience leading engineering and delivery teams for high-value projects, I’ve understood that technology changes fast — and the way people leverage technology changes faster. Through the emerging rhythm of ‘Vibe coding’ developers &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;speed up each stage of the SDLC, minimize mundane work, and experiment while maintaining quality. It also helps programmers with intelligent code completions, pre-built templates, and l&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;everage AI suggestions, so thathey can &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;focus more on innovation, complex logic, and architecture. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://radixweb.com/blog/artificial-intelligence-statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;72% of global organizations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; use AI in at least one of their business domains. AI utilization is thrilling yet equally unnerving. The potential is remarkable, but it also comes with a huge responsibility.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, here’s my take on the opportunities, the risks, and the guidelines every organization needs to consider.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764706343"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why ‘Vibe Coding’ Matters Now&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;use cases of AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; have grown beyond its specific role to be a significant component of the dev team. Large language models, code generation tools, and specialized AI agents help draft modules, propose optimizations, and auto-generate tests. For enterprises prioritizing data sensitivity, integration, and complexity, this transformation is more than a strategic imperative. It helps change how we define value, delivery velocity, and team dynamics.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Speaking from my tech leadership experience, I’ve witnessed project schedules accelerate, and prototypes that took weeks to design are completed in a few days. This gave product owners and architects more time to think about long-term goals. However, speed without a structured approach is simply chaos. And that’s where expertise and experience are pressing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568192838"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Opportunities: Velocity, Innovation, and Scale&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are three big opportunities I often reflect on.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Velocity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; - AI-powered programming speeds up routine tasks like data-mapping code, unit tests, boilerplate, scaffolding, which further allows engineers to emphasize more on the challenging elements – business rules, edge-cases, and architecture. And for specific implementations, where orchestrations, BAPIs, and connector code are commonly used, code automation can drastically minimize time-to-value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Innovation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – When algorithms manage mundane activities, teams can innovate faster. You must ensure that your product teams improvise on &amp;nbsp;feature ideas with AI-enabled flow diagrams and mockups, streamlining the feedback process from stakeholders and clients. It’s seamless to experiment when testing a hypothesis becomes more cost-efficient.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scale &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– AI helps maintain standardization across extensive codebases and team structures. Trained models automatically recommend uniform code patterns; this keeps your enterprise's ‘coding vibe’ logical and seamless.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371679333"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Threat: Complacency, Drift, and Hidden Pitfalls&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, the flip side also demands attention.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Complacency&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – This drawback is real. If dev teams start accepting AI results on the surface, bugs emerge. I’ve observed that even the teams with good intentions might push out integration logic or autogenerated SQL that didn’t adhere to data sovereignty standards, edge inputs, and concurrency. These lapses might violate compliance or breach master data integrity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Drift &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Model drift and hallucinations are also the most significant concerns. AI sometimes might generate credible code or documentation that indirectly breaks security standards or business logic. If not checked early, these drifts enter production.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Human Risk &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– The biggest hidden pitfall is loss of skill. If engineers stop learning basic concepts, like debugging middleware, understanding BAPI contracts, or reading complex ABAP flows, it can erode the organization’s long-term strategic capability. This is a real issue that can be combatted only with a culture of continuous learning. Afterall, AI is here to compliment human abilities, but without human governance and intervention, it cannot make ethicll calls. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175165828"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Guidelines: Build for Trust, Not Just Speed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To experience the strengths while also managing the risks, development teams require an architecture of practice and governance. Drawing from our experience of working on specific projects, here are solid guardrails I would suggest.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define a ‘Trusted AI Baseline’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Refine&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; prompt libraries and train models using your organization’s secure patterns and best practices. I recommend managing a library of carefully designed model policies and prompt templates in line with your specific integration patterns, security controls, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://aws.amazon.com/what-is/service-level-agreement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;client SLAs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Default to Human Supervision &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Humans should first review every AI-generated modification&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. For design-based decisions, transfer outputs to product owners for verification against the business results. And for code, combine the AI’s recommendation tools with a named reviewer who has a good know-how of system invariants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Observability and Provenance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Maintain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; the record of suggestions made by AI, who approved it, and which version/model generated it. This traceability is non-negotiable for continuous improvements, debugging, and audits — particularly for businesses that majorly function under strict compliance demands.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ongoing Validation: Tests + Contracts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Go&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for automatic test generation alongside &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-based programming&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. For seamless integrations, you can design contract tests that help define throughput limits, expected error modes, and assert schemas. The automatic tests are like your safety net that lets you speed up while ensuring reliability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Talent Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keep your team members' skills honed by conducting frequent in-depth workshops on core topics, switching up team roles and responsibilities, and AI-based training for higher efficiency. We invest in resources for structured learning workflows that integrate AI-powered labs guided by experts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-978652323"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How Can You Make it REAL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Try&amp;nbsp;implementing these principles across different initiatives and collaborations. Some proven strategies I advise using include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hybrid Pipelines -&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Incorporate AI into &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://about.gitlab.com/topics/ci-cd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CI/CD pipelines&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; so that AI-produced outputs prompt the same contract tests, security scans, and static analysis as human-generated code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Co-Created Models - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For long-term clients, continuously refine private models based on anonymized snippets of the code, architecture docs, and integration logs. This helps make AI-powered suggestions aligned to corporate frameworks and context-driven.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transparent Delivery -&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Every pull request AI assists or generates needs to be&amp;nbsp;identified, audited, and monitored, streamlining compliance and post-launch maintenance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Client Workshops - C&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;onduct governance and skills development training sessions that consist of red-team simulation exercises — deliberately coaxing AI toward risky results to train teams to identify and address potential issues.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782138818"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Human Equation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the race towards AI-led transformation, the human equation is of utmost importance. Cutting-edge technologies like AI help optimize decisions, analyze data at scale, and automate processes. Still, it is human perspective, ethical oversight, and creativity that unlock the real potential of AI. If you opt for AI-driven innovation, don’t just focus on deploying algorithms—keep your team members in the loop to ensure that teams guide, verify, and apply human context to machine outputs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, by focusing on seamless collaboration between AI and humans, businesses can align speed with responsibility, driving innovation while managing risks. Ultimately, it’s the amalgamation of human governance and AI capabilities that defines long-term evolution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-585625313"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Takeaway&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I’m optimistic! When powered by knowledge and structured by guardrails, Vibe Coding can revolutionize how dev teams build. It empowers humans to focus on things machines cannot - define objective, map out strategies, and employ critical thinking. The key for quick-moving businesses lies in striking the right balance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, if you’re considering integrating Vibe Coding, begin with pilot projects, capture all data, and keep humans in the loop. Well, the future isn’t humans vs. AI — it’s the seamless collaboration of AI with humans, vibing to design and develop more intelligent systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/vibe-coding-when-ai-writes-the-code-benefits-challenges-and-guardrails/ba-p/14266237"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T07:46:04.669000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-exploration-to-excellence-maturity-assessment-for-sap-btp/ba-p/14267457</id>
    <title>From Exploration to Excellence: Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T00:46:59.654000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>joanneks</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7268</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello, SAP Community!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You've made the investment in SAP Business Technology Platform. You've implemented integrations, built extensions, and connected your enterprise landscape. But here's the question that keeps IT leaders up at night: &lt;STRONG&gt;Are you truly maximizing SAP BTP's potential, or are you leaving transformative value on the table?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For most organizations, the honest answer is somewhere in between—and that uncertainty is precisely the problem. Without a clear baseline of your current capabilities, it's nearly impossible to chart an effective course forward or justify additional resources to stakeholders who demand measurable results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To tackle this challenge, SAP introduced the &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/maturity-assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;at &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/A&gt;—a comprehensive technical evaluation designed to transform uncertainty into actionable insights. If you missed it during SAP TechEd, here are all the exciting details. Here's the On-Demand session of the SAP TechEd 2025&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752172006673001rFWp?token_type=bearer&amp;amp;client_id=08cbc601-1128-43a8-9587-150cadca5f52" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;XP100v | Accelerate adoption of SAP Business Technology Platform with confidence.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635655399"&gt;What You'll Get: Immediate Value, Strategic Direction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;You'll gain a precise understanding of your organization's maturity of SAP BTP utilization, allowing you to identify and address areas for improvement with tailored recommendations. Additionally, you'll align your platform strategy with broader business objectives, ensuring that every effort contributes to your digital transformation goals. Moreover, you'll uncover hidden operational efficiencies and innovative solutions that can drive tangible business value, elevating your role as a strategic tech leader within the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568224613"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_0-1762981526771.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339783iCD1165D9648DAB6F/image-dimensions/592x318/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="592" height="318" role="button" title="joanneks_0-1762981526771.png" alt="joanneks_0-1762981526771.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Roadmap Clarity&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Transform vague improvement intentions into a structured roadmap with prioritized actions based on your specific needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Investment Justification&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Develop compelling business cases for additional SAP BTP investments, armed with concrete data on maturity levels and improvement opportunities, aligned with your overall business objectives.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Uncover potential inefficiencies in how you're consuming SAP BTP services and discover opportunities to optimize SAP BTP utilization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Innovation Acceleration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Identify new use cases and innovative solutions you haven't considered based on your maturity profile.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242628389"&gt;Getting Started: The Assessment Process&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The online questionnaire takes only 10-15 minutes to complete, which is less time than your daily stand-up. No lengthy interviews or extensive documentation reviews—just focused questions that get to the heart of your implementation. Upon completion, you receive immediate scoring along with a comprehensive report.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Complete the Questionnaire&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Answer focused questions across five key dimensions in just 10-15 minutes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Receive Your Results&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Get immediate feedback and access your comprehensive report in PDF to find areas for improvement and instant recommendations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Take Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Use the tailored recommendations to act.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_1-1762981526787.png" style="width: 588px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339785iFC0ECBD7C92D23CB/image-dimensions/588x250/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="588" height="250" role="button" title="joanneks_1-1762981526787.png" alt="joanneks_1-1762981526787.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_2-1762981526794.png" style="width: 586px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339784i1517B29B39462E2E/image-dimensions/586x269/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="586" height="269" role="button" title="joanneks_2-1762981526794.png" alt="joanneks_2-1762981526794.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175197603"&gt;Maturity Levels Explained&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-11-12 at 3.25.41 PM.png" style="width: 801px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339822iFA25E39E159C4ECA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-11-12 at 3.25.41 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-11-12 at 3.25.41 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP is designed to provide organizations with a clear, current snapshot of how to utilize SAP BTP effectively. This snapshot is segmented into five distinct maturity levels, each representing different stages of adoption and integration within the organization. These levels serve as indicators of an organization's ongoing journey towards digital transformation and innovation. By understanding and leveraging these levels, organizations can strategically evolve their usage of SAP BTP, ensuring that they derive maximum value from the platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_3-1762981526796.png" style="width: 910px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339786i29A35524113346AA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="joanneks_3-1762981526796.png" alt="joanneks_3-1762981526796.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Getting Started&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This initial phase involves early exploration of the platform, where learning and testing ideas occur in an ad hoc manner. Organizations at this level are in the discovery phase, familiarizing themselves with the platform's capabilities and potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In this stage, foundations begin to form as growing platform adoption occurs, although key practices are still maturing. Organizations start to incorporate SAP BTP more consistently into their operations, paving the way for broader implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Standardization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: At this level, clear processes and shared approaches are established across teams, ensuring consistent and strategic SAP BTP usage. This marks a critical point where the platform becomes an integral part of the organization's technology stack, contributing to more streamlined and effective operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Scalable Execution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Here, SAP BTP is deployed reliably at scale, driving innovation across the organization. This stage reflects a higher level of maturity, where the platform is not only used but also leveraged to achieve strategic business objectives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Center of Excellence&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The pinnacle of SAP BTP maturity, this level signifies that the organization recognizes SAP BTP as a strategic driver of its business. Enterprise architecture, operations, and delivery capabilities are optimized around SAP BTP, fostering an environment of continuous innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/maturity-assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; serves as a valuable tool for organizations to evaluate their current standing and plan for future growth. It not only aids in identifying areas for improvement but also provides actionable insights to enhance the platform's utilization, ultimately supporting the organization's continuous process of evolution and thriving in the digital landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849601379"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Act Now&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The role of SAP Business Technology Platform in driving intelligent enterprises continues to expand, with new capabilities emerging regularly—from enhanced integration patterns to advanced AI agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organizations with a clear understanding of their current maturity level can evaluate these innovations strategically, adopting what drives value while avoiding distraction. The objective is not only to assess your BTP maturity but also to create a continuous improvement cycle rather than being forced to react when gaps become critical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In conjunction with the new &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/maturity-assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;,&amp;nbsp; SAP BTP Adoption Phases are introduced on &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/guidance-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; as a beta version for SAP TechEd. This will provide a clear path to align the phases of SAP BTP adoption with &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.leanix.net/en/wiki/tech-transformation/sap-activate-methodology" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Activate Methodology&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Activate Methodology also offers additional common accelerators (e.g., project management templates) and an integrated tool chain (e.g. with SAP Cloud ALM) to run larger SAP implementation projects. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To illustrate the relationship between the Future Ready Enterprise Model, the new Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP, and the Adoption Phases, here’s a TAM of the process:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="joanneks_4-1762981526803.png" style="width: 668px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339787i0318FA5CB215AF8A/image-dimensions/668x452/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="668" height="452" role="button" title="joanneks_4-1762981526803.png" alt="joanneks_4-1762981526803.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-653087874"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your Next Steps: From Assessment to Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/10/sap-connect-btp-ai-business-suite/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bharat Sandhu, CMO of SAP BTP, notes&lt;/A&gt; that developers struggle to effectively utilize AI due to difficulties in integrating it with business-specific data and processes, resulting in diminished benefits. Additionally, the time and cost of building applications, along with the challenge of managing fragmented systems, underscore the need for a more robust AI-powered development platform. To solve those challenges, knowing precisely where your organization stands today is crucial for maximizing the transformative potential of SAP BTP. The Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP is designed to deliver this insight, helping you determine if your organization is fully harnessing its capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're at the beginning of your SAP BTP journey or looking to optimize mature investments, this assessment provides a comprehensive technical baseline alongside the strategic clarity, objective data, and actionable recommendations you need to move forward with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the SAP TechEd On-Demand Session: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Watch the On-Demand session&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1752172006673001rFWp?token_type=bearer&amp;amp;client_id=08cbc601-1128-43a8-9587-150cadca5f52" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;XP100v | Accelerate adoption of SAP Business Technology Platform with confidence &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for a demo of the Maturity Assessment for SAP BTP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Engage with the Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Join &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;upcoming webinars and workshops&lt;/A&gt; where SAP experts and peers discuss assessment findings and share best practices for advancing BTP maturity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leverage Additional Resources&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/use-cases.html?sort=latest_desc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;existing SAP BTP use cases&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the corresponding&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Discovery Center missions with accelerators.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Read about SAP Discovery Center Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everything-you-need-to-know-about-sap-discovery-center-before-teched/ba-p/14249744#M185626" target="_blank"&gt;Read this blog&lt;/A&gt; to learn all of the notable updates on SAP Discovery Center in preparation for SAP TechEd 2025.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-585657088"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Take the first step by visiting &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; today and unlock the insights that will drive your next breakthrough&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-exploration-to-excellence-maturity-assessment-for-sap-btp/ba-p/14267457"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T00:46:59.654000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-smarter-support-experience/ba-p/14266192</id>
    <title>A Smarter Support Experience</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T05:36:37.206000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>feliciashafiq</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1401024</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Your support experience is evolving. Key changes and what you need to know.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;As part of our ongoing efforts to make &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;support from SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;smarter and easier for you&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, we have been piloting new ways to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;optimize&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the support experience and better connect you with the right channels and the right experts. We are excited to share that these improvements &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;are &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;now &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;live&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s changing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As your entry point, the “Get Support” application has been enhanced to make it easier to create and manage your support cases.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A clearer, unified navigation structure now guides you through case creation, with each step accessible from the left-hand pane.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The detailed description field has been moved to the beginning of the process—helping you provide important context earlier and improving the quality of AI-driven recommendations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Improved UI consistency and AI disclosure messages to make the interface more transparent, intuitive, and ready for future innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In particular, the Incident Solution Matching (ISM) service has been further enriched with generative AI (GenAI) capabilities. Based on the information you provide, the service compiles relevant solutions and summarizes them into a single, easy-to-read answer—complete with links to the original knowledge articles used.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The GenAI feature is being rolled out to customers in phases, starting with a limited group and expanding over time. It includes a feedback option to continuously refine your experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When you create a case, you may receive a recommended priority based on your case details. This helps guide your selection so your case can reach the right experts and most suitable support channel, helping to enhance the overall resolution time. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You remain in full control and can always adjust the priority &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;to reflect your business impact or urgency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="New customer view in 'Get Support' application" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339083iF3732ACBE394B697/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NewGetSupport_SCT_Combined_Submit.png" alt="New customer view in 'Get Support' application" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;New customer view in 'Get Support' application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Set up your case for faster resolution&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To help ensure your case reaches the right experts as quickly as possible:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Write a concise title for the issue that states the key symptom.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use the detailed description section to provide evidence, error messages, recent changes, and attempted fixes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select the correct system that is affected by the technical issue you want to report&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select the most accurate product, function, or component.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clearly describe the business impact, along with any workarounds in place&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keep your case updated if conditions change and add feedback if you adjust the proposed priority.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for partnering with us as we continue to transform support from SAP into an experience that is smarter and more effective for you.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-smarter-support-experience/ba-p/14266192"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T05:36:37.206000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445</id>
    <title>Joule in SAP Build Code can now create freestyle UI5 apps</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:58:38.496000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndreasKunz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Last year, we&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-for-freestyle-sapui5-development-in-sap-build-code/ba-p/13650005" target="_blank"&gt;introduced the SAPUI5 extension for the Joule coding assistant in SAP Build Code&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/now-ai-helps-you-developing-sapui5-applications/ba-p/13649767" target="_blank"&gt;wrote about how to use it&lt;/A&gt;. Over time, it has received more features, like the AI-supported &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sapui5-meets-typescript-a-smooth-migration-journey-with-joule/ba-p/13958872" target="_blank"&gt;conversion of UI5 apps to TypeScript&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and setting up new pages and the respective navigation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The latest improvement, available from November 2025, lets you&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;create new freestyle UI5 apps&lt;/STRONG&gt; according to your requirements. The feature is not absolutely groundbreaking, as there are other tools doing a similar job like the &lt;A href="https://github.com/ui5-community/generator-easy-ui5" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Easy-UI5 templates&lt;/A&gt; and the recently published &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;UI5 MCP Server&lt;/A&gt;. But:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It brings the functionality right to the fingertips of developers using SAP Build Code—no other tools needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It extends the template capabilities beyond what the Easy-UI5 templates provide.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementing it within the Build Code Joule environment yielded interesting insights and further improvements. More on this in my &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_self"&gt;other article&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565993"&gt;The feature&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule makes specific features available using "slash commands". The new one is &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt;. When you open the Joule panel in SAP Build Code and start typing &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5&lt;/FONT&gt;, you might see it suggested, as well as other UI5 features. But which commands appear depends on the context. While some are only available &lt;EM&gt;within&lt;/EM&gt; UI5 apps, this new feature is only available when you are &lt;EM&gt;not&lt;/EM&gt; in a UI5 app. It won't be available e.g. in a workspace which has a ui5.yaml at top-level, or when you have a UI5 controller open in the code editor!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" style="width: 368px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338077i84DC1A2BF1286B93/image-dimensions/368x637/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="368" height="637" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762783668270.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Try it in a workspace with a &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/about/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;CAP&lt;/A&gt; project at root level, so you see some of its magic immediately: as soon as you finish typing the slash command or select it from the suggestion list, another suggestion list with sample prompts comes up. These are based on the actual data structures of the CAP project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" style="width: 470px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336598i81FF249A52996728/image-dimensions/470x310?v=v2" width="470" height="310" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762360829864.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means you can simply select the desired entity and service, then the actual full prompt will automatically be entered into the field(but of course you can also write your own prompt!). This full prompt includes even more details than the short prompt in the suggestion list did.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" style="width: 426px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336599iE4DE35FC0A4A5C5B/image-dimensions/426x146?v=v2" width="426" height="146" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762360943920.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that the prompt includes a concrete list of properties and the service URL. This information has been extracted from CAP using good old deterministic code—no Large Language Model (LLM) used. In fact, this is an area where AI would likely make up ("hallucinate") property names which do not actually exist. Acquiring all this information in advance in a deterministic way not only gives you the chance to review and adjust the prompt with little effort, but also leads to a more reliable functionality overall.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The paradigm: use LLMs (Large Language Models) where they excel—processing and "understanding" language—and use deterministic code for hard facts and well-defined operations, where possible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI part starts soon enough, when you submit this prompt. It proposes a specific app setup, highlighting the key choices for you to review. For example, it will suggest a sensible name (if you didn't provide one) or suggest the best location inside the project structure (which it knows from its context).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" style="width: 419px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336631iE19FE81A151525DB/image-dimensions/419x840?v=v2" width="419" height="840" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" alt="AndreasKunz_3-1762361609611.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But you can do more than just review those &lt;EM&gt;parameters&lt;/EM&gt;.&amp;nbsp;A suggested version of the app has already been created behind the scenes, so you can scroll through the 30+ files listed in the box at the bottom and click those you want to preview. If the result already looks fine to you—perfect. Just press the "Accept Application" button and the app will be set up in your workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439052488"&gt;Refining the app&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;But of course you are free to continue the conversation and tweak the result. The LLM in Joule will put its true strength at work, mapping its understanding of your request to what the underlying template can do. No need to type "change parameter x to value y": LLMs also understand you when you are less formal and direct. Look at the below screenshot for an example: it responds almost too compassionately to the developer who is "hesitant about new technologies" and recreates the app with changed parameters—using JavaScript instead of TypeScript. The user did not even mention the programming language specifically, but still the LLM decided that changing it would be the best way to accommodate the app code to the user's preferences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" style="width: 453px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336633i0D1C4439BEED17A1/image-dimensions/453x307?v=v2" width="453" height="307" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" alt="AndreasKunz_4-1762362503152.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this stage, you can refine the setup of the initial app—within the limits imposed by the application template used behind the scenes, which only has limited degrees of freedom. We want this &lt;EM&gt;initial&lt;/EM&gt; app to be robust and follow best-practice code. We also want those 30+ files to be created in &lt;EM&gt;one&lt;/EM&gt; fast step. Hence the code is not written by AI, but by using predefined template files we are back in the world of traditional deterministic coding here. You have plenty of opportunity for using AI later on to extend the app from this solid starting point.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule is aware of its limits in this step, so it will not say "yes" to every request you throw at it. Asking for "a trillion tables" or other features beyond the template scope will be politely rejected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" style="width: 444px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336641i7605E4A29BE73A9E/image-dimensions/444x350?v=v2" width="444" height="350" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" alt="AndreasKunz_5-1762362958997.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538983"&gt;Accepting the app&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the preview looks good and you have pressed the &lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" style="width: 120px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336642i611B7F59F8108180/image-dimensions/120x28?v=v2" width="120" height="28" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762363122124.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;button, the job of this &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; assistant is done. After app setup has finished (which may take a while because the dependencies need to be installed), it concludes with hints how to continue, including instructions on how to start the app in your respective workspace setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" style="width: 433px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336644i28549BEB965E64F1/image-dimensions/433x492?v=v2" width="433" height="492" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" alt="AndreasKunz_1-1762363265947.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The created application looks roughly like this, with a table and a detail form below. Note: only OData V4 services are supported at this time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" style="width: 852px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336941iA1EC68BDFAA86432/image-dimensions/852x529/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="852" height="529" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762439788736.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You get this kind of UI when you specify an OData V4 service and entity. If you don't, then there is just a generic "Hello World" success page instead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Of course this UI structure might not be exactly what is desired in the app or even requested in the prompt, but this is what the template can do. When an OData service and entity but no properties are requested, then the tool tries to detect existing properties. If this fails, the table will be empty (no columns at all)—but Joule's success message should then mention this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046025478"&gt;After creation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the assistant suggests, please move to the other Joule assistants&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5&lt;/FONT&gt; and &lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-page&lt;/FONT&gt; for developing the app further. In order to create more apps, reset the conversation with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" style="width: 23px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336645iB9B5AF8D09E44E81/image-dimensions/23x23?v=v2" width="23" height="23" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" alt="AndreasKunz_2-1762363377944.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;button at the top of the Joule pane.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;EM&gt;knows&lt;/EM&gt; that it cannot modify the app or re-create it, it will politely guide you to the options you have, no matter what your request is. It may even give instructions on how to achieve the given goal within a UI5 app, but it will not be able to modify the code and it will make this clear when needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849511973"&gt;AI Learnings&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;While there is not much more to say about this feature—simply try it!—there are some facts and learnings about its implementation! If you are curious, head over to the second part of this blog post:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447" target="_self"&gt;Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T15:58:38.496000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447</id>
    <title>Inside Joule: Lessons from building an AI coding assistant for SAP Build</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T16:00:38.750000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndreasKunz</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/189706</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1635565995"&gt;Flashback: the feature&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a &lt;EM&gt;"making of"&lt;/EM&gt; article about the implementation of the new&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; slash command available within Joule in SAP Build Code. In short, this new feature enables a conversation between AI assistant and application developer about a new freestyle UI5 application to build, with a full-fledged best-practice application starting point as result.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To see screenshots of this feature in action and understand it better, feel invited to read &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-in-sap-build-code-can-now-create-freestyle-ui5-apps/ba-p/14264445" target="_self"&gt;my previous blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are just here for the background and AI-related learnings—go ahead!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1439052490"&gt;General considerations&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;With open‑ended prompting, users aren’t restricted to predefined interactions. The user could ask for &lt;EM&gt;anything&lt;/EM&gt;. In contrast to traditional programming, a prompt input field can’t be handled with a sprawling web of if/else logic trying to cover all possible use-cases. Attempting this will lead to a frustrating user experience where the user often gets an "I do not understand your request".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some developers try to mimic this traditional programming pattern when crafting prompts and contexts for LLMs, telling an LLM "&lt;EM&gt;if the user asks for x, then answer y&lt;/EM&gt;". Instead, as demonstrated below, tell the LLM what it &lt;EM&gt;can&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;cannot&lt;/EM&gt; do and give it a goal to achieve. It's "smart" enough to figure out a suitable response to whatever the user will throw at it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1242538985"&gt;A fundamental choice&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking at this specific feature in the specific environment, the implementation options on the table were (for a variety of reasons) these two:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Either just provide a system prompt (a prompt that is added behind the scenes in addition to what the user typed) without interfering with the specific prompts and replies entered during the conversation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Or adopt a new way of creating an "agentic" multi-step execution plan. Similar to a guided activity, this would allow phases of data collection, possibly in different steps for different data, then an app creation step and so forth.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Surely "agentic" and "well-defined steps" sound good for app creation from a template, no? In fact, the initial implementation started like this, but it was soon apparent that this would neither provide the expected flexibility nor allow for a truly intelligent app creation experience. Defining phases in which to acquire specific information and having the application code created at a specific stage in this process did not feel right. The user would still feel like clicking through a traditional template creation process, as something specific was expected from the user at every stage, instead of giving the user the freedom to tweak every aspect at every stage. The true power of AI, on the other hand, would be totally underused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But then again... just a system prompt and that's it? No file read access to explore the environment, no dynamically updated instructions? Is this enough for an intelligent coding assistant?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1046025480"&gt;Creating an "AI agent" out of nothing&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consider the now common definition of an "AI agent" which has settled over the course of this year: it's nothing more than "&lt;A href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/395657404_An_LLM_Agent_Runs_Tools_in_a_Loop_to_Achieve_a_Goal_A_Comprehensive_Semantic_Framework_for_Defining_AI_Agents_and_Agentic_Systems_by_Simon_Willison_and_Leading_Research_Laboratories" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;an LLM with tools, called in a loop to achieve a goal&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;". The chat conversation provided by Joule can be our loop, an application template with its parameters is the tool and the goal of assisting the developer to create an app can be stated in the system prompt. Of course a real &lt;EM&gt;autonomous&lt;/EM&gt; agent would require the loop to run without user interaction, but for this feature a loop involving the user is just right.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system prompt used for this feature literally includes: "&lt;EM&gt;Y&lt;SPAN&gt;ou help users create new UI5 applications by analyzing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;their requirements and filling the project template parameters. [...]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your goal is to gather all necessary information to create a new UI5 application.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The application will be generated from a template which&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;has only one page and a hardcoded UI, but can optionally display data from an OData V4 service. [...]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You cannot create the application yourself, but the user will see a preview...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;". There you have it: the goal and the tool!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It then goes on with some behavioral hints and of course a detailed description of what exactly the template parameters do. Finally, it requests &lt;EM&gt;each reply&lt;/EM&gt; to contain a JSON object with the best choice of template parameters according to the current understanding of the user request. The JSON object could look like this example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;{&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "appNamespace": "com.myorg.myapp",&lt;/SPAN&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "basePath": "/path/to/workspace",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
   "createAppDirectory": true,&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;   "framework": "SAPUI5",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "frameworkVersion": "1.136.0",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "author": "John Doe",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "oDataV4Url": "https://services.odata.org/TripPinRESTierService/(S(s5xrj1t51r41s3ooztsynysq))/",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "oDataEntitySet": "Airports",&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "entityProperties": ["Name", "Address"],&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "runNpmInstall": true,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "initializeGitRepository": true,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;   "typescript": true&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;SPAN&gt;}&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This JSON object is removed from the LLM response before displaying it, then the application is generated with these parameters, so the user can accept it or request changes. In an environment where tools with a well-defined interface like MCP servers are not enabled, this JSON object as part of the conversation is how the integration with the templating tool is achieved. A note to make this very clear: this environment is &lt;EM&gt;not&lt;/EM&gt; the official SAP Joule assistant running inside end-user applications, as it is now also being enabled for development by customers. Instead, it is a sort of predecessor implementation specifically available in SAP Build Code since spring 2024.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some of these parameters in the JSON object are more important than others with regards to the user explicitly influencing them or having to accept them. Whether the app code is generated as TypeScript or JavaScript is something the user should not be surprised with &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; accepting the app! On the other hand, the author name, which is only written into package.json, can be reliably defaulted to the logged-in user name and also very easily changed later on if needed. Hence, the parameter descriptions explain not only &lt;EM&gt;what&lt;/EM&gt; they do, but also how much the user should be bothered with them. As result, Joule usually does not even mention half of the parameters, thus keeping the conversation focused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" style="width: 455px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339533i8B53DC0B3A50E913/image-dimensions/455x912/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="455" height="912" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762953076854.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-849511975"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to stop the agent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regarding the state &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; the app was accepted, the prompt explains "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AFTER the user has generated the application, you **MUST NOT** continue discussing parameters for generation, but rather [...] i&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;n particular by referring the user to the '/ui5' command for most requests or '/ui5-create-page'&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;for adding pages to the app, because they are much better than you in developing features, as they have the capability to automatically select a suitable context of files.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This means the transition in the overall process between refining parameters and "no more changes possible" is not a hardcoded step or denoted by changing the system prompt, but rather explained up-front. That's enough. Can you talk Joule into proposing another set of parameters after the app was accepted? Maybe. But its &lt;EM&gt;normal&lt;/EM&gt; behavior is just right: it will explain that the app can not be created again without restarting the conversation. Nevertheless, there are also non-AI guardrails in place to prevent the app from being generated again, thus causing trouble.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All in all, we shape Joule’s behavior by explaining the templating tool and its limits, by stating the goal and desired behavior towards this goal, and by explaining the general flow, in particular the state after app acceptance. This is enough to guide it to a suitable reaction for whatever the user requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Even if the user insists like this:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" style="width: 457px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/339649i5AAFEF728BB75C51/image-dimensions/457x620/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="457" height="620" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1762962593436.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-652998470"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Context, context, context!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To make the entire feature really user-friendly, however, it is not sufficient to write a good prompt, but the context must also provide enough information to the LLM to allow for informed decisions. Hence, information like the list of project root files and folders, whether a Git repository is present, plus CAP service/entity/property info, and more, are gathered (e.g. using the &lt;A href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@sap-ux/project-access" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@sap-ux/project-access&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;package). This knowledge is provided as prompt context behind the scenes or used in another way (like as content of the suggested prompts). This makes Joule aware of the environment it acts in, leading to better responses, like automatically avoiding app names that would conflict with existing folder names.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agentic coding assistants like Cline, GitHub Copilot, Cursor etc. usually have the ability to read files and execute shell commands as needed to understand their environment. In this pure user request + LLM response environment this might have been a bit harder to build. Basically, more tools could have been defined, e.g. by describing other JSON object structures for invoking them. But control would not so easily return to the LLM until after the user has entered another prompt.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But for a narrow scenario like app creation this wasn't necessary. Collecting the most relevant information up front not only provides sufficient context, but also improves performance and reliability by avoiding repeated tool calls and unpredictable LLM loops.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-456484965"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In-response prompting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The real-world context, however, changes over time. Specifically, once the app is created and accepted, there are new additional files present.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When developing the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_self"&gt;UI5 MCP server&lt;/A&gt;, we observed that the agentic AI tool (e.g. Cline) using the MCP server often decided to inspect the new app directory tree after creation, causing several LLM roundtrips which cost time and tokens. Or it would run "npm install" again, even though it had already been executed. Or it would make specific coding errors very often in subsequent modifications. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To avoid this, we extended the response of the MCP server after creating the app. Normally, it contains just the success message. &lt;A href="https://github.com/UI5/mcp-server/blob/a5a06382e0b3b8b39beaf1f40e95f2d887b3b50b/src/tools/create_ui5_app/createSuccessMessage.ts#L30-L66" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;But now it includes&lt;/A&gt; a full list of generated files, it states that "npm install" was already executed and it instructs how to prevent those coding errors. Basically, the MCP server response added further updated instructions to the conversation context. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Exactly the same principle was applied in this new Joule feature. While there is no autonomous agent loop in this case which would inspect the new files, the knowledge &lt;EM&gt;which&lt;/EM&gt; files were created can be valuable for the conversation with the user. And while the&lt;FONT face="andale mono,times"&gt;/ui5-create-app&lt;/FONT&gt; command doesn't modify any code after app creation (thus avoiding the coding issues), facts like whether "npm install" was already executed, or whether the created UI5 Table in the MainView is lacking any columns, are useful for giving the user hints how to continue. Therefore, the context is extended by adding a hidden message to the conversation history.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-259971460"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Traditional coding has its place(s)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition to the process of context collection, deterministic coding is also used &lt;EM&gt;after&lt;/EM&gt; the app has been accepted by the user for making the app consumption as smooth as possible. When inside a CAP project, it for example ensures that the &lt;EM&gt;cds-plugin-ui5&lt;/EM&gt; is added as dependency. This allows the UI5 tooling, including TypeScript transpilation of the UI5 app when needed, to run as part of the "cds watch" or "npm start" script of the CAP project itself.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Also, this dependency and all the UI5 app dependencies need to be installed. Unfortunately, there is a wide range of options and specific setups which might be used for dependency management in the already existing app. Probably&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;npm&lt;/EM&gt;? With or without workspaces? &lt;EM&gt;yarn&lt;/EM&gt;? &lt;EM&gt;pnpm&lt;/EM&gt;? Others? The code detects what is used and tries to cover the 95% case. The initial setup might not be complete in &lt;EM&gt;every&lt;/EM&gt; scenario, but for most users it will “just work,” providing a good developer experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is fine and all, but sometimes one has to go the extra mile and do some coding.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-63457955"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key takeaways&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use deterministic code where reasonable (because the space of possibilities is bounded and a deterministic and quick result is beneficial) .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use LLMs for language understanding or dealing with an unpredictable range of possible requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don't try to "program" the LLM with an if/else prompt, but treat it like an intelligent human: state the goal, options and boundaries—and let it decide on its own.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Provide solid pre-collected context so the LLM can make good decisions reliably.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--133055550"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;P.S.:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For those who prefer graphics over text to gain an understanding of something, here is a depiction of the overall information flow inside this feature.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" style="width: 931px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340805i5BAE698E5DCD6369/image-dimensions/931x498/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="931" height="498" role="button" title="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" alt="AndreasKunz_0-1763130462734.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/inside-joule-lessons-from-building-an-ai-coding-assistant-for-sap-build/ba-p/14264447"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T16:00:38.750000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
