<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Artificial-Intelligence-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Artificial Intelligence</title>
  <updated>2025-09-24T11:10:06.449376+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Artificial Intelligence/pd-p/c3c3a408-33ea-4c2a-ae6f-05461e76982d" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Artificial Intelligence blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/evolving-from-manual-ai-deployment-to-intelligent-operational-orchestration/ba-p/14210716</id>
    <title>Evolving from Manual AI Deployment to Intelligent Operational Orchestration: A COO’s Viewpoint</title>
    <updated>2025-09-08T12:26:34.864000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>da_radix</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/703241</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Over the years, I have firsthand witnessed how organizations adopt new, advanced technologies. Some move forward with bold vision, while others take the next step cautiously, assessing the terrain with small, contained pilots. Artificial Intelligence is no exception.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the majority of boardrooms today, AI has undeniably become essential to business. Yet, it is often leveraged on a project-by-project basis – an analytics dashboard, a predictive model, or a chatbot for any other department. These projects are strategic foundations but usually fail to achieve holistic transformation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The concern isn’t the AI itself. It’s how enterprises deploy it – disconnected, incremental, and fragmented from an integrated business roadmap. The outcome? Teams functioning in isolation, information gets siloed, and tech leaders struggle to align AI investments towards tangible business results.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is why I believe we stand at an inflection point: the paradigm shifts from manual AI deployment to what I call intelligent operational orchestration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759914734"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beyond Disconnected Pilots&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Leveraging AI in an isolated fashion might lead to a false sense of advancement. A department might only see cost savings or efficiency gains, but the larger picture often remains the same. When insights fail to flow across different organizational departments, AI stays experimental rather than driving enterprise-wide transformation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To leap forward, organizations need to change their mindsets - AI is not a collection of standalone applications. It's the binding network of data with decisions, people with processes, linking strategy with execution, and modern operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This highlights the path toward what I define as intelligent orchestration—a model where AI not only helps optimize tasks, but also orchestrates greater business outcomes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563401229"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Intelligent Operational Orchestration Actually Means&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At its heart, orchestration brings intelligence together across the enterprise. It advances beyond deploying more models or automation. Instead, it ensures that decision frameworks, processes, and data operate in unison.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Think of this as migrating from a series of solo performances to a finely tuned symphony. The significant instruments - AI models, data pipelines, and automation workflows - are already present. Orchestration unites them, ensuring every component contributes efficiently at the right time to deliver exponential impact.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this context, orchestration helps enterprises to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrate intelligence into processes rather than considering it an extra.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Allow cross-functional partnerships to break down silos where important information often stays confined.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Align technology with strategy to ensure &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI initiatives&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; directly contribute to long-term goals.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1366887724"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Orchestration: Significance and Relevance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The timing could not have been more crucial. We live in a rapidly changing era, also defined by uncertainty like mounting competition, regulatory changes, shifting client behaviors, and supply chain disruptions. In such an ecosystem, organizations can’t rely on standalone improvements anymore; they require systemic agility.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Intelligent operational orchestration helps with precisely the same. It delivers the most critical benefits enterprises should not overlook:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agility at Scale - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enterprises can respond rapidly to opportunities or disruptions because intelligence flows easily across functions and processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Operational Efficiency - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Orchestration helps eradicate duplicated efforts, redundant processes, and manual handoffs, which frees your employees to concentrate more on value-driven work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Future-Readiness - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Because orchestration is flexible, organizations can upgrade their operating models without revamping from the start, every time the market changes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data supports this! As per &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/quantumblack/our-insights/the-state-of-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;McKinsey’s research&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, organizations integrating AI across different workflows—not just in projects—illustrate 20–30% operational efficiency and solid market leverage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170374219"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lessons from the Field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In my conversations with different global leaders, I’ve spotted a repeating trend - scale drives results.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As per some reports by Deloitte, AI-driven financial automation can decrease closing time by up to 40% and enhance forecast accuracy by 20%.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A global food and beverage manufacturer also leveraged ThroughPut’s AI platform, which recovered &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://info.throughput.world/case-study-elimination-of-unplanned-outages-helps-global-food-manufacturer-boost-capacity-utilization?_gl=1*mu0na0*_gcl_au*NTA4NDI1MDM3LjE3NTYzNTcyNTM.*_ga*MTg4MzE3NDg1MC4xNzU2MzU3MjU0*_ga_E6X5Q0DQ9K*czE3NTYzNTcyNTMkbzEkZzAkdDE3NTYzNTcyNTMkajYwJGwwJGgw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;$0.5M in weekly productivity losses&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and increased output by 5% through reduced unplanned downtime and smarter machine utilization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These two stories highlight one crucial fact - AI serves as a revolutionary technology only when orchestrated, not when implemented in isolation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973860714"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From The COO’s Desk: Guiding Leadership Amid Orchestration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a COO, I regard orchestration as not just be treated as a technical challenge but a core leadership responsibility. Success with AI goes beyond experimentation; it's more about integrating intelligence rooted at the core of the operating model.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For leaders, this means:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Adopting an Ecosystem Mindset&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://radixweb.com/blog/ai-use-cases" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI use cases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; should not only be restricted to departmental barriers. Leaders should foster collective intelligence, where every process benefits from the shared insights.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Aligning AI with Strategic Results&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Orchestration must deliver outcomes beyond efficiency. It should solidify resilience, improve client value, and unlock innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scaling with Intention&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Expanding orchestration abilities needs governance models and systems that scale with the business. Short-term pilots should grow into long-lasting capabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Encouraging Cultural Readiness&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Most significantly, orchestration thrives on cultural alignment. Teams need to learn to trust AI-based information, emphasize enterprise-wide results, and collaborate across silos.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777347209"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In my view, the next great stride for organizations is more than just scaling AI—it’s all about orchestrating it smartly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This transformation highlights the next phase of enterprise growth. What once started as an experimental project is now entering its prime with company-wide orchestration frameworks that help drive scalability and resilience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Successful enterprises treat AI adoption not as a forward-thinking experiment, but as a coordinator of operations—a key driver of adaptability, agility, and strategic resilience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From my perception, as a COO, the ultimate proof of success is not how widespread AI is being leveraged, but how smartly it is orchestrated.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/evolving-from-manual-ai-deployment-to-intelligent-operational-orchestration/ba-p/14210716"/>
    <published>2025-09-08T12:26:34.864000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-blog-posts/understanding-cnns-convolutional-neural-networks-in-under-5-minutes/ba-p/14206164</id>
    <title>Understanding CNNs (Convolutional Neural Networks) in under 5 minutes</title>
    <updated>2025-09-08T12:53:19.338000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RaffaeleTalarico</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1615751</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI isn’t a dream of the future anymore; it’s all around us. With countless acronyms and concepts to grasp, one you can’t afford to ignore if you want to thrive at consulting is CNN, as it’s reshaping how companies operate and create value in digital economies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this quick guide, we’ll break down what CNNs are, why they matter, and how you can start building the skills to bring this knowledge into your consulting career.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Read through to the end for a resource that will help you take the first step in developing these skills.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1888247065"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, What is a CNN?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;CNN (Convolutional Neural Network)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a type of deep brain network that takes hints from how we see. Inspired by the way human brains interpret visual signals, it spots lines, edges, shapes, and patterns. Unlike the “old brain” webs that "see" each bit alone, CNNs can keep track of where things are. This helps them deal with big sets of pics, clips, etc.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why Convolutional? Well, the CNNs maintain spatial relationships by using layers called “convolutions” &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/image-classification-with-convolutional-neural-networks-2-my-final-results/ba-p/13159838" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Read more here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1691733560"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How does a CNN run? (In 3 steps)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Convolutional Layer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;” has three components: the input, which is an image, a kernel (also known as a filter) to detect features like lines, edges, or colors; and an output, which is a feature map summarizing the features found.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pooling Layer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;”: This layer simplifies the size of the feature map, keeping only the most important information.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fully Connected&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;” Layer takes all that information and uses it to perform classification or regression tasks&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="CNNSimpl.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308651i7A42296834C2DA9C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="CNNSimpl.png" alt="CNNSimpl.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1495220055"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is the difference between CNN and DNN?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DNN, Deep Neural Network&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, is an “AI brain web” with lots of links. It sees facts piece by piece, making it good for tasks like seeing pics, hearing speech, &amp;amp; dealing with words.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CNN&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is a kind of specialized DNN&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, well-suited for handling image data. The key difference is the ability to apply filters to the input image to extract key features. The information extracted through these layers is then passed to “fully connected layers,” which analyze the features and can generate predictions.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="DNNvsCNN.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308652iD2CA8443BF7B7075/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DNNvsCNN.png" alt="DNNvsCNN.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The big gap is what they do best: DNNs are all-around and work with many kinds of tasks. CNNs are top at jobs that need seeing &amp;amp; knowing visual facts.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1298706550"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What are CNNs mainly used&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;for&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1102193045"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tasks with Pics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CNNs work well at sorting, classifying, and detecting objects in images. They have transformed how companies manage visual information: from predictive maintainance tasks in manufacturing to smart supply chain management.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-905679540"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dealing with Docs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CNNs are widely used to automate the extraction of information from documents such as invoices, receipts, and contracts. Instead of relying on manual work or rigid rule-based systems, CNNs can identify and capture key data pointssuch as dates, monetary values, and vendor names with higher accuracy and speed. This also reduces human error, streamlines workflows, and ensures more reliable data for follow-up processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-709166035"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Seeing Things Early&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As said, CNNs are great for looking at things. And they are the perfect ally in enterprise contexts to “see things early”. CNNs can help look at data coming from equipment and machinery, for instance, and detect patterns and anomalies that signal possible failures. This potentially cuts costs &amp;amp; keeps work smooth.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-512652530"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CNNs in the SAP Ecosystem&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The integration of Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) and other advanced AI technologies within &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+AI/pd-p/73554900100700002751" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1247-1"&gt;SAP Business AI&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;is reshaping how businesses run and their competitiveness.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This means clients will increasingly expect you to explain not only the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;technology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, but also the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;business value&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; it creates. By embedding artificial intelligence into foundational business systems, SAP enables enterprises to enhance operational efficiency, leverage data-driven insights, and drive sustained innovation. As the company continues to evolve its AI offerings, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;consultants who can connect these capabilities to business outcomes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; will be the ones helping organizations achieve long-term success in an increasingly competitive marketplace.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you want to kickstart your career in consulting, explore the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/mena/training-certification/digital-skills-center.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Young Professionals Program&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; an initiative designed to upskill young talent in SAP’s latest solutions and prepare them as Associate Consultants, ready to deliver value across the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-blog-posts/understanding-cnns-convolutional-neural-networks-in-under-5-minutes/ba-p/14206164"/>
    <published>2025-09-08T12:53:19.338000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-practical-ai-enhanced-analytics-and-a-vision-for-the-future/ba-p/14211112</id>
    <title>🚀 SAP BTP Weekly: Practical AI, Enhanced Analytics, and a Vision for the Future</title>
    <updated>2025-09-08T19:09:05.766000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FedericoTokman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150724</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Joule Studio and No-Code AI Agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Creating intelligent agents without coding is now possible in SAP Build. This opens the door for both business and IT teams to build copilots that answer questions and automate tasks quickly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Beyond the &lt;EM&gt;no-code hype&lt;/EM&gt;, the challenge is cultural: will users trust an internally developed agent? Imagine a procurement team building an agent to negotiate with suppliers—it speeds up the process, but what if the agent misinterprets company policies? Human oversight remains essential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/spain/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-studio.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/spain/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-studio.html&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Joule for Consultants&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;A new program helps SAP consultants use Joule as a copilot during implementations. It includes guides, templates, and real-world use cases that can be applied directly to client projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The potential lies in reducing configuration time and accelerating deployments. But it also raises questions: to what extent will Joule replace manual tasks? For example, in a SuccessFactors project, it could generate initial configurations within minutes—though expert validation will always be required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/spain/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-assistant/sap-consulting-capability.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/spain/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-assistant/sap-consulting-capability.html&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Integration with Event Mesh and Kafka&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Advanced Event Mesh now connects with Apache Kafka, enabling hybrid and decentralized architectures. This allows for more resilient micro-integrations compared to traditional point-to-point models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The practical challenge lies in governance. A retail company might use it to synchronize inventories across multiple channels in seconds, but managing topics and ensuring traceability can become complex. SAP provides connectors, but the learning curve is real.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eur-expertsession-aemkafka/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/eur-expertsession-aemkafka/en_us/home.html&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Real-World FinOps on BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Companies adopting FinOps on BTP are gaining visibility and achieving up to 20% reductions in cloud costs. Dashboards and alerts help CIOs and CFOs make faster decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The challenge is organizational: finance and IT often “speak different languages.” Imagine a telco optimizing Integration Suite consumption—without internal agreements, discussions about who pays what can escalate. The technology is ready, governance isn’t always.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enhanced-finops-capabilities-for-sap-btp/ba-p/14113797" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enhanced-finops-capabilities-for-sap-btp/ba-p/14113797&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;New preconfigured processes allow automation of HR, compliance, and finance tasks in days. A “shortcut” for organizations seeking efficiency without large-scale projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The tricky part is resistance to change. An HR team may see value in automating vacation approvals, but users often fear losing control. SAP provides ready-to-use processes, but tailoring them to each organization still requires effort.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/public-site-for-sap-build-pre-built-content/ba-p/13562272" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/public-site-for-sap-build-pre-built-content/ba-p/13562272&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6. BDC and Databricks: Next-Generation Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The integration between SAP BTP Data &amp;amp; Analytics (BDC) and Databricks enables unification of SAP and non-SAP data in lakehouse environments for AI and advanced analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Picture a mining company combining SAP financial data with IoT sensor data in Databricks: the predictive potential is enormous. The challenge lies in governance: without a clear model, “data democratization” can turn into chaos. SAP ensures traceability, but governance is each organization’s responsibility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/02/sap-databricks-open-bold-new-era-data-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://news.sap.com/2025/02/sap-databricks-open-bold-new-era-data-ai/&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7. SAP Now Argentina – Business Highlights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The event showcased how local companies are applying SAP BTP and Joule to real business processes. Applied AI was the highlight, with use cases in retail, energy, and manufacturing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Beyond the excitement, scalability remains a question. Can a successful pilot in one area be extended across the entire organization? Use cases inspire, but customers still need clarity on timelines and adoption costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/databricks.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/databricks.html&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8. SAP Customer Success Day – Our Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This week we had the privilege of meeting with over 20 customers in an exclusive workshop on enterprise integration, exploring the power of SAP BTP Advanced Event Mesh (AEM) and SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Beyond the technology, what stood out was how different customers face similar challenges: shifting from point-to-point to event-driven models without losing control or simplicity. A bank raised the need to process thousands of transactions in real time; a retail company sought to orchestrate omnichannel inventory. Everyone agreed the key is not just the tool, but the ability to redesign processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7369726725749903369/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7369726725749903369/&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the end of the day, BTP is experienced differently depending on the role: for a CIO it’s efficiency and control, for an architect it’s integration, for a Basis administrator it’s security, and for a consultant it’s delivery speed. Yet ultimately, we all face the same question: how do we create real business value from technology without getting lost in complexity?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-practical-ai-enhanced-analytics-and-a-vision-for-the-future/ba-p/14211112"/>
    <published>2025-09-08T19:09:05.766000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-setup-for-sap-digital-manufacturing/ba-p/14211372</id>
    <title>Joule Setup for SAP Digital Manufacturing</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T07:08:49.388000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laxmipathivarma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1923093</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We're excited to announce that Joule, SAP’s AI-powered enterprise copilot, is officially integrated into SAP Digital Manufacturing. This marks the first-ever availability of Joule in the Digital Manufacturing domain, enabling manufacturers to tap into intelligent, conversational insights right within their production environments&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Digital Manufacturing is a suite of cloud-based and on-premise solutions that enables manufacturers to digitize, monitor, control, and optimise their production operations in real time. It integrates manufacturing processes with enterprise business systems, bridging the gap between ERP (like SAP S/4HANA) and shop floor operations, supporting Industry 4.0 and smart factory initiatives.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Core Capabilities Supported Scope&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Production Execution&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enterprise and Shop Floor Integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Visual Work Instructions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Quality Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manufacturing Analytics &amp;amp; KPIs (via DMi)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Production Orchestration &amp;amp; Monitoring&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Resource and Material Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Edge Integration / IoT Enablement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sustainability &amp;amp; Compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Supported Languages:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please refer to the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/JOULE/82a14f108cfa4d4788244d81371e072b/8d44120a69844638ad160569b8bdd60e.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;link&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for most up to date information on languages supported by Joule.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_2-1757392063142.png" style="width: 637px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311287iA82F87147F15B98F/image-dimensions/637x374/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="637" height="374" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_2-1757392063142.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_2-1757392063142.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;please note to validate the data centers supported by Joule &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/JOULE/3fdd7b321eb24d1b9d40605dce822e84/8b4d8708f6d646a995fdc50f8c508f1f.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;****************************************************************************&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;**********************************************&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog post is a series for Joule Activation:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/sap-business-ai-overview-for-all/ba-p/13871365" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business AI – Overview for all !!! &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(Includes information on Joule Supported Data Centers, Different scenarios during Joule setup, etc..)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/joule-unified-setup-bridging-simplicity-and-performance/ba-p/13924542" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule - Unified Setup: Bridging Simplicity and Performance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (Demo Video to understand the Unified Setup, Joule basics &amp;amp; architecture, how to set up Joule, etc...)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/joule-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-a-comprehensive-setup-guide/ba-p/13786453" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition - A Comprehensive Setup Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/joule-end-to-end-setup-guide-for-all-line-of-business-unified-approach/ba-p/13964602" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule Setup – End-to-End Setup Guide (for all Line of Business) Unified Approach&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/joule-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-setup-guide/ba-p/13965333" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition - Setup Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Digital Supply Chain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/joule-in-sap-integrated-business-planning-sap-ibp-setup-guide/ba-p/13965780" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule for SAP Integrated Business Planning (SAP IBP) – Setup Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/joule-getting-started-with-document-grounding-setup-guide/ba-p/13739501" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule – Getting Started with Document Grounding - setup guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/activate-joule-with-sap-build-work-zone-and-sap-mobile-start/ba-p/13999940" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Activate Joule with SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Mobile Start&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/analytical-insights-in-joule-setup-guide/ba-p/14096274" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analytics Insights in Joule – Setup Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule in SAP Signavio Process Transformation Suite – Setup Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-setup-for-sap-integrated-product-development/ba-p/14129828" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule Setup for SAP Integrated Product Development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_3-1757392063142.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311286i163BD9DC84AC03B9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_3-1757392063142.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_3-1757392063142.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule for SAP Digital Manufacturing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You are Here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Blogs - Work in Progress (WIP):&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Joule Activation (Refer to SAP Discovery Centre)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Digital Supply Chain (WIP)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Asset Performance Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Product Lifecycle Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Concur&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Ariba&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;and more to be added towards General Availability&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog will uncover the steps to activate Joule in two different ways: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Section&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(1):&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; create a Joule SAP Digital Manufacturing as a standalone product (Fresh activation), &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Section&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(2):&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Activating and adding Joule SAP Digital Manufacturing with an existing subaccount along with your other activated / current LoBs landscape&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;****************************************************************************&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;**********************************************&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scenario&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You want to integrate the generative AI copilot Joule with your SAP Digital Manufacturing application and require information about what to consider when you want to use Joule.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use Cases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following feature is available for Joule in SAP Digital Manufacturing:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conversational search of application help: Ask Joule questions about the SAP Digital Manufacturing apps and processes, and Joule gives you an answer based on the SAP Digital Manufacturing documentation from the SAP Help Portal.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pre-requisites&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ensure that you meet all requirements for Joule onboarding. For more information, refer to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/JOULE/6189c8655c484916bb8eb767126a653a/d42f2b7768f44b98a91f2d4178e8593c.html?version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in the Joule Onboarding Guide.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You have an entitlement for Joule in the same global account on SAP BTP as your entitlement for SAP Digital Manufacturing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You have subscribed to SAP Digital Manufacturing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration Process:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are activating Joule for the very first time for your SAP Digital Manufacturing system, then we refer to it as a standalone/single setup, as mentioned in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Section 1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;”.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this standalone setup process, you may decide to use the same SAP BTP Subaccount to activate Joule, or you may plan to use a new subaccount or if you would like to add SAP Digital Manufacturing to an existing subaccount and activate Joule that can be used which is a unified setup as described below in&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Section &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What does Unified Setup mean?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The unified setup of Joule with multiple SAP products allows business users to ask any question irrespective of the Joule client they are in. This approach helps avoid toggling between multiple applications, improves user efficiency, and deliver&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; a more consistent, connected experience across all LoBs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check your setup plan:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_4-1757392101308.png" style="width: 748px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311288iF816AEA371244D97/image-dimensions/748x385/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="748" height="385" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_4-1757392101308.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_4-1757392101308.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By now, we hope you've selected one of the setup plans. Before we begin activating Joule for SAP Digital Manufacturing, let’s take a moment to understand how Joule works.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;image below explains how Joule works with your landscape integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_5-1757392101308.png" style="width: 785px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311289iA991BAE127BB539A/image-dimensions/785x412/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="785" height="412" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_5-1757392101308.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_5-1757392101308.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note: In the current release of Joule for DM, we do not use the SAP Build Work Zone and Cloud Foundry services. This is planned for the next releases.   &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now, since you have a clear understanding about Digital Manufacturing and how Joule works now it is time for us to start the integration process:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let us have a look at the steps involved for the integration:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;****************************************************************************&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;**********************************************&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrating Joule&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 1: Setup Plan:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Section 1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: New Digital Manufacturing setup with no prior Joule setup.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Section 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: You have an existing Joule subaccount, and you want to enable Joule for Digital Manufacturing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;*************************************************************************************************************************&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 1: Setup Plan&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Section 1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: New Digital Manufacturing setup with no prior Joule setup.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you already have some experience with SAP BTP (Business Technology Platform) we request you to follow the steps in this blog - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/joule-end-to-end-setup-guide-for-all-line-of-business-unified-approach/ba-p/13964602" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule Setup – End-to-End Setup Guide (for all Line of Business) Unified Approach&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. I&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;n this blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; please check Section 2 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check your SAP BTP Account for Joule Entitlements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If this is your first time using the SAP DM (Digital Manufacturing) platform and you're unsure how to proceed with the activation, don’t worry - we’ve got you covered. Just follow the steps below to activate Joule for SAP DM easily. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fresh Digital Manufacturing setup – no existing Joule configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create the Subaccount and choose the relevant Data Centre&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Set up Trust Configuration with SAP Cloud Identity Service&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add Entitlements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Run the Booster and Integrations with the Product SAP Digital Manufacturing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note: Choose the SAP Digital Manufacturing Test as product to enable Joule in your SAP Digital Manufacturing quality tenant.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add the role “Joule_User” from the dmc application to a role collection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Assign those business users to the role collection that needs to interact with Joule.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure trusted domains in identity authentication for the SAP Digital Manufacturing domain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: For more information, refer to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap-solutions1/configure-trust-to-identity-authentication-tenant?q=onboarding%20joule" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure Trust to the Identity Authentication Tenant&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure a trusted domain in SAP BTP Cockpit for the same SAP Digital Manufacturing system&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: For more information, refer to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap-solutions1/configure-trusted-domain-in-sap-btp?q=onboarding%20joule" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure Trusted Domain in SAP BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add the DM_USER User Role Collection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to Launch the Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See Joule in Action&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step (1): Create the Subaccount and choose the relevant Data Centre&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-end-to-end-setup-guide-for-all-line-of-business-unified-approach/ba-p/13964602" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and follow step No – 5&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_6-1757392843748.png" style="width: 771px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311291i33D3EED42402837D/image-dimensions/771x457/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="771" height="457" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_6-1757392843748.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_6-1757392843748.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-end-to-end-setup-guide-for-all-line-of-business-unified-approach/ba-p/13964602" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and follow step No – 4&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_7-1757393445991.png" style="width: 761px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311299iE8DDFB9FEC2A8C56/image-dimensions/761x409/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="761" height="409" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_7-1757393445991.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_7-1757393445991.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step (2): Set up Trust Configuration with SAP Cloud Identity Service&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-end-to-end-setup-guide-for-all-line-of-business-unified-approach/ba-p/13964602" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and follow step No – 7&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_8-1757393578869.png" style="width: 759px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311304i2B658619F1ADAD3D/image-dimensions/759x366/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="759" height="366" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_8-1757393578869.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_8-1757393578869.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_9-1757393610072.png" style="width: 765px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311305iB154A46AE96DC5DA/image-dimensions/765x347/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="765" height="347" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_9-1757393610072.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_9-1757393610072.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_10-1757393647738.png" style="width: 763px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311306iF3F9B8043977CDB1/image-dimensions/763x448/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="763" height="448" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_10-1757393647738.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_10-1757393647738.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step (3): Add Entitlements&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-end-to-end-setup-guide-for-all-line-of-business-unified-approach/ba-p/13964602" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and follow step No – 8&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_12-1757393711141.png" style="width: 748px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311308i4C4E28EE761B0B0C/image-dimensions/748x377/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="748" height="377" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_12-1757393711141.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_12-1757393711141.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step (4): Run the Booster and Integrations with the Product SAP Digital Manufacturing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The complete setup process is documented in this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-end-to-end-setup-guide-for-all-line-of-business-unified-approach/ba-p/13964602" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Step No. 10 explains the process. For simplification, we have the simplified steps and images below. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Global Account&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select Booster&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Search for Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Run the Booster&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_13-1757393741898.png" style="width: 727px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311309i1025D8AF6573290C/image-dimensions/727x366/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="727" height="366" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_13-1757393741898.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_13-1757393741898.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The system will validate the entitlements required. Once it’s green, you can click on Next &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select the SAP BTP Subaccount and click on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_14-1757393790578.png" style="width: 717px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311310iA9A0EBFF8B89F9F7/image-dimensions/717x361/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="717" height="361" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_14-1757393790578.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_14-1757393790578.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select Integrations, you will be able to see the options for SAP&amp;nbsp;Digital Manufacturing , select it, and click on Next &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_15-1757393807926.png" style="width: 715px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311311i62F9C6902800215E/image-dimensions/715x362/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="715" height="362" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_15-1757393807926.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_15-1757393807926.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_16-1757393846088.png" style="width: 712px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311312i55CC9E9D10CC80A7/image-dimensions/712x338/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="712" height="338" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_16-1757393846088.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_16-1757393846088.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once you select the DM System, you can click on Next, review the selections, and click on Finish. The booster will take 5-9 minutes to activate Joule and set up the integrations with your DM system.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule will now return the success message after the integrations are completed. You can validate this setup by navigating to Systems and Formation, searching for the Joule formation that will be created for your setup, as shown below. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_17-1757393887977.png" style="width: 695px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311313iB412A6BD77AF1A7E/image-dimensions/695x238/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="695" height="238" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_17-1757393887977.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_17-1757393887977.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step (5): Add the role “Joule_User” from the dmc application to a role collection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After the booster run has completed and formation checks, add the role “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule_User”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; from the dmc application to a role collection.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Assign those business users to the role collection that needs to interact with Joule.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Subaccount&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Role Collections&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule_User&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Edit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Role Name&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_18-1757393912499.png" style="width: 690px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311314i7CADA00A8908AAA9/image-dimensions/690x345/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="690" height="345" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_18-1757393912499.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_18-1757393912499.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step (6): Configure trusted domains in identity authentication for the SAP Digital Manufacturing domain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information, refer to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap-solutions1/configure-trust-to-identity-authentication-tenant?q=onboarding%20joule" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure Trust to the Identity Authentication Tenant&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cloud Identity Services&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; click on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Applications &amp;amp; Resources&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;External Services&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trusted Domains&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_19-1757393951051.png" style="width: 704px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311315iB85D4AEC87D5DCD1/image-dimensions/704x286/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="704" height="286" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_19-1757393951051.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_19-1757393951051.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step (7): Configure a trusted domain in SAP BTP Cockpit for the same SAP Digital Manufacturing system&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information, refer to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap-solutions1/configure-trusted-domain-in-sap-btp?q=onboarding%20joule" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure Trusted Domain in SAP BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Sub Account &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Security&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Settings&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trusted Domains&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_20-1757393982610.png" style="width: 719px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311316i0A2E89AA5752CB62/image-dimensions/719x364/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="719" height="364" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_20-1757393982610.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_20-1757393982610.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step (8): Assign the role in Subaccount to launch the Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Sub Account &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Security&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Role Collection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add (DM_ROLE)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_21-1757394011666.png" style="width: 686px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311317iA327D3379C0A3E34/image-dimensions/686x350/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="686" height="350" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_21-1757394011666.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_21-1757394011666.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Step (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;9)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; See Joule in Action&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_22-1757394040336.png" style="width: 689px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311318i9737695835FC0DCB/image-dimensions/689x349/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="689" height="349" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_22-1757394040336.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_22-1757394040336.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Congratulations on successfully setting up the SAP DM Standalone system!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now, let’s walk through how to add SAP DM to your existing subaccount alongside your other active Lines of Business (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;LoBs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 1: Setup Plan&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Section 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You have an existing Joule subaccount, and you want to enable Joule for DM. In this option, we will show you how to activate DM in the context of an existing Joule formation. Within your SAP BTP Global Account, navigate to System Landscapes, click on Formations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Search for the Joule formation you have already set up. In my case, “I am using one of the existing formations, which has multiple SAP products connected to one Joule instance, as shown below”. You can click on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Include Systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_23-1757394068049.png" style="width: 719px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311319iCD75477015EDA1FE/image-dimensions/719x364/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="719" height="364" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_23-1757394068049.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_23-1757394068049.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the new window, filter for SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Digital Manufacturing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and click on Next step.  &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_24-1757394086623.png" style="width: 729px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311320iBE240DBD77A34148/image-dimensions/729x369/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="729" height="369" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_24-1757394086623.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_24-1757394086623.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select the option “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enable Capability Deployment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;” and “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enable the Joule Icon in Integrated System&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;” and click on Review&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_25-1757394099515.png" style="width: 719px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311321i313053F8358D4DA3/image-dimensions/719x364/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="719" height="364" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_25-1757394099515.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_25-1757394099515.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validate&lt;/STRONG&gt; the selections and click on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Include&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_26-1757394136574.png" style="width: 719px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311322iA4498AB45D4CCE4E/image-dimensions/719x364/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="719" height="364" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_26-1757394136574.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_26-1757394136574.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The process may take 5 to 8 minutes to complete, and you should be able to see the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;synchronizing &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;option, as shown image below.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Laxmipathivarma_27-1757394150273.png" style="width: 758px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311323i9AC8126DED3D0F9E/image-dimensions/758x384/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="758" height="384" role="button" title="Laxmipathivarma_27-1757394150273.png" alt="Laxmipathivarma_27-1757394150273.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once the status turns green and Ready, we are good to use &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Digital Manufacturing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; capabilities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Congratulations on successfully setting up SAP Digital Manufacturing with the Unified Approach!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In a similar approach, you may use Joule with a unified experience in other SAP products that you have integrated in the same subaccount.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you have any questions about the setup, you can reach us at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:SAP_AI_RIG@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP_AI_RIG@sap.com&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you for staying connected with our blog and successfully activating Joule for SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;D&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;igital Manufacturing !&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We hope you’ve had an exciting experience exploring the power of Joule, your intelligent business companion. From insightful decisions to streamlined processes, we trust you’re already seeing the incredible value Joule brings to your day-to-day work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here’s smarter, faster, and more impactful outcomes powered by Joule! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/joule-setup-for-sap-digital-manufacturing/ba-p/14211372"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T07:08:49.388000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-the-future-of-your-organization-with-our-new-sap-business-ai/ba-p/14210314</id>
    <title>Unlock the Future of Your Organization with Our New SAP Business AI Onboarding Resource Center!</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T07:28:04.523000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>patki_M</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46123</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Greetings, AI Enthusiasts!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Introducing our ORC page: your gateway to lay the foundation for success with SAP Business AI!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ready to unleash the potential of SAP Business AI and bring intelligent automation, innovation, and efficiency into your organization? A strong start is crucial for successful adoption. Our Onboarding Resource Center for Business AI is crafted to guide you through each step of effective SAP Business AI implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-08-21 at 12.52.32 PM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310857i92DD2CD8AAE2ED5D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-08-21 at 12.52.32 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-08-21 at 12.52.32 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Awaits You?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center/business-ai.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dive into the SAP Business AI Onboarding Resource Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Your ultimate hub for a smooth onboarding experience. Here, you'll uncover a treasure trove of open-access resources to get you up and running swiftly, including:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Detailed overviews of Joule, Embedded AI, and AI Foundation on SAP BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enlightening insights into responsible AI principles and secure implementation practices.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Guidance for tracking AI consumption with SAP AI Units to manage costs effectively.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Essential guides for access and security setup using Cloud Identity Services.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keep an eye out for AI Guides tailored to each solution area at SAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center/sap-customer-onboarding-webcasts/business-ai.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Harness AI Enablement, Best Practices, and Webcasts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Tap into a curated collection designed to help plan, execute, and continuously elevate your AI initiatives, featuring:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The SAP BTP AI Best Practices Guide for robust implementation strategies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;200+ real-world AI use cases to spark inspiration for your projects.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The AI Architecture Center and AI Catalog in SAP Discovery Center for reference designs and technical blueprints.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On-demand SAP Business AI Onboarding Webcasts, offering practical insights, showcasing solution capabilities, and sharing wisdom from SAP experts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your Onboarding Journey: Three Core Phases to Success&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Business AI Onboarding Resource Center content is strategically structured to accompany you from understanding to effective implementation within your business processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Phase 1: Get Started with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Establish a strong foundation by comprehending SAP’s AI portfolio and the tools available to you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Highlights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discover how Joule functions as your AI copilot.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dive into Embedded AI in SAP applications and explore AI Foundation capabilities on SAP BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gain insight into SAP’s AI-First Suite-First strategy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learn how to configure secure access with Cloud Identity Services for AI implementation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Phase 2: Plan Your Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Align AI adoption with your business strategy and empower your organization for success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Highlights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Define clear, business-aligned AI objectives that accentuate your strategic priorities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Employ structured project execution utilizing the SAP BTP AI Best Practices Guide.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Examine over 200 real-world AI use cases to identify and validate pilot opportunities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review proven solution architectures in the AI Architecture Center and explore the AI Catalog in SAP Discovery Center.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access On-demand SAP Business AI Onboarding Webcasts to educate yourself at your own pace, covering foundational concepts and practical implementation insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate governance, security, and change management best practices for enduring success.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Phase 3: Get Enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Objective:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Equip your team with the skills and resources needed to implement and scale transformative AI solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Highlights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Engage with free learning resources and role-specific enablement content.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Follow AI guides tailored to solution areas such as BTP, ERP, CX, Supply Chain, and HR.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Connect with experts and peers through the SAP Community.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seize the opportunity for hands-on learning through SAP Learning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In Conclusion:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Business AI Onboarding Resource Center is purpose-built to help you move from&lt;STRONG&gt; initial understanding to impactful business outcomes&lt;/STRONG&gt;. By combining strategic planning, secure and responsible implementation, and targeted enablement, you’ll be ready to deliver real value from AI across your organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center/business-ai.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Your journey to SAP Business AI success begins now&lt;/A&gt;—let’s make it happen!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stay tuned for the upcoming series of blogs from SAP BTP Onboarding Center:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Learn About AI Foundation Services on SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. AI in Application Development &amp;amp; Automation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. AI in Integration Suite&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. AI in Business Data Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5. Business AI Commercials- How SAP tracks AI Usage / Consumption&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Medha Patki | SAP BTP Onboarding Advisor&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customer Onboarding Center&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-the-future-of-your-organization-with-our-new-sap-business-ai/ba-p/14210314"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T07:28:04.523000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/keeping-the-human-in-human-resources-the-future-of-hr-in-the-age-of-ai/ba-p/14212592</id>
    <title>Keeping the human in human resources: The future of HR in the age of AI</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T03:03:59.866000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jasondesimone</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/21072</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As artificial intelligence moves beyond automating admin tasks and begins shaping decisions, culture, and careers, HR leaders are asking:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What does it mean to keep the “human” in human resources?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Katherine Gibbard, PhD and Autumn D. Krauss, Ph.D. from the Future of Work Research Lab at SAP SuccessFactors partnered with Aadesh Goyal (formerly Tata Communications), Herman Rolfers (The HEINEKEN Company), Rajamma Krishnamurthy (Microsoft), Marquam Piros (Seagate Technology), Mark Sankarsingh (PepsiCo), Dante Palazzo (Grupo Nós), and 8 other global HR executives explore the future of HR in the age of AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The result? A bold, actionable vision for what’s next.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; In our new research report, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keeping the Human in Human Resources: The Future of HR in the Age of AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, you’ll discover:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Which &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;human&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; capabilities will become essential (and why empathy, ethics, and leadership matter more than ever)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Where HR needs to upskill now to stay relevant and strategic&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; The six emerging archetypes of future-ready HR professionals&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; How AI can actually make HR &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;more human&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This isn’t a story about humans &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;versus&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; artificial intelligence. It’s about how we design a future where humans and AI work together to elevate the employee experience, strengthen culture, and lead with conscience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":open_book:"&gt;📖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Dive into the&amp;nbsp;full &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/08/0624a446-1b7f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;research report&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s not just keep up with change — let’s lead it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;#FutureOfWork #HRLeadership #AI #HRStrategy #HumanResources #HRTransformation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/keeping-the-human-in-human-resources-the-future-of-hr-in-the-age-of-ai/ba-p/14212592"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T03:03:59.866000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-driven-joule-enabled-warehouse-resource-amp-operations-management-for/ba-p/14212193</id>
    <title>AI-driven, Joule-enabled Warehouse Resource &amp; Operations Management for SAP EWM on S/4 HANA 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T16:58:05.917000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim_Dalm</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1777459</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tim_Dalm_0-1757515308715.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312444i11C39E82975AA0FE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tim_Dalm_0-1757515308715.png" alt="Tim_Dalm_0-1757515308715.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is a topic in every warehouse: Supervisors and Warehouse Operations Managers would like to see their planned workload for the day and see in real-time whether shipping times will be met. If shipping times are in jeopardy, the warehouse system is then expected to evaluate if an optimized resource allocation could pro-actively solve any potential delays. When a more optimal usage of the available resources is found, resources should automatically be directed to the critical areas. Being able to take action proactively is of the essence, because we do not want to only take action when we are already in delay.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following is an example of an AI-driven, Joule enabled Application that can accomplish the above outlined requirements and activities supported by AI. The Application leverages the embedded AI in the EWM Private Cloud Edition S/4 HANA 2023 FPS03 release and the Joule Studio available in SAP Build.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tim_Dalm_0-1757445553011.png" style="width: 849px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311902i8C85C1316F32C558/image-dimensions/849x482/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="849" height="482" role="button" title="Tim_Dalm_0-1757445553011.png" alt="Tim_Dalm_0-1757445553011.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Architecture of the Application looks as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tim_Dalm_0-1757444996110.png" style="width: 685px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311900i8856978AA3FE5860/image-dimensions/685x445/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="685" height="445" role="button" title="Tim_Dalm_0-1757444996110.png" alt="Tim_Dalm_0-1757444996110.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-based Warehouse Workload Visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the current version of the Application, the expected workloads of picking and packing operations are calculated leveraging the embedded AI capabilities in SAP EWM, which are then displayed in the UI5 Application (see in the example below):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tim_Dalm_0-1757511697370.png" style="width: 747px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312397iC01BCF8B5BC170A8/image-dimensions/747x295/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="747" height="295" role="button" title="Tim_Dalm_0-1757511697370.png" alt="Tim_Dalm_0-1757511697370.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is also clearly visible in which Activity Area the workload is currently exceeding the planned Resource capacity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Application then further allows a manual simulation of adding or removing Resources to evaluate the impact in a given activity area.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The fully "automatic rebalancing" function evaluates whether it is possible to optimize the resource allocation to the different areas, considering the allowed resource types in an Activity Area.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If an optimized resource allocation is possible, the warehouse operations manager, can accept these changes and the resources will be reassigned in the EWM system so that they will receive workload to execute from the new area.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule-enabled with custom EWM Joule Skills&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Further more the current version of the Application provides Joule support for Warehouse Operations Management with the following &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Skills&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Skill 1:&amp;nbsp;Current Workload Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Provide a comprehensive analysis of the current workload associated with picking and packing operations, considering the current resource allocation across different warehouse areas, as well as dependent scheduling of packing activities.&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Skill 2: Provide&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Optimized Resource Allocation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Simulate an optimal workforce allocation strategy to mitigate bottlenecks and criticalities within the warehouse operations, to avoid shipping delays.&lt;BR /&gt;- &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Skill 3:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accept Optimized Resource Allocation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Accept the optimization results and reassign the resources in EWM to the new areas.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Tim_Dalm_2-1757512858239.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312406iE55C75B11ADF12CD/image-dimensions/800x350/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="800" height="350" role="button" title="Tim_Dalm_2-1757512858239.png" alt="Tim_Dalm_2-1757512858239.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Coming soon an AI Agent will be introduce that autonomously orchestrates workforce allocation (monitored by the supervisor).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more Information on this Application &amp;amp; AI functionality please contact SAP Services (&lt;A href="mailto:EWMServices@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;EWMServices@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="daniele_oliva2_0-1757517311492.png" style="width: 753px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312459i1988F69EA8EDACD2/image-dimensions/753x402/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="753" height="402" role="button" title="daniele_oliva2_0-1757517311492.png" alt="daniele_oliva2_0-1757517311492.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-driven-joule-enabled-warehouse-resource-amp-operations-management-for/ba-p/14212193"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T16:58:05.917000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/agentic-ai-ai-which-finally-makes-sense/ba-p/14215135</id>
    <title>Agentic AI – AI which finally makes sense?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-11T22:08:13.878000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stevang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7643</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="nahrizul-kadri-OAsF0QMRWlA-unsplash.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313274i7633D573C4D6131D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nahrizul-kadri-OAsF0QMRWlA-unsplash.jpg" alt="nahrizul-kadri-OAsF0QMRWlA-unsplash.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“A computer can never be held accountable, therefore a computer must never make a management decision.” – IBM Training Manual, 1979[1][2]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, where are we with AI now? Isn’t Agentic AI doing exactly what it isn’t supposed to do?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760057984"&gt;AI or ML or?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are bombed with terms – small break! Let’s digest this &lt;STRONG&gt;grocery of terms&lt;/STRONG&gt;…&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data Science[3] is a broad &lt;STRONG&gt;interdisciplinary scientific field using scientific methods to extract knowledge and insights from the massive data sets&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It uses both; traditional data mining, data analysis and statistical methods; as well as ML techniques, to accomplish the given tasks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI (Artificial Intelligence) is the broadest concept, aiming to &lt;STRONG&gt;create machines that can "think" and perform human-like tasks&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ML (Machine Learning)[3] is a &lt;STRONG&gt;subset of AI where algorithms learn from data without explicit programming&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling predictions and pattern recognition. It does need Data Science to be employed first to clean, prepare and analyze unstructured big data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Deep Learning[4] is a &lt;STRONG&gt;type of ML based on artificial neural networks&lt;/STRONG&gt; impersonating human “thinking”.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Neither ML nor AI are something brand new. It is considered that earliest ML “program” was introduced in the early 1950s (by Arthur Samuel). Mid 1950s was the time when AI somehow emerged as well. However, only in 2000s ML/AI started being more popular – simply because machines could not cope with the complex ML/AI processing, before that time. The real break-through (sort-of) came only in 2012 with Deep-Learning. Everything else is now a “legend”…&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 1. Data Science as a discipline" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313277iF7BAB5EEE47E067E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="1. Data Science.jpg" alt="Figure 1. Data Science as a discipline" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1. Data Science as a discipline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is this the correct relationship between ML and AI?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are somewhat different views, but let’s stick with the one which is the most common; Deep Learning is a subset of ML, ML is subset of AI, and Data Science is here to “help” them all. Still let me just mention – some other interpretation would put “all” under umbrella of Dats Science, while some views say that AI is only “partially overlapping” with ML and Deep Learning. However, we will (at least in this article) stay with the relationships as presented in this diagram.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563544479"&gt;Generative AI&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI is great, but next big evolution happened with Generative AI (or GenAI)[5].&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, what is Generative AI? While AI is very broad field of computer science focused on enabling machines to perform human-like tasks, &lt;STRONG&gt;Generative AI is a specialized subset of AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; (or Traditional AI, as often referred) that &lt;STRONG&gt;creates new, original content&lt;/STRONG&gt; such as text, images, or music – impersonating human-like creativity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we talk about GenAI, sometimes we mixed it with LLM (Large Language Model) – but this is, of course, not correct. GenAI encompasses various forms of content generation, while &lt;STRONG&gt;LLM is a foundation model for NLP (Natural Language Processing) tasks&lt;/STRONG&gt; – oriented to text understanding and generation only.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Both GenAI, in general, and LLM are in the essence based on Deep Learning models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 2. Generative AI" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313282i68C2A4700BC940D9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2. GenAI.jpg" alt="Figure 2. Generative AI" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 2. Generative AI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether we talk about text, or image or music creation, the flow is basically the same; there is a &lt;STRONG&gt;prompt&lt;/STRONG&gt; (usually created by the user), invoking GenAI &lt;STRONG&gt;processing of the request&lt;/STRONG&gt; to understand and generate appropriate content (i.e. text or answer on the specific inquiry), and finally there is a GenAI generated &lt;STRONG&gt;response &lt;/STRONG&gt;returned to the requestor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367030974"&gt;Agentic AI&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;And here we come to Agentic AI, next big hype – AI which makes sense? AI which can make actual decisions!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In general, it is scary – I admit. But at least, now we have a concept which can really, really be useful in the daily work. Do not take me wrong GenAI is also useful for quite a few things, but it was mostly limited to do some recommendations, suggestions etc.– it was more as an assistant helping us do the work, but we still had to make decisions and do the work by ourselves. But now with Agentic AI &lt;STRONG&gt;we actually have a tool which can make the decision and do the actual work&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Yes, it is scary really – but it is a reality, as well…&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI[6][7] is an &lt;STRONG&gt;AI system, with enhanced autonomy, enabling it to independently set goals, make decision on it, plan actions accordingly, and finally execute necessary tasks, without human intervention&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Unlike Traditional AI, or “only” Generative AI, Agentic AI Systems are capable to understand complex context, learn from the interactions, and adapt to changing conditions. Within its “core”, Agentic AI Systems integrate LLMs – to work together with other agents. Agents can be other ML models, but those could be also calls to external tools (i.e. like API calls, DB actions etc.). In the system, through AI Orchestration each agent is performing specific subset of tasks required to reach the overall goal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 3. Agentic AI System has “brain”, “memory” and “tools”" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313265i1CD6F41FB098D1C3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3. AgenticAI.jpg" alt="Figure 3. Agentic AI System has “brain”, “memory” and “tools”" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 3. Agentic AI System has “brain”, “memory” and “tools”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is exactly because of “agents” working with LLM “brain”, this approach is demonstrating &lt;STRONG&gt;high autonomy in solving problems&lt;/STRONG&gt;; from understanding the context, invoking the right agents to perform “micro” tasks; aggregating all results, measure the success rate in meeting the goal, make the decision and execute the actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI is focused on decisions as opposed to creating the content, like GenAI. Agentic AI does not rely on human prompts and does not require human supervision. But Agentic AI and GenAI tools work together, each of them takes their own role. In fact, Agentic AI could not do what it does, if there are no GenAI capabilities – core of the Agentic AI System relies on GenAI to make actions on the initial prompts (or inputs invoking specific agents via AI Orchestration), evaluating responses received form the agents, and generating final human-like responses on the prompts (if such actions is needed).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 4. An example of  steps within Agentic AI System" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313264i998A7F7462350429/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4. AgenticAI - steps.jpg" alt="Figure 4. An example of  steps within Agentic AI System" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 4. An example of  steps within Agentic AI System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In real terms, the process could look like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agentic AI System uses its &lt;STRONG&gt;brain&lt;/STRONG&gt; (i.e. LLMs) to understand the context (i.e. understand that prompt is asking for the specific Sales Order status) and generate the content for the external tool agents (i.e. API call to the ERP system).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Usually, Agentic AI System will also have &lt;STRONG&gt;memory&lt;/STRONG&gt; to store past context – to be smarter with similar prompts in future.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI Orchestration will invoke &lt;STRONG&gt;tools&lt;/STRONG&gt; which will perform specific tasks (i.e. read the Sales Order detail from the ERP system, read LMD delivery status, retrieve knowledge from RAG or simply engage other agent) and return the results to the &lt;STRONG&gt;brain&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All responses will be aggregated (i.e. if we are invoking several &lt;STRONG&gt;tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agentic AI &lt;STRONG&gt;brain&lt;/STRONG&gt; may evaluate the conditions (if met) or it may measure success rate toward set goals (if satisfaction level reached).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;At the end, Agentic AI &lt;STRONG&gt;brain&lt;/STRONG&gt; may trigger some actions, including providing response to the requester –this time it will create the content (i.e. human-like response with the Sales Order status).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another typical example would be autonomous vehicles (or self-driving cars), where car AI must understand the complex context of the surrounding driving conditions, take the necessary inputs, and act toward reaching the goal. In this process car AI will make autonomous driving decisions and steer the vehicle accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is why &lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic AI is Ai which actual does make sense&lt;/STRONG&gt; – as it actually can work for us… Of course, will it (eventually) work only for us – this is completely different topic – which I will try to address in the separate article.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some more practical examples, addressing some additional topics about A2A, MCP including some SAP specific topics like Content Based Agents vs. Code Based Agents – I will also try to cover in the separate article.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And don’t worry. Agentic AI is current hype – but AI is evolving, there will more and more “hypes” in the future, I am quite certain…&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170517469"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, Agentic AI makes decisions – and not only that, but they also execute actions! Let’s think about future and “real” self-driving cars!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then, are we actually violating the principles set by IBM in 1979? I am not going to answer this question, but answer seems to be quite straight-forward, right?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Welcome to the future…&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974003964"&gt;Acknowledgment&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;*) Intro photo by &lt;A href="https://unsplash.com/@nahrizuladib?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=unsplash" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Nahrizul Kadri&lt;/A&gt; on &lt;A href="https://unsplash.com/photos/a-sign-with-a-question-mark-and-a-question-mark-drawn-on-it-OAsF0QMRWlA?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=unsplash" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;**) This article uses&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://wiki.scn.sap.com/wiki/x/shl7H" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform Solution Diagrams &amp;amp; Icons&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;as per &lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/nXJJmw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Terms of Use&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; governing the use of these SAP Materials (please note, newer version of the Solution Diagrams &amp;amp; Icons, as well as Terms of Use, might be in place after the publication of this article).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More guidelines on Solution Diagrams &amp;amp; Icons can be found in this&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2018/01/05/be-visual-use-official-icons-and-samples-for-sap-cloud-platform-solution-diagrams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;article&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://people.sap.com/bertram.ganz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bertram Ganz&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777490459"&gt;References&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;[1] IBM: &lt;A href="https://www.ibm.com/think/insights/ai-decision-making-where-do-businesses-draw-the-line" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AI decision-making: Where do businesses draw the line? | IBM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[2] LinkedIn: &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7271085510142439426/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7271085510142439426/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[3] IBM: &lt;A href="https://www.ibm.com/think/topics/data-science-vs-machine-learning" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Data science vs. machine learning: What's the Difference? | IBM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[4] Wikipedia: &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Deep learning - Wikipedia&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[5] Forbes: &lt;A href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2023/07/24/the-difference-between-generative-ai-and-traditional-ai-an-easy-explanation-for-anyone/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;The Difference Between Generative AI And Traditional AI: An Easy Explanation For Anyone&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[6] IBM: &lt;A href="https://www.ibm.com/think/topics/agentic-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;What Is Agentic AI? | IBM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[7] IBM: &lt;A href="https://www.ibm.com/think/topics/agentic-ai-vs-generative-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Agentic AI vs. Generative AI | IBM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/agentic-ai-ai-which-finally-makes-sense/ba-p/14215135"/>
    <published>2025-09-11T22:08:13.878000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-potential-of-artificial-intelligence-in-enhancing-user/ba-p/14212024</id>
    <title>Unlocking the Potential of Artificial Intelligence in Enhancing User Experience in SAP Guided Buying</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T10:32:49.684000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>angelinegregory</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44892</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi there and welcome to my latest blog.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My name is Angeline Gregory, I am one of the Solution Value Advisors based in the UK.&amp;nbsp; The world of procurement is continuously evolving, and with it are the tools and technologies aimed at optimizing organizational spend.&amp;nbsp; Here, I am excited to present my blog on how artificial intelligence can elevate the user experience in SAP Guided Buying.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Guided Buying can steer users towards more efficient and compliant buying processes.&amp;nbsp; It is crucial to integrate advanced technologies such as Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) into your buying processes to enrich the experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The below features in SAP Guided Buying make purchasing decisions smoother and smarter and hence improve cost effectiveness and increases compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Catalog Item Recommendation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ARIBA_PROCUREMENT/855d3e61ce304b1cb81987bdc5322911/item-recommendations?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2505" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;item recommendation feature&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;suggests products and services based on users' past purchases. &amp;nbsp;It collects purchasing history from your organization and uses artificial intelligence to recommend catalog items that might be of interest based on the individual user. Item recommendations display in a carousel at the top of the home page, in the item details page or as alternatives to non-catalog item.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature improves &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;productivity&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Encouraging usage of catalog item when creating a non-catalog request​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reducing effort when searching for items​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reducing distractions when browsing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improving user experience ​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/guided-buying-administration/enabling-machine-learning-features?version=2505" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enable this feature&lt;/A&gt; by turning on the below parameters in SAP Guided Buying:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/guided-buying-administration/guided-buying-parameters-ef4c199e9e2b401a8211585084d4d916?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2505#loioef4c199e9e2b401a8211585084d4d916__PARAM_ENABLE_ITEM_RECOMMENDATIONS" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;PARAM_ENABLE_ITEM_RECOMMENDATIONS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/guided-buying-administration/guided-buying-parameters-ef4c199e9e2b401a8211585084d4d916?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2505#loioef4c199e9e2b401a8211585084d4d916__PARAM_ENABLE_CLICKSTREAM_PUBLISH" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;PARAM_ENABLE_CLICKSTREAM_PUBLISH&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This feature is embedded AI-Feature included in your Guided Buying subscription&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;At first SAP Guided Buying will show “Popular Items” based on organization’s most frequent purchases.&amp;nbsp; AI will learn and start showing “Recommended for you” items / services based on users clicks​.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Guided Buying Usage Report&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ariba/978b7e36451a4c2c85321a3ef6f3a7e5/77d73cd169c5431d948e6f14ed2820da.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;q=popular" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;usage report&lt;/A&gt; in Guided Buying gives administrators insight into user searches, purchases, and overall interaction with SAP Guided Buying. SAP Guided Buying generates this report monthly to provides usage details, such as the number of users who signed in, number of users who added items to their cart, total number of items added to carts, and searches that returned no results.&amp;nbsp; This report helps answer business questions like which catalog areas to expand and the most popular search items.&amp;nbsp; By leveraging the insights from the Usage Report, organizations can continuously improve user experience based on data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature improves &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;efficiency&lt;/U&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Highlighting opportunities based on user behavior, search patterns​ and search effectiveness analysis​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Aids making catalog improvements and helps bring spend under management​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Providing evidence- to make quicker design decisions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/guided-buying-administration/enabling-machine-learning-features?version=2505" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enable this feature&lt;/A&gt; by turning on the below parameters in SAP Guided Buying:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/guided-buying-administration/guided-buying-parameters-ef4c199e9e2b401a8211585084d4d916?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2505#loioef4c199e9e2b401a8211585084d4d916__PARAM_ENABLE_USAGE_REPORTS" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;PARAM_ENABLE_USAGE_REPORTS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/guided-buying-administration/guided-buying-parameters-ef4c199e9e2b401a8211585084d4d916?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2505#loioef4c199e9e2b401a8211585084d4d916__PARAM_ENABLE_CLICKSTREAM_PUBLISH" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;PARAM_ENABLE_CLICKSTREAM_PUBLISH&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;​This feature is embedded AI-Feature included in your Guided Buying subscription&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Guided Buying generates reports only after at least 100 unique users have cumulatively clicked “Add to cart” more than 1,000 times. &amp;nbsp;It must first collect and analyze a significant number of searching and purchasing actions&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;​By using these features in guided buying systems, organizations can significantly help shape the way users buy goods or services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrating AI and ML into guided buying isn't just about improving technology; it's about strategically enhancing the procurement process better suited to users' needs, while staying compliant and cost effective.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, whether you are just starting out or looking to refine your procurement processes, consider how AI and ML can make a significant impact on your organization's guided buying system and watch as your bottom line and operational efficiencies improve.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take the next steps by having a look at our comprehensive &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/V4YHQfA?h=&amp;amp;ltr=a" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;one-pager&lt;/A&gt; on AI and ML in SAP Guided Buying.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for reading my blog!!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-potential-of-artificial-intelligence-in-enhancing-user/ba-p/14212024"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T10:32:49.684000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/kickstart-your-sap-btp-journey/ba-p/14175662</id>
    <title>Kickstart Your SAP BTP Journey</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T15:45:00.687000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>etienne_antoniutti</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1743004</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1995140292"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;All you need to know and where to start&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;You may have come across articles, presentations, interviews or discussions about SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP). You heard the term quite often, but you might still be asking: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What exactly is SAP BTP?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Why is SAP BTP important?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;And how do I begin exploring SAP BTP’s potential?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How does SAP BTP fit into the clean core strategy?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’re now at the right place.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're a &lt;STRONG&gt;decision maker looking to drive IT strategy&lt;/STRONG&gt;, an &lt;STRONG&gt;IT professional building solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a &lt;STRONG&gt;business user focused on innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or part of the &lt;STRONG&gt;academic community exploring cutting-edge technologies&lt;/STRONG&gt;, this post is your launchpad into the world of SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Curious where you fit in? Keep reading to discover the tools, learning paths, and support SAP BTP offers for every IT role: from developers and architects to students, educators, and decision makers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No matter your background or goals, there’s a starting point tailored just for you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1669544068"&gt;What We’ll Cover Here&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#_What_Is_SAP" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;What Is SAP BTP?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#_Why_SAP_BTP" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Why SAP BTP Matters&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#_SAP_BTP_and_clean_core" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP and clean core&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#_Try_Before_You_Buy" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Try Before You Buy: Trials &amp;amp; Pricing Models&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#_Real_Talk_What_Others_Do" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Real Talk: What Are Others Doing with SAP BTP?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#_SAP_BTP_Essentials" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Essentials: Resources for Every IT Role&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#_Stay_Ahead_Strategy_Roadmaps_Updates" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Stay Ahead: Strategy, Roadmaps &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="#_Start_Building_Today" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Start building today!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1473030563"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="_What_Is_SAP" id="toc-hId-1276517058"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is SAP BTP?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BTP is an intuitive, modern development and innovation platform for both professional IT and business users. It is a unified platform that brings quickly together everything you need to build any idea or business vision to life, extending, and integrating existing business applications, whether they’re SAP or not.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With self-service &lt;STRONG&gt;data discovery&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;modeling&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt; for business users in a &lt;STRONG&gt;governed environment&lt;/STRONG&gt;, it provides &lt;STRONG&gt;integration&lt;/STRONG&gt; solutions to connect and streamline applications and processes across the entire enterprise, offering &lt;STRONG&gt;pre-built business content&lt;/STRONG&gt; like built-in data products, integrations, workflows, app templates, and &lt;STRONG&gt;AI services.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s what’s in the toolbox:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/build.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;App Development &amp;amp; Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;: Rapidly develop applications or automate processes using low-code/no-code tools or opt for professional-code development when advanced customization and control are required&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/analytics.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/A&gt; Turn your data into decisions with built-in analytics and planning tools.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;: Connect SAP or non-SAP systems like a pro.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/ai.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;: Infuse AI into your workflows, apps, and decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/sap-business-technology-platform" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Platform Foundation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;: Secure, scalable, and ready for hybrid cloud environments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simply put, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP enables you to innovate and stay relevant by building on established foundations.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="_Why_SAP_BTP" id="toc-hId-1080003553"&gt;Why SAP BTP Matters?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because digital transformation is not just a trend, it’s essential for &lt;STRONG&gt;adaptability&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;resilience&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a.k.a. survival.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With SAP BTP, you can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automate&lt;/STRONG&gt; repetitive tasks and free up time for real work.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Connect all of your systems, so they &lt;STRONG&gt;integrate.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build custom apps&lt;/STRONG&gt; tailored to your business needs and vision.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; to make smarter decisions, faster.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Connect&lt;/STRONG&gt; and harmonize all your &lt;STRONG&gt;data, eliminating data silos&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get &lt;STRONG&gt;mission-critical insights&lt;/STRONG&gt; from your data without a background in data science&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;And the best part? You don’t have to start from scratch.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP offers thousands of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;pre-built content packages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, from application or automation templates to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; flows to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;dashboards&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI services&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="_SAP_BTP_and_clean_core" id="toc-hId-883490048"&gt;SAP BTP and clean core&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/resources/what-is-a-clean-core" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Clean core&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a &lt;STRONG&gt;set of guiding principles&lt;/STRONG&gt; that support &lt;STRONG&gt;continuous business&lt;/STRONG&gt; transformation by designing &lt;STRONG&gt;agile, innovative and efficient ERP systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The principles focus on &lt;STRONG&gt;building resilient business processes and extensions&lt;/STRONG&gt; supported by seamless integration, efficient operations, and data quality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Central to the clean core strategy are &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/09/20aece06-d87e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Side-by-side extensions&lt;/A&gt;,&lt;I&gt; &lt;/I&gt;powered by &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Side-by-side extensions allow organizations to enhance their SAP landscapes without directly modifying the core SAP S/4HANA system: instead of embedding custom code within the core, new functionalities, integrations, and custom applications are developed and deployed independently on SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach leverages SAP BTP's robust services, including various runtime environments (like Cloud Foundry, Kyma, and the ABAP Environment), development tools (like SAP Business Application Studio and CAP), and critical integration services (like &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Event Mesh&lt;/STRONG&gt;). Connectivity is securely handled by tools like the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Connector&lt;/STRONG&gt; for on-premise systems and the &lt;STRONG&gt;Destination Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring seamless data exchange via standard &lt;STRONG&gt;APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt; and business events from the core.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-557893824"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="_Try_Before_You_Buy" id="toc-hId-490463038"&gt;Try Before You Buy: Free Trials &amp;amp; Flexible Pricing Models&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Not ready to commit? No problem&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BTP offers a &lt;STRONG&gt;90-day free trial&lt;/STRONG&gt; with access to &lt;STRONG&gt;30+ services&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can explore, experiment, and learn at your own pace how to build, deploy, and integrate with a full suite of platform services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Start here your free trial&lt;/A&gt; of SAP Business Technology Platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you're ready to scale, you’ve got options:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Free Tier&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Build small apps, pay only for what you use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pay-As-You-Go&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Great for dynamic needs and innovation projects.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Agreement&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Predictable pricing for known use cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore all the possibilities SAP BTP unlocks. We’ve outlined the opportunities below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="etienne_antoniutti_1-1754685556432.png" style="width: 927px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/298790iC57AE7BE45EA1C0F/image-dimensions/927x408?v=v2" width="927" height="408" role="button" title="etienne_antoniutti_1-1754685556432.png" alt="etienne_antoniutti_1-1754685556432.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-293949533"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="_Real_Talk_What_Others_Do" id="toc-hId-97436028"&gt;Real Talk: What Are Others Doing with SAP BTP?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thousands of organizations, from global enterprises to emerging startups, are already leveraging &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP to transform their operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Let their success inspire you.&lt;BR /&gt;They are using SAP BTP to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automate&lt;/STRONG&gt; supply chains&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Personalize&lt;/STRONG&gt; customer experiences&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streamline&lt;/STRONG&gt; HR processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Build &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered&lt;/STRONG&gt; finance tools ... and &lt;STRONG&gt;achieve much more&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;With over 33,000 customers and 3,200 partners, you'll be in excellent company.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/customer-stories.html?sort=latest_desc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;See how SAP BTP customers are achieving a measurable impact across industries and lines of business.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--174308846"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="_SAP_BTP_Essentials" id="toc-hId--370822351"&gt;SAP BTP Essentials: Resources for Every IT Role&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s your go-to list of resources to get rolling, matched to your role:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="etienne_antoniutti_0-1757431626502.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311823iD90E4D75F41EFAD2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="etienne_antoniutti_0-1757431626502.png" alt="etienne_antoniutti_0-1757431626502.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This table is a starting point. Resource-role mappings are suggestions. Feel free to explore beyond your role based on your needs and interests. Find below what each of the resources has to offer.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/A&gt; - Learn about &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Services&lt;/STRONG&gt; in detail:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start your experience with Guided Missions to bring real life use-cases to life&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reference established &lt;STRONG&gt;architectures patterns&lt;/STRONG&gt; to guide your design and implementation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Understand how SAP BTP’s &lt;STRONG&gt;AI capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt; are used to infuse &lt;STRONG&gt;AI features&lt;/STRONG&gt; into SAP’s solution portfolio&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create an &lt;STRONG&gt;estimate&lt;/STRONG&gt; of your services to get a first impression about the usage cost.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center/business-technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Learning&lt;/A&gt; - &lt;STRONG&gt;Free&lt;/STRONG&gt; learning journeys tailored to your role and pace:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Familiarize yourself with the basic concepts of SAP BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get enabled.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Plan your implementation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prepare for your go-live.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-btp-guidance-framework/guidance-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/A&gt; - Provides a central access point for architects, developers, and administrators to build and run enterprise-grade solutions on SAP BTP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Decision Guides&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Quickly identify the best technology options for your specific needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reference Architectures&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Explore solution templates to effectively design and build on BTP, understanding key concepts and capabilities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Methodologies&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Access guided approaches to boost your cloud technology maturity, spanning both technical and organizational aspects.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technology Recommendations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Evaluate and choose the right implementation options across various technology domains.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DevOps Principles&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Empower your development and operations teams to achieve greater efficiency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- &lt;STRONG&gt;Kickstart&lt;/STRONG&gt; your projects with ready-to-use Business Content available for SAP BTP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Access over 4,000 pre-built objects, including integration flows, scripts, value mappings, and message mappings, to streamline your connections with SAP Integration Suite&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Development &amp;amp; Automation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Accelerate your projects with approximately 650 pre-built workflows, automations, applications, templates, and actions ready for use with SAP Build&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Jump-start your data insights using pre-built dashboards, stories, and data models specifically designed for SAP BTP's analytics capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Information:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Explore a rich repository of resources, including APIs, events, CDS views, business objects, interfaces, adapters, process blueprints, and SAP-validated partner use cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/business-technology-platform" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Community&lt;/A&gt; - Connect with fellow SAP BTP users, ask questions and share ideas, get help and help others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="_Stay_Ahead_Strategy_Roadmaps_Updates" id="toc-hId--567335856"&gt;Stay Ahead: Strategy, Roadmaps &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://readiness-at-scale.enable-now.cloud.sap/pub/20230621_ras/index.html?library=library.txt&amp;amp;show=book!BO_EC8330B09B97CDBE#slide!SL_120BDFE08096029D" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Release Navigator&lt;/A&gt; - Keep up with the latest innovations and updates across SAP BTP, track new features and plan your adoption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Road Map Explorer&lt;/A&gt; - Discover SAP’s product strategies and planned innovations with this go-to interactive tool. It highlights key advancements and offers a robust planning horizon, helping you precisely detail your transformation journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/resources.html?sort=title_asc&amp;amp;tab=fundamentals&amp;amp;pdf-asset=d29a141c-e47d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b&amp;amp;page=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Strategy White Paper for SAP BTP&lt;/A&gt; - When you are ready to get deeper, discover more with SAP’s strategy for SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--470446354"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="_Start_Building_Today" id="toc-hId--960362866"&gt;Start Building today!&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Start your journey today with the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Trial&lt;/A&gt; or explore your first mission at the &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Got further questions? Drop them below and let’s build something amazing, together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/kickstart-your-sap-btp-journey/ba-p/14175662"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T15:45:00.687000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/part-2-agentic-ai-governance-risks-and-dilemmas/ba-p/14216653</id>
    <title>Part 2: Agentic AI – Governance, risks and dilemmas</title>
    <updated>2025-09-14T13:11:33.819000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>stevang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7643</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="boliviainteligente-DEci5GH0r0k-unsplash.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314046iAA1800896D7FC0F2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="boliviainteligente-DEci5GH0r0k-unsplash.jpg" alt="boliviainteligente-DEci5GH0r0k-unsplash.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI is jet another evolution of Traditional AI, right? It brings more than Generative AI (GenAI), but is also carries out some more risks as well… It’s becoming “smart”, it’s making “decisions” – and IBM told us in 1979 we shouldn’t let computers make “decisions” because computers cannot be “accountable”[1]!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’ve tried to explain the AI evolution path in my previous article (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/agentic-ai-ai-which-finally-makes-sense/ba-p/14215135" target="_blank"&gt;Agentic AI – AI which finally makes sense?&lt;/A&gt;). Now, let’s talk about governance, risks and ethical dilemmas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We should be aware of it, and we should try to address it – in time…&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760092640"&gt;Let’s start with dilemmas…&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI can make &lt;STRONG&gt;autonomous decisions&lt;/STRONG&gt; and based on this it can &lt;STRONG&gt;execute some complex tasks&lt;/STRONG&gt; – also autonomously. This can be useful, yes – for sure this is much more than just GenAI assistants, where we had to make the decision and execute task on our own. Now &lt;STRONG&gt;we can have real robotic &lt;/STRONG&gt;personal assistants, or self-driving cars, or robotic support agents. Tomorrow (and this tomorrow can come very fast) we will have fully autonomous HR agents and procurement officers, as well as fully autonomous industrial and humanoid robots, and let’s say this loudly – war robots as well (oh, I am sure bunch of people are already working on it, as we speak).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 1. Are we concerned?" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314047iF05DB3EF694D095C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1. ethical dilemma.jpg" alt="Figure 1. Are we concerned?" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1. Are we concerned?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dilemma is clear – &lt;STRONG&gt;where does this lead us at the end&lt;/STRONG&gt;? Are we, out of our curiosity (or need to simplify our lives?) producing something which can replace us, or worse?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I do not have an answer on this&amp;nbsp;– &lt;STRONG&gt;future is unwritten chapter&lt;/STRONG&gt; – we are writing it now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agentic AI is reality, and now we should find the best way to use it! But at the same time,&amp;nbsp; we must create our future in a smart and sustainable way – and I hope we will.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563579135"&gt;Now, risks…&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As per risks with Agentic AI, like with any AI or GenAI, there are some “standard” risks, for sure. But here I see that primary risk, is the risk of &lt;STRONG&gt;misuse by design&lt;/STRONG&gt; – and this I link with the above dilemmas… I am not referring only to wrong design (i.e. being bias), I am referring on more serious “intentional” use for the “wrong” cause. What kind of &lt;STRONG&gt;agents and robots do we want to build&lt;/STRONG&gt;? How much &lt;STRONG&gt;autonomy do we really want to give to AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;? Although there are many articles, there are effectively no binding principles and guidelines. We are still too much intrigued with Agentic AI (or AI in general) – so no boundaries are set.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But it should be! As long as we do not set reasonable (and sustainable) boundaries, we are at (major?) risk.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 2. Key Risks leading to shortcomings" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314048i12B97120B6CF0C25/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2. Risks.jpg" alt="Figure 2. Key Risks leading to shortcomings" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 2. Key Risks leading to shortcomings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the “standard” risks, we have all those any GenAI might have – starting with &lt;STRONG&gt;security vulnerabilities like prompt injection and data poisoning&lt;/STRONG&gt;, to model &lt;STRONG&gt;hallucinations&lt;/STRONG&gt;. With Agentic AI both can lead not just to “ill” recommendations, but to “bad” decisions and “wrong” actions taken.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additional risk, also starting with GenAI – the more cognitive tasks we pass to AI, the less cognitive tasks we will execute – this may not be good, in the long run. Similar with Agentic AI – the more decisions and actions are done by AI, the more dependent we become – again, this is not good for us, in the long run.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are we aware of these risks? Well, we should be…&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367065630"&gt;Can we improve “things” with good Governance?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The key aspect of any governance is to, among others, &lt;STRONG&gt;minimize any shortcomings&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the new tools, methods, projects etc. How can we do this for Agentic AI?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How do we ensure that Agentic AI System has been built in the &lt;STRONG&gt;transparent and explainable&lt;/STRONG&gt; way – so we can easily understand its purpose and ability?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How do we ensure Agentic AI is &lt;STRONG&gt;fair and responsible&lt;/STRONG&gt; – that we do see it as non-bias in making decision?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How do we build-in &lt;STRONG&gt;accountability&lt;/STRONG&gt; within Agentic AI System (even these are “computers”) – in a way humans can accept it (also avoiding misuse by design)?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How do we ensure Agentic AI System is &lt;STRONG&gt;safe to operate&lt;/STRONG&gt; of – prompt injection and data poisoning has been effectively prevented.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many questions… But what are the key governing principles we must follow?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First and the most important – there are no strict or imposed principles and guidelines (at least not yet) what is that Agentic AI System (agent or robot) can and cannot do by design. So, if we talk about “formal” misuse of the technology – sorry there are none or close to none (at least formally) limitations. But “informally” yes – there are those “dilemmas” for potential misuse of the AI (by design).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While it looked like we were very far away from the “real” AI (it was just a hype, right?) we did not care too much about putting any “legislation”. However, now things do not look so distant... The closer we come to real technology break-through toward autonomous robotics – &lt;STRONG&gt;thighs are becoming more and more controversial&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So how to build AI, and especially Agentic AI (or some further evolutions) in a responsible manner?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 3. Responsible AI is Human-centric" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314049i0C8EE182623FADF4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3. Responsible AI.jpg" alt="Figure 3. Responsible AI is Human-centric" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 3. Responsible AI is Human-centric&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s call this &lt;STRONG&gt;Responsible AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;magic circle&lt;/STRONG&gt; of &lt;EM&gt;“interaction”&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;EM&gt;“imposes”&lt;/EM&gt; certain &lt;STRONG&gt;Risks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Risks&lt;/STRONG&gt; do &lt;EM&gt;“impact” &lt;/EM&gt;us, &lt;STRONG&gt;Human&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Human&lt;/STRONG&gt; must &lt;EM&gt;“build”&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt; rules and practices&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Governance &lt;/STRONG&gt;rules and practices are here to &lt;EM&gt;“control”&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The fact currently there are no “legally” binding rules and principles, does not prevent us to set company or industry standards on our own – let’s call it &lt;STRONG&gt;AI best practice&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If we talk about rules, let’s start thinking – what is that we want to keep for ourselves? What is that we don’t want AI to do? How far are we from some futuristic scenarios and the need to build basic &lt;STRONG&gt;rules of robotics&lt;/STRONG&gt;[2]? Maybe we should be ready to “move over” this mountain and embrace the fact “future is happening right now”!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For principles, things are a bit more straight-forward, and previous AI experiences can really help us:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Risk management:&lt;/STRONG&gt; identifying, assessing, and mitigating the unique risks posed by both GenAI and autonomous agents. We should try to address all risks; from &lt;EM&gt;compliance risks &lt;/EM&gt;and &lt;EM&gt;what and why do we build&lt;/EM&gt; (to be &lt;STRONG&gt;transparent and explainable&lt;/STRONG&gt;, to be &lt;STRONG&gt;fair and responsible&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and ensure maximum possible &lt;STRONG&gt;accountability&lt;/STRONG&gt;), to &lt;EM&gt;security risks&lt;/EM&gt; (to be &lt;STRONG&gt;safe to operate&lt;/STRONG&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Continuous monitoring and auditing:&lt;/STRONG&gt; agents/robots need to be monitored continuously to detect any deviation from intended behavior, any ethical issues, or security breaches. Also, audit trails and logging of agent decisions are vital for &lt;STRONG&gt;accountability&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where (ideally) no agents/robots should access, alter and remove any audit trails and logs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Organizational structure:&lt;/STRONG&gt; creating a cross-functional AI governance boards and bodies to &lt;STRONG&gt;create policies but also monitor adaptation of these policies in all Ai initiatives&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with special focus on agents/robots.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;All this, and more if needed, can be easily translated into any organization dealing with Agentic AI. Each organization will make adaptations on its own, of course – but key is to be aware of risks and shortcomings, as well as all the potential benefits new Agentic AI technology is bringing. If we are aware, and we try addressing it with proper governance – it’s a good start…&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, can we start all this and be open-minded?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170552125"&gt;Acknowledgment&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;*) Intro photo &lt;A href="https://unsplash.com/@boliviainteligente?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=unsplash" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;BoliviaInteligente&lt;/A&gt; on &lt;A href="https://unsplash.com/photos/a-close-up-of-a-keyboard-with-a-blue-button-DEci5GH0r0k?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=unsplash" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;**) This article uses&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://wiki.scn.sap.com/wiki/x/shl7H" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform Solution Diagrams &amp;amp; Icons&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;as per &lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/nXJJmw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Terms of Use&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; governing the use of these SAP Materials (please note, newer version of the Solution Diagrams &amp;amp; Icons, as well as Terms of Use, might be in place after the publication of this article).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;More guidelines on Solution Diagrams &amp;amp; Icons can be found in this&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2018/01/05/be-visual-use-official-icons-and-samples-for-sap-cloud-platform-solution-diagrams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;article&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://people.sap.com/bertram.ganz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bertram Ganz&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974038620"&gt;References&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;[1] IBM: &lt;A href="https://www.ibm.com/think/insights/ai-decision-making-where-do-businesses-draw-the-line" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AI decision-making: Where do businesses draw the line? | IBM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[2] Isac Asimov: &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three_Laws_of_Robotics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Three Laws of Robotics - Wikipedia&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/part-2-agentic-ai-governance-risks-and-dilemmas/ba-p/14216653"/>
    <published>2025-09-14T13:11:33.819000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/upcoming-live-sessions-register-now/ba-p/14217370</id>
    <title>Upcoming live sessions - Register now</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T13:17:38.515000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Margit_Wagner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/491</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;TABLE border="0" width="100%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Join&amp;nbsp;live webinars&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to connect with guides, ask questions, and gain insights from fellow practitioners.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Version Control Unlocked: Mastering Git for SAP Fiori Development" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/version-control-unlocked-mastering-git-for-sap-fiori-development?pttid=7635&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Version Control Unlocked: Mastering Git for SAP Fiori Development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;Sep 18, 10:00 - 12:00 AM (CET)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Get Certified: SAP Certified Associate - Solution Transformation Consultant with SAP Cloud ALM" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/get-certified-sap-certified-associate-solution-transformation-consultant-with-sap-cloud-alm?pttid=7635&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Get Certified: SAP Certified Associate - Solution Transformation Consultant with SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;Sep 18 and 25, 07:00 - 8:30 AM (CET)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Introducing the SAP CX AI Toolkit for SAP Commerce Cloud" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/introducing-the-sap-cx-ai-toolkit-for-sap-commerce-cloud?pttid=7635&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introducing the SAP CX AI Toolkit for SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Sep 26, 10:00 - 11:00 AM (CET)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="AI Features and Functions in SAP Service Cloud Version 2" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/ai-features-and-functions-in-sap-service-cloud-version-2?pttid=7635&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI Features and Functions in SAP Service Cloud Version 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;Sep 22, 10:00 - 12:00 AM (CET)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Human Capital Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Understanding Goal Calculations in SAP SuccessFactors Variable Pay" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/understanding-goal-calculations-in-sap-successfactors-variable-pay?pttid=7635&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Understanding Goal Calculations in SAP SuccessFactors Variable Pay&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;Sep 17, 03:00 - 05:00 PM (CET)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Get Certified: Implementation Consultant - SAP SuccessFactors Succession Management" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/get-certified-implementation-consultant-sap-successfactors-succession-management?pttid=7635&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get Certified: Implementation Consultant - SAP SuccessFactors Succession Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;Sep 19 and 26, 10:00 - 12:00 AM (CET)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Students&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Get ready for your first SAP Business Certification: Positioning SAP Business Suite" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/get-ready-for-your-first-sap-business-certification-positioning-sap-business-suite?pttid=7635&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get ready for your first SAP Business Certification: Positioning SAP Business Suite&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;Sep 30, Oct 2, 7 and 9, 3:00 - 4:30 PM (CET)&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unlock amazing benefits at no cost! Simply &lt;A title="register" href="https://learning.sap.com/free-student-edition?pttid=7635&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;register&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; and verify your university-linked email.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can find the full list of live sessions &lt;A title="here" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions?page=1?source=email-global-lhubnewsletter-prdteng-LSC&amp;amp;pttid=7635&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7B%7Blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7D%7D&amp;amp;LID=%7B%7Blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7D%7D&amp;amp;pttid=7635&amp;amp;InteractionType=%7b%7blead.Contact%20Profile%20Status%7d%7d&amp;amp;LID=%7b%7blead.p_encrypted_leadid%7d%7d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; and register directly with your SAP Learning Hub subscription.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/upcoming-live-sessions-register-now/ba-p/14217370"/>
    <published>2025-09-15T13:17:38.515000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-seguridad-reforzada-ia-aplicada-y-nuevas-alianzas/ba-p/14217615</id>
    <title>🚀 SAP BTP Weekly: seguridad reforzada, IA aplicada y nuevas alianzas estratégicas</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T15:51:26.229000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FedericoTokman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150724</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Core y modelos propios en BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt; Las empresas ya pueden entrenar y desplegar sus propios modelos en SAP AI Core con integración nativa a datos SAP. Esto abre la puerta a IA especializada en cada industria, pero plantea un dilema: ¿cómo equilibrar innovación con compliance? Una aseguradora podría entrenar un modelo para detección de fraudes, pero ¿qué pasa si no logra explicabilidad suficiente? La promesa es grande, el riesgo también.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Tu organización está lista para invertir en IA propia o preferís modelos preentrenados de SAP y partners?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-ai-core/sap-ai-core-service-guide/what-is-sap-ai-core" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nuevo release de SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; La suite incorpora conectores preconfigurados para Salesforce, Workday y ServiceNow, simplificando arquitecturas híbridas. El beneficio es velocidad en despliegues, pero la realidad es que muchas empresas ya tienen middleware paralelo. Un retail puede ver valor en unificar todo en BTP, pero el costo de “migrar lo viejo” nunca es trivial.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Vale la pena consolidar integraciones en una sola plataforma o es mejor convivir con múltiples soluciones?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-for-sap-integration-suite-june-amp-july-2024/ba-p/13787789" target="_self"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DataSphere y federación en tiempo real&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Datasphere suma capacidades para federar datos en vivo desde Snowflake y BigQuery, sin replicación masiva. Esto cambia el juego: menos ETL, más velocidad. Una minera podría consultar KPIs financieros y de producción en un único dashboard, pero la latencia y la calidad de metadatos pueden ser talón de Aquiles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Creés que el futuro es federar datos en vivo o seguir apostando a replicar en un único repositorio?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-datasphere/introducing-sap-datasphere-integration-options" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule for Developers: IA gratis hasta 2026&lt;/STRONG&gt; El programa permite a los desarrolladores usar capacidades de IA generativa dentro de SAP Build Code, Build Apps, Process Automation y entornos ABAP sin costo hasta septiembre de 2026. Esto acelera la creación de aplicaciones, automatiza procesos y mejora la productividad, pero también plantea un reto: ¿cómo asegurar que los equipos realmente adopten la herramienta y no quede como “demo eterna”? Imaginemos un equipo de manufactura que genera código para integrarse con sensores IoT en minutos, pero sin estrategia de adopción puede terminar en pilotos aislados sin impacto real.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿En tu empresa ya están explorando Joule for Developers o aún se percibe como una prueba de laboratorio sin plan de escalamiento?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7371164704255328256/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gestión de identidades con CIS: más allá del SSO&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Cloud Identity Services ya no es solo un proveedor de inicio de sesión único: hoy permite aplicar MFA (autenticación multifactor), gestionar identidades externas y controlar accesos en entornos híbridos. El beneficio es claro: menos riesgos de seguridad y más trazabilidad. Pero el desafío aparece en la práctica: ¿quién define los roles y quién se hace responsable de revisarlos periódicamente? Una empresa de energía implementó MFA para usuarios críticos, pero descubrió que sin procesos de recertificación, la complejidad administrativa creció exponencialmente.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿En tu organización la gestión de identidades es una práctica madura con roles y procesos claros, o sigue siendo una tarea reactiva que depende del equipo Basis?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/assetdetail/2024/10/46dcb1da-db7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sustainability Control Tower: visibilidad ESG en tiempo real&lt;/STRONG&gt; La herramienta permite consolidar métricas ambientales, sociales y de gobernanza en un solo panel conectado a SAP y fuentes externas. El valor es dar a CFOs y responsables de sostenibilidad una visión clara para reportes y decisiones estratégicas. Integrada con BTP, gana aún más potencia: puede aprovechar conectores preconfigurados, flujos de datos en tiempo real y dashboards de analítica avanzada, evitando desarrollos ad-hoc y reduciendo el time-to-value. El reto está en la calidad y consistencia de los datos: una empresa de retail logró integrar emisiones de su cadena logística, pero descubrió que sin estandarizar la captura de datos de proveedores, los reportes perdían comparabilidad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Tu empresa ya mide indicadores ESG de forma integrada con SAP o todavía depende de reportes manuales y dispersos?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/administering-sustainability-control-tower/integrating-sap-sustainability-control-tower-with-sap-systems" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Apps y citizen developers&lt;/STRONG&gt; El nuevo release permite que usuarios de negocio creen apps móviles con integración directa a SAP S/4HANA. Esto democratiza la innovación, pero el riesgo es el shadow IT. Un equipo de logística puede crear su propia app de seguimiento, pero ¿qué pasa si no pasa controles de seguridad? El rol de IT pasa de desarrollador a “curador”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿En tu empresa los citizen developers son aliados estratégicos o una fuente de dolores de cabeza?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-apps/service-guide/right-way-to-sap-build-apps" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agenda: SAP TechEd 2025 – primeros anuncios&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP adelantó que la próxima edición de TechEd pondrá foco en IA generativa, clean core y analítica en tiempo real. Más allá de los keynotes, lo interesante es ver cómo los anuncios aterrizan en roadmaps concretos. CIOs esperan claridad de inversión, consultores buscan nuevas certificaciones y arquitectos quieren entender las integraciones que vienen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Qué esperás con más interés: casos prácticos de IA, roadmap de S/4HANA o nuevas certificaciones de BTP?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Más información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP BTP ofrece un valor único según el rol que lo mire. Para el CIO significa eficiencia, para el CFO transparencia y control financiero, para el arquitecto la posibilidad de diseñar integraciones más simples, para el Basis la tranquilidad de la estabilidad operativa y para el consultor la oportunidad de acelerar la entrega de valor. Sin embargo, más allá de esas perspectivas, todos enfrentamos la misma tensión: cómo lograr que la innovación se convierta en resultados tangibles sin perder el control en el proceso.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-seguridad-reforzada-ia-aplicada-y-nuevas-alianzas/ba-p/14217615"/>
    <published>2025-09-15T15:51:26.229000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management/sap-ai-training-und-sap-ai-skills-self-assessment/ba-p/14220337</id>
    <title>SAP AI Training und SAP AI Skills Self-Assessment</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T18:28:43.018000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ThomasJenewein</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/594</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Es steht außer Frage: Der Aufbau von KI‑Kompetenzen ist heute entscheidend. Weil es so viele Möglichkeiten gibt, haben wir für Dich wichtige SAP KI Lernangebote kuratiert. Hier im Blog findest du:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ein kurzes &lt;A href="https://sapinsights.eu.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_eF1FHg6iM53YIFU" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI Skills-Assessment&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- zur eigenen Einschätzung als erster Schritt&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kostenfreie Lernangebote nach Job-Rolle für KI-Beginner, Berater, Entwickler&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lernangebote zu embedded AI in SAP Lösungen&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trainer-geführte Schulungen, in denen KI eine zentrale Rolle spielt&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI Lernangebote mit dem SAP Learning Hub Abo wie Live Sessions und Übungssysteme zu KI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Zertifizierung(en) in KI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Komme gerne zurück auf diese Seite, denn da KI so dynamisch ist und so viel passiert, werden wir die Seite mindestens einmal pro Monat updaten. Nutze gerne den Subscribe button oben um Updates zu bekommen.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760834474"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP AI Training nach Job-Rolle&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;hier gibt es u.a. folgende digitale kostenlose Lernangebote in englischer Sprache, &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;weitere sind auf der Überblicksseite zu finden&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Grundlagen&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business User&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administrator&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Berater&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/introducing-ai-fundamentals" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;KI-Grundlagen | 3+ h&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Einführung in KI-Grundlagen: Von Basiskonzepten bis Generative AI, SAPs Enterprise-Ansatz und verantwortungsvolle KI-Praktiken.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/boosting-ai-driven-business-transformation-with-joule-agents" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business-Transformation mit Joule Agents&lt;/A&gt; | 2+ h&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule Agents verstehen und nutzen: Entscheidungsfindung verbessern und KI-Funktionen integrieren.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/discovering-sap-business-ai" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business AI entdecken&lt;/A&gt; | 40 Min&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wie SAP Business AI Geschäftswert schafft durch Prozessautomatisierung, bessere Entscheidungen und Innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/putting-ai-ethics-into-practice-at-sap" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KI-Ethik bei SAP&lt;/A&gt; | 1 h&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPs KI-Ethikprinzipien, Governance-Framework und Regeln für verantwortungsvolle KI-Entwicklung und -Einsatz.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-new-ai-capabilities-for-sap-finance" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business AI für Finanzen entdecken &lt;/A&gt;| 3,5 h&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPs KI-gestützte Finanzlösungen incl., wie SAP Business AI Finanzprozesse durch datengetriebene Erkenntnisse und optimierte Abläufe transformiert.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-high-value-opportunities-for-agentic-ai" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hochwertige Einsatzmöglichkeiten für Agentic AI identifizieren&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;| 2 h&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beherrsche den Joule Agent Discovery Workshop, um wertvolle KI-Agent-Anwendungsfälle für dein Unternehmen zu identifizieren und zu priorisieren.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/applying-a-human-centered-approach-to-identify-and-define-business-ai-use-cases" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Menschenzentrierter Ansatz zur Identifikation von Business AI Use Cases&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;| 1 h 45 min&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lerne, wie du AI-Use-Case-Workshops durchführst und nimm an unserer Spot-the-Difference-Challenge teil, um Workshop-Materialien zu gewinnen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/exploring-sap-business-technology-platform" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform erkunden&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;| 4 h&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Einführung in die SAP Business Technology Platform und die Intelligent Enterprise Strategie.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-sap-process-orchestration" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Process Orchestration kennenlernen&lt;/A&gt; | 4 h&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Einführung in SAP Process Orchestration und die Advanced Adapter Engine Extended (AEX).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/provision-and-administer-databases-in-sap-hana-cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bereitstellung und Admin von Datenbanken in SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt; | 8 h&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bereitstellungs- und Administrationsaufgaben in SAP HANA Cloud durchführen.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/provisioning-and-implementing-joule" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Provisioning and Implementing Joule I 2h&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Konfiguration und Integration von Joule, SAPs KI-Copilot, über verschiedene SAP-Plattformen hinweg zur Produktivitätssteigerung und technischen Optimierung.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/using-advanced-ai-techniques-with-sap-s-generative-ai-hub" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Fortgeschrittene KI-Techniken mit SAPs Generative AI Hub&lt;/A&gt; | 1 h 39&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Aufbauend auf KI-Grundlagen: Fortgeschrittene Techniken wie Data Masking, Content Filtering und Vector Embeddings im SAP Generative AI Hub anwenden.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1564320969"&gt;Technische SAP KI Lernangebote&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Für Entwickler und technische Rollen empfehlen wir zudem folgende Lernangebote&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/navigating-large-language-models-fundamentals-and-techniques-for-your-use-case" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Navigating Large Language Models fundamentals and techniques for your use case&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- 2h 47&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/solving-your-business-problems-using-prompts-and-llms-in-sap-s-generative-ai-hub?userlogin=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Solving Your Business Problems Using Prompts and LLMs in SAP's Generative AI Hub&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- 5h 35&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/learning-how-to-use-the-sap-ai-core-service-on-sap-business-technology-platform" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learning how to use the SAP AI Core service on SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- 2h 42&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367807464"&gt;Lernangebote zu Embedded AI&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP bietet bei Erstellung dieser Übersicht 295 AI Features und Agenten (&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;aktuell immer hier im AI Katalog&lt;/A&gt;) - anbei eine Auswahl an Lernangeboten dazu&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/introducing-sap-business-ai-for-sap-spend-management-solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Introducing SAP Business AI for SAP Spend Management Solutions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/introducing-sap-business-ai-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Introducing SAP Business AI for SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/introducing-sap-business-ai-for-sap-successfactors-hcm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Introducing SAP Business AI for SAP SuccessFactors HCM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-new-ai-capabilities-for-sap-finance" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Discovering SAP Business AI Capabilities for SAP Finance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/introducing-sap-business-ai-for-sap-supply-chain-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Introducing SAP Business AI for SAP Supply Chain Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1171293959"&gt;SAP Schulungen - trainergeführt&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Trainergeführte Schulungen von SAP bieten ein Lernerlebnis das virtuell oder in SAP Schulungszentren stattfindet mit realen Anwendungsfällen, Zugang zu Übungssystemen geführt und geleitet von SAP Experten. In folgenden&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Schulungen spielt KI eine zentrale Rolle. Nach Auswahl des Landes findest Du konkrete Termine zum Buchen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/btp100-sap-business-technology-platform-foundation-classroom-011-de-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; - Erhalte eine Einführung in die SAP Business Technology Platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/admcld-introduction-to-sap-business-technology-platform-btp-administration-classroom-025-de-de/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Introduction to SAP Business&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;Technology Platform (BTP) Administration&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Lerne SAP BTP-Administrations-Grundlagen kennen, einschließlich Architektur, Tools, Sicherheitsmanagement und Anwendungslebenszyklus-Management in verschiedenen Laufzeitumgebungen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/bdc100-introducing-sap-business-data-cloud-classroom-043-de-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Introducing SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;Einführung in SAP Business Data Cloud und die Data Engineering-Komponenten von SAP Business Data Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/hrsf1-explore-sap-successfactors-solutions-remoteclassroom-023-de-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Explore SAP SuccessFactors &lt;U&gt;Solutions&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;Überblick über Funktionen und Features der SAP SuccessFactors Suite, verfügbar in verschiedenen Lernformaten und Bereitstellungsoptionen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/hrsf1-explore-sap-successfactors-solutions-remoteclassroom-023-de-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Performance &lt;U&gt;and Goals Academy&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;15-tägiger virtueller Kurs zur Konfiguration von SAP SuccessFactors Goal Management und Performance Management, primär konzipiert für SAP-Partner-Berater mit Zertifizierungs- und Bereitstellungsanforderungen.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/thr82-sap-successfactors-performance-and-goals-academy-remoteclassroom-043-de-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors &lt;U&gt;Recruiting: Recruiter Experience Academy&lt;/U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lerne die SAP SuccessFactors Recruiting-Konfiguration, einschließlich Systemeinrichtung, XML-Anpassung und Geschäftsregeln, konzipiert für SAP-Partner-Berater mit Zertifizierungsanforderungen.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wir planen auch eine unserer beliebten Schulungskonferenzen zu KI im ersten Quartal 2025. Bei &lt;A href="mailto:training.mee@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Interesse schicke uns gerne eine mail&lt;/A&gt; und Du bekommst ein Update, sobald Infos dazu online sind.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974780454"&gt;SAP AI Training im SAP Learning Hub&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mit einem &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/training-certification/learning-hub.html#pricing" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning Hub Abo&lt;/A&gt; gibt es viele zusätzliche "premium" Lernangebote wie Live-Sessions in 1-2 h durch Experten, Übungs-Systeme, Zertifizierungs-Gutscheine sowie Zertifizierungs-Updates, Learning Analytics und vieles mehr. Anbei ausgewählte KI Inhalte:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/deep-dive-into-joule-skills" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Deep Dive into Joule Skills&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;| 45 minutes | 23-SEPT-2025 -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Hands-on session with Joule, SAP's AI Copilot, featuring live demos and practical guidance for driving efficiency and productivity in your organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/step-by-step-guidance-to-extend-joule-via-joule-studio-in-sap-build" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Extend Joule Skills via Joule Studio in SAP Build&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;| 45 minutes | 16-SEPT-2025 -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Hands-on session on extending Joule with custom skills using Joule Studio in SAP Build, featuring live demos of creating and deploying tailored business automations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/exploring-the-latest-features-of-sap-btp-ai-services" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Exploring the Latest Features of SAP BTP AI Services&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;| 1 hour | 20-NOV-2025 -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Learn about recent updates and new capabilities in SAP AI services available on SAP BTP, with a focus on new features and improvements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/implementing-real-world-ai-models-on-sap-btp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Implementing Real-World AI Models on SAP BTP&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;| 1.5 hours | 11-NOV-2025 -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Learn how to implement AI models on SAP BTP, with a focus on practical business use cases and deployment strategies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/optimizing-ai-prompts-for-business-tasks-in-sap-btp-using-generative-ai-hub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Optimizing AI Prompts for Business Tasks in SAP BTP using Generative AI Hub&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;| 1 hour | 30-OCT-2025 -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Live session on prompt management and optimization techniques for AI-driven business tasks using SAP Generative AI Hub in SAP BTP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/sap-business-technology-platform-pillars-ai-solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform Pillars – AI Solutions&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;| 2 hours | 11-NOV-2025 -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Introduction to AI solutions in SAP BTP including embedded intelligence, machine learning services, and real-world business use cases.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-778266949"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;AI Übungssysteme im SAP Learning Hub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Es gibt bereits verschiedene &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/practice-systems?page=1" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Übungssysteme&lt;/A&gt;, in denen man verschiedene AI Features ausprobieren und damit experimentieren&amp;nbsp; und lernen kann. Das sind viele Systeme zu SuccessFactors oder SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) - anbei eine kurze Auswahl.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;S4C* (Sandbox) Joule activated/7 AI features activated&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;S4C LSC tenants Joule activated/7 AI features activated&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;S4D400/401/430 Joule (J4D: Joule for ABAP Developers) chat function on ADT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;C4H62 AI scenario: Account Takeover Protection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;S4TM2 AI scenario: Conversational Planning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;IBP (all 17 courses for 2508) Joule activated in Practice Systems, but no dedicated exercises&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581753444"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP KI Zertifizierungen&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-generative-ai-developer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Certified Associate - SAP Generative AI Developer&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;ist derzeit die erste Zertifizierung, weitere folgen die nächsten Monate, was wir auch hier updaten. Diese Zertifizierung&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;bestätigt, dass du SAPs Business AI-Funktionen verstehst und über die Fähigkeiten verfügst, SAP BTP-Anwendungen zu erweitern, während du führende Large Language Models (LLMs) nutzt, unter Verwendung von SAP AI Core/SAP AI Launchpad und SAPs Generative AI Hub.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-385239939"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Häufig gestellte Fragen (FAQ)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-317809153"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Was ist SAP Business AI?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business AI umfasst KI-Funktionen in SAP-Anwendungen und Plattformdiensten: Joule (KI-Copilot), eingebettete KI-Szenarien, Machine Learning auf SAP BTP und Entwicklungstools wie Joule Studio. Diese Technologien automatisieren Prozesse, liefern Datenerkenntnisse und steigern die Produktivität.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-121295648"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Für wen sind SAP AI Trainings geeignet?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business/Key User&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Für deine tägliche Arbeit mit KI-Tools&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Administratoren&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Für die Implementierung von KI-Lösungen&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Berater&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Für die Kundenberatung zu SAP-Lösungen&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Entwickler&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Für die Erweiterung von KI-Funktionen&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wir bieten Lernpfade für alle Kenntnisstufen.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--150449226"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Gibt es Voraussetzungen für SAP AI Trainings?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Einführungskurse: Grundkenntnisse von SAP-Lösungen&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Entwickler-Kurse: Vorteilhaft sind Programmierkenntnisse wie Python&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fortgeschrittene Kurse: Teilweise Erfahrung mit SAP BTP erforderlich&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--346962731"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Was kosten SAP AI Trainingsangebote?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kostenlos&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Selbstlernkurse, Webinare&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Einzelkurse&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Ab €640/Tag (Instructor-led)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning Hub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: €360 (Partner) und €1.260 (Kunden) jährlich&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--543476236"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wie lange dauert der Abschluss von SAP AI Lernpfaden?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Einführung&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: 10-15 Stunden&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Rollenbasiert&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: 20-40 Stunden plus Übungen&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Zertifizierung&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: 40-80 Stunden inkl. Prüfung&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Die Kurse sind für berufsbegleitendes Lernen konzipiert.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--739989741"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wie hilft mir SAP AI Training bei meiner Karriere?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fachkräfte mit KI-Kompetenzen erzielen 14-28% höhere Gehälter. SAP AI-Expertise ist besonders wertvoll in der digitalen Transformation. Unsere Absolventen berichten von Beförderungen und Führungsrollen in KI-Projekten.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--936503246"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wie starte ich mit SAP AI Training?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beginne mit unserem kostenlosen Skills Assessment für persönliche Empfehlungen. Erkunde dann Einführungskurse oder Learning Journeys. Unsere Lernberater helfen dir gerne bei deinem individuellen Entwicklungsplan. Melde Dich gerne bei&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:training.mee@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;training.mee@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;bei Rückfragen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP_Forum_Super_Human_Adoption_L42-72ppi_1920x580.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316030i461C0C5E1FA1BB6D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP_Forum_Super_Human_Adoption_L42-72ppi_1920x580.jpg" alt="SAP_Forum_Super_Human_Adoption_L42-72ppi_1920x580.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-training-and-change-management/sap-ai-training-und-sap-ai-skills-self-assessment/ba-p/14220337"/>
    <published>2025-09-17T18:28:43.018000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-us-at-sap-connect-in-las-vegas-discover-the-future-of-ai-driven/ba-p/14220733</id>
    <title>Join Us at SAP Connect in Las Vegas – Discover the Future of AI-Driven Customer Experience</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T06:57:08.398000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>oliverhuschke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35096</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Connect 2025_CX_PROMO.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316174i33CB3FC50429F894/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Connect 2025_CX_PROMO.png" alt="SAP Connect 2025_CX_PROMO.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":round_pushpin:"&gt;📍&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;October 7–8, 2025 | Fontainebleau &amp;amp; Resorts World, Las Vegas&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/event.68fc6278-9dd9-4761-a1b6-d24c49eb80fa.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Connect 2025&lt;/A&gt; is right around the corner, and we’re excited to showcase how AI, proactive support, services, and innovative cloud solutions are shaping the future of customer experience (CX).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Don’t miss your chance&lt;/STRONG&gt; to join inspiring sessions hosted by SAP Services and Support experts, customers, and partners. Gain hands-on insights into how leading organizations are driving resilience, scalability, and business impact with SAP solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are some highlights from the &lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Experience track&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889921033"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;Tuesday, October 7, 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2:00 – 2:20 PM PDT | Fontainebleau | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750454336492001qGlz" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CXP2030&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proactive, AI-driven support for resilient customer experiences&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speakers: Stefan Steinle (SAP) &amp;amp; Josh Sala (Meijer)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Discover how Meijer leverages AI to move from reactive to proactive support, boosting availability, compliance, and customer trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10:00 – 10:45 AM PDT | Fontainebleau | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750457592120001AP2L" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CXP2041&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fast-tracking business AI with a winning CX AI adoption strategy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speaker: Rajeev Ranjan (SAP)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Learn how SAP Preferred Success, agentic AI, and embedded copilots like Joule bridge the AI adoption gap and deliver real value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10:30 – 10:50 AM PDT | Fontainebleau | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749005566266001v32R" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CXP1149&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-driven system resilience: Enabling uptime and business continuity&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speakers: Tarun Luthra (SAP) &amp;amp; Suhain Mohamed (Douglas)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Hear how Douglas ensures 100% uptime during retail peaks with predictive AI-driven support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;12:45 – 1:30 PM PDT | Fontainebleau | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750360666988001njsH" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CXP1824&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transforming customer service with SAP Service Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speakers: Tarun Luthra, Kirsi Tarvainen (SAP), Sachin Vaidya (Pfizer)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Pfizer shares best practices for deploying SAP Service Cloud and driving operational excellence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3:15 – 4:00 PM PDT | Fontainebleau | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750355002605001QPVL" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CXP1803&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered customer support: Enabling smooth customer experiences&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speaker: Bharath Ramamurthy (SAP)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Explore how AI enables proactive support, self-service, and consistently exceptional CX at scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693407528"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;Wednesday, October 8, 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10:00 – 10:45 AM PDT | Fontainebleau | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755483361045001jMFX" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CXP2363&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Powering commerce with real-time events for future-ready scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speakers: Tarun Luthra (SAP) &amp;amp; Peter Brown (Meijer)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;See how Meijer modernized its retail systems with real-time, event-driven architecture on SAP Commerce Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10:15 – 11:30 AM PDT | Resorts World | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755016184145001vUYf" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CXP2333&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Premium for CX: Hands-on lab for intelligent Q&amp;amp;A and agentic AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speakers: Marcus Echter &amp;amp; Vinita Sinha (SAP)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Build a working AI use case and experience how agentic AI can be embedded into CX scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;12:30 – 1:15 PM PDT | Fontainebleau | &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750417633400001wkdH" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CXP1884&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerate go-live and impress sales and service leaders with rapid results&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Speaker: Rajeev Ranjan (SAP)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Discover the go-live accelerator for SAP Sales and Service Cloud and learn how to achieve rapid, low-risk adoption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stop by our demo station&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Experience track&lt;/STRONG&gt; to explore live showcases of AI-driven support, service excellence, and CX transformation with experts from SAP Services and Support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/event.68fc6278-9dd9-4761-a1b6-d24c49eb80fa.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; for SAP Connect in Las Vegas and make sure to join these sessions to see AI in action. A&lt;SPAN&gt;ttend the three-day event in person. Discover how to maximize your SAP solutions across every line of business with the help of SAP Services and Support.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-us-at-sap-connect-in-las-vegas-discover-the-future-of-ai-driven/ba-p/14220733"/>
    <published>2025-09-18T06:57:08.398000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/session-1-recap-amp-highlight-sap-bdc-the-future-of-intelligent-data/ba-p/14218631</id>
    <title>Session 1 Recap &amp; Highlight - SAP BDC The Future of Intelligent Data Architectures 🚀</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T08:17:50.731000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JaSoN_Luo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1708</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why SAP Invested in BDC &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The journey started with SAP’s recognition of a growing "context gap" in enterprise data—which emerges when organizations must stitch together SAP and non-SAP data across disparate platforms (think Databricks, Snowflake, Microsoft Fabric). Without business context, analytics and AI initiatives often struggle to deliver real value. BDC was built to close this gap by harmonizing and managing all enterprise data—structured, semi-structured, SAP, and non-SAP—in a unified, semantically enriched way.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Sets BDC Apart? &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":direct_hit:"&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation First:&lt;/STRONG&gt; BDC flips the script on traditional data management, automating data curation and harmonization. Instead of endless upfront effort, customers get ready-to-consume, semantically rich data products—saving time and reducing what SAP calls the “hidden data tax”.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Product Model:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP identifies “primary data products” (like finance, supply chain, HR) and brings them directly from SAP applications into BDC, curated and cataloged for instant use. The goal is to reach 500 data products by year-end—covering virtually every major enterprise domain.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Ready Fabric:&lt;/STRONG&gt; BDC’s lakehouse architecture and built-in “business fabric” layer empower businesses to use advanced analytics, natural language queries, and AI seamlessly. Dual integration and knowledge graph support mean both applications and users can access harmonized, context-rich insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_4031.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315134i24FE73D4E5E4735E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IMG_4031.jpeg" alt="IMG_4031.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interoperability &amp;amp; Ecosystem &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BDC Connect:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This technology helps integrate BDC with non-SAP systems like Databricks, enabling zero-copy data sharing and harmonized catalogs—perfect for hybrid and multicloud enterprises.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Marketplace Vision:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP is launching a data products marketplace, encouraging partners and customers to publish, consume, and innovate with SAP and non-SAP data. The upcoming announcement at SAP Connect will explain how the ecosystem and intelligent apps can grow—most delivered by partners, not just SAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Democratization: Empowering Every Employee &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":busts_in_silhouette:"&gt;👥&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pinar described SAP’s internal rollout—“customer zero”—where business users, not just IT, access BDC’s data products and build dashboards in hours. This isn’t just technology; SAP orchestrates enablement cohorts, training citizen analysts to maximize value and foster data-driven decision making at every level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reusable Data Products:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Designed for broad, multi-use case consumption, not one-off analytics. Both IT and business users (citizen analysts) can build, extend, and share data-driven solutions thanks to low-code/no-code tooling.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enablement &amp;amp; Governance:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP couples technology with strong governance and enablement programs—using Collibra for cataloging, trust-building, and making metadata as easy to navigate as grocery shopping.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="BDC Webinar Series APAC - post.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315135i7E3E776C36DF6317/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BDC Webinar Series APAC - post.png" alt="BDC Webinar Series APAC - post.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_showing_europe_africa:"&gt;🌍&lt;/span&gt;Whether you’re an enterprise architect, citizen analyst, or just curious about the future of business intelligence—SAP Business Data Cloud delivers a new foundation for turning data into real business outcomes, faster and smarter than ever before.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;🙋‍&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":male_sign:"&gt;♂️&lt;/span&gt; Which BDC feature excites you most? Are you ready for data democratization in your organization? Share your thoughts below!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note: Slides from the session and the recording would be only available to the registered attendees. So if you have not registered, please register now using the link below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eaa-bdc-apac/en_us/home.html#accordion-5d79451476-item-9ff3b2b36e" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://events.sap.com/eaa-bdc-apac/en_us/home.html#accordion-5d79451476-item-9ff3b2b36e&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important links &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Architecture Center:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://architecture.learning.sap.com/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enterprise Architect Learning Journey:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-sap-enterprise-architecture" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-sap-enterprise-architecture&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Learning Journey:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/introducing-sap-business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/courses/introducing-sap-business-data-cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1502031"&gt;@IrfanKhan&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1608450"&gt;@Gaurish-Dessai&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/214941" target="_blank"&gt;@ralph_richter&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/session-1-recap-amp-highlight-sap-bdc-the-future-of-intelligent-data/ba-p/14218631"/>
    <published>2025-09-18T08:17:50.731000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/future-proof-your-sap-support-journey-with-support-accreditation/ba-p/14222032</id>
    <title>Future-proof your SAP support journey with Support Accreditation</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T08:30:12.242000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SharvariSosale</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2134440</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discover what’s new in the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/getting-started-with-support-from-sap-support-accreditation" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Support Accreditation 2025 release&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s fast-paced business environment, speed and resilience are critical. Organizations that fully leverage their SAP solutions are better positioned to overcome challenges swiftly, avoid disruptions, and generate long-term value. That’s where Support Accreditation comes in — your guided path to mastering SAP’s intelligent support capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support Accreditation is a free, self-enabled learning journey that empowers SAP customers, partners, and employees with the requisite knowledge of SAP’s support offerings and tools. The latest six-unit accreditation is designed to equip all SAP users when engaging with support from SAP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Support Accreditation learning journey on learning.sap.com" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316799i23C86353475EA2F7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-17 172929.png" alt="Support Accreditation learning journey on learning.sap.com" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Support Accreditation learning journey on learning.sap.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Support Accreditation Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support Accreditation offers a quick, easy, and impactful way to upskill through a structured learning journey - empowering you and your teams to stay ahead. Here’s how it delivers impact:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maximize Your SAP Investment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Learn how to unlock the full value of your SAP solutions by leveraging support resources for faster, more effective problem-solving.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resolve Issues Proactively:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Prevent disruptions and avoid escalations using self-service tools and real-time support capabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stay Ahead with Intelligent Support:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Get familiar with SAP’s AI-driven and predictive support technologies to stay on the cutting edge.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streamline Support Interactions:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Reduce back-and-forth by understanding how to navigate SAP’s support channels and escalate efficiently.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Earn a Recognized Accreditation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Validate your knowledge with an official digital badge that demonstrates your expertise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Follow Scenario-Based Learning Paths&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Access tailored guidance for SAP Concur, Procurement, and explore key tools like SAP Cloud ALM.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Learning journey is easy to consume with relevant screenshots and walkthrough videos" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316780i1D3C0BA9F0645812/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-16 153137.png" alt="Learning journey is easy to consume with relevant screenshots and walkthrough videos" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Learning journey is easy to consume with relevant screenshots and walkthrough videos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Interactive yet easy quizzes for quick knowledge checks" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316800i9C1D2A3A8A1941F4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Interactive yet easy quizzes for quick knowledge checks.png" alt="Interactive yet easy quizzes for quick knowledge checks" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Interactive yet easy quizzes for quick knowledge checks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New in the Latest 2025 Release&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 2025 update to Support Accreditation introduces powerful new content designed to help you get even more from your SAP support tools and services. With the latest release, we have streamlined and updated the content to include the latest most relevant information while also introducing new units that can enhance your support services utilization and experience. Here's what’s new:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Insights Dashboard: Your Command Center for the health of your SAP system&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Monitor your SAP landscape with a single, interactive dashboard. View case statuses, usage statistics, service consumption, and more through tailored reports — all in one place. The &lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Insights Dashboard&lt;/STRONG&gt; will help you align support insights with business goals to improve decision-making and drive greater value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Search: Smarter Answers, Faster&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No more wading through endless documents. The new &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered search in SAP for Me&lt;/STRONG&gt; understands the intent behind your questions, not just the keywords. It connects you instantly to the most relevant documentation, KBAs, community posts, or embedded help content. With semantic understanding and vector-based retrieval, this is your shortcut to faster problem-solving and more confident self-service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Support Interaction Survey: Your Voice, Our Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your feedback now directly shapes the future of SAP support. The &lt;STRONG&gt;Support Interaction Survey&lt;/STRONG&gt; prompts you to share your experience after closing a case, whether positive or challenging. Low-effort scores trigger proactive follow-ups from our support managers, while high ratings help us celebrate and recognize excellence across our teams. Every response ensures your voice is heard and drives tangible improvements in the support you receive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strengthening Collaboration with SAP Partners: A Unified Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Collaboration just got more seamless with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;dedicated partner engagement section.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Partner engagement and management&amp;nbsp;in SAP for Me helps customers and partners work hand-in-hand with SAP support. With partner-specific dashboards, role-based access and analytics tools, this update empowers partners to deliver faster, more effective support on your behalf. The result? Greater visibility, smoother collaboration, and a stronger ecosystem working together for your success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started Today&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Support Accreditation, you’re not just learning, you’re future proofing your SAP journey. Whether you’re new to SAP or a seasoned professional, this is your opportunity to stay prepared, stay informed, and stay ahead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get accredited today at &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/getting-started-with-support-from-sap-support-accreditation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Support Accreditation on learning.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check out our &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/09/f235b1b9-1f7f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;info-sheet for a quick overview on Support Accreditation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Badge of completion issued as record of achievement" style="width: 254px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316792iBBF19C1A7690E320/image-dimensions/254x254/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="254" height="254" role="button" title="getting-started-with-support-from-sap-support-accre.1.png" alt="Badge of completion issued as record of achievement" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Badge of completion issued as record of achievement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blog-posts-about-sap-websites/future-proof-your-sap-support-journey-with-support-accreditation/ba-p/14222032"/>
    <published>2025-09-19T08:30:12.242000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-the-future-of-supply-chain-management-at-sap-connect-las-vegas/ba-p/14222055</id>
    <title>🚀 Unlock the Future of Supply Chain Management at SAP Connect Las Vegas</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T09:04:05.164000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>oliverhuschke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35096</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Connect 2025_SCM_track.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/316821iB9BB9D74D1E048DD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Connect 2025_SCM_track.png" alt="SAP Connect 2025_SCM_track.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mark your calendar for &lt;STRONG&gt;October 6–8, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, in &lt;STRONG&gt;Las Vegas&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Fontainebleau &amp;amp; Resorts World). &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Supply Chain Connect&lt;/A&gt; is back—and this year, it’s bigger, smarter, and more action-oriented than ever. SAP is bringing experts, customers, and innovative tools together to help you build more resilient, agile, and efficient supply chains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re in supply chain, procurement, operations, or logistics, here are several sessions you won’t want to miss. Make sure you add them to your agenda—and don’t miss the chance to meet SAP Services &amp;amp; Support executives and experts onsite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889973952"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;Key SCM Sessions to Attend&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Date Time (PDT) Session / Speakers Why It’s Worth Attending&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tuesday, Oct 7, &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3:15-4:00 PM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Fontainebleau&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754420440491001kOZ2" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCM2264&lt;/A&gt; – Future-ready now: Accelerate business transformation for agility and resilience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thomas Pfiester (SAP) • Richard Bancel (Schlumberger)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Learn how the SAP Services &amp;amp; Support engagement model + RISE with SAP Methodology help accelerate innovation, optimize logistics, and streamline manufacturing processes.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wednesday, Oct 8, 12:30-12:50 PM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Fontainebleau&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1750428170423001dpLn" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCM1914&lt;/A&gt; – Connect with business partners through integration and efficient management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Mert Oezkan&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Explore how SAP Integration Suite supports scalable, secure B2B integrations; managing partner onboarding, EDI or APIs, and partner connectivity.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wednesday, Oct 8, 1:00-2:15 PM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Resort World&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749740439993001okUD" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCM1443&lt;/A&gt; – Guided implementation in SAP Cloud ALM to transform your supply chain&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Vijay Prakash&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;See how guided implementation with Cloud ALM, best practices, and real-time visibility can speed up your transformation and reduce risk.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tuesday, Oct 7, 4:15-5:00 PM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Fontainebleau&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/vegas/flow/sap/sc25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755742210493001WUpD" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SCM2415&lt;/A&gt; – Sourcing and procurement collaboration at ST Engineering&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Jeff Korol • Mandy Moulton&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Hear how ST Engineering adopted SAP Business Network in a secure environment (SAP NS2) to meet aerospace/security compliance and improve procurement collaboration.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693460447"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt;Why These Sessions Are Important&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real customer stories.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Learn from organizations who are actually doing this. Their challenges and learnings matter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tangible tools &amp;amp; guidance.&lt;/STRONG&gt; These are not just theoretical; get insights into best practices, tools like SAP Cloud ALM and Integration Suite, and how to apply them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet the experts.&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Services &amp;amp; Support executives and experts will be present. Bring your questions. Speak with them. Tap into their experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496946942"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;What You Should Do Next&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; for the event—if you haven’t already.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add the sessions above&lt;/STRONG&gt; to your agenda now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet our SAP Services and Support experts&lt;/STRONG&gt; on the show floor within the Supply Chain Management track.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to seeing many of you in Vegas—let’s make Supply Chain Connect a turning point for resilience, efficiency, and transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlock-the-future-of-supply-chain-management-at-sap-connect-las-vegas/ba-p/14222055"/>
    <published>2025-09-19T09:04:05.164000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-a-cap-service-with-cds-mcp-and-cline-hands-on-super-basic-guide/ba-p/14223349</id>
    <title>Building a CAP service with cds‑mcp and Cline — HANDS‑ON SUPER BASIC GUIDE [ with screenshots ] 🍌</title>
    <updated>2025-09-21T22:27:22.791000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>smarchesini</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125739</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Everything you’re about to read started with this brilliant SAP blog: &lt;A target="_new" rel="noopener"&gt;Boost your CAP development with AI: Introducing the MCP Server for CAP&lt;/A&gt;. Think of it as the seed that grew into my little CAP + Cline + banana adventure. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":banana:"&gt;🍌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890006599"&gt;What you’ll get&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A friendly walkthrough to spin up a CAP service in VS Code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to wire it to S/4HANA via a BTP Destination for local tests&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A few real‑world bumps on Windows PATH and global installs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A silly “banana mode” at the end to prove handlers actually run &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":banana:"&gt;🍌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693493094"&gt;Prereqs (aka “don’t skip me”)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;VS Code on Windows&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Node.js installed and on PATH&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP subaccount with a Destination, e.g. DEVTOBERFEST_DEST to you S4H public cloud [follow my Devtoberfest session for this]&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Optional: Postman for poking endpoints&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496979589"&gt;Step 1 — Tools on deck&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you try to run &lt;FONT face="terminal,monaco"&gt;cds init&lt;/FONT&gt; and it's not working, follow the next steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_0-1758470144854.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317439i6AAD273BE7F7C538/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="smarchesini_0-1758470144854.png" alt="smarchesini_0-1758470144854.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1429548803"&gt;CAP dev kit&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;npm add -g @sap/cds-dk&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;If global installs act shy on Windows, add this to PATH then restart VS Code:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C:\Users\&amp;lt;YourUser&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming\npm&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496979589" id="toc-hId-1103952579"&gt;Step 2 —&amp;nbsp;Cline + CAP MCP server&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are a bunch of AI coding assistants out there — GitHub Copilot, Codeium, Cursor, Tabnine — so why bother with Cline and not Copilot or the others?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Copilot is amazing for inline coding, Cline felt like the right fit for &lt;STRONG&gt;building and testing a whole CAP service with AI in the loop&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_1-1758470196350.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317440i122E48B40A2D78EE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="smarchesini_1-1758470196350.png" alt="smarchesini_1-1758470196350.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Install &lt;A href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=saoudrizwan.claude-dev&amp;amp;utm_source=website&amp;amp;utm_medium=header" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cline from the VS Marketplace&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_2-1758470223336.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317441i8DDE7C3CA5025BDB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_2-1758470223336.png" alt="smarchesini_2-1758470223336.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_3-1758470245401.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317442i225C41439CDD285C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_3-1758470245401.png" alt="smarchesini_3-1758470245401.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add the CAP MCP server:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;npm i -g @cap-js/mcp-server&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_4-1758470286552.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317443i48A3A864296E08DB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_4-1758470286552.png" alt="smarchesini_4-1758470286552.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;VS Code settings (snip):&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_5-1758470320117.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317444i3ABD349E25BB21DC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_5-1758470320117.png" alt="smarchesini_5-1758470320117.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add the MCP Server configuration to your Cline:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;{
  "mcpServers": {
    "cds-mcp": { "command": "cds-mcp", "args": [], "env": {} }
  }
}&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Heads‑up: &lt;A href="http://Agents.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Agents.md&lt;/A&gt; wasn’t supported by Cline when I tried it; check again later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bonus guardrails, I told Cline:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;- Always use cds‑mcp to look up CDS definitions before reading *.cds files.
- Always check CAP docs via cds‑mcp before proposing changes.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you check on the bottom, you can find the model version:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_6-1758470378191.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317445i8DDBB09D395D061D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_6-1758470378191.png" alt="smarchesini_6-1758470378191.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cline model picks I tried:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;anthropic/claude-sonnet-4&lt;/STRONG&gt; — great for agentic coding, supports images/browser/prompt caching.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;openai/gpt-5&lt;/STRONG&gt; — state-of-the-art for long tasks, supports images/browser, no caching.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;x-ai/grok-code-fast-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; — free (handy after I burned credits), supports prompt caching but no images/browser.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can see the differences between all the models, but Grok is free. After using my 10 free prompts, I switched to Grok on my daily to continue working (but not for this blog)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-907439074"&gt;Step 3 — New CAP project&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;cds init&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The cds init command scaffolds a &lt;STRONG&gt;new CAP project&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;It creates the basic folder structure (app/, db/, srv/), adds a package.json, and sets up config files so you don’t start from scratch.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short: it’s the “hello world” starter for CAP — without it, you’d have to wire everything by hand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-710925569"&gt;Step 4 — Bring in Business Partner and scaffold&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;After importing the EDMX file [check my video on the Devtoberfest], let's try a prompt. We want to apply this prompt to Cline:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Extend API_BUSINESS_PARTNER.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create service.cds and service.js.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expose only BusinessPartner with READ and CREATE. If the name contains “banana”, throw an error.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Result: service.cds and service.js created. MCP caching made later calls cheaper. Nice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For this blog, I bought 2$ of credit just for testing (I already used all the free ones). Let’s see how much it will be used.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_7-1758470566557.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317446i00551918E0DD1099/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="smarchesini_7-1758470566557.png" alt="smarchesini_7-1758470566557.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_10-1758470706094.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317447i4054FE74939CA97E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_10-1758470706094.png" alt="smarchesini_10-1758470706094.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The creation seems to be working fine, and we used 82.6k credits, which is close to $1. Let’s continue the process and create the service.cds by clicking save.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_11-1758470747820.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317448iECA65DC6A46DDEF9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="smarchesini_11-1758470747820.png" alt="smarchesini_11-1758470747820.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The service.js file was created correctly. We also used fewer tokens because we cached the query before sending it to the MCP server.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The file also seems fine. I would not expect anything else after this, but Cline is asking me that :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let me check if there's a package.json file to understand the project setup and then test the implementation. and it want to read the package.json file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;I want to be more specific in this case. I have a destination defined in my btp with already access to my S4HC and exposed the business partner scenario. I would like to test locally by using this destination and my new project. Let’s then correct and add new information with my prompt.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like you check the package.json and prepare the project for deploy and test locally. I have a BTP destination ready and connected with name DEVTOBERFEST_DEST&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;!--           notionvc: 257f8e46-37f8-4be9-9869-3ef56c969725           --&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_13-1758470799460.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317449i1916BE772E09803E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_13-1758470799460.png" alt="smarchesini_13-1758470799460.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_14-1758470809477.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317450i53FC37C7C229A9B1/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="smarchesini_14-1758470809477.png" alt="smarchesini_14-1758470809477.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a money saver, I get a little annoyed paying 3 cents to ask me to run npm install, even though I know I need to do it always.&lt;BR /&gt;It’s fine for testing and learning purposes lol.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_16-1758470928344.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317451i0A629453D9983810/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_16-1758470928344.png" alt="smarchesini_16-1758470928344.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And another 6 cents to check and suggested me npm start. But let’s imagine we are new in this CAP world and we follow blindly Cline and the MCP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_17-1758470944331.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317452iF27933E158A017B1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_17-1758470944331.png" alt="smarchesini_17-1758470944331.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-514412064"&gt;Step 5 — Prep for local testing with a Destination&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have a BTP Destination named DEVTOBERFEST_DEST that points to the S/4HANA Business Partner API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After this point, I decided to add my MTA file and the destination configuration (to connect to the system) by myself. Without using any AI tool&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;cds add mta;&lt;BR /&gt;cds add xsuaa,destination,connectivity;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_18-1758471011289.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317453i2AF3B57634F0AB09/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="smarchesini_18-1758471011289.png" alt="smarchesini_18-1758471011289.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-317898559"&gt;Step 6 — Build, deploy, and test&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Install all the package dependencies with&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;npm i&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;I decided to build and deploy by using Cline.&lt;BR /&gt;Something I notice differently in my usual process is the new terminal type Cline on the right.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_19-1758471059158.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317454i919195B196F92B68/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_19-1758471059158.png" alt="smarchesini_19-1758471059158.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Everything went fine, and from my postman, I can see the call&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_21-1758471103480.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317455iAA360E10F188205F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_21-1758471103480.png" alt="smarchesini_21-1758471103480.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This one was the first significant milestone. I think the most challenging part was to make VSCode (for me, who I am a Business Application Code user). Let's try something more fun.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-121385054"&gt;Step 7 — Banana mode (purely for fun)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;I asked (Because why not?):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;When filtering by BusinessPartnerFullName for "Sebastiano Marchesini", make every field say "banana".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_22-1758471312259.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317459i0668E427066942CA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_22-1758471312259.png" alt="smarchesini_22-1758471312259.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This request took the MCP multiple steps and ended with $0.89 in expenses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_23-1758471366190.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317461i22F8239C314448F0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="smarchesini_23-1758471366190.png" alt="smarchesini_23-1758471366190.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not bad for banana mode, but it didn’t fully understand my request. The code set everything to ‘banana’ whenever it found one in the result.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="smarchesini_24-1758471404885.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317463i8E4CA6D95AE0F4D7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="smarchesini_24-1758471404885.png" alt="smarchesini_24-1758471404885.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This still teaches a big truth about our development: we cannot leave everything to the AI, but we need to take care of our code and pay attention to what we produce.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Now....&lt;BR /&gt;Send to prod? Absolutely not. Demo at parties? Maybe.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-143043187"&gt;Token Cost Breakdown &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":money_bag:"&gt;💰&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current Usage:&lt;/STRONG&gt; ?? / 256K tokens I used in 3 sessions to prepare this blog.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Estimated Cost:&lt;/STRONG&gt; $2.45 USD&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Per 1K tokens:&lt;/STRONG&gt; $0.004 - $0.011&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--346873325"&gt;Quick fixes when things go sideways&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Global CLI not found → fix PATH and restart VS Code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;npm start explodes → run npm i in the project root&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Destination calls fail → ensure destination + connectivity are added and bound in BTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;401/403 after deploy → check xsuaa&amp;nbsp; and use the client id and secret only from Postman&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--543386830"&gt;Copy‑paste corner&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;# Global tools
npm add -g @sap/cds-dk
npm i -g @cap-js/mcp-server

# Project
cds init
# import EDMX as needed

# BTP integration
cds add mta
cds add xsuaa,destination,connectivity
npm i

# Local run
npm start
# or
cds watch

# Build &amp;amp; deploy
npm run build
npm run deploy&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--446497328"&gt;Final questions and next steps&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId--1816622861"&gt;Did you try with other tools? How did you feel?&amp;nbsp; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":eyes:"&gt;👀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Next blog, I want to try the integration with SAPui5 MCP and Copilot.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkler:"&gt;🎇&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;!--           notionvc: 979ccd25-475f-459c-85a9-c149ec09e7bf           --&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;!--           notionvc: 9641f12f-0fc4-4029-b2e2-6e2a4a53ead0           --&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;!--           notionvc: a39c14df-2664-454e-8914-64da4ae0aa23           --&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-a-cap-service-with-cds-mcp-and-cline-hands-on-super-basic-guide/ba-p/14223349"/>
    <published>2025-09-21T22:27:22.791000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enabling-agent-interoperability-a-practical-path-from-api-to-mcp-server/ba-p/14203372</id>
    <title>Enabling Agent Interoperability: A Practical Path from API to MCP Server</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:28:10.147000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yarloy_Wang</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1879819</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The future of enterprise AI will be driven by the deep and seamless integration of LLMs into existing enterprise products and workflows. To stay competitive, companies must make their vast landscape of existing capabilities directly accessible and usable by AI, empowering a new generation of intelligent ecosystems. This requires a clear strategy for enabling agent interoperability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this article,&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;we will &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;establish that the journey to agent interoperability begins with a foundational pillar: enabling agents to reliably connect with tools (Agent-to-Tool). We'll start by defining the foundational challenge that prevents agents and tools from communicating effectively. We will then introduce the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/docs/getting-started/intro" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Model Context Protocol&lt;/A&gt; (MCP) as a standardized solution and walk through a step-by-step tutorial on how to transform a standard REST API into a fully compliant MCP Server using a cloud-native gateway.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1629994205"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is Agent Interoperability and Why Does It Matter?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agent Interoperability is a comprehensive framework for a complete AI ecosystem, which relies on two fundamental pillars: Agent-to-Agent (A2A) interaction and Agent-to-Tool (A2T) interaction.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While A2A interaction—how agents collaborate and delegate tasks—represents a sophisticated, multi-agent system's goal, A2T interaction is the foundational prerequisite. The ability of agents to collaborate is contingent upon their individual capacity to connect to tools.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Therefore, solving the Agent-to-Tool challenge is the most critical first step towards the broader goal of agent interoperability. While not an Agent-to-Agent protocol itself, solving the Agent-to-Tool challenge is the most critical first step towards the broader goal of agent interoperability: how to let any agent discover and use any external capability in a standardized way.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1433480700"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Foundational Challenge: Connecting Agents to Enterprise Tools&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In an enterprise environment like SAP,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;this challenge presents distinct engineering considerations on both sides of the connection:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On the agent side&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: The challenge is building agents with the autonomy to dynamically discover and utilize a diverse set of capabilities, moving beyond static tool integrations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On the capability side&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;The engineering task is to adapt SAP's vast landscape of powerful APIs for a new type of consumer: the autonomous AI agent.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;The goal is to create AI-consumable interfaces for these existing capabilities, which involves adding the necessary semantic context and standardized formats that agents require for dynamic interaction&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This difference in design paradigms creates a natural "Interoperability Gap”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bridging this gap requires a foundational layer for communication: a standardized protocol that enables dynamic discovery and standardized interaction between agents and established enterprise APIs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1236967195"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Solution: MCP as a Standardized Protocol Bridge&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, how do we bridge this "Interoperability Gap"? The solution lies in a shared standard—a common language that both agents and tools can speak. This is where the Model Context Protocol (MCP)&amp;nbsp; comes in.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;MCP is an open protocol that standardizes how applications provide context to large language models (LLMs). MCP provides a standardized way to connect AI models to different data sources and tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We use MCP to build agents and complex workflows on top of LLMs. The key participants in the MCP architecture are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MCP Host&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The AI application that coordinates and manages one or multiple MCP clients&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MCP Client&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A component that maintains a connection to an MCP server and obtains context from an MCP server for the MCP host to use&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MCP Server&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A program that provides context to MCP clients&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-02 at 18.23.05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307786i34101443A9040C2B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-02 at 18.23.05.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-02 at 18.23.05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As for enterprise like SAP, the best practice will be:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757496429561.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312186iAC4A61BEC1A4FF81/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757496429561.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757496429561.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, a protocol is only useful if capabilities adopt it. The enterprise landscape is filled with valuable, pre-existing REST APIs that were not built for this new paradigm. Therefore, a critical first step toward achieving agent interoperability is to bridge these legacy APIs to the MCP standard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The act of transforming a standard API into a discoverable MCP Server is the foundational process for unlocking existing enterprise value for AI agents.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1169536409"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MCP Adoption Strategy in Enterprise Ecosystems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When adopting a new standard like MCP within a large enterprise ecosystem like SAP, there are typically two primary strategic paths to consider for implementation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. The Standard Path:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Platform-Managed Solutions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For most common use cases, the standard approach is to leverage platform-integrated, centrally managed solutions. This path involves using automated services, often provided by the enterprise platform (e.g., SAP BTP), to convert existing APIs into standardized tools. By using unified method for transformation, this approach ensures consistency and manageability across the entire ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. The&amp;nbsp;Flexible Path: Custom or "Native" Implementations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For scenario demanding greater flexibility or more complex business logic, a more custom approach is required. This involves building what can be considered "native" MCP servers. This approach allows teams to build custom implementations using a variety of technologies, such as open-source libraries or different programming languages, giving them full control over the implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This Guide's Focus: A Hands-on Example of the Flexible Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following guide, we will focus on the flexible, native server approach. &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;We will demonstrate a powerful and practical pattern for this by using a cloud-native gateway, Higress, to wrap an existing API. This method is ideal for teams who require full control over the transformation logic and deployment environment, providing a valuable, hands-on example of building a native-style MCP server.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-843940185"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step-by-Step Guide: Transforming API into MCP Server&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To see how this concept works in the real world, let's take a standard REST API and use a gateway to transform it into a fully-compliant MCP server.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our Goal&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Wrap a simple HTTP API as an MCP Server and invoke it from an agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Simple API:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A REST API that returns&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;real-time currency exchange data&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Gateway:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://higress.cn/en/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Higress&lt;/A&gt;, an open-source, cloud-native gateway with a powerful plugin architecture.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Standard:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The Model Context Protocol (MCP), which we'll implement using the Higress MCP Plugin.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Environment:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;A Kubernetes environment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-776509399"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-579995894"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A Modern Transport Protocol: Streamable HTTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before we begin, it's important to understand transport mechanisms for client-server communication we'll be using. This guide utilizes a modern and powerful approach defined by the MCP standard: &lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/specification/2025-03-26/basic/transports#streamable-http%20" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Streamable HTTP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We chose this approach for several key advantages that make it superior for modern AI systems:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified Architecture:&lt;/STRONG&gt; In the Streamable HTTP transport, the server operates as an independent process that can handle multiple client connections. Because the session context is maintained within this single, stateful connection, the need for an external session manager like Redis is often eliminated.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bidirectional and Flexible Communication:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The protocol handles simple request-response patterns efficiently but also enables true bidirectional communication. Server can optionally make use of Server-Sent Events (SSE) to stream multiple server messages. This permits basic MCP servers, as well as more feature-rich servers supporting streaming and server-to-client notifications and requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-383482389"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step 1: The Starting Point - A Simple REST API&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the requirement of Streamable HTTP, The server MUST provide a single HTTP endpoint path (hereafter referred to as the MCP endpoint) that supports both POST and GET methods.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To demonstrate the transformation process, this guide will use the ExchangeRate-API, a professional service that provides real-time currency exchange data. We'll use its lasted&amp;nbsp;endpoint, which returns up-to-date global rates based on the US Dollar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;API Endpoint:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://open.er-api.com/v6/latest/USD" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://open.er-api.com/v6/latest/USD&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;A successful request to this endpoint returns a JSON object with a structure similar to this, containing metadata and a nested rates object:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "result": "success",
  "time_last_update_utc": "Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:02:31 +0000",
  "base_code": "USD",
  "rates": {
    "USD": 1,
    "EUR": 0.925,
    "GBP": 0.789,
    ...
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This represents a typical "legacy" capability—useful, but not inherently agent-friendly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-186968884"&gt;Step 2: Preparing the Gateway with Higress&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of modifying the API's code, we'll use a gateway to act as a transformation layer. Higress is an ideal choice because its plugin architecture is designed to extend gateway capabilities, including native support for AI scenarios through protocols like MCP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-119538098"&gt;2.1 Higress Deployment&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First, install Higress into your cluster environment (To simplify, we use k3s as an example).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check your console's node port:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;kubectl get svc higress-console -n higress-system&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once the installation succeeds, you can access the Higress Console in browser by &lt;A target="_self"&gt;http://&amp;lt;your-cluster-external-ip&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;console-port&amp;gt;&lt;/A&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757496799751.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312202i2AEEFF7078F6613E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757496799751.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757496799751.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--152206776"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--348720281"&gt;2.2 Config MCP Server&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once deployed, we need to enable the MCP Server functionality globally by editing the higress-config ConfigMap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;kubectl edit configmap higress-config -n higress-system&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the ConfigMap data, we'll add the MCP Server configuration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;apiVersion: v1
data:
  higress: |-
    mcpServer:
      sse_path_suffix: /sse  # Suffix for the Server-Sent Events connection path
      enable: true           # Enable the MCP Server
      servers: []
  downstream:
    # ... (rest of the config)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--545233786"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--448344284"&gt;Step 3: Transforming the API with the MCP Plugin&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--938260796"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.1 Add a Service Source&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Higress Console, navigate to&amp;nbsp;Service Source page&lt;A target="_self"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A target="_self"&gt;http://&amp;lt;your-cluster-external-ip&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;console-port&amp;gt;/service-source&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and add a new source pointing to our API's address (&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://open.er-api.com/v6/latest/USD" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://open.er-api.com/v6/latest/USD&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757931121414.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314428i214A6174BD4262C4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757931121414.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_0-1757931121414.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1134774301"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1331287806"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3.2 Create a Route&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, go to the&amp;nbsp;Route&amp;nbsp;page&amp;nbsp;and create a new route.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click "Route Config" on the left sidebar&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click "Create Route" button&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fill in the form with the following details:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Route Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: exchange-rate-route&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Path&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Select&amp;nbsp;Exact&amp;nbsp;and enter&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;/exchange-rates&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Select the service source you just created&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_1-1757931163528.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314430i005F91659DF6F9D8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_1-1757931163528.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_1-1757931163528.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will create a route that matches the path &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;/exchange-rates&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and forwards requests to the service source you created. Now you can see the new route in the list.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this point, Higress will simply proxy requests from&lt;EM&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;/exchange-rates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;to our API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1821204318"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1724314816"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Configure the MCP Server Plugin&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click the&amp;nbsp;Strategy&amp;nbsp;link on your new route and find the&amp;nbsp;MCP Server&amp;nbsp;plugin.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Route Config3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307673i3B89CFE60DE8E011/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Route Config3.png" alt="Route Config3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After enabling the plugin, click "Configure" and switch to the YAML view. This is where we define the metadata that makes our API discoverable and understandable to agents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_2-1757931258146.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314431i2976D125D06884AC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_2-1757931258146.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_2-1757931258146.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Paste the following configuration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;server:
  name: "exchange-rate-server"
tools:
  - name: "get-latest-usd-rates"
    description: "Fetches the latest currency exchange rates based on the US Dollar."
    requestTemplate:
      method: "GET"
      url: "https://open.er-api.com/v6/latest/USD"
    responseTemplate:
      body: |-
        **Latest Exchange Rates (Base: {{.base_code}})**
        *Updated at: {{.time_last_update_utc}}*
        
        - **Euro (EUR):** {{.rates.EUR}}
        - **Japanese Yen (JPY):** {{.rates.JPY}}
        - **British Pound (GBP):** {{.rates.GBP}}
        - **Chinese Yuan (CNY):** {{.rates.CNY}}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's break this down:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;server.name: A human-readable name for our new MCP server.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;tools: A list of capabilities this server provides.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;name &amp;amp; description: The crucial metadata for agent to intelligently discover and select this tool when a user asks about exchange rates.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;requestTemplate &amp;amp; responseTemplate: These define how Higress calls the backend API and formats the response. Here, the requestTemplate specifies a simple GET request, and the responseTemplate transforms the JSON output into a clean, agent-friendly format.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Save the plugin configuration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our standard REST API is now exposed as a fully functional and discoverable MCP Server, ready for any compliant AI agent to use.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1627425314"&gt;Step 4: Connecting and Invoking from an Agent with Streamable HTTP&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, any MCP-compliant agent or client can connect to our gateway and use this new tool. To test our new MCP server, we can use any compliant MCP Host app, such as Cline, Cursor, Trae, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For this guide, we'll use &lt;A href="https://cline.bot%20" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Cline&lt;/A&gt; as example. It's &lt;SPAN&gt;an autonomous coding agent&lt;/SPAN&gt; that can be&lt;SPAN&gt; installed&lt;/SPAN&gt; as a VS Code extension&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;Configure Cline with the following setting to establish a connection to our new server:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "mcpServers": {
    "exchange-rate-server": {
      "url": "http://&amp;lt;your-cluster-external-ip&amp;gt;/exchange-rates",
      "type": "streamableHttp"
    }
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now you can test the server in Cline:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757931306012.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314432iA494F5F67F1D73A3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757931306012.png" alt="Yarloy_Wang_3-1757931306012.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1655755128"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this post, we've navigated a practical path toward the broader vision of agent interoperability. We established that the most critical first step is solving the Agent-to-Tool (A2T) challenge: making existing enterprise APIs discoverable and usable by AI agents. We then demonstrated a powerful pattern to achieve this, using a cloud-native gateway, Higress, to transform a standard REST API into a fully compliant MCP Server. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The most powerful takeaway is demonstrating a flexible path to a native server: You've learned how a gateway-centric pattern can be used to build a "native" MCP server, offering full control to teams that require flexibility and customization in their MCP adoption strategy. It means existing, valuable enterprise services can be rapidly integrated into the agent ecosystem, making them dynamically discoverable and usable by any MCP-compliant agent.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solving the Agent-to-Tool problem building the foundation for agent interoperability. With a robust A2T layer in place, the path is cleared for more advanced Agent-to-Agent collaboration, paves the way for a future where countless enterprise services can be seamlessly integrated with agent ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enabling-agent-interoperability-a-practical-path-from-api-to-mcp-server/ba-p/14203372"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:28:10.147000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
