<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Artificial-Intelligence-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Artificial Intelligence</title>
  <updated>2025-10-25T23:10:27.557243+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Artificial Intelligence/pd-p/c3c3a408-33ea-4c2a-ae6f-05461e76982d" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Artificial Intelligence blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-commitment-to-business-continuity-that-protects-what-matters/ba-p/14232343</id>
    <title>SAP’s Commitment to Business Continuity that Protects what Matters</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T10:49:05.255000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JeaneFerreira</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1759223</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When people want to guard valuable items from their personal collections, they turn to protected places, such as banks, where they can rest safely, shielded from any unanticipated events. For centuries, individuals have entrusted institutions to safeguard what is most treasured by them, whether personal belongings or other assets. In the same fashion, SAP is dedicated to assisting customers protect their business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Disruptions can happen at any time. The difference stands in how well-prepared customers can be for these challenging periods. For example, Black Friday and Cyber Monday are the busiest shopping periods of the year for retailers. During these events, downtime or poor performance can cost millions in lost sales and customer trust, which could hamper core business operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Holiday Season Readiness Program&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To support industries processes during these times, SAP enhanced the Holiday&amp;nbsp;Season&amp;nbsp;Readiness Program for Commerce Cloud customers. This joint initiative between Support, Engineering, and Cloud Operations ensured retailers were fully equipped with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Introduction of a Preventative Care Model powered by AI and automation, using the Agentic AI framework to proactively detect and even resolve issues before they impacted customers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Weekly health checks, 360° action plans, proactive cases, and a 24x7 global control room with real-time monitoring and on-site staffing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP for Me&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Aligned with our commitment to being a reliable partner, SAP for Me is evolving into a customer’s digital companion, in one of the most exciting innovations within SAP. It’s no longer just a portal; it’s becoming a central hub for transparency, guidance, and predictive insights. It holds:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-driven transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt; - SAP for Me aggregates critical alerts, metrics, and insights across a customer’s entire SAP product portfolio. With the integration of Business AI, it now gives visibility into AI unit availability, consumption, and expirations, helping customers avoid surprises and plan proactively.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proactive business assurance&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Instead of waiting for a billing or system issue, SAP for Me provides real-time and predictive views into usage, health, and risks. For instance, customers can track consumption trends by product and feature, updated hourly, and receive early warnings when capacity is at risk.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified control&lt;/STRONG&gt; - All AI usage is linked to finance and legal statements, so customers get a single source of truth that connects technical consumption with business accountability. This prevents overspend, protects return on investment (ROI), and ensures contractual clarity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Continuous innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt; - SAP is expanding SAP for Me with embedded AI copilots and guided recommendations, so in the future, customers won’t just see metrics — they’ll get actionable guidance on how to optimize systems and safeguard value.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ongoing support and maintenance are critical to sustaining business value with SAP systems. A successful go-live is just the starting point; systems need to remain secure, compliant, and optimized as business needs to evolve. With proactive monitoring, automation, and AI-driven insights, customers can prevent disruptions, reduce risk, and maintain high availability. In practice, this means lower operational costs, higher uptime, and continuous ROI over the entire lifecycle of their SAP investment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Just as we expect care when trusting our valuables to others, SAP is committed to safeguarding business value, providing seamless experiences that protect decisive revenue and build sustained trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;A special thanks to Keith Ho, Customer Engagement Lead, and Manoj Gupta, SAP experts who have contributed to this article.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-commitment-to-business-continuity-that-protects-what-matters/ba-p/14232343"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T10:49:05.255000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/agentic-ai-testing-for-greenfield-s-4hana-outbound-interfaces-part-1/ba-p/14232427</id>
    <title>Agentic AI Testing for Greenfield S/4HANA Outbound Interfaces - Part 1</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T11:01:36.832000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichalKrawczyk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45785</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761818507"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intro&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Outbound interfaces are the lifeline between your new S/4HANA Greenfield or Selective Data Transition system and the outside world. Customers, vendors, 3PL partners, they still expect the same EDI (or non-EDI) output messages, even if you’ve reshaped half your internal processes in the course of the SAP S/4HANA transformation. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The real challenge? Functional consultants need to validate those outbound messages themselves, without waiting on an EDI provider, an integration colleague, or an EDI partner. That’s where &lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic AI validation with Int4 Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; comes in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This playbook shows how functional consultants can independently test and validate outbound interfaces, step by step, without leaving the SAP S/4HANA + Int4 Suite environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565305002"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why functional consultants, not integration teams?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Most SAP projects (Greenfield, Selective Data Transition, or any other complex SAP S/4HANA upgrades) involve huge shifts inside SAP, but &lt;STRONG&gt;the outside world doesn’t care&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Partner EDI flows must remain identical.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditionally, testing those flows meant:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Asking the EDI partner/provider for some sample messages&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trying to run the transaction in SAP S/4HANA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Asking the EDI provider to re-check/confirm outbound messages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Pulling in a specialist from the integration team if something takes too long.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Repeating the same process multiple times with very little time to do it&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our approach flips this. It empowers the SAP &lt;STRONG&gt;functional consultant&lt;/STRONG&gt; to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Insert thousand of historical EDI messages from any productive system&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ask Int4 Suite to find the test data within those messages&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reproduce SAP transactions from historical payloads, like Sales Order Confirmation, Delivery (ASN) notification, Invoice Notification&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validate the EDI outbound messages directly in Int4 Suite by the functional consultant&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The whole process takes minutes not hours and can be done hundreds of times per hour with no external dependencies (other partners)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;No waiting on specialists, no bottlenecks, and much faster iterations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368791497"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Reality-first message mining with Robotic Crawler&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;Int4 Robotic Crawler&lt;/STRONG&gt; to load hundreds or thousands of real historical messages (EDI or otherwise) into Int4 Suite. These are not toy examples — they’re your actual outbound payloads as they once moved through production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Robotic_Crawler.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321917i97866240497CF8B0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Robotic_Crawler.png" alt="Robotic_Crawler.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - Int4 Suite Robotic Crawler can fetch EDI messages from any supported archive or integration platform on mass scale&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why it matters:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Consultants can work with authentic data, not spec sheets or made-up test cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172277992"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Conversational selection of test cases&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Functional consultants don’t need to master payload filtering. Instead, they can simply chat with the agent to select which messages they want to test.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Want to see all outbound orders from a specific customer? Or deliveries with a particular Incoterm? Just ask the agent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Select_Message.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321918i0F9347CA00B3AFEC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Select_Message.png" alt="Select_Message.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - select a historical EDI messages using different criteria (business document, partner, material, etc.) and use this data for testing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why it matters:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Test-case discovery becomes intuitive, not a technical exercise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975764487"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Reconstruct SAP business objects from payloads&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once a message is selected, the consultant can instantly &lt;STRONG&gt;recreate a business document&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., a Sales Order) inside S/4HANA using the data from that outbound message.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="va01_order.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321922i5C8342C0A127DC10/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="va01_order.png" alt="va01_order.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - creating a sales order using the data from the historical EDI message as input&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now you have a living document in S/4HANA, built directly from the same payload your partners receive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why it matters: Consultants can validate the end-to-end logic of their own functional processes, with no dependency on integration experts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779250982"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Agentic comparison of original vs. new outbound message&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;After posting the new Sales Order (or Delivery, or Invoice), the consultant sends the &lt;STRONG&gt;newly generated outbound reference&lt;/STRONG&gt; back to the AI agent. The agent compares this outbound message to the original one from Step 1.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Change_reference.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321924i87421C2FA0E542D9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Change_reference.png" alt="Change_reference.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - use the historical EDI message to compare with the new one and fetch is by just supplying the new order reference number&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are they still identical? Has anything in S/4HANA configuration changed the outbound structure? Did the partner-facing fields remain untouched?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="validate_EDI.png" style="width: 804px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321927i3147647BF9891CE8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="validate_EDI.png" alt="validate_EDI.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - display the comparison of the two EDI messages (original and the new one) to fix any SAP S/4HANA configuration issues (like line item category determination, substitutions, calculations, etc.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why it matters:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Consultants get a precise answer immediately, without needing to export messages into external systems or call for backup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who benefits from this approach?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Functional consultants&lt;/STRONG&gt; in SAP S/4HANA Greenfield or Selective Data Transition projects who must ensure message stability despite deep process changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Project teams&lt;/STRONG&gt; that want faster, independent validation without pulling scarce EDI resources.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business stakeholders&lt;/STRONG&gt; who need assurance that partners will keep receiving the same documents as before, no surprises.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who is this &lt;EM&gt;not&lt;/EM&gt; for?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration consultants&lt;/STRONG&gt; looking to stress-test iFlows or middleware mappings — this isn’t their playground. Int4 Suite has other features to facilite those requirements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;EDI providers&lt;/STRONG&gt; who validate full partner connectivity, that’s still their domain.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pure developers&lt;/STRONG&gt; focused on code-level regression, this approach is tailored for business-facing validation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-582737477"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why it matters for S/4HANA programs where EDI messages remain the same but SAP S/4HANA can change?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Outbound interfaces are always the fragile bridge in any migration. By equipping functional consultants with agentic AI validation, you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Shorten test cycles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduce reliance on external partners.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Increase confidence in project quality.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Outbound messages stay consistent, partners stay happy, and your SAP S/4HANA Greenfield program keeps its velocity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach isn’t about replacing integration experts — it’s about &lt;STRONG&gt;freeing functional consultants&lt;/STRONG&gt; to independently confirm that what leaves the system is still what the outside world expects. It’s the missing puzzle piece for smooth, low-friction interface validation in SAP transformations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/agentic-ai-testing-for-greenfield-s-4hana-outbound-interfaces-part-1/ba-p/14232427"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T11:01:36.832000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/int4-suite-agents-empowers-functional-consultants-to-test-integrated-sap-s/ba-p/14234100</id>
    <title>Int4 Suite Agents Empowers Functional Consultants To Test Integrated SAP S/4HANA Business Processes</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T11:41:59.491000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichalKrawczyk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/45785</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761875137"&gt;Introduction&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Integrated business processes are the bloodstream of SAP systems. Every Sales Order, Purchase Order, Delivery, and Invoice has to flow smoothly, not just within SAP, but across EDI partners (customer, vendors, 3PL partners) banks, warehouses, tax portals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s the paradox: SAP S/4HANA projects have plenty of sophisticated automation tools, but they &lt;STRONG&gt;rarely help functional consultants in their manual tests&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Instead, those tools get pushed into the narrow niche of automation testers. Functional consultants treat them like mythical dragons, complicated, dangerous, and likely to drag them away from their real work into procedural swamps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result? Slow testing cycles, dependency on integration specialists, and endless waiting for external partners to provide messages or confirmations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565361632"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Changing the story with simulation agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The better path is not to force functional consultants into scripting or automation frameworks, but to give them &lt;STRONG&gt;simulation agents&lt;/STRONG&gt; that mimic the system environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of saying: &lt;EM&gt;“learn a test framework and run automated scripts,”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;we can say: &lt;EM&gt;“here are agents that simulate your missing EDI partner, your unavailable 3rd party/legacy system and you can test with them right now.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This changes the game:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No competition with automation teams.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No learning curve with complex frameworks and procedural delays.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultants get something they instantly understand: &lt;STRONG&gt;realistic test conditions on demand, using actual historical production data.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368848127"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How Int4 Suite Agents Work&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Int4 Suite, simulation agents provide a simple interface: the consultant performs the transaction in SAP, the agent feeds in authentic historical test data, and then automatically checks whether the newly generated EDI or non-EDI message matches what was sent in production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below are examples of key agents and how they fit into typical integrated OTC and P2P processes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Agents.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322568iEB56C9B840B5AB9A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Agents.png" alt="Agents.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - meet the Int4 Suite Agents&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301417341"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;EDI Partner Agent (based on historical data)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Replays authentic production EDI messages from trading partners (ORDERS, DESADV, INVOIC).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant performs the transaction in SAP (e.g., creates delivery, sends invoice).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent provides historical test data from previously exchanged documents.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent automatically compares the newly generated EDI message with the production one for a similar case.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OTC examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant in the OTC team replays historical &lt;STRONG&gt;ORDERS&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the largest customer and verifies whether, after pricing condition changes, the system still calculates correctly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests goods receipt with historical &lt;STRONG&gt;DESADV&lt;/STRONG&gt; data; agent compares the new EDI message against the production one.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant issues a sales invoice (&lt;STRONG&gt;INVOIC&lt;/STRONG&gt;) and agent validates it against the original production invoice, checking VAT rules.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Select_Message_with_MatNR.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322531i577899AB75CC39FB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Select_Message_with_MatNR.png" alt="Select_Message_with_MatNR.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - Select Historical EDI messages from Production system which need to be rerun on Test System&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P2P examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant creates a purchase order; agent provides a historical &lt;STRONG&gt;ORDRSP&lt;/STRONG&gt; where the supplier delivered partially, then compares the new outbound message.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent simulates a supplier &lt;STRONG&gt;INVOIC&lt;/STRONG&gt; and verifies whether workflows behave the same after configuration changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="change_data_for_Each_message.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322532iA3CB0B92921AF310/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="change_data_for_Each_message.png" alt="change_data_for_Each_message.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - manipulate the historical/production landscape EDI message data before sending that to the test environment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104903836"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unavailable System Agent (Non-SAP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Simulates external systems (banks, customs, WMS/TMS, tax portals) with historical production communications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant runs the business process in SAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent injects historical test data from the external system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent compares the new outbound message with the original production one.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OTC examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests e-invoicing using a historically rejected invoice; agent checks whether the new output matches the original and if the new rules handle it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests shipment confirmations with historical WMS responses.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P2P examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests bank payments; agent supplies historical payment files and checks the new output structure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests tax submissions; agent provides historical records and compares new vs. old messages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Display_the_EDI_Data_for_test.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322533i24936AE9F9E8CEDC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Display_the_EDI_Data_for_test.png" alt="Display_the_EDI_Data_for_test.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure - Display the historical EDI data used on production landscape before rerunning that on the test environment&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-908390331"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Historical Data Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The production message librarian, replays large volumes or special cases directly from production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant triggers transactions in SAP (bulk orders, invoices, returns).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent provides the historical payloads.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent verifies test messages against the production equivalents.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OTC examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant replays a “Black Friday” scenario with 10,000 &lt;STRONG&gt;ORDERS&lt;/STRONG&gt;; agent validates each new EDI message against its production twin.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests credit memo flows from historical complaint cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="run_all_test_cases.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322534i9D036A8DB1F8EC62/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="run_all_test_cases.png" alt="run_all_test_cases.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure – run many historical messages on the test environment for bulk testing purposes&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P2P examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests bulk supplier invoices; agent validates the outputs against production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant tests blocked spare-parts orders with historical references.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-711876826"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Consultant Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A technical assistant that retrieves and compares messages from middleware layers (PI/PO, CPI).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant executes the business process in SAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent fetches the historical integration payload.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent highlights differences between new and historical messages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OTC examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant creates a sales order; agent compares the IDoc/XML message with the historical SAP Integration Suite payload.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent highlights mapping differences at field level after configuration changes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="validate_EDI.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322535i531DC430CE0A96BA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="validate_EDI.png" alt="validate_EDI.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Figure – fetch an EDI payload produced by the integration platform (SAP Integration Suite, etc.) from a newly created business document and compare with the historical one from the production landscape without asking SAP Integration Consultant for help&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;P2P examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consultant enters a supplier invoice; agent pulls historical Ariba-CPI payload and checks consistency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent validates purchase order messages across production and test runs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-386280602"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why it matters for SAP S/4HANA projects&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In S/4HANA transformations, the external world doesn’t care about your internal redesigns. Customers, suppliers, and banks still expect exactly the same messages they used to get. Outbound and inbound interfaces are fragile bridges that must remain stable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By equipping functional consultants with Int4 Suite agents:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test cycles shorten dramatically.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reliance on external partners and scarce integration resources drops.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confidence in end-to-end quality rises.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This isn’t about replacing automation experts or integration teams. It’s about enabling functional consultants to independently confirm that what leaves SAP (or comes into it) is still what the outside world expects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s the missing puzzle piece for smooth, low-friction testing of integrated business processes in SAP transformations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-189767097"&gt;More information:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/agentic-ai-testing-for-greenfield-s-4hana-outbound-interfaces-part-1/ba-p/14232427" target="_blank"&gt;Agentic AI Testing for Greenfield S/4HANA Outbound Interfaces - Part 1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/int4-suite-your-sap-joule-testbed-and-skills-builder/ba-p/14229790" target="_blank"&gt;Int4 Suite — your SAP Joule testbed and skills builder&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/process-aware-agentic-testing-of-sap-with-int4-suite/ba-p/14196856" target="_blank"&gt;Process-Aware Agentic Testing of SAP with Int4 Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/agentic-testing-and-simulation-with-int4-suite-s-sap-business-knowledge/ba-p/14076453" target="_blank"&gt;Agentic Testing and Simulation with Int4 Suite's SAP Business Knowledge Graph&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/int4-suite-agents-empowers-functional-consultants-to-test-integrated-sap-s/ba-p/14234100"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T11:41:59.491000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-ai-adoption-with-btp-highlights/ba-p/14233554</id>
    <title>Driving AI Adoption with BTP: Highlights</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T12:10:01.619000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnaLoperaSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1790870</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AI Adoption Day 2025 - Banner website.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322334iAA3C41BC85A96CB6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AI Adoption Day 2025 - Banner website.jpg" alt="AI Adoption Day 2025 - Banner website.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A couple of days ago,&amp;nbsp; AI experts and SAP customers gathered at &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Adoption Event in Barcelona&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to explore how Artificial Intelligence is reshaping business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There we innovate with a fresh format designed to maximize both learning and practical engagement. The morning featured &lt;STRONG&gt;plenary&amp;nbsp;sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where SAP leaders and experts shared the latest insights on how AI is transforming business. In the afternoon, participants had the opportunity to go deeper—joining &lt;STRONG&gt;hands-on workshops and 1:1 discussions with dedicated SAP experts&lt;/STRONG&gt; to explore solutions tailored to their unique challenges.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The mix of high-level perspectives and practical deep dives created an environment where strategy met execution, ensuring that every attendee left not just inspired, but equipped with actionable next steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Why AI Now - and Why SAP?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI is no longer experimental—it’s driving real business outcomes. Organizations need AI to &lt;STRONG&gt;boost efficiency, turn data into actionable insights, and respond proactivel&lt;/STRONG&gt;y to changing business conditions. SAP’s Business AI helps companies act faster and smarter across every function.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP stands out because AI is &lt;STRONG&gt;embedded in core business processes,&lt;/STRONG&gt; powered by trusted, unified data, and designed for scalability and customization. This ensures reliable insights, faster decisions, and measurable impact at enterprise scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Why it matters?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI adoption today &lt;STRONG&gt;determines competitive advantage.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Companies that leverage AI effectively can accelerate growth, improve customer experiences, optimize operations, and achieve sustainability goals—while those that wait risk falling behind.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agenda Highlights &amp;amp; Session recap&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Welcome &amp;amp; Introduction &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speaker:&amp;nbsp;Marc Nolla&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set the stage with SAP’s strategic push on Artificial Intelligence&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Challenge: What AI competitive advantage are you going to Build&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="SAP AI Adoption - Intro &amp;amp; Welcome" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/nEwTRxp/Intro_Marc_-_AI_Adoption_Barcelona.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1243404" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Link to presentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exploring the Potential of SAP BTP AI&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speaker: Daniil Bolobonov &amp;amp; Marco Holzwarth&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explanation of our enterprise AI offering that integrates easily with your SAP systems (and also non-SAP!) to help you work smarter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Architecture perspective of Joule extensibility and AI Foundation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="SAP AI Adoption - Exploration phase" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/cyb3cJt/Potential_BTP_AI_BCN_.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1243408" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Link to presentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Best Practices with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speaker: Alex Dalentzas&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI Evolution since 2016&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Some learnings on how you can apply AI to your business processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Autonomous ERP: a real case scenario&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The relevance on an AI Architect&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="BTP AI Adoption - Best practices" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/oEvrzEN/BCN_AI_Adaption_Best_Practices.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1243193" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link to presentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP AI Portfolio and What's New&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Speaker: Arthur Liebhardt&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sneak peek on the lastest innovations on Joule&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule Agents as the next era of business automation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Live demo of Generative AI Hub and Vibe Coding&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="BTP AI Adoption - Product version" href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/9XZWXHC/AI_Adoption_Product_what_s_new.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1243406" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link to presentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Hands-On Workshops&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Four breakout room SAP BTP AI topics:&amp;nbsp;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Retrieval-Augmented Generation with SAP HANA&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Business Document proccessing with SAP Document AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From Automation to Intelligent Business Conversations with Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI capabilities in Data and Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Interaction with many customers and discussion on particular use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Opportunity to gain the digital badges for the hands-on&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The portal for hands-on will be open until 2nd October 2025 for you to finish the exercises&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For inquiries, please reach out to SAP BTP Adoption Workshop team: &lt;A href="mailto:sap_btp_adoption_workshop@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;sap_btp_adoption_workshop@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Closing Notes / Adoption and Next Steps&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;Speaker: Ana Lopera&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to engage with your BTP CSM and move forward&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP initiatives to support the AI and how can we help you to achieve it&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI is delivering real business value today&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trusted, business-ready AI is essential&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP’s differentiator is integration at scale&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collaboration accelerates innovation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Act now or risk falling behind&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1750205083" id="toc-hId-1890932068"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Next?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Here’s how to keep the momentum going:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Contact your SAP BTP Customer Success Manager&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":graduation_cap:"&gt;🎓&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Visit&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center Missions on BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/driving-ai-adoption-with-btp-highlights/ba-p/14233554"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T12:10:01.619000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-innovaci%C3%B3n-segura-automatizaci%C3%B3n-inteligente-y-futuro/ba-p/14235800</id>
    <title>🚀 SAP BTP Weekly | Innovación segura, automatización inteligente y futuro sostenible</title>
    <updated>2025-10-06T15:12:57.277000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FedericoTokman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150724</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="ember690" id="toc-hId-1890994374"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":shield:"&gt;🛡&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_1:"&gt;1️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Seguridad mejorada en BTP: rotación automática de claves y CAPTCHA ampliado&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; SAP anunció en su Q3 2025 mejoras clave en &lt;STRONG&gt;Security &amp;amp; Identity Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; Incluye &lt;STRONG&gt;rotación automática de claves de acceso&lt;/STRONG&gt;, nuevos &lt;STRONG&gt;logs de aprovisionamiento en tiempo real&lt;/STRONG&gt; y &lt;STRONG&gt;protección CAPTCHA&lt;/STRONG&gt; incluso para verificación telefónica. &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; También llegan &lt;STRONG&gt;comandos de consola&lt;/STRONG&gt; para certificados personalizados.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Análisis:&lt;/EM&gt; SAP sigue fortaleciendo la capa operativa de seguridad. La rotación automática reduce riesgos humanos, pero exige revisar integraciones para que las apps soporten las nuevas claves. Además, las APIs y logs abren la puerta a integraciones con SIEM corporativos.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":paperclip:"&gt;📎&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3 2025 Quarterly Release Highlights: SAP BTP Security &amp;amp; IAM&lt;/A&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":question_mark:"&gt;❓&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;¿Tus pipelines ya contemplan rotación automática de credenciales o siguen siendo manuales?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember694" id="toc-hId-1694480869"&gt;🧱 &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_2:"&gt;2️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Riesgos en arquitecturas híbridas: seguridad entre BTP y el core&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;El crecimiento de BTP en entornos híbridos trajo nuevos retos: &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":gear:"&gt;⚙️&lt;/span&gt; conexiones mal configuradas, &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bust_in_silhouette:"&gt;👤&lt;/span&gt; cuentas técnicas con privilegios excesivos, &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":police_car_light:"&gt;🚨&lt;/span&gt; y falta de monitoreo entre sistemas on-premise y cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Onapsis recomienda aplicar el &lt;STRONG&gt;principio de menor privilegio&lt;/STRONG&gt;, segmentar destinos y usar alertas de comportamiento anómalo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Análisis: &lt;/EM&gt;La promesa del híbrido es flexibilidad, pero también implica más puntos vulnerables. Cada destino en BTP es una posible puerta lateral si no se gestiona bien. La buena noticia: SAP ya integra alertas y trazabilidad más robustas; la mala, que muchas organizaciones aún no tienen visibilidad unificada de sus conexiones. Un gobierno efectivo requiere mapear todos los destinos, controlar privilegios y automatizar validaciones.Para el CIO, esto no es un problema técnico: es un riesgo reputacional si una brecha surge desde el entorno cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":paperclip:"&gt;📎&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://onapsis.com/blog/sap-btp-security-hybrid-architectures/?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Securing the Bridge – Onapsis&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember699" id="toc-hId-1497967364"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":graduation_cap:"&gt;🎓&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_3:"&gt;3️⃣&lt;/span&gt; SAP TechEd 2025: confianza, IA y estrategia BTP&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":round_pushpin:"&gt;📍&lt;/span&gt; Berlín y online | 4–6 noviembre Este año, SAP TechEd pone el foco en &lt;STRONG&gt;IA responsable, seguridad y automatización empresarial&lt;/STRONG&gt;. La pista &lt;EM&gt;“Building Trust on BTP”&lt;/EM&gt; mostrará cómo aplicar IA generativa con cumplimiento normativo, y habrá nuevas &lt;STRONG&gt;certificaciones en SAP Build y AI Developer&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Análisis: &lt;/EM&gt;TechEd siempre marca tendencias. Este año, SAP busca demostrar que IA y seguridad no son opuestos, sino complementarios. La idea de “trust by design” será central: usar IA generativa bajo marcos de control auditables. Para los arquitectos, esto significa que el BTP no solo será más inteligente, sino también más predecible. Y para los líderes de negocio, TechEd será el momento de evaluar cómo conectar Joule y Build con la realidad operativa.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":paperclip:"&gt;📎&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Agenda oficial SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember703" id="toc-hId-1301453859"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_4:"&gt;4️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Joule Studio y automatización inteligente&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule Studio&lt;/STRONG&gt; permite crear agentes de IA sin código directamente sobre &lt;STRONG&gt;Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Un CFO o analista puede describir en lenguaje natural un proceso, y Joule lo convierte en flujo automatizado. El reto: asegurar trazabilidad y control en automatizaciones generadas por usuarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Análisis: &lt;/EM&gt;Este paso cambia el juego: los procesos dejan de ser diseñados solo por TI. Con Joule Studio, áreas como Finanzas o RRHH pueden construir automatizaciones útiles en minutos. Sin embargo, el reto está en la &lt;STRONG&gt;gobernanza&lt;/STRONG&gt;: definir quién puede crear, auditar y modificar esos flujos. El CIO gana velocidad, pero debe mantener control. El equilibrio entre autonomía y seguridad definirá el éxito.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":paperclip:"&gt;📎&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/spain/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-studio.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Joule Studio&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember707" id="toc-hId-1104940354"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":recycling_symbol:"&gt;♻️&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_5:"&gt;5️⃣&lt;/span&gt; FinOps y sostenibilidad: control financiero y ambiental en una sola vista&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP refuerza su visión ESG con &lt;STRONG&gt;Sustainability Control Tower&lt;/STRONG&gt; y &lt;STRONG&gt;Green Ledger&lt;/STRONG&gt;, integradas con BTP y S/4HANA Cloud. CFOs y COOs pueden medir impacto ambiental junto al financiero, automatizando reportes ESG. Combinado con &lt;STRONG&gt;FinOps&lt;/STRONG&gt;, permite reducir gastos cloud y alinear sostenibilidad y rentabilidad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Análisis: &lt;/EM&gt;El control financiero y la sostenibilidad se vuelven inseparables. BTP permite que el impacto ambiental se mida con el mismo rigor que el financiero. Para el CFO, significa tener visibilidad completa de costos y emisiones. Para TI, implica integrar métricas ESG dentro de los procesos operativos. Este enfoque convierte la sostenibilidad en una ventaja competitiva, no en un “compliance más”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":paperclip:"&gt;📎&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/sustainability-control-tower.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sustainability Control Tower&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember711" id="toc-hId-908426849"&gt;🧩 &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_6:"&gt;6️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Extensibilidad guiada: el “wizard” que simplifica SAP Build y CAP&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;El nuevo &lt;STRONG&gt;Extensibility Wizard&lt;/STRONG&gt; ayuda a construir extensiones seguras para S/4HANA desde BTP, asegurando compatibilidad con upgrades y manteniendo el &lt;EM&gt;clean core&lt;/EM&gt;. Menos “custom code spaghetti”, más agilidad y trazabilidad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Análisis: &lt;/EM&gt;SAP da un paso firme hacia la estandarización de extensiones. El wizard facilita que incluso equipos sin experiencia profunda en ABAP construyan ampliaciones seguras y mantenibles. Esto acelera proyectos sin comprometer el core. El desafío: convencer a los equipos de desarrollo tradicionales de abandonar el “custom code” artesanal y adoptar un enfoque guiado, pero más sostenible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":paperclip:"&gt;📎&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/the-extensibility-wizard-one-tool-to-rule-them-all/ba-p/13901799" target="_self"&gt;Extensibility Wizard – Blog SAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember715" id="toc-hId-711913344"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_7:"&gt;7️⃣&lt;/span&gt; Joule + Microsoft Copilot: colaboración aumentada entre ecosistemas&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;La alianza SAP–Microsoft da un paso más: &lt;STRONG&gt;Joule se integra con Microsoft 365 Copilot&lt;/STRONG&gt;, permitiendo consultar y accionar datos SAP directamente desde Teams, Outlook o Excel. Ejemplo: “¿Cuál fue el gasto real del Q3?” — y Joule responde en segundos con datos de SAP Analytics Cloud. Una nueva forma de &lt;STRONG&gt;productividad aumentada&lt;/STRONG&gt;, donde BTP se convierte en el puente entre AI empresarial y colaboración diaria.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Análisis: &lt;/EM&gt;La frontera entre ERP y oficina se difumina. Con Joule + Copilot, un usuario puede consultar información crítica de SAP sin salir de Teams. Esto convierte la colaboración diaria en un entorno de decisión asistida por IA. Para los CIOs, implica una nueva prioridad: gobernar el acceso a datos sensibles que ahora fluyen por herramientas colaborativas. Una integración poderosa, pero que exige políticas sólidas de seguridad y contexto de uso.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":paperclip:"&gt;📎&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://news.sap.com/2023/05/sap-microsoft-joint-generative-ai-offerings-talent-gap/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP + Microsoft AI Partnership&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¿Qué equilibrio te resulta más desafiante hoy? &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Seguridad &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Velocidad &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Gobernanza&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Déjamelo en los comentarios — la transformación BTP la construimos entre todos &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-innovaci%C3%B3n-segura-automatizaci%C3%B3n-inteligente-y-futuro/ba-p/14235800"/>
    <published>2025-10-06T15:12:57.277000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/intelligent-natural-language-interaction-in-abap-uis-introducing-the-fpm/ba-p/14242346</id>
    <title>Intelligent Natural-Language Interaction in ABAP UIs — Introducing the FPM GenAI Service</title>
    <updated>2025-10-14T09:21:21.127000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simon_hoeg</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/194084</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the upcoming &lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP Platform 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA 2025 Private Cloud Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the new &lt;STRONG&gt;FPM GenAI Service&lt;/STRONG&gt; offers a new way to bring AI-powered interaction into classical FPM-based applications.&lt;BR /&gt;This service can be consumed via &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP credits&lt;/STRONG&gt; and is designed to seamlessly integrate &lt;STRONG&gt;large language models (LLMs)&lt;/STRONG&gt; into ABAP-based UIs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Floorplan Manager (FPM)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;UI Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt; provides an especially suitable foundation for this, thanks to its &lt;STRONG&gt;event-based control flow&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;stateful backend integration&lt;/STRONG&gt; — both essential for combining generative AI logic with transactional business processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762741128"&gt;What is the FPM GenAI Service?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The FPM GenAI Service enables developers to connect their FPM applications with LLMs in order to interpret &lt;STRONG&gt;natural-language user input&lt;/STRONG&gt; and transform it into application-specific operations at runtime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of navigating through the user interface in a traditional way, users can simply &lt;STRONG&gt;express their intent in natural language&lt;/STRONG&gt; — for example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Please create a new business partner for SAP Deutschland SE &amp;amp; Co. KG”&lt;BR /&gt;“Show all open invoices from last month”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The service interprets the user’s request and executes the corresponding FPM events in the backend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Users no longer need expert-level knowledge about the UI or data model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reduced number of manual UI steps — one prompt replaces multiple operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Improved accessibility for occasional or business users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Architecture Overview:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Architecture Overview of FPM GenAI Service" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328755i8FAFB3CF9BDA22A3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FPM_GenAI_Architecture.png" alt="Architecture Overview of FPM GenAI Service" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Architecture Overview of FPM GenAI Service&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566227623"&gt;Step-by-Step Integration Guide for Application Developers&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following steps outline how to enable AI-driven interaction in an existing FPM application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1498796837"&gt;1. Define AI Use Cases&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Collect all possible actions your application can perform that make sense for AI interaction.&lt;BR /&gt;Examples:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Create a new business partner”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Display all open sales orders for customer XYZ”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1302283332"&gt;2. Define Parameters&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each operation may require parameters such as NAME, ADDRESS or SALES_ORDER_ID.&lt;BR /&gt;Collect them and describe how they relate to the operation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105769827"&gt;3. Add Natural Language Descriptions&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide concise, meaningful text descriptions for both operations and parameters.&lt;BR /&gt;Keep them short and precise — the LLM will use these to interpret prompts accurately.&lt;BR /&gt;(English is recommended for maintainability.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-909256322"&gt;4. Integrate AI into the UI&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the current stage, you can integrate the AI trigger via a button in your FPM toolbar.&lt;BR /&gt;In the demo applications, this is done using a button with an &lt;STRONG&gt;AI icon&lt;/STRONG&gt; (sap-icon://ai), which opens the &lt;STRONG&gt;FPM Prompt RUIBB&lt;/STRONG&gt; (component FPM_AI_QUICK_PROMPT).&lt;BR /&gt;A deeper integration with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the Fiori Launchpad is planned for the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-712742817"&gt;5. Register Your Operations&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once your operations, parameters, and descriptions are ready, register them in the FPM GenAI Manager.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;DATA: ls_operations TYPE if_fpm_genai_manager=&amp;gt;ty_s_operation,
      lt_operations TYPE if_fpm_genai_manager=&amp;gt;ty_t_operation,
      ls_parameter  TYPE if_fpm_genai_manager=&amp;gt;ty_s_parameter.

ls_operations-event_id    = 'AI_CREATE_BP'.
ls_operations-description = 'create a new business partner (BP)'.
ls_parameter-name         = 'COMPANY_NAME'.
ls_parameter-description  = 'only the company name (without legal form)'.
APPEND ls_parameter TO ls_operations-parameters.
APPEND ls_operations TO lt_operations.

DATA(lo_fpm_genai_manager) = cl_fpm_factory=&amp;gt;get_instance( )-&amp;gt;get_genai_manager( ).
lo_fpm_genai_manager-&amp;gt;set_operations( lt_operations ).&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s recommended to register only those operations that are relevant to the current screen — this keeps prompts short and improves accuracy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-516229312"&gt;6. Execute the User Request&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When the user submits a prompt, obtain the GenAI Manager API and call:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;lo_fpm_genai_manager-&amp;gt;execute_user_request( ).&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-319715807"&gt;7. Process the FPM Event&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;After receiving the LLM response, the FPM GenAI Manager creates and raises FPM events.&lt;BR /&gt;Handle these events in your implementation of IF_FPM_UI_BUILDING_BLOCK, typically in the method PROCESS_EVENT( ).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-123202302"&gt;8. Handle Errors Gracefully&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use exception class CX_FPM_GENAI for error handling.&lt;BR /&gt;Possible cases include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;NO_USER_INPUT&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;USER_INPUT_ERROR&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;NO_OPERATIONS&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;GENAI_SDK_ERROR&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;FPM Message Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt; to communicate errors back to the user:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;DATA(lo_msg_manager) = cl_fpm_factory=&amp;gt;get_instance( )-&amp;gt;get_message_manager( ).
lo_msg_manager-&amp;gt;report_error( cx_fpm_genai=&amp;gt;get_text( ) ).&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That's everything for now &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt; Now, let's check out the first&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-144860435"&gt;Example: EPM Demo Application (S_EPM_UX_BP)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The EPM demo application (S_EPM_UX_BP) has been enhanced to showcase the new GenAI capabilities.&lt;BR /&gt;The scenario demonstrates how the AI assistant can help with tasks such as creating business partners, listing products, and generating sales orders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--345056077"&gt;Step 1 – Create a New Business Partner&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the result list toolbar, select the AI button (“New”) and enter one of the following prompts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Please add a new business partner in the role customer, name = SAP Deutschland SE &amp;amp; Co. KG, street = Hasso-Plattner-Ring 7, city = 69190 Walldorf.”&lt;BR /&gt;“Hi, we have a new customer: &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SE&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Deutschland.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Copy the details from their imprint page.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="example2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326724i86C8A01DD8090642/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="example2.png" alt="example2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each of these prompts triggers the creation of a new business partner in the “Customer” role.&lt;BR /&gt;The AI framework interprets both structured and casual prompts and even derives parameter values (e.g., currency from country).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="example3.png" style="width: 531px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326726iB1BB86EBDF5A2B2D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="example3.png" alt="example3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--541569582"&gt;Step 2 – Find Suitable Products&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, the user can ask for product recommendations:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Please compile a list of products that fit into the category laptops.”&lt;BR /&gt;“The customer wants laptops.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI assistant understands synonyms (“laptop” ↔ “notebook”) thanks to semantic enrichment in parameter definitions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="example4.png" style="width: 530px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326727iBCA0CC1A4CEF73DC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="example4.png" alt="example4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--738083087"&gt;Step 3 – Create a Sales Order&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, the user can create a sales order:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Please create a new sales order with each of the listed products.”&lt;BR /&gt;“Create a new SO, 10 items each, except the cheapest one.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI framework handles parameter logic and even comparative instructions (“except the cheapest one”).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="example5.png" style="width: 588px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327073i6AE8B8A4AD8D73A3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="example5.png" alt="example5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--641193585"&gt;Outlook and Further Resources&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In upcoming releases, tighter integration with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Fiori Launchpad&lt;/STRONG&gt; will further streamline the AI experience across the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more details, please refer to the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/9c91640bf34c49d8bad6bc560bedd707/8de5700bd13e49c39397372629f8c0f1.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help documentation.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You may also combine the new AI feature with the new FPM &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/9c91640bf34c49d8bad6bc560bedd707/1be8fedb42534f60aa0fae0a4a7d116a.html?version=202510.000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Camera&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ABAP_PLATFORM_NEW/9c91640bf34c49d8bad6bc560bedd707/b6870b7f4d2b4d0296dbd8b6ea9f5e0a.html?version=202510.000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Audio&lt;/A&gt; functionalities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks to our developers&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":red_heart:"&gt;❤️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;and I hope you like it&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/intelligent-natural-language-interaction-in-abap-uis-introducing-the-fpm/ba-p/14242346"/>
    <published>2025-10-14T09:21:21.127000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-cloud-application-programming-model-september-2025/ba-p/14242646</id>
    <title>What's new in SAP Cloud Application Programming Model – September 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-14T09:43:07.148000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BirgitS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/41902</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dear SAP Community,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m happy to announce that the September release of SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP) is available. It’s packed with many great new features! &lt;SPAN&gt;This blog post highlights some of the new features&lt;/SPAN&gt;. It presents a range of exciting new capabilities, such as the new MCP servers or the integration with Application Frontend service. In addition, we collected &lt;SPAN&gt;some informative blog posts delving into various aspects of CAP and give you an overview on upcoming events.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check out the details of what's new!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling Agentic Development with MCP Servers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/docs/getting-started/intro" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Model Context Protocol (MCP)&lt;/A&gt; is an open standard&amp;nbsp;that bridges the gap between large language models (LLMs) and external resources such as services, tools, data, and workflows, so models can fetch context, take actions, and deliver more accurate results. MCP is already supported by clients such as Claude, Cline, Cursor, and VS Code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Beginning of September, SAP introduced MCP servers for &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/boost-your-cap-development-with-ai-introducing-the-mcp-server-for-cap/ba-p/14202849" target="_blank"&gt;CAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-tools-update-first-release-of-the-sap-fiori-mcp-server-for/ba-p/14204694" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Fiori elements&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, and &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/give-your-ai-agent-some-tools-introducing-the-ui5-mcp-server/ba-p/14200825" target="_blank"&gt;SAPUI5&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. These MCP servers are designed specifically for building enterprise-grade SAP business applications taking into account proven best practices and providing recommendations tailored to SAP Business Technology Platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="BirgitS_0-1760368014256.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326856i59D5FACBBE59F6FD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BirgitS_0-1760368014256.png" alt="BirgitS_0-1760368014256.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Welcome to cap-js/mcp-server&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further information, I highly recommend you to read this blog post: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introduces-new-mcp-servers-to-enable-agentic-development-for/ba-p/14205602" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Build introduces new MCP Servers to enable agentic development for Enterprise Applications&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Easily Integrate with Application Frontend Service &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/application-frontend-service" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Application Frontend service&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; is a SaaS application on SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), which serves as a single entry point for hosting, serving and operating frontend applications. It is part of SAP Build, SAP’s unified solution for application development and process automation. By consolidating all aspects of UI application management under one managed service, Application Frontend service simplifies the development experience and enhances custom application operations. For an introduction to Application Frontend service, please read &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-application-frontend-service/ba-p/14091408" target="_blank"&gt;this blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With our latest CAP release it is now possible to &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/releases/sep25#cds-add-app-frontend" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;easily integrate the Application Frontend service&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. All you have to do is use the command &lt;EM&gt;cds add app-frontend&lt;/EM&gt;. This adds all the needed configuration to your project providing you access to Application Frontend’s cool features. No additional work for you to do!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note: The support for this service is currently limited to single-tenant applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration with SAP Integration Suite, Advanced Event Mesh now Generally Available &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite/advanced-event-mesh.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Integration Suite, advanced event mesh&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;enables real-time, asynchronous communication. It works across hybrid, multi-cloud, and edge environments. The advanced event mesh integrates SAP and non-SAP systems into your event-driven architecture and allows you to form meshes of event brokers. You can publish and subscribe to business events from all kinds of SAP and non-SAP event sources. As a result, event-driven architecture and advanced event mesh keep systems and users up to date when critical changes occur. Advanced event mesh allows to manage, monitor, and visualize decentralized event streaming across your landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In May, we released the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/releases/archive/2025/may25#aem" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;beta version of our integration with advanced event mesh&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. After a successful test and evaluation phase, we are now happy to tell you that both open-source plugins (for Node.js and for Java) are now&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/releases/sep25#sap-integration-suite-advanced-event-mesh-ga" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;generally available&lt;/A&gt; (GA). The GA release comes with a notable addition: the support for cross-subaccount broker validation, allowing you to share advanced event mesh instances between multiple subaccounts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additional details can be found&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/plugins/#advanced-event-mesh" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Translated Error Messages in CAP Node.js&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For a better user experience, error messages that appear on the UI should be translated into the same language as the rest of their application. Therefore, &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/releases/sep25#translated-error-messages" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CAP Node.js delivers translations for annotation-based input validations&lt;/A&gt; out of the box in all CAP-supported languages. For a list of the messages that are currently translated, see the &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/node.js/events#translations-for-validation-errors" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="BirgitS_1-1760368014280.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326857i7EC4C47075310316/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BirgitS_1-1760368014280.png" alt="BirgitS_1-1760368014280.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Screenshot: Translation of error codes to German language&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more about error handling in Node.js, please read the following &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/node.js/events#req-reject" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;section in the documentation&lt;/A&gt;. For additional information about internationalization in Node.js, check out &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/node.js/cds-i18n" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;this section&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For those of you, who use CAP Java: translated error messages are also &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/releases/archive/2025/jan25#default-runtime-messages-bundle" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;supported there&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. Please look at the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/java/event-handlers/indicating-errors#messages" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, to gain further insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further Readings &amp;amp; Events&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Avoiding Data Loss When Loading Initial Data with CSV Files in CAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using CSV files to load initial data or sample data is convenient but you must be careful when deploying data to SAP S/4HANA Cloud as you might risk losing data. In his blog post&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/avoiding-data-loss-when-loading-initial-data-with-csv-files-in-cap/ba-p/14215172" target="_blank"&gt;Avoiding Data Loss When Loading Initial Data with CSV Files in CAP,&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; SAP Champion Mio Yasutake explains alternative approaches how to avoid data loss.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Providing Feedback on CAP Documentation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your feedback is crucial for us to improve. Thus, we would like to ask you to share your feedback on our CAP documentation. There are many ways to provide us your feedback. In his blog post&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/multiple-ways-to-give-feedback-on-cap-documentation/ba-p/14199559" target="_blank"&gt;Multiple Ways to Give Feedback on CAP Documentation&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;my colleague Rene guides you through the different options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model Customer Roundtable &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next CAP Customer Roundtable is just around the corner. If you are interested in an overview of the recent features, demos, presentations and questions raised by the CAP community, mark your calendar for October 15th, 2025, 11 AM EST | 5 PM CE(S)T. Find further details (including the agenda and dial in data) &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-application-programming-model-cap-customer-roundtable-october/ba-p/14222428?emcs_t=S2h8ZW1haWx8dG9waWNfc3Vic2NyaXB0aW9ufE1GWFNRMFVIVjRFMUwxfDE0MjIyNDI4fFNVQlNDUklQVElPTlN8aEs" target="_blank"&gt;in this blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Devtoberfest 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/gh-p/Devtoberfest" target="_blank"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; already started. In 2025, the event is taking place from September 29th until October 24th. But you can still consume the content. Devtoberfest is a virtual event giving SAP developers a great opportunity to get ready for SAP TechEd. It is packed with enablement sessions around topics in the area of CAP, ABAP, Tooling and Frontend, Integration, Data and AI, combined with a lot of fun. For further information, read the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-welcome/ba-p/14182817" target="_blank"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 Welcome!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; blog post and join &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/gh-p/Devtoberfest?sap-outbound-id=C5C40C877E97CD6101872ADE15DCDDA2A45F79F2" target="_blank"&gt;the Devtoberfest group&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; in SAP Community to take part in this great event!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From November 4–6, 2025 &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; takes place providing you the opportunity to learn about the latest innovations and advancements in SAP technologies and to connect with the community. In 2025, SAP TechEd will be a hybrid event combining the best of both worlds: the in-person event in Berlin and the virtual event. Both events are taking place in parallel. Make sure to save the date and register now for &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Berlin&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;virtual&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The session catalogs for the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;in-person&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;virtual&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; event are now live, featuring a wide range of topics across various tracks, where you'll find many sessions on the SAP Cloud Application Programming Model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further information on new features, please have a look at the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/releases/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model Release Notes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. If you want to stay up-to-date with news, learning resources, and product and strategy updates for CAP:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;follow our&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Cloud+Application+Programming+Model/pd-p/9f13aee1-834c-4105-8e43-ee442775e5ce" target="_blank"&gt;tag&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;in the SAP Community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We look forward to seeing how you use these new capabilities to create innovative solutions and drive your projects forward. Stay tuned for more updates and happy coding! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-cloud-application-programming-model-september-2025/ba-p/14242646"/>
    <published>2025-10-14T09:43:07.148000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-hana-ml-in-porto-2025-09-recap/ba-p/14243214</id>
    <title>SAP CodeJam HANA ML in Porto 2025-09 Recap</title>
    <updated>2025-10-14T14:35:01.823000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vitaliy-R</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At the end of September, we held an SAP CodeJam event in Vila Nova de Gaia, Portugal. The event focused on exploring the foundations of &lt;STRONG&gt;AI applications with the SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Vector Engine and Knowledge Graph Engine.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="1759244464907s.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327110iCD4CB9E60043D716/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1759244464907s.png" alt="1759244464907s.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks to the local host and organizers:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1399953"&gt;@MatheusBrasil&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140615"&gt;@MRobalinho&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the rest of the team...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="1759244464087s.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327290iE479ADBDF99FFA1A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1759244464087s.png" alt="1759244464087s.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;...and participants!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="1759320697575s.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327301i5A5E02C7955ADA0D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1759320697575s.png" alt="1759320697575s.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="1759244459990s.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327309i99FA67503DD52898/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1759244459990s.png" alt="1759244459990s.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="1759244462099s.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327308iF42799CA81DC8A9A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1759244462099s.png" alt="1759244462099s.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It was great to have my teammate and fellow developer advocate&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/53"&gt;@qmacro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;joining us...&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;not only during the lunch break &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":fish:"&gt;🐟&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="PXL_20250926_125614277.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327291i6E40105A1DE96A38/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PXL_20250926_125614277.jpg" alt="PXL_20250926_125614277.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CodeJam in Porto was the day before the very first SAP Inside Track there, so it was great to share a drink during a Stammtisch after the CodeJam...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Image0s.png" style="width: 762px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327292i4DEE7B74AE9F0260/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Image0s.png" alt="Image0s.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;The following day, I had a chance to present the long story of LLM auto completion to AI agents—we went in just three years! And invited everyone to join SAP TechEd to watch our Developer Keynote.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Image5s.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327306i20E83ED820F72DE0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Image5s.png" alt="Image5s.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;November is going to be an intensive month with SAP TechEd on Tour in &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Berlin&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://events.masteringsap.com/sydney2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sydney&lt;/A&gt;, and &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/apj-savethedatetechedontourbangalore2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bengaluru&lt;/A&gt;, followed by SAP CodeJams in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-melbourne-australia/ev-p/14233023" target="_blank"&gt;Melbourne&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/getting-started-with-generative-ai-hub-on-sap-ai-core-singapore/ev-p/14233018" target="_self"&gt;Singapore&lt;/A&gt;, and the Middle East.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I always take the opportunity to experience at least a little bit of the city I am in, so you can see my photos:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DPyfRcMDKko/?img_index=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/p/DPyfRcMDKko/?img_index=1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Would you like to host such an SAP CodeJam?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-hana-ml-in-porto-2025-09-recap/ba-p/14243214"/>
    <published>2025-10-14T14:35:01.823000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-blog-posts/sap-for-energy-amp-utilities-conference-workshops-now-live/ba-p/14242458</id>
    <title>SAP for Energy &amp; Utilities Conference – Workshops Now Live</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T09:18:54.158000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/126997</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Utilities Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://tac-insights.com/events/sap-for-energy-and-utilities-conference" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP for Energy and Utilities Conference&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, taking place &lt;STRONG&gt;April 21–23, 2026&lt;/STRONG&gt; in &lt;STRONG&gt;Toulouse, France&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&amp;nbsp; a city recently named &lt;EM&gt;#1 destination to visit in 2025&lt;/EM&gt; by Lonely Planet. Hosted at &lt;STRONG&gt;The MEETT&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a state-of-the-art convention center, this event promises to be a transformative experience for professionals across the energy and utilities sector.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This year’s theme, &lt;EM&gt;“Connecting Minds. Powering the Future,”&lt;/EM&gt; reflects the conference’s focus on innovation, AI, asset management, distributed energy resources,&amp;nbsp;sustainability, and customer experience. Whether you're an SAP customer, prospect, partner, or industry leader, this is your opportunity to gain insights, share your story, and shape the future of energy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762742122"&gt;Workshops Are Now Live!&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 2026 conference agenda is still evolving, but registration is already open, and workshop seats are limited! These interactive sessions offer a deep dive into the most critical challenges and key in the energy and utilities sector. Below are the confirmed workshops:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Utilities Focus – Powering the Future: The Next Era of Utilities with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Future of Energy Supply and Distributed Energy Resources&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Connected Utility with SAP Customer Experience: Omnichannel Journey Transformation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Asset Management in Energy and Utilities&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Energising the Industry: SAP's Oil, Gas &amp;amp; Energy Solution Portfolio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each workshop includes expert-led discussions, real-world case studies, and interactive Q&amp;amp;A sessions. You’ll walk away with actionable insights and practical tools to drive transformation in your organisation,&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;how to apply AI and BDC effectively, while strengthening your understanding of SAP’s service portfolio, fully equipped to turn knowledge into measurable results.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566228617"&gt;Why Attend?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network&lt;/STRONG&gt; with SAP experts, industry pioneers, and peers from around the globe.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learn&lt;/STRONG&gt; from immersive experiences like the SAP Pop-up Campus and deep-dive sessions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Empower&lt;/STRONG&gt; your team with knowledge on the latest SAP innovations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1369715112"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":admission_tickets:"&gt;🎟&lt;/span&gt;️ Early Bird Offer&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Secure your spot now with the &lt;STRONG&gt;advance access rate of €999&lt;/STRONG&gt; (standard price €1,599) – available for customers until &lt;STRONG&gt;October 31, 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read more and register&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://tac-insights.com/events/sap-for-energy-and-utilities-conference" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="SAP EUC" href="https://tac-insights.com/events/sap-for-energy-and-utilities-conference/agenda" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="EUC 2026 Banner 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327060iA3AD7E5DD7203324/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="EUC 2026 Banner 2.png" alt="EUC 2026 Banner 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-blog-posts/sap-for-energy-amp-utilities-conference-workshops-now-live/ba-p/14242458"/>
    <published>2025-10-15T09:18:54.158000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/self-refining-prompts-for-a-better-customer-experience/ba-p/14245356</id>
    <title>Self Refining Prompts for a better Customer Experience</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T08:50:03.203000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>santhosini_K</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/138505</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Teaching AI applications to Self-Critique&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Experiments with Self-Refining prompts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Most of us treat a prompt like a one-shot instruction. You ask, the model answers, and… that’s it. But in practice, good work is iterative: we write a draft, critique it, and then refine. &lt;STRONG&gt;Self-Refine&lt;/STRONG&gt; applies that same loop to AI — the model acts as &lt;STRONG&gt;writer&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;critic&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;editor&lt;/STRONG&gt; in quick succession until the result feels right.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;In this post, I’ll share what clicked for me, a simple three-step pattern, and a few mini-experiments you can try (and screenshot) to see the lift for yourself.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The 3-Step Loop (that changed how I prompt)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1) Generate&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Ask for the initial output.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2) Feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Ask the model to critique its own output with specific, actionable notes.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3) Refine&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Tell it to rewrite using only that feedback.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Repeat until it says, “no further refinement.”&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;This is simple. The magic is in &lt;STRONG&gt;good feedback prompts&lt;/STRONG&gt; (“point out tone, missing details, structure” vs. vague “improve it”).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How it works (in 10 seconds)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generate:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Draft the answer&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Critique:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The model reviews itself (JSON feedback + score)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Refine: &lt;/STRONG&gt;It rewrites using that feedback&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stop:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;when the score plateaus or hits your bar&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Task-specific effectiveness: Self-refinement works better for some task types (code generation, technical documentation) than others (creative writing). Measures vary for each task category.​&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mini-Experiments&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Building a self-improving web search Agent&lt;/FONT&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Building a Web Search Agent with Self-Improving Prompts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The foundation combines SAP AI Core's Generative AI Hub with LangChain's Google Search wrapper:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;```python
# SAP AI Core client setup
ai_core_client = AICoreV2Client(
    base_url=BASE_URL, auth_url=AUTH_URL,
    client_id=CLIENT_ID, client_secret=CLIENT_SECRET,
)
llm = init_llm(MODEL_NAME, temperature=0.0, max_tokens=512)

# Google Search integration
search = GoogleSearchAPIWrapper(k=5)
google_tool = Tool.from_function(
    name="google_search",
    description="Search Google and return the first results",
    func=search.run
)
agent = initialize_agent(tools=[google_tool], llm=llm, agent=AgentType.OPENAI_FUNCTIONS)

#This gives us both a base LLM and an agent that can search the web when needed.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Three-Prompt Pattern&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The self-refinement uses three distinct prompts with clear roles:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generator Prompt&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Creates initial draft without second-guessing&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;GEN_PROMPT = """You are a careful, precise assistant.
TASK: {task}
Produce the best possible answer. Do not include any self-critique here."""
```&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Critic Prompt&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Evaluates with structured feedback&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;CRITIC_PROMPT = """You are a meticulous reviewer. Given the TASK and the DRAFT answer,
1) list EXACTLY 3 concrete issues or improvement opportunities,
2) give a numbered improvement plan,
3) rate current quality from 0–100,
4) decide if refinement is still needed.

Respond with a SINGLE JSON object and NOTHING ELSE:
{{"issues": ["...", "...", "..."], "plan": ["step 1", "step 2", "step 3"], "score": 0, "stop": false}}"""
```&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Refiner Prompt&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Applies improvements systematically&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;REFINE_PROMPT = """You are a senior editor. Apply the plan below to improve the DRAFT.
Keep all correct content; fix issues; increase clarity, correctness, and usefulness.
Return ONLY the improved answer (no commentary)."""```&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The key is separating generation from critique to avoid the model sabotaging its own initial work.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Self-Refine Loop&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def self_refine(
    task: str,
    max_iters: int = 3,
    min_delta: int = 2,
    use_agent_for_initial: bool = False
) -&amp;gt; Dict[str, Any]:
    """
    Self-refine loop: GENERATE -&amp;gt; CRITIQUE -&amp;gt; REFINE until stop or plateau.
    Returns final answer and iteration history.
    """
    history: List[Dict[str, Any]] = []

    # 1) Initial draft
    draft = call_llm_text(GEN_PROMPT.format(task=task), use_agent=use_agent_for_initial)
    history.append({"iteration": 0, "draft": draft, "score": None, "feedback": None})

    best = draft
    best_score = -math.inf

    for i in range(1, max_iters + 1):
        # 2) Critique
        critic_raw = call_llm_text(CRITIC_PROMPT.format(task=task, draft=draft))
        critic = extract_json_block(critic_raw)

        # Safety coerce
        issues = critic.get("issues", [])[:3]
        plan = critic.get("plan", [])
        score = int(critic.get("score", 50))
        stop_flag = bool(critic.get("stop", False))

        history.append({
            "iteration": i,
            "draft": draft,
            "score": score,
            "feedback": {"issues": issues, "plan": plan, "raw": critic_raw}
        })

        # Plateau / stop condition
        if stop_flag and i &amp;gt; 1:
            break
        if best_score != -math.inf and (score - best_score) &amp;lt; min_delta and i &amp;gt; 1:
            # No meaningful improvement
            break

        # Track best
        if score &amp;gt; best_score:
            best = draft
            best_score = score

        # 3) Refine
        plan_str = "\n".join(f"- {p}" for p in plan) if plan else "- Improve clarity and correctness."
        refined = call_llm_text(REFINE_PROMPT.format(task=task, draft=draft, plan=plan_str))
        draft = refined

    # Final scoring pass to attach a last score
    final_critic_raw = call_llm_text(CRITIC_PROMPT.format(task=task, draft=draft))
    final_critic = extract_json_block(final_critic_raw) or {"score": best_score if best_score != -math.inf else None}
    final_score = int(final_critic.get("score", best_score if best_score != -math.inf else 0))

    return {
        "task": task,
        "final": draft,
        "final_score": final_score,
        "history": history,
        "final_critic_raw": final_critic_raw
    }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Usage Example&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;# runner + example usage
def run_task_self_refine(
    task: str,
    max_iters: int = 3,
    min_delta: int = 2,
    use_agent_for_initial: bool = False,
    verbose: bool = True
) -&amp;gt; Dict[str, Any]:
    result = self_refine(
        task=task,
        max_iters=max_iters,
        min_delta=min_delta,
        use_agent_for_initial=use_agent_for_initial
    )
    if verbose:
        for rec in result["history"]:
            it = rec["iteration"]
            pretty_print_blocks(f"Iteration {it} — Draft", rec["draft"])
            if rec["feedback"]:
                fb = rec["feedback"]
                pretty_print_blocks(f"Iteration {it} — Feedback (score={rec['score']})", json.dumps({
                    "issues": fb["issues"],
                    "plan": fb["plan"]
                }, indent=2))
        pretty_print_blocks(f"FINAL (score={result['final_score']})", result["final"])
    return result

# Example task (swap in anything you like)
Search_Query = "How to integrate SAP Shopping Assistant with SAP Commerce Cloud?"

result = run_task_self_refine(
    Search_Query, 
    max_iters=3, 
    min_delta=2, 
    use_agent_for_initial=True  # Use web search for initial draft
)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Setting &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;`use_agent_for_initial=True`&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; leverages the Google Search agent for the first draft when current information might be needed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Using LLM, I compared all three outputs I got. Here is the result&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;TABLE width="905"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.385px" height="30px"&gt;Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="115.438px" height="30px"&gt;Iteration 0&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="177.76px" height="30px"&gt;Iteration 1 (Feedback)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150.885px" height="30px"&gt;Iteration 2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="170.979px" height="30px"&gt;Iteration 2 (Feedback)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="175.885px" height="30px"&gt;FINAL&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.385px" height="57px"&gt;UI Navigation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="115.438px" height="57px"&gt;Generic&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="177.76px" height="57px"&gt;Ask for detailed paths&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150.885px" height="57px"&gt;Adds named tabs/panels&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="170.979px" height="57px"&gt;Request more explicit steps&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="175.885px" height="57px"&gt;Clear, step-by-step paths&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.385px" height="57px"&gt;Performance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="115.438px" height="57px"&gt;Separate checklist&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="177.76px" height="57px"&gt;Ask to integrate in steps&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150.885px" height="57px"&gt;Still separate&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="170.979px" height="57px"&gt;Ask for actionable guidance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="175.885px" height="57px"&gt;Embedded, actionable tips&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.385px" height="57px"&gt;Validation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="115.438px" height="57px"&gt;Brief &amp;amp; vague&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="177.76px" height="57px"&gt;Ask to expand per component&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150.885px" height="57px"&gt;Incomplete&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="170.979px" height="57px"&gt;Ask for full, concrete checks&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="175.885px" height="57px"&gt;10 concrete, testable checks&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.385px" height="30px"&gt;Pitfalls&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="115.438px" height="30px"&gt;Short list&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="177.76px" height="30px"&gt;—&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150.885px" height="30px"&gt;Same&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="170.979px" height="30px"&gt;Ask for fixes&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="175.885px" height="30px"&gt;Pitfalls paired with fixes&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="113.385px" height="57px"&gt;Completeness&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="115.438px" height="57px"&gt;OK&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="177.76px" height="57px"&gt;—&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="150.885px" height="57px"&gt;Cuts off&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="170.979px" height="57px"&gt;Ask to finish&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="175.885px" height="57px"&gt;Complete &amp;amp; ready to run&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-Quality Improvement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Typical 15-25 point score increases over 2-3 iterations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-Cost Control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Plateau detection prevents wasteful refinement cycles&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-Flexibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Can use plain LLM or web-search agent based on task needs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;-Transparency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Full iteration history shows the improvement process&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Quality Improvement Analysis ( So far, the best score that I achieved)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Score Progress&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Iteration 0:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;45/100&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Basic initial draft&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Iteration 1:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;68/100&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;+23 Points improvement&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Iteration 2:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;87/100&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;+19 Points improvement&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Total Improvement&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;EM&gt;+42 points (93.3% increase)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&amp;nbsp;The Answers t&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ransformed from vague steps to specific, executable instructions&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The simulation shows the typical self-refinement pattern where the biggest jump occurs in iteration 1 (+23 points), with diminishing but still valuable returns in iteration 2 (+19 points).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;But here's the reality check:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;This represents a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;best-case scenario&lt;/EM&gt;. During my experiments, I also encountered:&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Complete refinement failures&amp;nbsp;where systems produced identical content across iterations despite clear feedback,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Content truncation issues&amp;nbsp;where later iterations became incomplete, cutting off mid-sentence,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Score plateaus&amp;nbsp;where quality metrics stayed flat (75/100) even after visible improvements&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The approach works especially well for tasks requiring accuracy and completeness, like coding, technical procedures, troubleshooting guides, and detailed explanations, where initial drafts often miss important details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Examples and Analysis" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1vg26RnqWbOhvMRA_al33EV_smCampcMdiJnvAFyOYSE/edit?usp=sharing" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Self Improving Prompts - Example&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; -- This was the most common behavior&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What surprised me&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;The biggest gains come in the &lt;STRONG&gt;first 1–2 rounds&lt;/STRONG&gt;. After that, returns fade.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Weak models can struggle to give good feedback. Strong instruction-following models do best. [ I call them the most obedient models:-)]&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;If feedback is vague, the rewrite is useless. If feedback is &lt;STRONG&gt;dimensioned and specific&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the quality of the output excels.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to use Self-Refine in a Customer Support Chatbot&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Self-Refine is perfect for support bots because real customers are often vague (“my order didn’t arrive,” “can’t login”).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goals&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clarify fast&lt;/STRONG&gt; when the query is vague and has very less details.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ground answers&lt;/STRONG&gt; in your KB/CRM (no hallucinations).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Converge&lt;/STRONG&gt; in 1–2 refinement rounds to keep latency low.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Escalate&lt;/STRONG&gt; cleanly when confidence stays low.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;How can we model this?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328159i7431DEA983AAC9A9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture3.png" alt="Picture3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture2.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328171i26736CB11E7E0378/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Picture2.png" alt="Picture2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TLDR for practitioners&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Treat prompts like drafts. Ask the model to &lt;STRONG&gt;critique with structure&lt;/STRONG&gt;, then &lt;STRONG&gt;refine under constraints&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Screenshot the three steps (Generate → Feedback → Refine) to make the improvement visible. Once you see it, it’s hard to go back to one-shot prompting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Self-refinement works better for some task types (code generation, technical documentation) than others (creative writing).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cost vs. quality tradeoff: Calculate the token cost per quality point gained. For some applications, a single well-crafted prompt may be more cost-effective than multiple iteration refinements.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bottom line:&lt;/STRONG&gt; self-refining prompts make your bot think twice—so customers don’t have to ask twice.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/self-refining-prompts-for-a-better-customer-experience/ba-p/14245356"/>
    <published>2025-10-16T08:50:03.203000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-blog-posts/brazil-as-one-of-the-leading-hubs-for-artificial-intelligence-2024-2025/ba-p/14248521</id>
    <title>Brazil as One of the Leading Hubs for Artificial Intelligence (2024–2025)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T13:14:18.683000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MRobalinho</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140615</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Over the past two years, Brazil has established itself as one of the main &lt;STRONG&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI)&lt;/STRONG&gt; hubs globally, standing out for its combination of &lt;STRONG&gt;public investments&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;expanding business ecosystem&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;regulatory progress&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Traditionally a leader in innovation and technology in Latin America, Brazil is now attracting international attention by accelerating the adoption of AI across strategic sectors such as finance, energy, agribusiness, and public services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In 2024, the Brazilian government launched the &lt;STRONG&gt;Brazilian Artificial Intelligence Plan (PBIA) 2024–2028&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a program with an estimated investment of &lt;STRONG&gt;R$ 23 billion&lt;/STRONG&gt; dedicated to AI research, development, and infrastructure. The plan aims to strengthen technological sovereignty, foster innovation through universities, and support companies in applying AI to practical use cases, particularly in areas of public interest.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The Main pillars of the PBIA 2024–2028 are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Expansion of &lt;STRONG&gt;AI research&lt;/STRONG&gt; and innovation centers;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tax incentives&lt;/STRONG&gt; for startups and public–private partnerships;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Training&lt;/STRONG&gt; and qualification of AI professionals;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementation of &lt;STRONG&gt;AI in public service&lt;/STRONG&gt;s (health, security, education).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This initiative positions Brazil as a &lt;STRONG&gt;regional leader in AI policy&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ahead of countries like Mexico, Chile, and Argentina.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Brazil’s private sector is undergoing a phase of &lt;STRONG&gt;rapid AI adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;. By 2025, a national survey identified &lt;STRONG&gt;396 Brazilian AI companies&lt;/STRONG&gt; focused on marketing applications, reflecting diversification across &lt;STRONG&gt;generative AI, automation, analytics, and digital services&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;According to a &lt;STRONG&gt;Bain &amp;amp; Company (2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt; study, &lt;STRONG&gt;67% of Brazilian companies&lt;/STRONG&gt; now consider AI a &lt;STRONG&gt;strategic priority&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a major leap from 2024, when only about 12% had active projects. This demonstrates the transition from experimental use to &lt;STRONG&gt;mature, production-level adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Brazil received international investments and technological infrastructure. That's why Brazil’s consolidation as an AI hub also stems from the confidence of major global players. In September 2024, &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft&lt;/STRONG&gt; announced a &lt;STRONG&gt;US$ 2.7 billion investment&lt;/STRONG&gt; in &lt;STRONG&gt;cloud and AI infrastructure&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Brazil, one of the largest technology investments in Latin American history. In 2025, &lt;STRONG&gt;Eletrobras&lt;/STRONG&gt; partnered with &lt;STRONG&gt;C3 AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; to modernize Brazil’s power grid using AI and machine learning, highlighting the industrial applications of advanced technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;These moves strengthen Brazil’s position as a &lt;STRONG&gt;regional hub for data and high-performance computing&lt;/STRONG&gt;, essential for scaling generative AI and automation initiatives.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Despite major progress, Brazil still faces structural challenges. A &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Brazil (March 2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt; survey revealed that:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;29%&lt;/STRONG&gt; of companies lack clarity on how to integrate AI into their business systems;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;28%&lt;/STRONG&gt; cite a &lt;STRONG&gt;shortage of skilled professionals&lt;/STRONG&gt; as the main obstacle.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;On the regulatory front, Brazil has emerged as a key player. In 2024, the &lt;STRONG&gt;National Data Protection Authority (ANPD)&lt;/STRONG&gt; suspended &lt;STRONG&gt;Meta Platforms’&lt;/STRONG&gt; privacy policy, which used Brazilians’ personal data to train generative AI models. This decision marked an important milestone in &lt;STRONG&gt;ethical governance and digital sovereignty&lt;/STRONG&gt;, aligning Brazil with European-style data protection principles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The main sectors driving AI growth in Brazil include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance and digital payments:&lt;/STRONG&gt; automation and predictive analytics;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Energy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; smart grids and real-time system optimization;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agribusiness:&lt;/STRONG&gt; crop forecasting and climate analytics;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Healthcare:&lt;/STRONG&gt; assisted diagnostics and telemedicine;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Public administration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; chatbots and natural language processing for citizen services.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;These industries attract investments from both &lt;STRONG&gt;large corporations&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;local startups&lt;/STRONG&gt;, making Brazil a fertile ground for experimentation and innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;About the Outlook for 2025 and Beyond the trends indicate continued expansion of generative AI and process automation in Brazilian companies. &lt;STRONG&gt;By the end of 202&lt;/STRONG&gt;5, it is expected that:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Over &lt;STRONG&gt;60% of corporate AI solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Brazil will involve generative models;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The country will consolidate &lt;STRONG&gt;international research and training partnerships&lt;/STRONG&gt;;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;General Artificial Intelligence Law&lt;/STRONG&gt; (under discussion in Congress) will advance the national governance framework.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;With growing public and private investments, Brazil is on track to become a &lt;STRONG&gt;Latin American reference in AI innovation and ethics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, combining &lt;STRONG&gt;economic growth&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;responsible technological governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The 2024–2025 period marks a &lt;STRONG&gt;strategic turning point&lt;/STRONG&gt; for AI in Brazil, shifting from an emerging topic to a &lt;STRONG&gt;core pillar of industrial and business competitiveness&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The alignment between &lt;STRONG&gt;government vision&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;international investments&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;technological maturity&lt;/STRONG&gt; positions Brazil as &lt;STRONG&gt;one of the leading AI hubs in the Southern Hemisphere&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with the potential to export technology, talent, and regulatory best practices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;At &lt;A class="" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/make-value-s-a/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;MakeValue&lt;/A&gt;, we develop &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered applications for SAP Finance&lt;/STRONG&gt;, focused on enhancing financial visibility and decision-making. Our &lt;STRONG&gt;Cash Flow Intelligence App&lt;/STRONG&gt; leverages data from &lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain, Sales, Treasury, Accounts Receivable, Accounts Payable, and real-time Bank Balances&lt;/STRONG&gt; to deliver accurate forecasting and scenario simulation, ensuring that financial teams have a clear, data-driven view of their company’s liquidity at any time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Is your company already exploring AI implementation projects? &lt;/STRONG&gt;In which &lt;STRONG&gt;sectors or business processes&lt;/STRONG&gt; are you seeing the greatest potential for transformation?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember228" id="toc-hId-1892004448"&gt;References&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reuters: &lt;A class="" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/microsoft-make-27-billion-cloud-ai-investments-brazil-2024-09-26/?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Microsoft to invest $2.7 billion in Brazil&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reuters: &lt;A class="" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/brazil-proposes-4-billion-ai-investment-plan-2024-07-30/?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Brazil proposes $4 billion AI investment plan&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP News Brazil (2025): &lt;EM&gt;Brazil leads in AI adoption among enterprises&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bain &amp;amp; Company (2025): &lt;EM&gt;Artificial Intelligence Adoption Survey&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Instituto IA – LNCC (2024–2025): &lt;EM&gt;Mapping of AI Research Groups in Brazil&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Poder360 (2024): &lt;EM&gt;Brazil to become Latin America’s AI hub with R$ 22 billion by 2028&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-blog-posts/brazil-as-one-of-the-leading-hubs-for-artificial-intelligence-2024-2025/ba-p/14248521"/>
    <published>2025-10-20T13:14:18.683000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-sap-enterprise-support-day-and-elevate-your-business/ba-p/14248513</id>
    <title>Join the SAP Enterprise Support Day and Elevate Your Business Transformation!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T13:18:18.482000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>oliverhuschke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/35096</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Banner - SAP ESD 2025.png" style="width: 980px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329834iCD9084E5852F9CD4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Banner - SAP ESD 2025.png" alt="Banner - SAP ESD 2025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hello fellow support enthusiasts,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The annual &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://url.sap/r7mvi2" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Day&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(November 12-13, 2025) is around the corner! – your gateway to unlocking the full potential of SAP’s support experience. This global virtual event is tailored to help you accelerate your digital business transformation journeys with confidence. Centered around the evolving deliverables of SAP Enterprise Support, the event highlights SAP’s latest innovations in AI-driven support, smart self-services, and integrated toolchains that simplify operations and reduce downtime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The event fosters a collaborative environment where insights and transformation strategies converge, reflecting SAP’s vision for a seamless customer journey across its cloud and suite solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z-TQcEEWGCg" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Click here&lt;/A&gt; to see your personal message by Stefan Steinle, EVP and Head of Customer Support &amp;amp; Cloud Lifecycle Management at SAP SE.:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="50%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="100%"&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2Fz-TQcEEWGCg%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3Dz-TQcEEWGCg&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2Fz-TQcEEWGCg%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="SAP Enterprise Support Day 2025: Register Today!" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Through a series of expert-led sessions offered in multiple languages and time zones, you will gain a deeper understanding of how to elevate your business transformation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;November 12, 2025 I 1 p.m. EST (Spanish, Portuguese, English)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;November 13, 2025 I 1 p.m. SGT (Chinese, Japanese, English)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;November 13, 2025 I 1 p.m. CET (German, English)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What can you expect?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transformative Support Experience:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Discover how SAP’s preventative support shifts from reactive to proactive, enhancing customer satisfaction and reducing downtime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-Enabled Processing: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn how AI simplifies support across cloud and suite landscapes, enabling faster resolutions and seamless access via SAP for Me.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Confidence Across the SAP Journey:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore onboarding strategies that unlock value and build trust throughout the SAP lifecycle, boosting confidence in the SAP Business Suite.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerated Transformation: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Gain actionable insights into how SAP’s integrated toolchain empowers you to drive innovation and speed up their transformation journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/hWNbJRT?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1245658" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Here&lt;/A&gt; you can find the detailed agenda!&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Register today!" href="https://url.sap/r7mvi2" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register today &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;and don’t miss this opportunity to gain fresh perspectives and practical insights that will empower your business transformation. This is your opportunity to learn, connect, and take actionable steps toward optimizing your SAP solutions. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please spread the word and share the invitation with your teams.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you need any support, please reach out to the event &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:mailto:sapenterprisesupportday@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;organization team&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We look forward to seeing you at the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Day&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your SAP Enterprise Support Day Organization Team&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-sap-enterprise-support-day-and-elevate-your-business/ba-p/14248513"/>
    <published>2025-10-20T13:18:18.482000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-innovation-day-in-dallas-focused-on-the-intersection-of-ai-and-ux/ba-p/14248883</id>
    <title>SAP Fiori Innovation Day in Dallas focused on the intersection of AI and UX</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T02:40:59.757000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PeterSpielvogel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/543</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks to the ASUG Dallas chapter for helping us reach new audiences with SAP Fiori Innovation Day Dallas. We had a dedicated track within the larger ASUG event in which participants could learn about the latest user experience innovations, build an SAP Fiori elements app in less than 90 minutes, and see some sneak previews of AI-powered functionality that we’re working on. They also asked our sponsors questions during a panel discussion and found many useful tips they could use back in the office.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PeterSpielvogel_0-1761007050538.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329989i8841FEEBC98D637A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PeterSpielvogel_0-1761007050538.png" alt="PeterSpielvogel_0-1761007050538.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the keynote, ASUG CEO, Geoff Scott, made a compelling case that moving to the cloud is a prerequisite for innovation at speed. In his interactive session, he polled the audience to give people a sense of how they compare to their peers in terms of innovation and adoption of various technologies. Many companies were using AI in some capacity, and some rely on multiple AI tools. &amp;nbsp;It was interesting to see what use cases the attendees find most relevant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PeterSpielvogel_1-1761007050544.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329988iE81C15D3D44DB7EF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PeterSpielvogel_1-1761007050544.jpeg" alt="PeterSpielvogel_1-1761007050544.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;ASUG found that automation and analytics are the top AI use cases. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the UX Strategy and What’s New section, Ioannis and Ute talked about the continuing evolution of SAP Fiori, how &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/fiori-elements" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori elements&lt;/A&gt; brings the Fiori design system to apps in SAP S/4HANA, and demoed the Fiori experience in SAP Cloud ERP. They showed new AI-powered capabilities in My Home, such as &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/tyBYABf?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1227640" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Recap&lt;/A&gt; and recommendations, and explained how AI built into the SAP Fiori elements framework powers &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/UWBaJpb?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1165618" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;easy filter&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/nCKuxVH?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1166391" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;smart summarization&lt;/A&gt;, and &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/V2V6rwq?ltr=v&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1166518" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;error explanation&lt;/A&gt;. All of this functionality combines to make business users more productive by making it faster and easier to find the apps and data they need in their S/4HANA system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PeterSpielvogel_2-1761007050545.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329987i26529AB309FE2835/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PeterSpielvogel_2-1761007050545.png" alt="PeterSpielvogel_2-1761007050545.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;We had a day full of learning and fun.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the partner panel, experts from &lt;A href="https://mygoconsulting.com/en-us/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mygo Consulting&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.qubittron.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Qubittron&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.mindsetconsulting.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mindset Consulting&lt;/A&gt;, and &lt;A href="https://www.cbs-consulting.com/us/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;cbs Corporate Business Solutions&lt;/A&gt; shared their expertise on:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How organizations measure the return on investment for UX and AI projects.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Where AI playing a role in UX and how agents fit into the picture.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The relative value of AI for business users and developers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The top AI use cases that make sense for companies&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Where to focus your efforts in the near term to gain benefits from AI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks to Sujeeth, Sidhartha, Andy, and Bastian for your unique insights and actionable advice. I found it interesting that many of the topics that people mentioned would be useful in the future were already part of our “one more thing” session at the end of the day.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The hands-on workshop focused on using AI to accelerate the process of building SAP Fiori apps. Participants used AI in three main ways:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gathering user requirements in a business requirement documents or via sketching&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-idea-to-app-using-ai-powered-project-accelerator-to-develop-sap-fiori/ba-p/14095300" target="_blank"&gt;Uploading the resulting document into SAP Fiori tools AI to generate an SAP Fiori elements app&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Making further updates and refinements to the application&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;We used &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/fiori-tools" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori tools&lt;/A&gt; extensively. This is a logical choice since they are built into &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/business-application-studio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The final session of the day (and highest rated) was our lab preview / sneak peak at a few projects are currently in development. As with any discussion of future functionality, we made it clear that these demos might or might not turn into actual products. With this in mind, Sebastian and Katja showed:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vibe coding&lt;/STRONG&gt; using MCP servers. (Vibe coding was also part of the ASUG keynote, so this is clearly becoming a mainstream topic, at least among software developers.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;App Finder&lt;/STRONG&gt; to make it easier to find information in your S/4HANA system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/AfZ3KfF?ltr=v&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1224347" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Easy Fill&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which speeds up data entry by extracting content from an email or other text and using it to update the relevant fields in an app built using an SAP Fiori elements object page.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart Helpers&lt;/STRONG&gt; to make it easier to get your work done in SAP. I’m being deliberately vague here as we’ll share more at SAP TechEd and its companion roadshows in early November 2025.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Thanks to everyone who made SAP Fiori Innovation Day a success&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Presenters (in order of appearance): Ioannis Grammatikakis, Ute Oemler, Sebastian Steinhauer, Katja Zoch&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Fiori Innovation Day sponsors: &lt;A href="https://www.cbs-consulting.com/us/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;cbs Corporate Business Solutions&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.mindsetconsulting.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mindset Consulting&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.qubittron.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Qubittron&lt;/A&gt;, and &lt;A href="https://mygoconsulting.com/en-us/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mygo Consulting&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ASUG events team: Nicole Kern, Kara Hughes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ASUG volunteers: Heather Davis, Simon To&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Behind the scenes team: all the developers, architects, product managers and other colleagues who built the functionality and set up the demos and hands-on systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the customers: we appreciate your questions, which help us understand your priorities and focus our development resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://tinyurl.com/elementsroundtable" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register for the monthly SAP Fiori development roundtable&lt;/A&gt; call to meet other developers and architects who build SAP Fiori apps.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/cmp/nl/sap-fiori-development-newsletter/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Subscribe to the SAP Fiori development newsletter&lt;/A&gt;, in which we share updates on SAP Fiori elements, SAP Fiori tools, SAPUI5, and SAP Build Code every other month.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://ui5.sap.com/test-resources/sap/fe/core/fpmExplorer/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Explore the SAP Fiori Development Portal&lt;/A&gt; to see how SAP Fiori elements can boost developer productivity, drive UX consistency, and ensure your apps have the enterprise readiness features your users expect.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Join us at &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;TechEd Berlin&lt;/A&gt; or &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog?tab.sessionplanned=1692641568884001cZ9d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;virtual&lt;/A&gt; or at the next &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eur-fiori-innovation-day-walldorf-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori Innovation Day in Walldorf&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-fiori-innovation-day-in-dallas-focused-on-the-intersection-of-ai-and-ux/ba-p/14248883"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T02:40:59.757000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/do-you-know-how-to-solve-business-problems-using-sap-s-generative-ai-hub/ba-p/14249030</id>
    <title>Do you know how to solve business problems using SAP's Generative AI Hub?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T12:19:08.576000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Katrin1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1489671</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I recommend to look at our latest&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Solving Business Problems using SAP's Generative AI Hub" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/solving-business-problems-using-sap-s-generative-ai-hub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Solving Business Problems using SAP's Generative AI Hub&lt;/A&gt; Learning Journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762946745"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Learning outcome&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;After completing this learning journey,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You will discover how SAP Business AI streamlines processes, improves decisions, and drives scalable innovation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After this, you will gain a strong grasp of Large Language Models and their application within SAP, including their strengths, limitations, and integration through SAP’s generative AI hub.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You will explore the capabilities of SAP’s generative AI hub, learning to navigate its interfaces, manage models, and orchestrate AI workflows for enterprise use.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You will develop hands-on skills in designing, refining, and managing prompts, using prompt templates and the Prompt Registry to ensure consistency and scalability across business applications.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Finally, you will master grounding techniques to connect AI outputs with trusted enterprise data, enabling context-aware and reliable solutions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;By the end, you will be equipped to design, implement, and optimize robust AI solutions that drive measurable value and innovation for your organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566433240"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Goals&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get started with SAP: Building the basics&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Develop your expertise:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Skill deepening learning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Excel in your expertise:&amp;nbsp;Advanced specialization learning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please post you question related&amp;nbsp;to the digital learning Journey in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/qa-p/learningqanda-board" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q&amp;amp;A area&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our SAP Learning Experts will get back to you as soon as possible!&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;We are here to support you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I appreciate your feedback and we will make sure to continue sharing interesting topics.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Kind regards,&amp;nbsp;Katrin&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/do-you-know-how-to-solve-business-problems-using-sap-s-generative-ai-hub/ba-p/14249030"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T12:19:08.576000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everything-you-need-to-know-about-sap-discovery-center-before-teched/ba-p/14249744</id>
    <title>Everything You Need to Know About SAP Discovery Center Before TechEd</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T19:45:59.708000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>joanneks</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7268</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd&lt;/A&gt; 2025 is approaching—the premier annual event for SAP developers, solution architects, and IT professionals worldwide.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;With thousands of sessions, hands-on workshops, and networking opportunities waiting for you, success at TechEd depends on how well-prepared you arrive. That's where the &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;'s latest updates come in.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From a comprehensive SAP AI Return-On-Investment (ROI) calculator that provides real-time financial justification for AI packages to an enhanced SAP BTP Guidance Framework that serves as your star map to best practices, these updates, these updates directly address the challenges you face every day: proving value, reducing implementation risk, and accelerating digital transformation timelines.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're a solution architect planning your next &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt; implementation, a developer exploring AI possibilities, or an IT leader who needs to justify technology investments with hard numbers, the new SAP Discovery Center features will become your most valuable pre-TechEd preparation. Let's dive into what's new, why it matters, and how you can leverage these tools to maximize your TechEd experience and drive immediate value back to your organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="287863_GettyImages-1190582403_x_small_jpg.jpg" style="width: 553px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330337i93E8A94C0C79886B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="287863_GettyImages-1190582403_x_small_jpg.jpg" alt="287863_GettyImages-1190582403_x_small_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1633870788"&gt;AI on SAP Discovery Center&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566440002"&gt;1. Enhanced AI Catalogue: Your Complete AI Solution Navigator&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business AI Catalogue&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;has received a major upgrade that transforms how you explore and evaluate AI solutions. The catalogue now features dedicated categories for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/canada/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-assistant.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule&lt;/A&gt;"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;"&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/canada/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-agents.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI Agent&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"&lt;/STRONG&gt;, making it easier than ever to find the specific AI capabilities you need for your organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Major Enhancements:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The catalogue now reflects SAP's new&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;per-user-per-month commercial model&lt;/STRONG&gt;, providing transparent pricing visibility&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI packages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that bundle AI agents and features alongside consumption-based &lt;STRONG&gt;AI agents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and features for flexible implementation options&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comma-separated value (CSV) export functionality&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;allows you to download the entire AI catalogue for offline analysis, team sharing, and integration with your procurement processes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore the enhanced AI Catalogue:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-catalog/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1369926497"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1173412992"&gt;2. Streamlined Discovery with Intelligent Filtering&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;completely redesigned filters &lt;/STRONG&gt;improve the experience of searching through SAP Discovery Center’s AI offerings. The updated interface and enhanced look-and-feel make finding relevant offerings faster and more efficient.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Improvements:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart filters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;help you pinpoint AI offerings that match your specific use cases, industry, and technical requirements&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;At-a-glance information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;on catalogue cards provides essential details without requiring deep navigation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved user experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that reduces time-to-insight and accelerates your AI exploration journey&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-976899487"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-780385982"&gt;3. ROI-Driven Decision Making with the AI Estimator&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new &lt;STRONG&gt;Return-on-Investment (ROI) calculation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;feature added to the AI Estimator transforms how organizations evaluate and justify AI investments. With the ROI estimation, users can make more informed decisions on AI packages and consumption-based AI offerings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Game-Changing Capabilities:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-time ROI calculations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for both AI packages and consumption-based AI offerings&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transparent methodology&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that explains how ROI estimates are calculated, building confidence in your investment decisions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business case support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that provides the financial justification needed for executive approval and budget allocation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculate your AI ROI:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-estimator-v1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/ai-estimator-v1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-583872477"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-387358972"&gt;4. Integrated AI and SAP BTP Service Connections&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The enhanced SAP BTP Service Catalogue with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;clear linkage between AI offerings and SAP BTP services&lt;/STRONG&gt; now shows exactly which AI offerings relate to specific services, providing comprehensive visibility into how AI capabilities can amplify your existing SAP BTP investments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Revolutionary Features:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Direct AI offering visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;within SAP BTP service detail pages eliminates the guesswork in finding relevant AI capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved use case planning and implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;by understanding how AI can enhance your existing SAP BTP services, and with clear connections between&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;the AI foundation&lt;/SPAN&gt; and AI capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore integrated AI offerings:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-build-process-automation?region=all&amp;amp;tab=relatedaiofferings" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/serviceCatalog/sap-build-process-automation?region=all&amp;amp;tab=relatedaiofferings&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="293148_GettyImages-530185374_x_small_jpg.jpg" style="width: 510px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330416i66E82E54D44C591E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="293148_GettyImages-530185374_x_small_jpg.jpg" alt="293148_GettyImages-530185374_x_small_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-61762748"&gt;Other Updates on SAP Discovery Center&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--5668038"&gt;1. SAP BTP Guidance Framework: Your Star Map for Guidance Assets&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a resource that extends the scope for architects by providing comprehensive methodologies and guidance. This framework serves as your guide toward architecting, developing, and deploying enterprise-grade solutions on SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Makes This Framework Essential:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Structured adoption phases&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;provide clear direction and a proven approach for adopting SAP BTP according to industry best practices&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tailored recommendations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;drive your organization's SAP BTP maturity through an integrated maturity assessment&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strategic decision support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;helps you make the right decisions at the right time, maximizing value from your SAP BTP investments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comprehensive guidance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;covers everything from initial planning to advanced enterprise implementations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This framework is particularly valuable for SAP TechEd attendees who want to move beyond tactical implementations to strategic, enterprise-scale SAP BTP adoption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access the BTP Guidance Framework:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/guidance-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/guidance-framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-145072814"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp; Events: Expanding the SAP Discovery Center Knowledge Universe&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Discovery Center homepage now features a dedicated Events section. This new section serves as a centralized resource for hands-on events designed for both SAP customers and partners, adding another dimension to the Discovery Center's comprehensive learning ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner and Customer Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hands-on learning opportunities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;help customers and partners deepen their knowledge and enhance their technical skills&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Knowledge transfer&lt;/STRONG&gt; that benefits the entire ecosystem by making expertise more accessible to all audiences&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Networking opportunities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;connect partners with SAP experts and fellow practitioners&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer value enhancement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;through access to more knowledgeable, qualified partners&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ecosystem strengthening&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;by making partner enablement more visible and accessible&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerated adoption&lt;/STRONG&gt; through joint events that align partner capabilities with customer needs and use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discover events:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html#&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--344843698"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--247954196"&gt;3.&amp;nbsp; Latest Mission Releases: Learning That Drives Results&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Discovery Center continues to expand its use case portfolio with five new missions that address the most pressing enterprise challenges:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4631/4920/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Activate Joule with SAP Integrated Business Planning (IBP)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4649/4938/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Setup of Joule in Mobile Start&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4652/4941/?tab=overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Accelerate Smart Supplier Selection with Retrieval-Augmented Generative AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4639/4928/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Migrate data from SAP Business One to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4678/4967/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Accelerate your BTP Journey with FRE Acceleration Datasphere Pack&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These hands-on experiences provide practical, implementable knowledge that bridges the gap between theoretical understanding and real-world application, ensuring both partners and customers can immediately leverage cutting-edge SAP technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How Missions Guide Your Journey:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hands-on learning experiences&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that provide practical skills through guided, interactive tutorials and real-world scenarios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Self-paced exploration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;allows partners and customers to learn at their own speed and revisit content as needed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comprehensive skill development&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;covering beginner to advanced topics across SAP's entire technology portfolio&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immediate practical application&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with step-by-step guidance that can be implemented directly in production environments &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reduced learning curve&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for new SAP technologies through expert-designed tutorials and best practices&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore all new missions&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missioncatalog" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missioncatalog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--737870708"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform – Priority Use Cases&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore the comprehensive range of SAP Business Technology Platform use cases that these missions support here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/use-cases.html?sort=latest_desc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/use-cases.html?sort=latest_desc&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--347578199"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your Next Steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you prepare for SAP TechEd 2025, think of these tools as your spacecraft's vital systems: the ROI Calculator as your fuel efficiency monitor, ensuring every investment delivers maximum propulsion; the SAP BTP Guidance Framework as your star maps, guiding you safely through complex architectural decisions; and the Events as your communication array, keeping you connected with the broader SAP ecosystem of knowledge and expertise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The countdown to SAP TechEd has begun. Your mission parameters are set. These SAP Discovery Center updates aren't just features—they're your launch sequence for achieving breakthrough results. Whether you're embarking on your first SAP BTP expedition or you're a seasoned space traveller ready for advanced AI exploration, you now have everything needed for a successful mission.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ready for liftoff to transform your SAP journey?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register now&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and start building your agenda&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/sap/posts/?feedView=all" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Connect with us&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;on social media for real-time updates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Join the conversation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;using #SAPTechEd2025&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next blog, we will discuss our recommended sessions for your &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog?tab.sessionplanned=1692641568884001cZ9d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd agenda&lt;/A&gt; in more detail.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don't just attend SAP TechEd 2025—make it the catalyst for your next breakthrough.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everything-you-need-to-know-about-sap-discovery-center-before-teched/ba-p/14249744"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T19:45:59.708000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/generative-ai-mcp-and-sap-what-are-these-and-how-to-make-the-most-of-it/ba-p/14233242</id>
    <title>Generative AI, MCP and SAP; What are these and how to make the most of it?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T08:03:21.499000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aman_Orchard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2215164</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Generative AI is the current buzzword in the market. Potentially, every clients, companies and adapting to it on fast pace. Recently SAP had introduced support for Model Context Protocol. With this particular blog, I'll be trying to make you all understand what MCP is, how we can make the best use of it for your SAP systems.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is Model context protocol? (MCP)?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;It is basically an open, standardized approach that enables Large Language Models (LLMs) and AI agents to access up to date,&amp;nbsp; enterprise data - In our case, across SAP and other business systems on demand.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT-4, Claude, Gemini, Llama3 etc evolve, we need standardized ways to connect them to tools, APIs, and systems. Imagine trying to follow different connectors/API for each LLM!&lt;BR /&gt;However, these models operate in isolation based on pre-trained data and don’t have built-in access to real-time data, databases , external APIs, or local files. Which is where MCP kicks in.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Below figure shows how MCP Client( Potentially LLMs or AI Agents) could connect to SAP systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Aman_Orchard_0-1759389145778.png" style="width: 502px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322198i7DE4D99EFCA2A9D9/image-dimensions/502x161?v=v2" width="502" height="161" role="button" title="Aman_Orchard_0-1759389145778.png" alt="Aman_Orchard_0-1759389145778.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;MCP follows a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;client-server architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clients&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(like AI applications or LLMs) connect to&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Servers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(MCP tool providers) expose tools, APIs, or data sources to clients.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our case, As an example- We can connect any AI agent to automate the workflows, or any AI models, using MCP to SAP systems, which would have access to the system and train from enterprise data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Potential Use-cases:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP GUI automation- Autonomous GUI Agent:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agent to automate interactions with SAP GUI, enabling programmatic control of SAP transactions. This can automate manual processes, activities which users perform on day to day basis.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Automation scope:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automation and workflows&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automating repetitive SAP business processes and transactions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extracting specific data from SAP screens and tables for reporting or analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrating SAP GUI automation into AI-powered desktop assistants or custom applications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;How does it work?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI Agent can be fed with recorded steps, It can read and understand the fields, adapt with time; Unlike using RPA which is trained to exactly copy and execute the system actions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Advantage&lt;/U&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;Automate repetitive, heinous tasks.&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Analytics and Reporting- Create dashboard and statistics.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;Scope:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/U&gt;System reads, understands data and patterns and potentially (examples) answer below queries:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;“Whats the usage of product XXX?”&lt;BR /&gt;“Tell me the product which is most used during XXX months/quarter?”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Aman_Orchard_0-1759389619496.png" style="width: 507px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322199iEDD715028C4B0405/image-dimensions/507x113?v=v2" width="507" height="113" role="button" title="Aman_Orchard_0-1759389619496.png" alt="Aman_Orchard_0-1759389619496.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Advantage&lt;/U&gt;&lt;U&gt;:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build dashboards, reports instantly based on the data required&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understand what custom functionality does, AI can read the code, Create of functional, technical documentations:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s consider a case where a vendor has done custom development and It is a blackbox to us, AI helps us to read, analyze and provide a basic understanding of the custom enhancement, saving time and efforts. The same can be extracted as documentation for future references.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Examples:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explain this legacy ABAP report in plain english and add detailed in-line comments”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Result- Understand complex, undocumented Z-programs, making analysis and decisions faster.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fiori MCP Server/Write UI5 code using agents:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;-Developers&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;can build apps faster using MCP servers.&lt;BR /&gt;-Write UI5 code using agents.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Examples:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Add flexible row layout for the app”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Generate a new project and SAP Fiori app based on “my sketch.jpg”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“How can I style an sap.m.Button to appear as a "reject" action?"&lt;BR /&gt;"Help me migrate any deprecated UI5 API usage in this UI5 controller"&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Aman_Orchard_1-1759390100953.png" style="width: 511px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322200iEA458E1E04972480/image-dimensions/511x225?v=v2" width="511" height="225" role="button" title="Aman_Orchard_1-1759390100953.png" alt="Aman_Orchard_1-1759390100953.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;AI Assisted coding:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MCP Clients to assist Consultants with coding, code reviews etc&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Aman_Orchard_2-1759390150860.png" style="width: 461px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322201i5F54CECAEA84B0C6/image-dimensions/461x181?v=v2" width="461" height="181" role="button" title="Aman_Orchard_2-1759390150860.png" alt="Aman_Orchard_2-1759390150860.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart IoT, Yard integrations, Smart Dock scheduling, Automated calls etc&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-Attain End to End track and trace information for Boxes with prompting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-Dock Appointment scheduling using phone calls with AI voice assistant.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Chatbot- Only integrated for client data:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;End users can enquire, ask things to the chatbox which is integrated with SAP. (Can be Enabled for consultants as well).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Gain Information on business processes; In most organizations, Information relevant to any business process is often scattered across multiple business applications, databases, cloud systems, and files, both inside and outside of SAP.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For AI agents to deliver meaningful answers and actions, they need access to all relevant data, not just data isolated SAP tables.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With MCP, the connection between entire enterprise system and AI agents can be built easily.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Aman_Orchard_0-1759396554810.png" style="width: 504px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322220iD1C2AD259071E160/image-dimensions/504x141?v=v2" width="504" height="141" role="button" title="Aman_Orchard_0-1759396554810.png" alt="Aman_Orchard_0-1759396554810.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;How could this fit in EWM?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Since I come from EWM (Extended Warehouse Management) background, These are few use-cases which I had in mind:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Chatbot- &lt;SPAN&gt;only integrated for client data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Demand Forecasting- &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enable models to predict future demand of products&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Slotting &amp;amp; rearrangement- &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Suggest optimal bin placement for products- Helping drastically in production, Kanban processes, Urgent flows etc&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Labour Management-&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Estimate, optimize workforce allocation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Picking optimization- &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn, optimize picking routes for different processes on floor.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learn queue, issues, patterns and take corrective/follow on actions.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;Please do share your feedback, ideas pertaining to your modules and your thoughts. Thanks for your time!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Aman Orchard&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/generative-ai-mcp-and-sap-what-are-these-and-how-to-make-the-most-of-it/ba-p/14233242"/>
    <published>2025-10-22T08:03:21.499000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/session-reply-amp-slides-available-hot-topic-joule-activation-for-sap-cloud/ba-p/14251657</id>
    <title>[Session Reply &amp; Slides Available] Hot Topic: Joule Activation for SAP Cloud ERP (Public Edition)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-23T13:28:22.139000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LilingJia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8414</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Expertise Service Team and SAP AI RIG team recently co-present a deep-dive session focused on&lt;STRONG&gt; enabling ‌Joule‌ - SAP’s generative AI copilot - for SAP Cloud ERP.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The agenda covered as below and feel free to access [&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/bgdZGY4?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1249301" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Slides&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;] [&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/UUBmJ8S?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1249311" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recording&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;].&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business AI capabilities and use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule’s technical architecture on SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Step-by-step activation process for S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Q&amp;amp;A and live troubleshooting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/UUBmJ8S?rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1249311" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-10-23_19-35-33.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331546iBA1EAD5112F447E6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-10-23_19-35-33.jpg" alt="2025-10-23_19-35-33.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892720492"&gt;1. Key Objectives‌&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Demonstrate Joule’s value in streamlining business processes (e.g., sales order management, issue resolution in status check).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Guide participants through end-to-end setup using BTP booster, destinations, and identity management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Equip partners to deploy Joule for customers with minimal friction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696206987"&gt;2. Business AI &amp;amp; Joule Introduction‌&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1757858920"&gt;Joule Definition‌&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP’s generative AI copilot embedded in cloud solutions to automate tasks, provide contextual insights, and reduce manual effort.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1561345415"&gt;Primary Use Case‌:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigational support (e.g., finding apps without memorizing transaction codes)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transactional support (e.g., creating insights cards, resolving incomplete sales orders)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Informational support (e.g., find SAP Help document for relevant business process)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1364831910"&gt;Demo Highlight&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create Insights Cards with Joule&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Check Sales Order Status with Joule‌:Joule identifies incomplete orders, highlights missing fields (e.g., payment terms), and guides users to resolve issues&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-910152967"&gt;3. Technical Architecture &amp;amp; Activation Flow‌&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-842722181"&gt;3.1 Core Components‌:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule Web Client‌ is embedded across SAP cloud solutions (e.g., SuccessFactors, S/4HANA)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BTP Subaccount‌&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hosts Joule instance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;connectivity services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cloud Identity Services‌&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Manages authentication (IAS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identity / role synchronization (IPS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;S/4HANA Cloud APIs‌: Data source for Joule’s responses.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-646208676"&gt;3.2 Activation Steps‌:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-578777890"&gt;Prerequisites‌:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BTP global account with Joule entitlements&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;S/4HANA system registered to BTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-382264385"&gt;BTP Subaccount Setup‌:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create subaccount in preferred region/hyperscaler&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign entitlements:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Build Work Zone (foundation or standard edition)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule service&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Establish trust to Cloud Identity Services tenant&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add S/4HANA domain to trusted destinations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--734451941"&gt;Joule Booster Execution‌:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Guided setup for BTP formations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate S/4HANA, Build Work Zone, and Cloud Identity Services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--930965446"&gt;Post-Booster Configurations‌:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify communication arrangements in S/4HANA (e.g., Digital Assistant Service - 0882).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify BTP Destinations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify SAP Build Work Zone Content for S/4HANA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure Identity Provisioning (IPS) to sync users/roles from S/4HANA to Build Work Zone&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1127478951"&gt;Validation‌:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure Joule icon appears in S/4HANA Launchpad.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test capabilities (e.g., querying open sales orders).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--737186442"&gt;4. Critical Notes &amp;amp; Pitfalls‌&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trust Configuration‌: Ensure all solutions in a Joule formation use the ‌same Cloud Identity Services tenant‌.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Destination Errors‌: Verify hostnames, client IDs, and secrets in navigation service manually if not auto-generated.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identity Provisioning‌: Ensure IPS jobs run successfully to propagate roles to SAP Build Work Zone.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--933699947"&gt;5. Next Steps &amp;amp; Resources‌&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1717019466"&gt;Discovery Center Missions:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4538/4826/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4538/4826/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4452/4738/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4452/4738/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1913532971"&gt;Support Channels‌:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Community - Business AI&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Support for technical errors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--2110046476"&gt;Upcoming Sessions‌:&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/sep/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00011427.html?eventdate=27%20Oct%202025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Implement SAP Business AI for SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/A&gt; (Oct 27th)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/library/education/psd/2025/sep/e_oe_te_w_PSD_WEB_00011426.html?eventdate=28%20Oct%202025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Vietnam localization for implementation&lt;/A&gt; (Oct 28th)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/session-reply-amp-slides-available-hot-topic-joule-activation-for-sap-cloud/ba-p/14251657"/>
    <published>2025-10-23T13:28:22.139000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060</id>
    <title>Upcoming SAP BTP Adoption Webinars – Unlock the Power of AI, Data, and Integration</title>
    <updated>2025-10-23T20:29:52.412000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JiaRu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1490527</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get ready for a packed lineup of&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;expert-led sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;designed to help you accelerate innovation with&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. From AI best practices to integration and analytics, these webinars will equip you with practical insights and real-world examples you can apply right away.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;ul =""&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId-1892744541"&gt;Oct 30 | Pipeline Concept in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId-1696231036"&gt;Nov 04 | Service and Service Excellence with AI Driven Insights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId-1499717531"&gt;Nov 05 | Accelerate Insights with SAP Business Data Cloud Intelligent Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId-1303204026"&gt;Nov 05 | Best practices for secure and scalable LLM model usage in BTP AI apps with SAP AI Core&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId-1106690521"&gt;Nov 13 | AI-Driven Business Solutions – Exploring the Potential of SAP BTP AI - Americas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId-910177016"&gt;Nov 13 | Enablement on SAP Mobile Start and SAP Build Work Zone with Showcase of Joule as AI Copilot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId-713663511"&gt;Nov 19 | AI-Driven Business Solutions – Exploring the Potential of SAP BTP AI - APAC/EMEA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId-517150006"&gt;Nov 20 | BTP AI Best Practices – Knowledge Graph-based Retrieval Augmented Generation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId-320636501"&gt;Dec 03 | BTP AI Best Practices – Vector-based RAG, Document Grounding, and Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId-124122996"&gt;Dec 09 | AI-Driven Business Solutions – Exploring the Potential of SAP BTP AI (Americas Session)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:30px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060#toc-hId--147621878"&gt;Dec 15 | AI-Driven Business Solutions – Exploring the Potential of SAP BTP AI (APAC/EMEA Session)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember515" id="toc-hId-1892744541"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Oct 30 | Pipeline Concept in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Learn how the pipeline concept accelerates your migration from SAP Process Orchestration to SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.sap.com/noam-iac-btp-int-suite-webinar-pipeline-concept/en_us" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Now&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember524" id="toc-hId-1696231036"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;Nov 04 | Service and Service Excellence with AI Driven Insights&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Experience how SAP solutions transform intelligence into action—turning service into a seamless, revenue-driving experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.sap.com/apj-adoption-wb-service-excellence-with-ai-nov-25/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Now&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember530" id="toc-hId-1499717531"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;Nov 05 | Accelerate Insights with SAP Business Data Cloud Intelligent Apps&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Explore how to deploy, consume, and extend SAP BDC Intelligent Apps in SAP Analytics Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/e5c852c2-1b14-4e98-8f31-990e853130ca@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Now&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember537" id="toc-hId-1303204026"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Nov 05 | Best practices for secure and scalable LLM model usage in BTP AI apps with SAP AI Core&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Discover how to make secure and scalable large language model usage in BTP AI applications with SAP BTP AI Core.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Register Now: &lt;A class="" href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/0fa4ed32-defe-425b-b31d-b4c654f61db5@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;EMEA/MEE/APAC Session&lt;/A&gt; | &lt;A class="" href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/5b173ab2-8b94-4424-a792-cad2ef0c06a3@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Americas/EMEA Session&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember543" id="toc-hId-1106690521"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Nov 13 | AI-Driven Business Solutions – Exploring the Potential of SAP BTP AI - Americas&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Discover how enterprises are turning AI hype into real business outcomes with SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/506e0408-24e6-436e-8ca1-e3d81844d78e@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Now&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember549" id="toc-hId-910177016"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Nov 13 | Enablement on SAP Mobile Start and SAP Build Work Zone with Showcase of Joule as AI Copilot&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Discover how to leverage SAP Mobile Start and SAP Build Work Zone as central entry point with Joule AI Copilot for connected SAP solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.sap.com/eur-adoption-webinar-sap-btp-mobile-start-build-joule-september-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Now&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember556" id="toc-hId-713663511"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Nov 19 | AI-Driven Business Solutions – Exploring the Potential of SAP BTP AI - APAC/EMEA&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Discover how enterprises are turning AI hype into real business outcomes with SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.sap.com/apj-adoption-webinar-sap-btp-ai-driven-business-solutions-nov-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Now&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember564" id="toc-hId-517150006"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Nov 20 | BTP AI Best Practices – Knowledge Graph-based Retrieval Augmented Generation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Learn how to combine Knowledge Graphs with Large Language Models for advanced RAG scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Register Now: &lt;A class="" href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/0fa4ed32-defe-425b-b31d-b4c654f61db5@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;EMEA/MEE/APAC Session&lt;/A&gt; | &lt;A class="" href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/5b173ab2-8b94-4424-a792-cad2ef0c06a3@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Americas/EMEA Session&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember570" id="toc-hId-320636501"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Dec 03 | BTP AI Best Practices – Vector-based RAG, Document Grounding, and Examples&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;See how to ground large language models on company-specific data using SAP Document Grounding.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Register Now: &lt;A class="" href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/ad603257-6fa3-4c3c-a627-160a90ba1872@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;EMEA/MEE/APAC Session&lt;/A&gt; | &lt;A class="" href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/866e330f-58dd-4917-bee4-d4139b0b2a92@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Americas/EMEA Session&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember579" id="toc-hId-124122996"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Dec 09 | AI-Driven Business Solutions – Exploring the Potential of SAP BTP AI (Americas Session)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Discover how enterprises are turning AI hype into real business outcomes with SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/723cb552-206f-466c-8141-f1e3895d7154@42f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Now&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember584" id="toc-hId--147621878"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Dec 15 | AI-Driven Business Solutions – Exploring the Potential of SAP BTP AI (APAC/EMEA Session)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Discover how enterprises are turning AI hype into real business outcomes with SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://events.sap.com/apj-adoption-webinar-sap-btp-ai-driven-business-solutions-dec-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register Now&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;Don’t miss the opportunity to &lt;STRONG&gt;learn from SAP experts&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;accelerate your journey to the Intelligent Enterprise&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/upcoming-sap-btp-adoption-webinars-unlock-the-power-of-ai-data-and/ba-p/14252060"/>
    <published>2025-10-23T20:29:52.412000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-innovations-in-sap-cloud-erp-private-2025/ba-p/14249159</id>
    <title>AI-innovations in SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-24T09:18:52.133000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yannick_PTT</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40565</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The release of SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 marks a significant leap forward in enterprise automation and intelligence, as presented in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-erp-private-2025-product-release-highlights/ba-p/14237649" target="_blank"&gt;this product blog&lt;/A&gt; by &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8440"&gt;@BeSchulze&lt;/a&gt;. This release, the result of two years of focused development, places&amp;nbsp;artificial intelligence at the core – seamlessly integrated across business areas to redefine how work gets done.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Central to this update is the new&amp;nbsp;agentic AI framework, where task-specific agents work together under the orchestration of our copilot Joule. More than just assistance, SAP’s persona-based AI acts as the&amp;nbsp;new interface – guiding users through processes, answering questions, and delivering relevant insights within the tools they use every day. Customers can now experience improved transparency, faster decision-making, and simplified operations, with intelligent capabilities integrated directly into their business flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dive into the accompanying video for a glimpse of how these AI-driven capabilities are transforming daily work and setting a new benchmark for enterprise management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_b2gy08gn" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762947777"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566434272"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic Use cases&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499003486"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Asset Management: Maintenance Planner&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the area of Asset Management, planning maintenance activities often requires seamless access to the right tools at the right time. The Maintenance Planner feature, newly integrated with Joule, enhances this process by providing direct navigation to scheduling applications within SAP S/4HANA Asset Management. This innovation means that maintenance planners no longer need to sift through catalogs, as they can intuitively access relevant apps directly from their conversations, such as asking, "How to visualize maintenance work?" and receiving immediate links to resource scheduling applications. By embedding SAP Help documentation into Joule’s conversational responses, planners gain quick insights and can focus more on optimally scheduling maintenance tasks, thus ensuring that assets are well-managed without the hassle of navigation detours.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Eager to learn more? Check out our &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/joule-capabilitiesjoule-capabilities-eac-199dd5b0a3044c07bfc1ecad291f43f2/maintenance-planner-agent?state=DRAFT&amp;amp;version=DEV&amp;amp;q=maintenance+planner" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt; and watch the demo video below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_g5q9pa91" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1302489981"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105976476"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance: Simpliyfying invoice dispute with the dispute manager &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Untangling an incorrect invoice can feel like detective work, searching for clues across different systems. Now, with the Dispute Manager agent in SAP Cloud ERP Private your finance team has a new partner. A finance expert can simply ask Joule to pull up a dispute case by its number or show recent invoices for a customer. From that single conversation, they can review the details and then instruct Joule to either reject the dispute or navigate them directly to the app to create a credit note. This conversational approach turns a complex, multi-step investigation into a streamlined and guided dialogue. It not only saves valuable time for your team but also leads to quicker resolutions, helping maintain positive customer relationships.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Dispute_manger_23.10png.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331430i47AD738607889F29/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Dispute_manger_23.10png.png" alt="Dispute_manger_23.10png.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information, please refer to the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/joule-capabilitiesjoule-capabilities-eac-199dd5b0a3044c07bfc1ecad291f43f2/dispute-resolution?state=DRAFT&amp;amp;version=DEV&amp;amp;q=dispute" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-909462971"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-712949466"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance: Empowering Trade Classification with an AI Agent &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine trying to import a new fitness tracker and facing a complex web of customs classifications, where one wrong choice could mean costly delays.&amp;nbsp;The Joule Agent for Trade Classification in SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 makes this task straightforward by analyzing your product's data against global customs rules. For example, it might conclude a fitness tracker falls under the wristwatches category and provide legal notes to back this decision, keeping your team informed and in control. By transforming the complex classification process into a guided interaction, your trade professionals have more time to focus on strategy rather than paperwork. This not only enhances the speed and accuracy of your compliance processes but also strengthens your ability to meet market demands swiftly. With this AI innovation, your business can confidently and efficiently pursue global growth, minimizing delays and maximizing opportunities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more, consult our &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/f5d3e1005efd4e86acf9a65abf428082/f71f71283d8c4bce92aff58392a4bbad.html?version=2025.000%20LESS" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; and watch the demo video below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_eyck2cdl" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-387353242"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales LoB&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-319922456"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Elevating sales efficiency with AI-driven solution quotation management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Speaking of the Sales line of business, where time is of the essence, managing solution quotations can be a complex task. The introduction of Joule as a digital assistant in SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 simplifies this process by allowing sales reps to execute tasks like creation, updating, and searching of solution quotations with conversational, natural language commands. This empowers sales teams to focus on high-value opportunities, such as quotations about to expire or those with significant client interest, and make well-informed decisions with clarity and speed. By streamlining the access to critical information, Joule helps reduce operational time and enhances the agility of sales professionals, allowing them to concentrate on building stronger customer relationships and fulfilling sales targets.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="quotation management 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330191i81ED043BB23F4F9A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="quotation management 1.png" alt="quotation management 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="quotation management 2.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330190i966D3AF4B7BC54CF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="quotation management 2.png" alt="quotation management 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information read our dedicated pages on &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/perform-release-and-acceptance-of-solution-quotations" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;performing release and acceptance of solution quotations&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/fetch-solution-quotation-information" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;fetching solution quotation information&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-123408951"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--148335923"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamlessly creating billing documents with AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine transforming the intricate process of billing document creation into an efficient, effortless operation—this is where Joule steps in. The AI-powered capabilities of Joule allow users to effortlessly generate billing documents, whether they stem from a single reference or a collection of sales and delivery documents. This intuitive system supports the creation of both individual and collective billing documents, tailored to meet diverse business needs with pinpoint accuracy. For R&amp;amp;D departments, this means a streamlined workflow where administrative overhead is minimized, allowing more focus on innovation and product development. By simplifying navigation and enabling quick access to essential apps like Display Billing Documents, Joule enhances the accuracy and efficiency of billing processes, paving the way for more strategic decision-making. With this kind of intelligent assistance, your team spends less time on the nitty-gritty and more time driving the business forward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Billing docs.png" style="width: 968px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330193i4F4C146C5FCA5D03/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Billing docs.png" alt="Billing docs.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;For more details, consult the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/fetch-billing-document-information" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--51446421"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sourcing &amp;amp; Procurement LoB&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--541362933"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-assisted creation of purchase requisitions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s take a look at the Sourcing &amp;amp; Procurement Line of Business. In this area creating purchase requisitions is a task that demands accuracy and efficiency. With the AI-assisted capabilities of Joule, the process becomes intuitive, allowing users, particularly casual ones, to navigate and complete requisitions merely through conversational prompts. This smart assistance helps in understanding various languages, correcting misspelled data, and even suggesting sources of supply promptly, thereby minimizing manual overhead and enhancing speed in decision-making. By embracing the future potential of speech recognition, Joule promises to make procurement tasks even more seamless, supporting operational purchasers in reducing free text entries and ensuring order clarity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="purchase requisition2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330196i2B8EB5EC9892BD79/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="purchase requisition2.png" alt="purchase requisition2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;For more details, refer to &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/joule-capabilitiesjoule-capabilities-eac-199dd5b0a3044c07bfc1ecad291f43f2/create-purchase-requisitions?state=DRAFT&amp;amp;version=DEV&amp;amp;q=purchase+requisitions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--444473431"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance LoB&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--934389943"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified subscription order management*&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Finance, is often fragmented and error-prone. Teams spend valuable time reconciling contracts, processing changes, and ensuring compliance - effort that slows down financial operations and puts transparency at risk.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule tackles this challenge by simplifying subscription management end to end. It guides users through creating orders, automatically filling key fields once core details are entered. Contract information is easy to access and aligned with attributes like customer or product ID, while intuitive summaries provide quick snapshots of activation status. By streamlining these steps, Joule boosts efficiency, improves transparency, and allows businesses to focus on growth rather than administrative tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="subscription order management.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331394i04D23126C9F9A01B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="subscription order management.png" alt="subscription order management.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, consult the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/subscription-order-management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1130903448"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule for cash management assistant*&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Picture your finance team, once bogged down in manual cash flow tracking, now effortlessly navigating a sea of numbers with ease. With Joule, you can quickly verify if due bank statements are received, fetch opening balances, and factor in expected cash flows, all in one seamless process. By providing accurate calculations of expected closing balances, Joule proactively alerts you to potential cash shortages or surpluses. This efficiency not only saves substantial time but also empowers you to optimize cash usage strategically. In a world where timing is everything, having this level of clarity allows your business to maintain a robust financial footing and seize opportunities as they arise.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Cash management assistant.png" style="width: 803px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331395i032D3B398E146C8B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Cash management assistant.png" alt="Cash management assistant.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more details, refer to the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/cash-management" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;*&lt;SPAN&gt;planned availability in November 2025&amp;nbsp; with the&amp;nbsp; update of Joule framework&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1034013946"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain LoB&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1523930458"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule navigation in SAP Fiori apps for extended warehouse management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In managing warehouse operations, finding the right tools quickly can make all the difference between seamless or sluggish performance. With the introduction of Joule copilot navigation in SAP Fiori apps for extended warehouse management, SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 enhances user experience by guiding employees effortlessly to the most suitable applications for their tasks. This AI-driven assistance not only accelerates warehouse processes but also minimizes the need for extensive user training, ensuring employees can focus on their core responsibilities rather than app navigation. The real value lies in the comprehensive insights this innovation provides, empowering users to make informed decisions that enhance efficiency across operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Joule Navigation EWM.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330197i076479E777D5FB85/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Joule Navigation EWM.png" alt="Joule Navigation EWM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Eager to learn more? Consult our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/joule-capabilitiesjoule-capabilities-eac-199dd5b0a3044c07bfc1ecad291f43f2/finding-apps?state=DRAFT&amp;amp;version=DEV&amp;amp;q=Joule+navigation+in+SAP+Fiori+apps+for+extended+warehouse+management" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1427040956"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Management LoB&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1916957468"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creating follow-ups for in-house service objects with Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let’s have a look at the Service Management LoB. Here, Joule's AI-driven capabilities enable service managers to easily search, display, and create follow-ups for in-house service objects using conversational interactions. This human-centric approach optimizes daily tasks by allowing managers to seamlessly access critical information and act upon it without the need for complex navigation. By streamlining these processes, service management teams can focus on what truly matters—delivering quality service to their customers. Such enhancements in task efficiency lead to more responsive service operations, ensuring a proactive approach toward managing service demands.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="in-house services_blog.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330789i1D1EEFD4558CA501/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="in-house services_blog.png" alt="in-house services_blog.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information, refer to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/joule-capabilitiesjoule-capabilities-eac-199dd5b0a3044c07bfc1ecad291f43f2/searching-for-in-house-services-and-service-objects?state=DRAFT&amp;amp;version=DEV" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1651884275"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Research and Development LoB&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--2141800787"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent project assistant capabilities with Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigating through a sea of data is commonplace in Research and Development (R&amp;amp;D) area, yet it doesn't have to be a drain on your team's creativity and productivity. The intelligent project assistant capabilities powered by Joule allow users to derive project data through natural language inquiries without the hassle of navigating multiple applications. This ease of access aids in quickly retrieving updates on project changes, identifying missing parts, and tracking due activities, all through Joule’s conversational interface. By supporting informational, navigational, and transactional capabilities, Joule transforms project management into a streamlined process, helping teams stay focused on innovation rather than administrative tasks. Moreover, the ability to open projects and WBS elements directly through Joule means that users can engage with their data more efficiently, fostering a productive and satisfied work environment. With these enhancements, businesses can ensure that their R&amp;amp;D projects are not only well managed but also effectively advancing toward their goals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="R&amp;amp;D_Joule Assistant Capab.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330199i1B5988E62D1659DE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="R&amp;amp;D_Joule Assistant Capab.png" alt="R&amp;amp;D_Joule Assistant Capab.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1956653004"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Navigating Bill of Materials with Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine a workspace, where accessing Bill of Materials (BoM) is as straightforward as asking a colleague for the latest update, that's the seamless interaction Joule brings to the table. This AI-assisted natural language capability supports end users in navigating and managing BoM scenarios with ease, removing previous barriers to information. With Joule, users can effortlessly access header information, query BoMs by material-plant combinations, and select specific items, all through simple conversational prompts. Such simplification boosts productivity, allowing R&amp;amp;D teams to devote more time to product innovation and less to administrative navigation. By transforming BoM management into an intuitive, efficient process, Joule empowers users to make informed decisions, enhancing operational efficiency and ultimately driving business success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="BOM_new.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330204i1A3DF919F9D549AA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BOM_new.png" alt="BOM_new.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, refer to the &lt;A href="applewebdata://212989B8-9EB4-404F-9A2D-93F58B2AB362/For%20more%20information,%20you%20can%20refer%20to%20%5bSAP%20Help%20on%20Fetching%20BoM%20Information%5d(https:/help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/fetch-bill-of-material-information)." target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1760139499"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1563625994"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Enabled Precision in Handling Change Records&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Research and Development, managing change records is often time-consuming and complex. Teams must sift through detailed information, track overdue items, and ensure compliance – all of which takes attention away from innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine handling change records as effortlessly as discussing project milestones with your team – this is the transformative experience Joule brings to R&amp;amp;D operations. Joule simplifies interactions around change records, offering users intuitive access to detailed information at both header and item levels. By expediting the summarization process and enabling status changes, Joule ensures that overdue change records are discovered and addressed promptly, promoting efficient workflow and compliance. The capability to find records based on criteria such as product and reason for change further streamlines the management process, enabling teams to focus on innovation rather than paperwork. With these enhancements, R&amp;amp;D departments can make informed decisions more swiftly, driving their projects forward with the confidence that change management is both smooth and reliable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Change Record.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330206i4C19CEDA6A328568/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Change Record.png" alt="Change Record.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more details, refer to the dedicated pages on &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/summarizing-change-record-information" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;summarizing change record information&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/fetch-change-record-information" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;fetching change record information&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1660515496"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Portfolio and Project Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1170598984"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Streamlined project financials with Joule’s AI assistance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Handling complex financial data is one of the biggest hurdles in Enterprise Portfolio and Project Management. Now, picture managing a multifaceted project with the ease of a friendly chat – that’s the vision Joule brings to life. With enhanced project assistant capabilities, Joule enables users to seamlessly access project financial and master data through intuitive natural language interactions. Gone are the days of toggling through applications and complex reports; now, project system users can effortlessly retrieve and summarize financial insights, aligning their focus on high-value tasks. This AI-driven ease not only boosts user satisfaction but also streamlines data collection and consolidation, making project management more efficient and effective. As a result, project teams can better navigate financial landscapes, ensuring that each decision supports the strategic vision. By leveraging Joule’s summarization and analytical prowess, organizations can enhance precision in project financial control, translating insights into impactful actions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="EPPM2.png" style="width: 221px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330211i1BED4BDDBA759698/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="EPPM2.png" alt="EPPM2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information, refer to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/enterprise-portfolio-and-project-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1267488486"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1070974981"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we have explored, the SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 release introduces a transformative suite of AI-driven innovations that redefine what’s possible in enterprise operations. By harnessing the power of specialized agentic AI and Joule, businesses are now equipped to navigate complexities with clarity and precision, leading to optimized processes and strategic growth. We’re excited for you to experience these advancements firsthand and to see how they can empower your organization to achieve its goals with new-found efficiency and insight. Thank you for joining us on this journey through the future of intelligent enterprise solutions. Stay connected for more updates by following the &lt;SPAN&gt;with the PSCC_Enablement tag&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;as we continue to innovate and shape the path forward for businesses worldwide. &lt;SPAN&gt;Don't forget to follow me (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40565" target="_self"&gt;@Yannick_PTT&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;) in the community as well as on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yannickpeterschmitt/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to not miss any updates and insights.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information on intelligent capabilities integrated SAP Cloud ERP Private, explore the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/joule-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-956677396" id="toc-hId-874461476"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/5fc51e30e2744f168642e26e0c1d9be1?Product_Line=SAP+S/4HANA;SAP+S/4HANA+and+SAP+S/4HANA+Cloud+Private+Edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="https://news.sap.com/2025/10/sap-cloud-erp-private-2025-release-innovation-impact/" href="https://news.sap.com/2025/10/sap-cloud-erp-private-2025-release-innovation-impact/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;From Innovation to Impact: SAP Cloud ERP Private 2025 Release (SAP News Center)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD_PE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Help Portal SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/what-s-new-for-joule-capabilities?version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What`s New for Joule Capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73554900100800000266&amp;amp;PRODUCT=73555000100800004663" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Roadmap Explorer for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/sap-s-4hana-product-expert-training?userlogin=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Suite Product Expert Training 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://chart-bdmaicr0au.dispatcher.eu2.hana.ondemand.com/index.html?hc_reset" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="PSCC Wheel.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330225i3B23C9CEE40C671B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="PSCC Wheel.png" alt="PSCC Wheel.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ai-innovations-in-sap-cloud-erp-private-2025/ba-p/14249159"/>
    <published>2025-10-24T09:18:52.133000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ux-and-application-development-with-ai-at-asug-tech-connect-2025-a/ba-p/14252832</id>
    <title>UX and application development with AI at ASUG Tech Connect 2025 a companion event to SAP TechEd</title>
    <updated>2025-10-24T18:39:30.067000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PeterSpielvogel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/543</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This year, SAP TechEd has several options to allow you to learn about the latest SAP technologies and how to apply them to your organization. In addition to &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;TechEd in Berlin&lt;/A&gt; and the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;virtual&lt;/A&gt; option, there are “SAP TechEd On Tour” events in &lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/asug-tech-connect" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Louisville&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://events.masteringsap.com/sydney2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sydney&lt;/A&gt;, and &lt;A href="https://go4.events.sap.com/apj-savethedatetechedontourbangalore2025/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bangalore&lt;/A&gt;. In this post, I’ll share the sessions on application development and user experience that we are presenting at ASUG Tech Connect in Louisville, Kentucky. As you would expect many have AI -assisted capabilities to make both business users and developers more productive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PeterSpielvogel_0-1761323767225.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/332120i0FE9DE5752B30851/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PeterSpielvogel_0-1761323767225.png" alt="PeterSpielvogel_0-1761323767225.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At ASUG Tech Connect, we have both lectures and hands-on workshops.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lectures &lt;/STRONG&gt;are a chance to hear from SAP experts and have your questions answered in the room.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda?session=4d6f1642-85e2-4252-aaee-3af28873ec3b&amp;amp;shareLink=true" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Extensibility with ABAP Cloud and AI in SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/A&gt; (Jens Weiler)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore on-stack key user and developer tools in the ABAP Cloud development model, now enhanced with generative AI. Extend standard apps and manage custom ones in SAP Cloud ERP and explore transactional, analytical, and integration use cases like the extensibility AI assistant, queries for analytical SAP Fiori apps, and SQL services.&lt;BR /&gt;Tuesday, November 4, 2025, 11:15 AM-12:05 PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda?session=0691b1d5-cf70-45fd-bba8-b1043c308349&amp;amp;shareLink=true" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s Next: AI-First Innovations in SAP Cloud ERP and SAP Business Suite&lt;/A&gt; (Ullas Holla, Peter Spielvogel)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get a fast-paced look at how SAP is embedding AI and delivering cross-suite innovations that break down silos and speed up decision-making. We’ll cover the latest highlights from releases of SAP Cloud ERP and SAP Business Suite—plus give you a sneak peek at what’s coming in 2026 and beyond.&lt;BR /&gt;Tuesday, November 4, 2025, 3:30 PM-4:20 PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda?session=3a567dd4-0c26-460b-b297-f600995503ef&amp;amp;shareLink=true" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Customer Show and Tell: From CDS View to Fiori Launchpad: Full-Stack Development with Eclipse ADT with Naturipe&lt;/A&gt; (Brian Galloway, Dario Cruz)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session covers the end-to-end development workflow in the RISE with SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Private Edition environment using Eclipse ABAP Development Tools (ADT). It demonstrates how to define a data source and expose it via a CDS view, enabling consumption through SAP Fiori elements, Eclipse ADT, and Postman. A live demo illustrates the creation of a simple SAPUI5 application that consumes the same OData service and is deployed to the SAP Fiori Launchpad, showcasing full-stack integration from backend data modeling to frontend delivery.&lt;BR /&gt;Wednesday, November 5, 2025, 8:00 AM-9:30 AM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda?session=49dcc5e0-c8c1-4a5d-b50b-0d207c4c9925&amp;amp;shareLink=true" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using Generative AI to Accelerate SAP Fiori App Development&lt;/A&gt; (Ullas Holla)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI changes everything, especially for developing business applications. See how SAP’s latest coding agents let you build SAP Fiori elements apps using a conversational interface. Create apps using Joule, including a CAP service, sample data, and SAPUI5 customizations.&lt;BR /&gt;Wednesday, November 5, 2025, 4:10 PM-5:00 PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda?session=c82cf156-8203-47a2-8515-1ca1ca2ba24b&amp;amp;shareLink=true" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating Better User Experiences with AI-Powered SAP Fiori Apps&lt;/A&gt; (Peter Spielvogel)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how the latest AI features in SAP Fiori apps enhance user productivity and streamline onboarding. Starting with My Home and diving into commonly used SAP Fiori apps, see how AI simplifies information access, supports informed business decisions, and fosters seamless collaboration. Explore how conversational interactions are making SAP more intuitive than ever.&lt;BR /&gt;Thursday, November 6, 2025, 4:15 PM-5:05 PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hands-on workshops &lt;/STRONG&gt;give you the opportunity to test the latest SAP innovations and gain access to the same tools and technologies we use to build apps for SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda?session=f181974d-585f-43a9-97ef-30cd0574d949&amp;amp;shareLink=true" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hands-on Lab: Get Started with ABAP Cloud for Classic ABAP Developers&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Familiar with classic ABAP development? Explore how similar development works with ABAP Cloud using the ABAP RESTful application programming model. Use ABAP Cloud to build cloud-ready business apps, services, and extensions that follow clean core principles by default—on SAP Business Technology Platform and in any edition of SAP S/4HANA.&lt;BR /&gt;Tuesday, November 4, 2025, 1:10 PM-3:10 PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda?session=2682f82f-fbb2-4989-a7f3-d6aa1548d32e&amp;amp;shareLink=true" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hands-on Lab: Explore Joule for Developers, ABAP AI Capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn how to develop transactional applications using the ABAP RESTful application model in ABAP Cloud while leveraging Joule capabilities for ABAP developers.&lt;BR /&gt;Wednesday, November 5, 2025, 8:00 AM-10:00 AM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda?session=aa78a571-9325-4161-a0b3-e9d87184b311&amp;amp;shareLink=true" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hands-on Lab: Build On-Stack Extensions with ABAP Cloud in SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how to build extensions, applications, and services with the ABAP Cloud development model, using the ABAP RESTful application programming model and generative AI. You can explore how to extend standard SAP applications, consume public SAP APIs, and build new apps and services from scratch while getting practical insights through exercises&lt;BR /&gt;Wednesday, November 5, 2025, 1:00 PM-3:00 PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.asug.com/event/e7bd56fe-4c89-4e90-bc2c-ff75b4cc099b/agenda?session=fd8dd51b-0257-4fdf-b04e-7ba12e239d85&amp;amp;shareLink=true" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hands-on Lab: Modernize Classic Extensions for Clean Core in SAP Cloud ERP Private&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Practice clean core extensibility in SAP Cloud ERP Private. Learn how to govern clean core development using the ABAP test cockpit, and how to use the ABAP Cloud development model and clean core extensibility principles to modernize your custom on-stack extensions.&lt;BR /&gt;Thursday, November 6, 2025, 1:00 PM-3:00 PM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope you can join us.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/ux-and-application-development-with-ai-at-asug-tech-connect-2025-a/ba-p/14252832"/>
    <published>2025-10-24T18:39:30.067000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
