<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Careers-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Careers</title>
  <updated>2025-10-16T11:10:25.759758+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Careers/pd-p/724690177700823984208969627109459" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Careers blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/breaking-out-of-comfort-zones-the-learning-journey-of-danielle-larocca/ba-p/13885575</id>
    <title>Breaking Out of Comfort Zones: The Learning Journey of Danielle Larocca</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T09:00:00.035000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anne_Lenhardt94</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39755</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There is no doubt that the way we learn today has changed – dramatically. “I remember what it was like to attend SAP training classes back in the late 90’s”, Danielle Larocca recounts, “back then they were hosted onsite only and you would get paper-based certificates via a small ceremony each time.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It was 1995, and for Danielle, her SAP HCM and Payroll reporting experience was just about to start. She was working for Doubleday Direct, which later became a Bertelsmann AG and AOL Time Warner Partnership in Garden City, New York. The company had decided to implement SAP amidst fears that their legacy payroll system would cease functioning in the Y2K era. And as part of the implementation project, she was sent off for ABAP/4 training.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning all about AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today, the learning experience looks very different for the global VP for Strategic Alliances. “Over the past several months, I have been dedicating my educational hours to all things AI.” What else would it be in the year 2024? The SAP Mentor started writing a series of blogs, ranging from &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/picture-me-its-made-entirely-ai-danielle-larocca%3FtrackingId=JUbFl3ZIT4uUc2nIrxNeMA%253D%253D/?trackingId=JUbFl3ZIT4uUc2nIrxNeMA%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-generated headshots&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, to functional &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/daniellelaroccasap_epiuselabs-ai-hxm-activity-7092870962244681728-aYLi/%22%20/t%20%22_blank" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;video avatars&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/did-you-know-i-can-speak-five-languages-danielle-larocca-dvlic%3FtrackingId=4J0JCcjQSieqg%252B3W9j7yCQ%253D%253D/?trackingId=4J0JCcjQSieqg%2B3W9j7yCQ%3D%3D%22%20\t%20%22_blank" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;video language conversions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Her work – and learning experience – has become way more digital, fast-paced, and versatile compared to previous decades. “I have even let &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/daniellelaroccasap_the-latest-article-in-my-ai-series-is-out-activity-7150185480947396608-7b-Q?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI write a blog post for me&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and make a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.epiuselabs.com/lets-talk-hcm/sap-hcm-for-s/4hana-on-premise-h4s4-an-ai-generated-ppt" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ppt for me&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;", she highlights. “I also make an effort to share a weekly #&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/daniellelaroccasap_sap-ai-activity-7213917980567441408-W9EA?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI Byte on LinkedIn&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; that shares with others some key topics on AI that should be on their radar.” No doubt that the way she learns and the topics she learns about have changed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F_8lhkhQeg_w%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D_8lhkhQeg_w&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F_8lhkhQeg_w%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="SAP Learning Hub: Stay Ahead with Certifications and Continuous Learning" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But there is more to is, says Danielle: “My life has changed in the sense that I have gone outside my comfort zone.” Moving away from HCM, Payroll, and reporting – her familiar turf – Danielle started to learn about technologies outside of her world, “to expand my horizon on the art of the possible with what technology can do.” Her latest achievement: The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Introducing SAP Business AI Commercial Model”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;learning journey on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, which rewarded her with an official record of achievement to demonstrate her expertise.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adapting to changing technologies is important&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, Danielle admits that learning a new skill sometimes comes with a small damper: “It is hard to A) carve out the time and B) learn something new but it is rewarding and exciting to be in the loop on the latest technological advancements that will transform our everyday lives.” As we get older, she states, “it's easy to settle into our homeostasis of what we know and what we are experts on and it's easy to stay in that comfort zone, but it does not allow for personal growth.” According to Danielle, we all must adapt and learn new things to survive and thrive, especially in an ever-changing technological evolution climate.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“With all that said I have carved out time from my very busy schedule to learn something new each week.&amp;nbsp; I call it my education hours and they usually fall on a Sunday night.&amp;nbsp; I am committed to learning something new for 2 hours every week that is outside the scope of my day-to-day life and it involves some form of cutting-edge tech, for me its AI.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How do you learn? Share!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How do you tackle learning a new skill? Let us know about your strategy in the comments and start your next chapter of boosting your career with future-focused learning on the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC-learnerstory" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt; today.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/breaking-out-of-comfort-zones-the-learning-journey-of-danielle-larocca/ba-p/13885575"/>
    <published>2024-10-04T09:00:00.035000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/come-say-hi-at-an-sap-teched-tour-stop/ba-p/13895409</id>
    <title>Come Say Hi at an SAP TechEd Tour Stop</title>
    <updated>2024-10-10T16:55:42.974000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anne_Lenhardt94</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39755</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It’s a wrap! Yes, sadly, SAP TechEd Virtual is already over, but it’s been a blast! But the good news is: If you want to continue to learn, network, and bring out your best, you can still participate in one of five &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd on Tour or SAPinsider events&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; worldwide – with learning sessions and meet-ups with SAP experts. Here’s what you need to know to come and say “Hi”:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is offering five separate tour stops around the globe, organized in collaboration with SAP user groups. Each stop will offer hands-on learning opportunities, deep-dive lecture sessions, and meet-the-experts all presented by SAP experts, partners, and many customers. We are also bringing back the Developer Garage for you as a great opportunity to learn by doing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Choose the US or Europe to meet SAP experts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From November 12-14, join technical practitioners and SAP experts at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ASUG Tech Connect 2024&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in West Palm Beach for immersive sessions, SAP insights, and networking. Over three days, you'll enhance your skills, stay at the forefront of digital advancements, and grow professionally.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you prefer a trip to Europe, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPinsider EMEA 2024&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in Copenhagen, Denmark, is for you. From November 12-14, you can develop&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; the skills and expertise needed to thrive in your role. Hear from customers about their successful digital transformations, learn implementation best practices from SAP partners, and connect with peers and SAP experts in a three-day learning event aligned with SAP TechEd Virtual.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get an overview of the SAP ecosystem in Australia&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you fancy a trip to Down Under, we’re excited to meet you at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAUG-x 2024&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; this year! From November 19-20 you can learn from unique insights, network with your peers, hear from SAP experts, and get an overview of our ecosystem. Don’t miss these relevant knowledge sharing, learning, and networking sessions – all in Melbourne, Australia!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And if you’re still in the mood for SAP TechEd by December, join us in Birmingham, UK, at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;UKISUG Connect 2024&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. At the ICC in Birmingham, expect to learn from experts, network with like-minded peers and collaborate together. Benefit from knowledge-rich keynotes, engaging breakout sessions, a range of workshops and an exhibition hall of over 70 SAP partners.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Last, but not least, head over to the motherland of SAP – Germany – and join us at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DSAG-TechXchange 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on April 4, 2025! Yes, it might be a couple of months away, but having your next trip planned is always a nice thing, don’t you think?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whichever location you prefer – we are looking forward to seeing you there! Make use of the unique opportunity to connect with like-minded individuals, gain valuable insights into the tech industry, and get hands-on experience with the latest SAP technologies. Whether you're a developer, architect, IT manager, or business executive, SAP TechEd on Tour has something for everyone. Don't miss out on this opportunity to stay ahead of the curve and propel your tech career to new heights!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For more information on the SAP TechEd on Tour stops, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-TechEd" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;visit this page&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And while you’re at it, make sure to attend &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/eb-p/codejam-events?source=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC-TechEd" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP CodeJam events&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in your area - free, hands-on coding experiences where you can collaborate with fellow developers to solve real-world challenges while diving deep into the latest SAP technologies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/come-say-hi-at-an-sap-teched-tour-stop/ba-p/13895409"/>
    <published>2024-10-10T16:55:42.974000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/kickstart-your-career-become-an-sap-certified-solution-transformation/ba-p/13913961</id>
    <title>Kickstart your Career: Become an SAP-Certified Solution Transformation Consultant</title>
    <updated>2024-10-21T14:59:22.019000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>YannickRutt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140352</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In a fast-paced world where companies rely on adaptation and transformation to have success, the role of the solution transformation consultant takes center stage. SAP Solution Transformation Consultants are responsible for guiding the entire business transformation journey, from initial design to final deployment, using a comprehensive end-to-end toolchain. They play a crucial role in accelerating transformation projects by leveraging best practices and ensuring high-quality business outcomes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;They navigate through digital landscapes and guide customers on a transformative journey from traditional ERP systems to the innovative SAP S/4HANA Cloud. Envision playing a central role in the RISE with SAP initiative, empowering enterprises to surge ahead in their market spaces. And with this brand-new role-based certification, we are helping you to achieve this goal.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are you ready to shape the future of business transformation?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check out our&amp;nbsp;brand-new role-based certification &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-solution-transformation-consultant-with-sap-cloud-alm?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Certified Associate - Solution Transformation Consultant with SAP Cloud ALM&lt;/A&gt;. This certification validates that you possess&amp;nbsp;the application lifecycle management skills and core knowledge in SAP Cloud ALM required for the consultant profile. By getting certified, you&amp;nbsp;demonstrate&amp;nbsp;that&amp;nbsp;you&amp;nbsp;have a comprehensive understanding, and the in-depth skills required to lead a project team as a solution transformation consultant, guiding the team through the solution transformation journey using SAP Cloud ALM.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start with this free learning journey&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To get started, take the new free, self-paced learning journey&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/transforming-for-success-solution-transformation-with-sap-cloud-alm?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;"Transforming for Success: Solution Transformation with SAP Cloud ALM"&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp; In just 16 hours – divided into six sections– you will learn how SAP Cloud ALM, as part of SAP's transformation approach, supports the entire solution transformation journey—from business and solution transformation methodology to agile implementation and efficient operations. After completing this learning journey, you will have the skills to leverage SAP Cloud ALM for comprehensive solution transformation and have an overview of SAP's business transformation strategy.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you want to learn more about how SAP can help you accelerate digital transformation, check out the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/accelerating-digital-transformation-an-insider-s-journey-to-sap-cloud-alm/ba-p/13851761?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC" target="_blank"&gt;story of Martina Ohlerth&lt;/A&gt; and benefit from her first-hand experience!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Certified learners need to continuously keep their skills up-to-date and certifications valid by completing mandatory assessments before their certification expires. With an&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/training-certification/learning-hub.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning Hub&lt;/A&gt; subscription, you can prepare for and take the stay certified assessments at any time during the validity period of your certification.&amp;nbsp; If you want to know more on how to get and stay certified, you can read &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/ba-p/13660165?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC" target="_blank"&gt;this blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open new professional opportunities for you with new learning and a sought-after certification. Build the skills you need on the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt; and get inspired by reading learner stories on &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;, ask questions and connect with fellow learners. When you’re ready, take your certification exam and start shaping your industry's future!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/kickstart-your-career-become-an-sap-certified-solution-transformation/ba-p/13913961"/>
    <published>2024-10-21T14:59:22.019000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/career-corner-blog-posts/coach-s-corner-the-essential-act-of-receiving/ba-p/13910451</id>
    <title>Coach's Corner: The Essential Act of Receiving</title>
    <updated>2024-10-24T16:26:42.184000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jason_Cao</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15694</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1072812346"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When organizations start out on the path of creating a “Feedback Culture,” they are so focused on the delivery methodology that they forget the important other-half of the equation – receiving.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="toa-heftiba-_UIVmIBB3JU-unsplash.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/181394iBAFAD976CE12D4B4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="toa-heftiba-_UIVmIBB3JU-unsplash.jpg" alt="toa-heftiba-_UIVmIBB3JU-unsplash.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-876298841"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-679785336"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Give. Give. Give.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s no wonder. In the West especially, we are instructed by faith leaders to “Give, and you will receive.” Since we were young, we were taught by parents and teachers to share, because “sharing means caring.” In school, we were expected to give our opinions, ask questions and share ideas as part of the learning process. We are encouraged to give compliments because this will result in making friends and keeping neighbours happy. In life, this ‘Pay It Forward’ mindset spawns an entire industry of charities and crowd-funding outlets for doing-good. Finally, at work, we are expected to join training programs and learn how to give feedback to our colleagues, our managers, our suppliers and even our customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-483271831"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-286758326"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To receive.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;By contrast, in Eastern societies, children are taught to receive. I mean receiving in the way of accepting, and want to distinguish this from ‘taking.’ The main role of children in the East is to receive the resources, opportunities and energy of their parents and elders, and to focus on studying and preparing for the future. From a very young age, they were taught to listen in class and receive the knowledge of their teachers. When it comes to work and life, the practice of receiving shows up as acceptance and common understanding of each person’s role in a team and in an organization. The Taoist tenet to “be like water” shapes the values, and therefore the mindset and behaviours of many in Eastern society.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We seem to have an easier time giving feedback, advice and opinions, yet struggle with receiving them when they are offered to us. See my post “&lt;A href="https://stonesoupcoaching.wordpress.com/2024/03/19/feedback-the-gift-thats-hard-to-accept/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Feedback: The Gift That’s Hard to Accept&lt;/A&gt;” for reasons why we struggle with this. One action is not better than the other. However, without the corresponding practice of receiving there would be no value in the feedback. By receiving and accepting someone’s gift, we also honour them and fulfill their good intentions. The combination of both giving and receiving completes the equation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-90244821"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How do we become better at receiving?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Be present&amp;nbsp;– Preparing our mind, our breath, and our emotions isn’t just reserved for delivering presentations or giving bad news. We must also prepare ourselves to receive, by calming our mind and focusing on the person we’re with. If you’re not in a state to receive, then you’re not going to get the maximum benefit of the gift.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assume best intentions&amp;nbsp;– Our biases and interpretations stand in the way of learning. Focus on the content and the words to remove biases of who may be delivering the message. This also means keeping your ego in check – even the most junior member of your team or the most unexpected source can offer you value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Be curious and ask questions&amp;nbsp;– Some of us need to overcome our default to only give, while others may need to strengthen our propensity to receive. Our ability to receive can be learned and reinforced by asking simple questions. For example, “Would you be OK if I asked for some more feedback in the future?”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our life, there will be times when we see things as opposing each other – ebb and flow; push and pull; Yin and Yang; workers and management. When we choose to look at these forces as part of the same system, they are actually complimentary. In developing a Culture of Feedback, we need to be as good at receiving as we are at giving.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[Reposted from the &lt;A href="https://stonesoupcoaching.wordpress.com/2024/03/22/the-essential-act-of-receiving/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Stone Soup Coaching blog&lt;/A&gt;]&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/career-corner-blog-posts/coach-s-corner-the-essential-act-of-receiving/ba-p/13910451"/>
    <published>2024-10-24T16:26:42.184000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/education-determination-and-tech-how-pegah-integrated-and-succeeded/ba-p/13925240</id>
    <title>Education, Determination, and Tech: How Pegah Integrated and Succeeded</title>
    <updated>2024-10-31T17:00:52.487000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anne_Lenhardt94</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39755</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;“My way to set foot in Germany was through education – that's how I integrated.” When speaking about her journey from a refugee to a woman in tech @ SAP – that’s how Pegah Eghbali Alamdari titled one of her speaking engagements – you would have never guessed that she struggled with public speaking. “This fear was always there, like a shadow.” But today feels different for the 33-year-old, who always dreamt of working at SAP.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Pegah and her sister were born in Iran, but her parents early on decided that their girls shouldn’t grow up in their home country. When the family fled, Pegah was merely seven years old. “My father went ahead, he wanted to get us to Germany quickly, but that didn't work out right away, so Pegah, her sister, and their mother made a two-month journey to Germany”, she explains. And when they were finally reunited, life looked very different suddenly: “new culture, new language, new people”, Pegah says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP was the big goal&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But one thing she recognized, felt comfortable with, was math. “As a universal language, math was one of the few things I knew from my previous life and understood without needing to speak the language. That’s what I knew and how I could show what I was capable of. Thanks to my achievements in math, I was able to belong.” She graduated with success and went on to study medical informatics. “And when I studied, the big goal was SAP.”&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Pegah and her sister were born in Iran, but her parents early on decided that their girls shouldn’t grow up in their home country." style="width: 267px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/185686iFBF5CAF4E717F23B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Pegah 2.jpg" alt="Pegah and her sister were born in Iran, but her parents early on decided that their girls shouldn’t grow up in their home country." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Pegah and her sister were born in Iran, but her parents early on decided that their girls shouldn’t grow up in their home country.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Four years ago, she was hired and now works as a Senior Technology Consultant in Cybersecurity and Compliance. “Our team ensures that our customers' S4HANA systems are secure and compliant”, she explains, adding that her expertise is in authorizations. “I help customers by developing secure authorization concepts for their S4HANA systems. I am rarely on-site with customers, which allows me to work very flexibly and support multiple projects at the same time.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"You have to face your fears"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But besides projects at work, there’s also other projects close to her heart: As a volunteer, Pegah taught math in Zanzibar (Tansania), passing on what was her path to success: education. “I want to show everyone that you can be successful and that you can do it, if you want it.” According to her, hard work and passion are essential to make dreams come true. “You have to face your fears, put the goal above everything else”, she advises. Adding: “And you must be prepared to learn something new.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pegah shares, "I feel like life moves really quickly. To not fall behind tomorrow, it's important to realize that life itself is a school. If we stop learning, we'll eventually just stay in one place. I know I love learning, so I want to absorb as much as I can to move forward with the best." Learning about secure authorization concepts for SAP systems has allowed her to be more efficient and provide valuable support to her customers. Pegah reflects on her journey, saying, "I have received an important voice which means to have the power to make a difference".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Started a non-profit organization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition to professional growth, the knowledge she has gained empowered her to give back to the community. Pegah has started with her sister and two other SAP colleagues (Cigdem Guendogdu and Dilara Yarar) a non-profit organization names “BLESSMANITY Germany e.V.” that focuses on improving access to education for children in developing countries.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Currently they are building a canteen at a kindergarten in Zanzibar to ensure that the children receive a nutritious meal once a day. The skills she has mastered have given her the confidence and capability to make a difference in the lives of those in need.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Pegah, learning new skills has been life-changing, giving her a sense of purpose and the power to create a positive impact. Pegah shares, "I want to inspire people and be a role model, showing that integration and success are possible through education, determination, discipline, and courage. Anything is possible in life. I am very grateful for everything I have received in life and see it as my duty to give back."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning offers life-changing potential&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Her personal story is a testament to the countless benefits of learning and growing. Whether it's professional growth, work-life balance, or the ability to make a difference, the advantages are significant and impactful.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you’re considering learning and growing, Pegah’s story is a compelling reminder of the life-changing potential it holds. Whether it’s for professional advancement or personal fulfilment, learning SAP skills could also be the right path for you. Benefit from tailored and self-paced learning opportunities that meet you when and where you learn best on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Get certified to demonstrate your expertise and boost your career.  &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/education-determination-and-tech-how-pegah-integrated-and-succeeded/ba-p/13925240"/>
    <published>2024-10-31T17:00:52.487000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/what-you-need-to-get-and-stay-certified/ba-p/13927850</id>
    <title>What you need to get and stay certified</title>
    <updated>2024-11-04T16:26:14.191000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anne_Lenhardt94</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39755</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please ask a question in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Q&amp;amp;A area" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/qa-p/learningqanda-board" target="_blank"&gt;Q&amp;amp;A area&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our SAP Learning Experts will get back to you as soon as possible!&amp;nbsp;We are here to support you.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;There’s no doubt about the tangible and compelling benefits of an IT certification. According to the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://home.pearsonvue.com/About/News/2023/2023-Value-of-IT-Certification-Candidate-Report.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“2023 Value of IT Certification Candidate Report”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; by Pearson VUE, 79% of certified individuals received or anticipated a salary increase after getting certified. 81% of them produced a higher quality of work – besides the fact that 92% felt more confident in their abilities. So, getting certified makes sense.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But how do you get certified in the first place? And more importantly: How do you stay certified? You’ll find out in this blog post!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s start with the basics: A new certification program and offering&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The demand for skilled IT professionals is expected to grow dramatically – up 23% by 2031 in the United States alone, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap.sharepoint.com/:p:/t/SAPLearningEngagement-ProductMarketing/Ean3SU04PLlIqKwQ8FqNCZwBvKuvAWPLCmnVXMGbrfzBwA?e=7YDDyU" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;according to the U.S. Department of Labor&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. This pace of change and the talent shortage call for a new approach to identifying future-focused skills and the necessity of staying up to date. To help meet these new circumstances, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certification-transformation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP enhanced its certification program&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in the beginning of 2024 with the launch of the enhanced SAP Learning Hub.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FkSZlsBMqcFg%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DkSZlsBMqcFg&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FkSZlsBMqcFg%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="Unlocking Opportunities with SAP Certification: Your Key to Success" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One subscription for all certification resources&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The great thing about the enhanced SAP Learning Hub is that you can both get and stay certified with one single subscription to the premium, guided learning offering. Once subscribed, you get &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;access to future-focused learning content, expert guidance in live sessions, on-demand access to hands-on practice systems, and enhanced analytics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When you’re ready to get certified, you don’t need to worry about buying certification attempts like in the past: Four attempts per year are already included and once successfully passed, your SAP Certification is valid for 12 months! You can then continuously expand the validity of your certification by passing the yearly assessments to stay certified.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Can I still buy single certification attempts?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don’t worry – if you wanted to buy &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/cer001-sap-certification-exam-one-attempt-certification-online-010-us-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;one&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; or &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/cer006-sap-certification-exam-six-attempts-certification-online-010-us-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;six&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; SAP Certification attempts like in the past – you still can. But there are some things you should consider: You can still complete all your learning, successfully pass the exam, and demonstrate your expertise with your badge for 12 months.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, after one year, you will need to re-certify – leaving you with two options: 1. Subscribing to the enhanced SAP Learning Hub, where stay certified assessments are included or 2. buying a new SAP Certification exam attempt. But that would mean you had to retake the full certification exam as well.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s the difference between the SAP Certification exam and the stay certified assessment?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Great that you ask – because the difference is big! As said, as a subscriber to SAP Learning Hub, your annual stay certified assessments are included in your subscription. But in contrast to classic SAP Certification exams, stay certified assessments are short, not proctored quizzes with unlimited trials. They test only the knowledge between releases to make sure learners stay continuously up to date with the solution updates. Plus: To prepare for your assessment, you have access to dedicated learning materials, like live sessions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The rules for an SAP Certification exam are different: The exams are proctored and can typically take up to three hours. Candidates are required to answer 40-80 questions, out of which 60-70% correctly to pass the exam. If candidates fail the exam, they need to repurchase an SAP Certification exam attempt and retake the exam.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, what’s the recommendation here?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Of course, this totally depends on your role and personal learning preferences. However, we do see the benefits of opting for the SAP Learning Hub subscription. With one single subscription, you can get access to all resources you need to prepare for certification, take the exams with four included attempts and stay certified – at better value than ever before.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To learn more about the ways to get and stay certified, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;visit &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/frequently-asked-questions#sap-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;this FAQ&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and let us know in the comments about the benefits you had thanks to SAP Certifications!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/what-you-need-to-get-and-stay-certified/ba-p/13927850"/>
    <published>2024-11-04T16:26:14.191000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/empowering-your-sap-journey-insights-from-sap-champions-and-mentors/ba-p/13929979</id>
    <title>Empowering Your SAP Journey: Insights from SAP Champions and Mentors</title>
    <updated>2024-11-06T11:31:19.306000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anne_Lenhardt94</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39755</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;As tech professionals, we understand the importance of staying ahead in the constantly evolving tech industry. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Thanks to the cloud, SAP is innovating every day – and we need (and want to) keep up with the speed. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;That’s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; not only true for newcomers in the field, but also for well-versed professionals like SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Mentors and SAP Champions.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Listen to the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;top influencers, contributors, and advocates within the SAP ecosystem &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;and learn why you should invest in continuous learning, SAP skills, and certification now, with this new video series:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F_8lhkhQeg_w%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D_8lhkhQeg_w&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F_8lhkhQeg_w%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="SAP Learning Hub: Stay Ahead with Certifications and Continuous Learning" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The first video, "Stay Ahead with Certifications and Continuous Learning," features SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Mentors emphasizing the importance of continuous learning and certifications in keeping up with the fast-paced tech industry. They share their own experiences and insights on how SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;C&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ertifications have helped them stay ahead in their careers. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kL2SbQvtSQU" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;"Empowering Your Digital Transformation with SAP"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; delves into the topic of digital transformation and how SAP is at the forefront of enabling companies to prepare for and embrace this transformation. The SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Mentors share their insights on the importance of aligning with SAP's digital transformation strategy and how it can drive success for businesses in today's digital age.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FXOVZ6jNdvaw%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DXOVZ6jNdvaw&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FXOVZ6jNdvaw%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="Stay Ahead with AI: Unlock New Skills with SAP Learning" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In the next video, "Leveraging AI Resources to Drive Innovation and Efficiency," SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Mentors discuss the role of AI in driving innovation and increasing efficiency within the SAP ecosystem, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;providing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; valuable advice on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;leveraging&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; these resources effectively. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FW7BiC7P7qJ0%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DW7BiC7P7qJ0&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FW7BiC7P7qJ0%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="Master SAP Learning: Stay Updated with New Products and Skills" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To wrap up, "Unlocking Potential with SAP Learning Hub" focuses on the power of SAP Learning Hub in providing valuable resources and training for tech professionals. The Mentors share their thoughts on how SAP Learning Hub has played a crucial role in their professional development and how it can benefit others in the SAP community. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the words of our SAP Mentors:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“SAP Certifications have never been easier to get. Now you simply just go to learning.sap.com and you can access all of the learning content.“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5526"&gt;@DanielleLarocca&lt;/a&gt;, SAP Partner, Strategic Alliances, EPI-USE Labs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“One of the most important things to our customers and partners is to keep up with all this latest innovation. That is why it’s so important to take a look at the new learning journey around the SAP Business AI portfolio.“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;– &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11760"&gt;@DiegoDora&lt;/a&gt;, SAP Partner, Founder, CEO and Chief Architect at Diff Consulting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Start your own success story today and head over to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; now!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/empowering-your-sap-journey-insights-from-sap-champions-and-mentors/ba-p/13929979"/>
    <published>2024-11-06T11:31:19.306000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/career-corner-blog-posts/coach-s-corner-be-water-and-let-your-career-flow/ba-p/13943815</id>
    <title>Coach's Corner - Be Water and Let Your Career Flow</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T17:26:43.378000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jason_Cao</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15694</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The phrase "Be water" is most&amp;nbsp;famously associated with Bruce Lee, the martial artist, movie star and philosopher. He shared this idea during an interview in 1971, where he explained the concept of adaptability and flexibility. His full quote is:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;"Empty your mind, be formless, shapeless—like water. Now you put water in a cup, it becomes the cup; You put water into a bottle, it becomes the bottle; You put it in a teapot, it becomes the teapot. Now water can flow or it can crash. Be water, my friend."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="generatedImage (1).png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/193527i41FF31ADC92CE7D9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="generatedImage (1).png" alt="generatedImage (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;(image generated by AI)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Bruce Lee was influenced by Taoism. Taoism, particularly through its foundational text, the &lt;EM&gt;Tao Te Ching&lt;/EM&gt; by Laozi, heavily emphasizes the concept of "being like water" and "going with the flow." This philosophy emphasizes being adaptable, flexible, and able to adjust to different circumstances, much like water takes the shape of whatever contains it.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;The parallel I'd like to draw between our careers and being like water comes from a recent conversation I had with a senior recruiter at SAP. One of the most challenging part of his job was to explain to job seekers (especially young applicants within the same organization) why they weren't picked to interview for a position that was 2 or 3 pay-grades higher than their current role. Getting an interview in this circumstance is rare, and the chances of getting the job is even slimmer. His advice for job seekers is to have the right expectations and get to know the process. This advice is basic but essential, and isn't unique to SAP but applies to almost all seeking to progress upwards in any organization.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Every organization has a flow - a rhythm, cycle or way of doing things. It has established processes, schedules and systems to regulate hiring, assess skills, provide training, manage performance, distribute pay, promotions and raises, and plan for leadership succession. By knowing what the rhythm is and adapting your expectations and actions to fit this flow, you will not only be more successful but also encounter greater satisfaction with your career trajectory.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;If you've ever done the opposite and tried to go against the established process within a company, you'll know it is like swimming against a river's current. The likely outcome is greater fatigue and missing your target destination. Job seekers and employees who expect and push for changes off-cycle to the company's flow often end up exhausted and frustrated with the results. Sure, it's possible for an intern to become CEO in the same organization, but the chances are miniscule and I usually advise a more pragmatic and achievable goal for my clients that involves manageable and realistic steps towards the aspirational goal.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1333841444"&gt;Be Content Without Being Complacent&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;While "going with the flow" inherently requires trust and patience with the system we're in, there is also a large dose of appreciation and contentment we must learn to adopt within ourselves. The pull-through benefit of adopting this approach is the reduction of stress and pressure we feel from unrealistic expectations (whether created by ourselves or by others) and better management of our scarcity mindset.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Being content with our current condition does not mean being stagnant in pursuing our personal aspirations and career growth. To move from a 'scarcity mindset' to an 'abundance mindset,' we must proactively manage our thoughts while intentionally managing our behaviours.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Here are 3 ways to remain content without being complacent:&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Continuous learning&lt;/STRONG&gt; - One of the first things to learn is the timing and schedule of relevant systems in your organization or the organization you're interested in working for. The goal is to understand how processes such as hiring, promotions, transfers and succession planning work in the organization. I would advocate spending time adapting your approach to the organizational flow, rather than trying to find back-doors, exceptions and ways to game the system.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build your network and relationships&lt;/STRONG&gt; - The best way I can recommend learning about a company's flow is from your network. This means building new connections, reconnect with those you've loss touch with, and maintaining your existing relationships. Even though career networking sites (like Glassdoor and LinkedIn) are available, speaking directly to your network of friends and acquaintances is the fastest and most trusted way to learn about a company's flow. Stay curious and ask lots of questions, and you might find you're actually pretty good at it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find help&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Whether it's a coach or a mentor, you can fast-track your efforts when you have a trusted advisor close by to support and sanity-check your plan. A good coach or mentor will not let you forget your strengths and accomplishments, and will encourage you to apply those experiences to achieve your short term and long term goals. They will also help you take stock of your achievements and put expectations into perspective. Ask for help to develop a strategy and tactics to use the company's flow to get you across faster, safely and on-track to reach your career destination.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Embracing the philosophy of "being like water" in your career means adapting to your organization's flow, understanding its processes, and aligning your expectations with its rhythm. By doing so, you'll not only increase your chances of success but also find greater satisfaction in your career journey. Remember, being content doesn't mean being complacent. Continuous learning, building your network, and seeking help from mentors or coaches are proactive ways to maintain an abundance mindset and propel your career forward. So, be water, my friend, and let your career flow.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(Blog reposted from stonesoupcoaching.wordpress.com&amp;nbsp;)&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/career-corner-blog-posts/coach-s-corner-be-water-and-let-your-career-flow/ba-p/13943815"/>
    <published>2024-11-21T17:26:43.378000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/customer-course-ux100-sap-fiori-foundation-available-for-sap-s-4hana-2023/ba-p/14033235</id>
    <title>Customer course UX100 (SAP Fiori – Foundation) available for SAP S/4HANA 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T08:39:54.134000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StefanFell</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4321</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The course development of the UX100 is (again) finished. Let’s summarize all the new and updated topics in a central place. Welcome to my fourth blog post about the customer training &lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/UX100" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;UX100 (SAP Fiori – Foundation)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are more interested in a digital learning for SAP Fiori, please read my blog post:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/03/22/sap-learning-learn-the-basics-of-sap-fiori/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning Course – Learning the Basics of SAP Fiori&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1704588103"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Starting in 2016, this is now the seventh incarnation of the introduction to SAP Fiori for on-premise. SAP Fiori moved on and therefore the UX100 moved on. With SAP S/4HANA 2023, the SAP Fiori groups are deprecated and were removed from UX100. In addition, the &lt;EM&gt;SAP Fiori launchpad designer&lt;/EM&gt; is no longer recommended and was reduced to its core tasks, where no other tool is in place, yet. Finally, the appendix was dropped with all those long-ago-features from the SAP Business Suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The units in the current version are the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;End-User Perspective&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Technology&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Architecture&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Content Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Content Administration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Adaptation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mobility&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Further Information&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are interested in an adapted version of the material, you can order a &lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/content/customer-specific-training" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;customer specific&lt;/A&gt; version of the course including only the topics you wish.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1508074598"&gt;System Landscape&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s start with the system release: SAP S/4HANA 2023 FPS02. Our system landscape – we call it universal target – is used in nearly all our technology courses and offers full access for the participants from the &lt;EM&gt;SAP Fiori launchpad (FLP)&lt;/EM&gt; in the browser down to SAP HANA on the SUSE Linux Enterprise server (SLES). Everything is set up following the newest guidelines of SAP so that it can really act as a template for customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="UX100 System Landscape (Screenshot from System Setup Guide)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/232777iA1457D7B45CCB7FA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Folie1.PNG" alt="UX100 System Landscape (Screenshot from System Setup Guide)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;UX100 System Landscape (Screenshot from System Setup Guide)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, we offer a self-service for participants to create a subaccount in SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) for the exercises. It is comparable to the SAP BTP trial but limited to services used in UX100 and only valid for the training week. If you need more time to test SAP BTP, please check out the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP trial&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1311561093"&gt;User Experience&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;One goal of this update was to update all slides to the newest design guidelines of SAP. Nowhere can this be seen better as in the &lt;EM&gt;SAP Fiori launchpad&lt;/EM&gt; itself. SAP Fiori with Horizon provides a fresh look and feel with new colors and a better user guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="How to Add Apps as Favorite to My Home Page (Screenshot from UX100)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/232780i14C4C3BAAF59C541/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Folie2.PNG" alt="How to Add Apps as Favorite to My Home Page (Screenshot from UX100)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;How to Add Apps as Favorite to My Home Page (Screenshot from UX100)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first thing users see when starting the &lt;EM&gt;SAP Fiori launchpad&lt;/EM&gt; is the new &lt;EM&gt;My Home&lt;/EM&gt;. It is a page just for the user, which can be personalized in many ways. Beside to dos, pages, and insights, the apps section can be populated with favorites. This can be done in two ways:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose &lt;EM&gt;Add Apps&lt;/EM&gt; in the &lt;EM&gt;Apps&lt;/EM&gt; section to open the app finder and select an app from a catalog.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On an SAP Fiori page assigned to your user in FLP, choose &lt;EM&gt;Edit Current Page&lt;/EM&gt; in the &lt;EM&gt;User Actions Menu&lt;/EM&gt; and choose &lt;EM&gt;Add to&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;EM&gt;My Home&lt;/EM&gt; in the context menu of a tile.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The first way comes in handy if you browse all apps assigned to you without concerning, if the app is already part of any page. It is a search for functionality rather than process. The second way instead allows to bring an app in the foreground, which may be the start of a bigger process the user regularly runs from a page. It is about getting faster access to this process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information about the SAP Fiori user experience, please read the blog post of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149639" target="_blank"&gt;ThomasReiss&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/user-experience-advances-with-sap-s-4hana-2023-fps01-private-cloud-and-on/ba-p/13634354" target="_blank"&gt;User Experience Advances with SAP S/4HANA 2023 FPS01 (Private Cloud and On-Premise)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1115047588"&gt;Technology&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The other ongoing goal is to keep track with all the advancements in SAP Fiori technologies. For example, TypeScript got introduced in SAPUI5 to ease the work of developers and consuming OData V4 services gets more and more common. The development tools continue to advance, too.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="How to Access a Dev Space in Visual Studio Code (Screenshot from UX100)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/232781i0BDAA7A052DDDA55/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Folie3.PNG" alt="How to Access a Dev Space in Visual Studio Code (Screenshot from UX100)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;How to Access a Dev Space in Visual Studio Code (Screenshot from UX100)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;EM&gt;SAP Business Application Studio toolkit&lt;/EM&gt; extension allows to connect and access dev spaces of &lt;EM&gt;SAP Business Application Studio (BAS)&lt;/EM&gt; in &lt;EM&gt;Visual Studio (VS) Code&lt;/EM&gt;. It can be found and installed in the extension marketplace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The extension adds the &lt;EM&gt;SAP BAS Desktop Client&lt;/EM&gt; as side panel. For the connection, the URL to access the &lt;EM&gt;SAP BAS&lt;/EM&gt; is needed. The logon uses a Web browser window asking for your credentials and establishing an SSH connection in a new &lt;EM&gt;VS Code&lt;/EM&gt; window. You can access and change the connection details choosing the blue SSH URL at the bottom of the window.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Accessing a dev space in &lt;EM&gt;VS Code&lt;/EM&gt; loads all extensions of the dev space in the local &lt;EM&gt;VS Code&lt;/EM&gt; window. This includes extensions, which are not available in the extension marketplace like Joule. In addition, you can add additional extensions from the extension marketplace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can start and stop dev spaces, open the dev space manager, and connect to multiple dev spaces of different accounts. All settings are saved in the dev spaces but are used locally in &lt;EM&gt;VS Code&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information about the &lt;EM&gt;SAP BAS &lt;/EM&gt;in &lt;EM&gt;VS Code&lt;/EM&gt;, please read the blog post of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/868" target="_blank"&gt;geert-janklaps&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-members/access-sap-business-application-studio-as-a-remote-from-visual-studio-code/ba-p/13565427" target="_blank"&gt;Access SAP Business Application Studio as a remote from Visual Studio Code&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-918534083"&gt;Spaces and Pages&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The heart of the UX100 will always be the content management of the &lt;EM&gt;SAP Fiori launchpad&lt;/EM&gt;. One part of this is spaces and pages. Introduced in SAP S/4HANA 2020, they got some new features in the latest releases like sort priority or merging spaces and pages with other spaces and pages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Merge of SAP Fiori Pages (Screenshot from UX100)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/232782iF31A25D6381F1E7F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Folie4.PNG" alt="Merge of SAP Fiori Pages (Screenshot from UX100)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Merge of SAP Fiori Pages (Screenshot from UX100)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sometimes users see the same apps several times or have similar pages assigned more than once, because they have similar roles assigned. For example, the sales manager and the sales accountant have overlapping tasks and therefore apps in their pages. Such pages can be merged to combine the apps or sections in one transient page at runtime. This means that the merged page is not visible in the &lt;EM&gt;Manage Launchpad Pages&lt;/EM&gt; app, but just for the user in the &lt;EM&gt;SAP Fiori launchpad&lt;/EM&gt; having all pages assigned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customer pages can be merged with other customer pages or with an SAP page. For the second one, you enter the name of the SAP page in the &lt;EM&gt;Merge ID&lt;/EM&gt; field in the &lt;EM&gt;General Data&lt;/EM&gt; tab of the customer page. When merging customer pages, you can define an own name for the merged page and enter it as &lt;EM&gt;Merge ID&lt;/EM&gt; in all pages you want to merge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information about merging spaces and pages, please read the blog post of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4295" target="_blank"&gt;KattiaJ-P&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/merging-spaces-and-pages/ba-p/13634304" target="_blank"&gt;Merging Spaces and Pages&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-722020578"&gt;Catalog Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The other part of SAP Fiori content is catalogs. There were several advances in the latest releases, for example, the introduction of typed catalogs in SAP S/4HANA 2020. The tool for managing those catalogs is the &lt;EM&gt;SAP Fiori launchpad application manager (FLPAM)&lt;/EM&gt;. In SAP S/4HANA 2023, it got a new feature.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="How to Adapt a Technical Catalog (Screenshot from UX100)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/232783iB00D38056DA60A4B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Folie5.PNG" alt="How to Adapt a Technical Catalog (Screenshot from UX100)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;How to Adapt a Technical Catalog (Screenshot from UX100)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The adaptation mode in the FLPAM allows you to make (limited) adaptations in the launchpad app descriptor items (LADI) of SAP-delivered technical catalogs. The changes are directly available in all references in business catalogs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Switching to the adaptation mode adds the &lt;EM&gt;Adaptation&lt;/EM&gt; tab to the details of a LADI. Enlarge the tab and choose &lt;EM&gt;Edit&lt;/EM&gt;: You can now select the &lt;EM&gt;Adapt&lt;/EM&gt; checkbox for each property you want and enter your adaptation in the input field behind. Adapted values can be translated using the SE63.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information about adapting technical catalogs, please read the blog post of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/365081" target="_blank"&gt;ruth_groene&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/sap-fiori-launchpad-new-fast-and-easy-option-to-adapt-sap-delivered/ba-p/13550177" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Fiori Launchpad: New Fast and Easy Option to Adapt SAP-delivered Launchpad Content (for On-Premise and Cloud, Private Edition)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-525507073"&gt;Key User Adaptation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are so many other topics around SAP Fiori that there is just not enough room for everything in a 5-day-couse. But one topic was always there as an outlook: Key user adaptation. With key user adaptation or UI adaptation at runtime (RTA), SAP Fiori apps based on SAPUI5 that support RTA can be changed directly and intuitively in the &lt;EM&gt;SAP Fiori launchpad&lt;/EM&gt; without developing any source code. With SAP S/4HANA 2023, versions of such app variants were introduced.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="How to Activate and Publish a New Version (Screenshot from UX100)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/232784i6A92CE2FD65E1D3A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Folie6.PNG" alt="How to Activate and Publish a New Version (Screenshot from UX100)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;How to Activate and Publish a New Version (Screenshot from UX100)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the adaptations to an app have been saved in a variant, they can be activated as a new version. This sets this variant as the active version for all users in the system replacing the original app or any previously active version. You can switch to an older version by activating it as a new version.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the active version being selected, the &lt;EM&gt;Publish&lt;/EM&gt; button can be used to assign it to a transport request. A customizing or workbench request can be selected to decide, if the adaptations should be available client-specific or cross-client in the follow-up system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information about key user adaptation, please read the tutorial of &lt;A href="https://github.com/VitorSAP" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Vitor Seifert&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/sapui5-flexibility-keyuseradaptation-2-deepdive.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Key User Adaptation for SAPUI5 Applications - UI Changes and Modes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-328993568"&gt;Summary&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have read so far, it seems that you are really thinking about attending the course. Don’t hesitate and check out the physical and virtual events we offer:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/UX100" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://training.sap.com/course/UX100&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are more interested in a digital learning, please visit &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;. Many parts of the UX100 are already available free-of-charge:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/learning-the-basics-of-sap-fiori" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/courses/learning-the-basics-of-sap-fiori&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For any other questions around the offerings of SAP Learning Services, please jump to our community page and get in contact with us:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/training-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/training-certification&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope even if you won’t attend the UX100 in any kind, you found some useful information or references around SAP Fiori in this blog post.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy learning&lt;BR /&gt;Stefan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/customer-course-ux100-sap-fiori-foundation-available-for-sap-s-4hana-2023/ba-p/14033235"/>
    <published>2025-03-12T08:39:54.134000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-create-custom-api-for-talent-intelligence-hub-data-to-integrate-with/ba-p/14045851</id>
    <title>How to create custom API for Talent Intelligence Hub data to integrate with downstream system(s)</title>
    <updated>2025-03-15T22:27:07.205000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ujjalgupta2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/27321</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Case 1&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Sending TIH Attribute Library (Eg: Skills &amp;amp; Competencies) to 3rd party or downstream systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Case 2&lt;/STRONG&gt; – A BTP Application wants to read skill data from TIH Attribute Library via API for using it in another process&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Current Challenge:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;As of 2H2024 release&amp;nbsp;Talent Intelligence Hub doesn't have an API which will allow the customers to connect their third party or downstream system(s) via API to read Attributes Library data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workaround Solution:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;In this blog we will focus on this limitation and provide a workaround to build a custom API using Custom MDF approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Following steps to be done to achieve above business scenarios:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create an Attribute Custom MDF with all the fields as available in Attribute Library, since APIs are readily available for custom MDF.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ujjalgupta2_0-1742073797783.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/238048iA803AE5C83EF5AE9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ujjalgupta2_0-1742073797783.png" alt="ujjalgupta2_0-1742073797783.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Now we need to ensure this MDF gets data updated as and when new Attributes are added in Attribute Library or existing Attributes are updated or made inactive.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For this we need to schedule an Attribute Export Integration Centre Job and send the .csv file to sftp server. (check the implementation guide for this standard step &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_SUCCESSFACTORS_PLATFORM/e15477b0414b4b25b224a97ad52c12ec/f8293af9defc4d46be08c6ff41984287.html?version=2411" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a CPI Job to do following steps:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fetch the file which contains all skill master data from SFSF SFTP server.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Compare the data in the file with the data in custom MDF based on the key field: wsmid . If any of the fields: Attribute&amp;nbsp;Name, Attribute&amp;nbsp;Description, Attribute&amp;nbsp;External Code, Attribute&amp;nbsp;Status are different. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Generate the delta changes file and then&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Update the delta attribute changes into Attribute Custom MDF.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once the custom MDF has Attributes data available, this can be accessed by third party, downstream system(s) and BTP Application for any extensions via custom MDF's API seamlessly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This way using Custom MDF we can create a Custom API for TIH Attributes data to be used with third party, downstream system(s) or even utilised by BTP Applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Notes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Attribute export Integration Center job can be scheduled for once daily. However if required the Attribute export job can be run on adhoc basis as well and data can be sent to SFTP server.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CPI job can be scheduled as many times in a day, so schedule it as per business requirement for other applications or downstream system(s)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Attribute custom MDF can also have extra fields related to the Attributes depending on business requirements. (however, these need to be updated manually)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As per business requirements different checks or filters can be added in the CPI job to ensure only required Attribute data gets update into the custom MDF eg: Standard Attribute external code when created from UI is like "101-1234" and customer may have a requirement to use alphanumeric external code for Attributes, so such cases can be filtered out from SFTP file and not updated into the custom MDF.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks for reading this blog, please share your feedback or inputs about this blog. In case you have come across similar scenarios, would be happy to understand other such workaround solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This solution is for specific business requirement. For other scenario's, please check the standard options available first as there could be further enhancements in subsequent release to standard functionalities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. For integration data between SAP cloud based systems, MDI is the recommended standard for SAP system integration due to its centralized approach, ensuring a single source of truth and improved data quality.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;For TIH data using MDI integration please refer to the following help guide as this should be the goto approach for anything standard&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_SUCCESSFACTORS_PLATFORM/e15477b0414b4b25b224a97ad52c12ec/1bce1251940b4318bc80890ae2930664.html" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_SUCCESSFACTORS_PLATFORM/e15477b0414b4b25b224a97ad52c12ec/1bce1251940b4318bc80890ae2930664.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_SUCCESSFACTORS_PLATFORM/e15477b0414b4b25b224a97ad52c12ec/1bce1251940b4318bc80890ae2930664.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Using this custom solution may lead to&amp;nbsp; rework and migration costs when transitioning to the standard API&lt;EM&gt;(once available for Attributes Library),&lt;/EM&gt; as SAP will not support the migration from custom implementations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-create-custom-api-for-talent-intelligence-hub-data-to-integrate-with/ba-p/14045851"/>
    <published>2025-03-15T22:27:07.205000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/empowering-through-learning-sandra-s-path-to-sap-champion/ba-p/14091290</id>
    <title>Empowering Through Learning: Sandra’s Path to SAP Champion</title>
    <updated>2025-05-05T16:22:19.035000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichelleGeraghty</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2019658</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When Sandra first shared her &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-a-failed-exam-to-a-successful-career-sandra-s-inspiring-journey-in/ba-p/13578397" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;story&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; with us in December 2023, she was already making waves in the SAP community. An ABAP developer and systems engineer from Mexico, she turned an early career setback—failing an ABAP certification exam—into motivation. What followed was a passionate journey of learning, teaching, and deepening her connection to the SAP ecosystem. Today, Sandra is not only a certified expert in her field, but she has also been named an SAP Champion, in recognition of her contributions to the global community.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New Certifications, New Confidence&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since our last conversation, Sandra has earned two new SAP Certifications to her resumé including &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-back-end-developer-abap-cloud?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Certified Associate – Back-End Developer - ABAP Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp; “Earning these certifications was a major personal achievement for me, especially because I had developed a fear of certifications after failing the ABAP 7.50 exam in the past.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These milestones didn’t just mark progress in her skills; they also rebuilt her confidence. Her commitment to learning and helping others thrive has become a central part of her identity. Through her YouTube channel, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8D5JKi6nMeLL7VgRPLPO4g" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mundo ABAPer&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, she continues to empower Spanish-speaking developers with technical insights, learning hacks, and encouragement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“I’m passionate about continuous learning, developing efficient solutions for my customers, and helping others that are starting as SAP developers, to make their journey easier.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From Learner to Leader&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Sandra Solís, SAP consultant and Champion" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/257993i4D98532445D917ED/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Sandra Solis Blue.png" alt="Sandra Solís, SAP consultant and Champion" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Sandra Solís, SAP consultant and Champion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Sandra’s contributions extend far beyond certifications. She was featured in SAP Advocate Antonio Maradiaga “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2YNtyXlDPj0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Code Talk&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;” podcast, where they discussed ABAP in Spanish. She won &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/gh-p/Devtoberfest?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Devtoberfest by SAP TechEd&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for a second time—an accolade that allowed her to attend &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in Florida in 2024. And in 2025, Sandra became an &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/sandra-solis/ba-p/14000317" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Champion&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, an honor that reflects not only her technical expertise but also her dedication to knowledge-sharing, mentorship, and inclusion within the community.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“My learning journey is a part of why I became an SAP Champion,” she admits. “By sharing not just my successes but also my struggles, I was able to connect with others and encourage them to keep going.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“My goal was always to build a supportive and inclusive learning environment, and I think SAP recognized that passion for community and knowledge-sharing.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Building for the Future&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking ahead, Sandra has her eyes set on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-backend-developer-sap-cloud-programming-model?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; certification and plans to expand her YouTube channel into a sustainable platform for education and inspiration. Her dream? To combine her technical knowledge with her love of content creation and make it her full-time work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whatever her future brings, Sandra will always be a firm advocate of the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: “It’s a great opportunity to improve your skills and advance your career, regardless of where you’re starting from,” she shares. “Even if you are new to SAP, there are a lot of paths and journeys for beginners, you don’t need to be an expert.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Her advice to anyone starting their SAP journey is simple but powerful: “Start where you are, use what you have, and do what you can.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start your SAP Learning Journey today&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Did you feel inspired by Sandra’s story? Then kick-start your own success story with SAP today. Benefit from &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;tailored and self-paced learning opportunities that meet you when and where you learn best&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get certified to demonstrate your expertise and boost your career.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/empowering-through-learning-sandra-s-path-to-sap-champion/ba-p/14091290"/>
    <published>2025-05-05T16:22:19.035000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-it-support-to-sap-consultant-a-learner-s-evolution/ba-p/14091279</id>
    <title>From IT Support to SAP Consultant: A Learner’s Evolution</title>
    <updated>2025-05-05T16:26:11.388000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichelleGeraghty</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2019658</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Nwankwo Chinonso—known to colleagues as Charles—every step in his career has been shaped by resilience, a hunger for learning, and a knack for recognizing the right opportunities. Raised in southeastern Nigeria as the third of four siblings, Charles developed a deep curiosity for technology early on. After earning a degree in Computer Engineering, he moved to Lagos in 2019, driven by a clear goal: to build a meaningful career in IT. Despite his solid foundation in IT support—specializing in troubleshooting and software upgrades—breaking into the right role wasn’t easy. He often found himself praying for an opportunity that would not only match his skills but also fuel his passion for innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finding the Right Path&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Charles Learner Story Photo.jpg" style="width: 253px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/257971i2FFB391DD96C51CD/image-dimensions/253x316?v=v2" width="253" height="316" role="button" title="Charles Learner Story Photo.jpg" alt="Charles Learner Story Photo.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Charles’ prayers were answered during his mandatory National Youth Service Corps (NYSC) program. “I discovered the SAP Young Professionals Program through a local community initiative focused on sharing job opportunities,” he recalls. “It was actually a WhatsApp group where members exchanged valuable information.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The program—still thriving today—offers recent graduates in Nigeria the opportunity to develop skills in Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP), analytics, and business process transformation. Intrigued by the reach and impact of SAP, Charles applied and was thrilled to be selected as one of just 27 candidates. “The rest, as they say, is history,” he says with a smile.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What followed was a transformative period of intensive learning, practical application, and personal growth, culminating in four SAP Certifications with a specialization in SAP S/4HANA. But for Charles, learning has never been about just collecting credentials. He describes the experience as both rewarding and life-changing—one that equipped him with the critical technical expertise and soft skills needed to thrive in today’s corporate world.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From Certification to Transformation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since then, Charles has carved out an impressive career as a Senior SAP Consultant, guiding manufacturing and other enterprises through complex digital transformations with SAP solutions. His journey with SAP has not only accelerated his professional growth but also opened doors to financial stability, global travel, and a wealth of invaluable industry experience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Charles, the rewards have extended far beyond the workplace—shaping both his career and his worldview. “My SAP Certifications have significantly enhanced my communication abilities, interpersonal relationships, leadership qualities, problem-solving skills, and business acumen, including decision-making.” Charles is now leading a movement called ‘SAP saturdays’, designed to equip students with SAP skills for both today and tomorrow."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start Your Own Success Story&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Charles’ story is proof that obtaining the right skills, combined with determination and the courage to seize opportunities, can change the course of a career, and open doors to a better life. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are you ready to begin your SAP journey? Explore &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and take the first step to transform your future. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-it-support-to-sap-consultant-a-learner-s-evolution/ba-p/14091279"/>
    <published>2025-05-05T16:26:11.388000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/become-a-certified-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-project-manager/ba-p/14103669</id>
    <title>Become a Certified SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Project Manager</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T16:16:17.716000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter_Voll</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/620</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the dynamic world of digital transformation, where businesses are constantly evolving to stay competitive, project management is more crucial than ever. Central to this landscape is the role of professionals equipped to manage complex cloud projects. With the newly launched &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-managing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-projects?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Certification for Managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Projects (C_S4PM)&lt;/A&gt;, you can now become a certified project manager and take charge of leading transformative initiatives.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Designed for Project Managers, Consultants, and Technical Leads, this certification empowers you to excel in managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition implementations, positioning you as a key player in your organization's digital transformation projects with strategic guidance and expert integration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How can you prepare for this certification?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can prepare for the exam in your own pace, by completing the "&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/managing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-projects?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Projects" learning journey&lt;/A&gt;, designed to provide comprehensive insight into SAP S/4HANA Cloud project management. With free access to the learning journey, you can deepen your expertise of managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition implementations, specifically focusing on SAP tools, methodologies, and SAP Business Suite portfolio. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additionally, SAP Community blog posts provide some supporting information to deepen your understanding and preparation:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/guiding-your-cloud-journey-the-new-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14028554" target="_blank"&gt;Guiding Your Cloud Journey: The New SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition - Adoption Plan Roadmap&lt;/A&gt;" &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-partner-sap-s-4hana-cloud-implementation-tools-overview/ba-p/13545052" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Partner: SAP S/4HANA Cloud Implementation Tools Overview&lt;/A&gt;" &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/news-from-sap-activate-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2502-and-more/ba-p/13996283" target="_blank"&gt;News from SAP Activate - SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2502 and more"&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can also explore more insights about &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/roadmapviewer/group/658F507A-D6F5-4B78-9EE1-0300C5F1E40F/roadmapoverviewpage/82b2db84548d41209cda972f0fac428b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Activate for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition on SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt; and taking a look at the release notes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a prerequisite, candidates should possess project management experience, preferred in ERP implementation, especially SAP Cloud-related projects. Additionally, hands-on experience with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition solutions and experience with managing cloud-based SAP projects is beneficial. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kickstart your journey today&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By becoming a &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-managing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-projects?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;certified project manager for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;, you will be able to position yourself as a key contributor to your organization's growth and innovation. You can demonstrate a high level of competency in orchestrating SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition projects, showcasing expertise and leadership in cloud initiatives that are aligned with business objectives. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Certified learners need to continuously keep their skills up-to-date and certifications valid by completing mandatory assessments before their certification expires. With an&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/training-certification/learning-hub.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning Hub&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;subscription, you can prepare for and take the stay certified assessments at any time during the validity period of your certification.&amp;nbsp; If you want to know more on how to get and stay certified, you can read&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/ba-p/13660165?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank"&gt;this blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open new professional opportunities for you with new learning and a sought-after certification. Build the skills you need on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and get inspired by reading &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/bg-p/learner-stories?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank"&gt;learner stories on&amp;nbsp;SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;, ask questions and connect with fellow learners. When you’re ready, take your certification exam and start shaping your industry's future!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/become-a-certified-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-project-manager/ba-p/14103669"/>
    <published>2025-05-16T16:16:17.716000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/taking-flight-with-sap-marco-s-journey-to-sap-champion/ba-p/14109561</id>
    <title>Taking Flight with SAP: Marco's Journey to SAP Champion</title>
    <updated>2025-05-27T10:51:39.358000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichelleGeraghty</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2019658</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“In a world that is constantly reinventing itself, I enjoy collecting and passing on knowledge and always thinking one step ahead.”&amp;nbsp; That mindset has guided Marco Büscher from his early days supporting flight operations in the military to becoming a highly skilled SAP consultant and solution architect.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Over the past 15 years, his drive to understand how various business processes fit together has led him to master multiple SAP solutions. What started as a curiosity has evolved into expertise, and Marco now thrives in the dynamic world of business informatics, constantly learning and growing, both as a professional and a mentor.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Marco’s SAP journey began after his time in the German Armed Forces, where he gained invaluable insights into flight operations. It was there he realized the importance of understanding complex systems from all angles, a lesson he later applied to his work with SAP software. He first encountered SAP solutions in his professional life as a business IT specialist, quickly recognizing how the system’s many modules could integrate to manage business processes effectively.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A Personal Learning Sabbatical&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Over the years, Marco’s curiosity pushed him to continually expand his knowledge. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I received my first certification in 2009, when SAP S/4HANA was still a long way off,” he recalls. “Over the years, SAP has reinvented itself again and again”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; To keep up with the evolving technology, he decided to take what he calls a “learning sabbatical”. He used this time to focus on deepening his expertise in SAP solutions and acquiring multiple SAP Certifications in ABAP and SAP S/4HANA solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Marco Buscher Photo Landscape.jpg" style="width: 357px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265178i708020545EACC6C8/image-dimensions/357x247?v=v2" width="357" height="247" role="button" title="Marco Buscher Photo Landscape.jpg" alt="Marco Buscher Photo Landscape.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“My certifications form the basis for my work as a consultant and technical architect at NTT DATA Deutschland SE,” he explains. “I utilize this experience to lead the way as a pioneer, provide guidance as a navigator and offer promising solutions as a designer in a complex and ever-changing landscape”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Marco credits SAP Learning Hub for providing clear, well-structured, guided learning resources that helped him to get and stay certified: “The learning journey was the best way for me to learn SAP,” he adds. From his perspective, upskilling and training is the only way to unlock the full potential of SAP software.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"By acquiring knowledge in all key SAP solutions&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;and combining it with my understanding of the system from a developer’s perspective, I am now able to satisfy customer requirements in both standard and customized SAP solutions”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A Leader and Mentor in the SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Marco’s journey didn’t stop at mastering the technical aspects of SAP. Today, he is not only an expert in his field but also a mentor, sharing his knowledge and experiences with others who are looking to build their careers in SAP.&amp;nbsp; Through his active involvement in the SAP Community, particularly his participation in SAP CodeJams, he has become recognized as an SAP Champion, a role that fills him with pride.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As he continues to guide others, he’s not just solving complex problems—he’s helping them see the bigger picture and empowering them to chart their own success in SAP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Power of Continuous Learning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Marco’s story is a testament to the power of continuous learning and self-improvement. His curiosity, commitment, and the willingness to learn new things has led him to embrace the full potential of SAP and seek out opportunities for growth. In doing so, Marco has not only shaped his own career but is also making a lasting impact on others, as is the goal of every SAP Champion.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerate your Career Today&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You too can benefit from tailored and self-paced learning opportunities that meet you when and where you learn best on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC-learnerstory" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get certified to demonstrate your expertise and boost your career. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/taking-flight-with-sap-marco-s-journey-to-sap-champion/ba-p/14109561"/>
    <published>2025-05-27T10:51:39.358000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/quot-certification-elevated-my-confidence-and-brand-quot-how-rudy-s/ba-p/14120001</id>
    <title>"Certification Elevated My Confidence and Brand": How Rudy’s Commitment to Learning Inspires Others</title>
    <updated>2025-06-05T12:05:13.124000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichelleGeraghty</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2019658</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Rudy Abrahams describes himself as “an introvert who is not shy” — a lifelong learner, activist for equity and equality, and a passionate advocate for healthy living. Growing up in humble beginnings in South Africa, Rudy’s early life shaped the values he holds today: resilience, fairness, and a deep belief in continuous self-improvement. Now an SAP employee based in Singapore, he balances his high-paced career with family life, proudly married to Dorianne for 25 years and raising two sons.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“I love anything that includes healthy living (in all aspects of health),” Rudy shares. “And I’m a lifelong learner — it’s something I do naturally.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A Leadership Journey Across Continents&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since joining SAP in 2017, Rudy has embraced change, leadership, and growth at every step. Over just eight years, he has held five major roles across five countries, including Head of Presales in EMEA, Head of Digital Transformation Office in Southeast Asia, Head of SAP SuccessFactors in SEA, and President &amp;amp; Country MD in the Philippines. Today, he serves as Head of Industry &amp;amp; Value Advisory for SAP APAC.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Through it all, Rudy credits his success to self-discipline and focus. His daily routine starts early: "I rise at 5am to meditate, then 45 minutes of exercise, and I start work at 8am. I'm flat out until 6pm daily." His workday is filled with customer engagements, leadership meetings, and supporting SAP’s Customer Advisory Team.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Leading by Example with SAP Certification&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But despite his busy schedule, personal growth and leading by example are high priorities for Rudy. True to his leadership style, he believes in setting the standard for his team. “I’m not willing to ask my team to do anything I’m not willing to do myself,” he says.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Rudy Abrahams, Head of Industry &amp;amp; Value Advisory for SAP APAC" style="width: 303px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/270055iA99681E8103C4DC7/image-dimensions/303x456?v=v2" width="303" height="456" role="button" title="Rudy Abrahams Photo 3.jpg" alt="Rudy Abrahams, Head of Industry &amp;amp; Value Advisory for SAP APAC" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Rudy Abrahams, Head of Industry &amp;amp; Value Advisory for SAP APAC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;This was just one of the reasons Rudy made the decision to pursue an SAP Certification. He saw it as an opportunity to inspire through action while enhancing his own skillset. Although the certification was not mandatory for Rudy, he likes to lead from the front. "Closing skills gaps starts with leaders who commit to learning, and certified teams drive better outcomes – it's that simple,” Rudy explains. "I also know that this certification is an investment in my credibility and knowledge."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;He chose to certify in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/positioning-sap-business-suite?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Positioning SAP Business Suite&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, one of SAP’s newest offerings for all SAP employees and partners. It includes practical exercises that build skills to help position SAP Business Suite, so was the ideal choice to strengthen Rudy’s product and strategic knowledge. But the journey wasn’t always smooth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“It was fun upfront, but the exam was fairly tough for me,” he admits. After failing his first attempt, Rudy didn’t give up. “I was disappointed but motivated to pass, so I decided to study hard and rebooked my test.” Passing the exam brought a renewed sense of confidence: “I feel much more confident and liberated now, especially knowing this was not an easy certificate to secure. I feel beyond proud.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transforming Confidence into Connections&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The benefits of certification extended far beyond product-related skills. Rudy found that it increased his visibility and credibility within SAP. “I have elevated my brand in our business,” he says. “I met new colleagues who walked up to me and asked me for tips and insights.” This unexpected networking has created new friendships and stronger professional bonds.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beyond professional recognition, the experience boosted Rudy’s personal sense of achievement. "It made me feel like I could achieve just about anything." What’s more, Rudy's example has inspired others to follow his lead: “Many of my colleagues have turned to me and told me they are motivated to do their certification too. It’s a win-win for all, I guess.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A Lifelong Learning Mindset&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Rudy, the journey doesn't stop here. Learning has always been a way of life — a philosophy he’s lived through every chapter of his career and personal growth. Although it requires dedication, time and motivation, he believes it's well worth the investment. “Lifelong learning isn’t a choice anymore, it’s a mindset.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As SAP and the wider technology world continue to evolve, Rudy’s story is a reminder that investing in yourself — even when it’s tough — opens new doors, builds new relationships, and paves the way for even greater success.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start your own success story&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Did you feel inspired by Rudy’s story? Then kick-start your own success story with SAP today. Benefit from tailored and self-paced learning opportunities that meet you when and where you learn best on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Get certified to demonstrate your expertise and boost your career.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/quot-certification-elevated-my-confidence-and-brand-quot-how-rudy-s/ba-p/14120001"/>
    <published>2025-06-05T12:05:13.124000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/certification-and-beyond-stories-from-sap-s-top-trainers/ba-p/14122892</id>
    <title>Certification and Beyond: Stories from SAP’s Top Trainers</title>
    <updated>2025-06-09T15:33:23.054000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichelleGeraghty</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2019658</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Tinus Brink and Lisa Merrill&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;have a lot in common&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;t&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;hey&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;both work as SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;c&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;onsultants and trainers; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;were&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; both&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;commended&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;as&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP’s&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;highest&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;achieving&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;trainers&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;in the 2024 SAP Authorized Trainer Program&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;they’re&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; both passionate about their respective hobbies. But the similarities &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;don’t&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; end there. Their deep-rooted &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;commitment&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;for lifelong&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;learning and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;inspiring others through &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;education&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; shines through &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;everything they do&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;And b&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;oth embrace continuous learning through &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/training-certification/learning-hub.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory-toptrainers1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Learning H&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, balancing their professional &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;expertise&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; with rich personal lives and unique interests.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From Family Support to Global Impact&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tinus’ SAP career began thanks to his mother-in-law, who took a leap of faith in him and backed his initial journey with a loan on her home. And her belief in him and in SAP paid off. Today, over 20 of Tinus’ family members and friends now work with SAP in some capacity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="Tinus Brink - Photo 1.jpg" style="width: 219px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/271767iFE1681CC955810AD/image-dimensions/219x297?v=v2" width="219" height="297" role="button" title="Tinus Brink - Photo 1.jpg" alt="Tinus Brink - Photo 1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Originally from South Africa, Tinus has been living in Texas for two years and calls it home. With five SAP Certifications under his belt, ‘Tiny’, as he is affectionately known by those he trains, believes knowledge truly is power: “Being the consultant with the answers not only builds confidence but also strengthens your ability to support clients effectively,” he says. “The skills we gain through SAP training unlock new opportunities for growth and success”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Over the years, Tinus has had the privilege of participating in inspiring programs like SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/africa/2025/03/deep-dive-into-sap-learnership-programs-in-south-africa-cultivating-the-next-generation-of-tech-leaders/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Skills for Africa&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/mena/training-certification/digital-skills-center.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Young Professional Program&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and the Dual Study initiative with various universities.&amp;nbsp; But his love of learning and training extends outside of the workplace. When he’s not exploring new technologies and experimenting with software and AI, he’s coaching rugby in local schools.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Supporting others in their growth and development has always been at the heart of my work”, he explains. “I take great pride in helping new talent enter the SAP ecosystem and kick-start their careers”. And it’s never been easier. The flexibility of remote learning through SAP Learning Hub fits perfectly with his lifestyle: “I can study on weekends or evenings without disrupting family time. I’ve already planned two new certifications this year.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Helping Others Dive Deeper Into Their Potential&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lisa Merrill, an SAP consultant and SAP Authorized Trainer from Chicago agrees. “SAP Learning Hub has been a wonderful tool and there are days when I wonder how we lived without it. I am a better trainer because I have a place that I can go to 24/7 to read, review, and practice.”  &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Lisa Merrill - Photo 7.png" style="width: 237px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/271765i462FA4E49A76B890/image-dimensions/237x321?v=v2" width="237" height="321" role="button" title="Lisa Merrill - Photo 7.png" alt="Lisa Merrill - Photo 7.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Like Tinus, Lisa’s love of learning opened new doors beyond her career. In 1997, while working on a global SAP implementation, she was introduced to the world of scuba diving, completed a course, and it has been a passion ever since. Today, when Lisa isn’t diving 30-120 feet below sea level in the Bahamas with her family, she’s diving into a new project or training a new intake of SAP users in a classroom.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As her SAP skills deepened, so did her impact. Over her 25+ year career, Lisa has been fortunate to work on consulting projects as well as provide training to SAP clients around the globe. But a clear highlight is her involvement in SAP’s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://ns2serves.org/about/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;NS2 Serves initiative&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; that provides military veterans with SAP training, certification, and career opportunities after service. The program provides them with new skills and a fresh start. “It is an honor and a privilege,” she fondly recalls. “Having the opportunity to help veterans prepare for SAP Certifications and later hear about the impact it has made on their lives is incredibly rewarding and fulfilling”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Lisa is a firm believer that a lack of training is one of the main reasons projects aren’t successful.  Over the years she has seen companies design great systems that never reach their potential because users aren’t sufficiently trained in the systems. “When I train, I hope, in some small way, that I am contributing to the overall success of an implementation,” she shares. “My motto is: When you stop learning, you stop evolving”. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A Path to Purpose&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For both Lisa and Tinus, SAP Certification wasn’t just a checkbox. It validated their knowledge, sharpened their skills, and opened meaningful new opportunities to support others on their SAP journeys. With SAP Learning Hub, they’ve been able to stay current, fuel their innate curiosity, and continue doing what they both love most: helping others succeed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You too can benefit from self-paced learning opportunities that meet you how you learn best. With SAP Learning Hub, you can unlock guided learning resources including live sessions, practice systems and everything you need to get and stay certified and boost your career.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/certification-and-beyond-stories-from-sap-s-top-trainers/ba-p/14122892"/>
    <published>2025-06-09T15:33:23.054000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/certified-to-inspire-top-trainers-who-never-stop-learning/ba-p/14122926</id>
    <title>Certified to Inspire: Top Trainers Who Never Stop Learning</title>
    <updated>2025-06-09T16:12:05.914000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichelleGeraghty</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2019658</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Behind every great trainer is a journey shaped by curiosity, resilience, and a drive to help others succeed. For Michael &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wegelin&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, Kouassi Mathé, and Angelo Minutella — three of the top trainers commended in the 2024 SAP Authorized Trainer Program — SAP Certification wasn’t just about personal growth. It was about staying relevant, deepening their impact, and unlocking opportunities to support and inspire others in their learning journeys.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Leading by Example&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="Michelle Profile Blue.jpg" style="width: 188px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/271782i98071FCB7A4508A6/image-dimensions/188x251?v=v2" width="188" height="251" role="button" title="Michelle Profile Blue.jpg" alt="Michelle Profile Blue.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Michael Wegelin from Germany is an SAP trainer and ABAP full stack programmer and has been passionate about training since childhood. Back then he bought his first guitar from the money he earned helping his classmates pass their exams. Upon completion of his PhD in physics, he worked as a software engineer and taught coding. He discovered SAP software in 1995 and dedicated four intensive weeks to studying ABAP. Just four weeks later, Michael stepped into the classroom as an SAP trainer and the rest, as they say, is history.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;According to Michael, the best way to learn something is to teach it to other people: “Because I love learning, I love teaching,” he explains. When he’s not staying up-to-date using his SAP Learning Hub subscription, he’s refreshing his memory on long forgotten IT-related subjects with his two children who are studying computer science.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Michael, who has always led by example, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;obtained his first SAP Certifications in 1995 and hasn’t looked back. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Learning something new is like discovering a whole new world,” he shares.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;In 2024 alone, he completed seven&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;learning journeys for free on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys?page=1&amp;amp;url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, which helped him pass three SAP Certification exams.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Training with Purpose&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Like Michael, learning has been an integral part of Kouassi Mathé’s life from an early age. “As the son of two teachers, I quickly understood how important training is for oneself and that feeling of joy when knowledge is transferred to others,” he recalls.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Kouassi Mathé - Blue.png.jpg" style="width: 173px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/271780i066C8064D42DCF6E/image-dimensions/173x231?v=v2" width="173" height="231" role="button" title="Kouassi Mathé - Blue.png.jpg" alt="Kouassi Mathé - Blue.png.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Kouassi, who is based in France, first discovered SAP solutions when his then employer, an SAP trainer, offered him training to implement SAP projects. 18 years later, he works as a Finance and Controlling SAP consultant and an SAP authorized trainer, and the combination is effective. “Training adds value to my consulting activities and vice versa,” he says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Kouassi, training is deeply personal. He’s passionate about knowledge-sharing and mentoring the next generation of talent. “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learning something new gives me the feeling of having taken another step towards growth,” he shares. “What is also important is to be able to share what I have learned.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a father of three, Kouassi balances his demanding work life with raising a family and his passion for sport. Remote training via &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/training-certification/learning-hub.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory-toptrainers2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning Hub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; has made this balance easier: “It allows me to be at home more with my children and still deliver the same quality of training to my students”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Driven by Curiosity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="Angelo Minutella_blue.jpg" style="width: 199px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/271784i0C2A70980F44E968/image-dimensions/199x266?v=v2" width="199" height="266" role="button" title="Angelo Minutella_blue.jpg" alt="Angelo Minutella_blue.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Passionate about travel, being able to offer remote training sessions and access learning materials online has also been a game-changer for Angelo Minutella. It allows him to teach and learn while &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;travelling and hiking around remote areas of Europe in his 4x4 campervan with his family, sometimes for months at a time. When he’s not exploring the continent, he spends his free time tinkering with his Raspberry Pi and coding&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; AI applications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Based in Switzerland, Angelo began working with SAP Finance and Controlling in 1999—just a few years after completing his studies in electronical engineering—and gradually began offering SAP training. In 2005, after a company downsizing, Angelo struck out on his own and founded a consultancy company. Over time, training became one of the most fulfilling parts of his work and he has since transitioned many of his sessions online, offering virtual courses that fit with his lifestyle. Staying up –to date with SAP Certifications has been crucial to his success both as an SAP consultant and an SAP authorized trainer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning Hub allows me to familiarize myself with new products exactly when I need them for my project work, regardless of my project time or location,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; he explains&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Being able to learn something new and expand my skills is a privilege.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shared Lessons and Lasting Impact&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Michael, Kouassi, and Angelo, learning has never been an obligation. It’s a core part of who they are and offers a pathway to new insights, stronger credibility, and the ability to support others on their professional journeys. Whether they’re leading global teams, mentoring new talent, or exploring new technologies, these trainers are united by a common thread: a passion for learning, and a belief in its power to transform lives.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You too can benefit from self-paced and free learning opportunities that meet you how you learn best. With SAP Learning Hub, you can unlock guided learning resources including live sessions, practice systems and everything you need to get and stay certified and boost your career.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/certified-to-inspire-top-trainers-who-never-stop-learning/ba-p/14122926"/>
    <published>2025-06-09T16:12:05.914000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/reigniting-purpose-through-sap-certification/ba-p/14125140</id>
    <title>Reigniting Purpose Through SAP Certification</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T12:49:27.897000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MichelleGeraghty</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2019658</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Yasir Sheikh, an SAP Project Manager based in Dubai, has spent more than two decades leading ERP transformations across global firms like IBM, PwC, Deloitte, BearingPoint, and EY. With a career dedicated to bridging business and IT, Yasir has always been passionate about delivering high-impact ERP transformations — and equally committed to continuously upskilling himself along the way. “What drives me most is creating real value for clients while continuously upskilling myself.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1861435099"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Staying Ahead&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Yasir Photo 2.jpg" style="width: 259px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273022i29C267592BC0F3EC/image-dimensions/259x327?v=v2" width="259" height="327" role="button" title="Yasir Photo 2.jpg" alt="Yasir Photo 2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In his current role, Yasir leads implementations of SAP Fieldglass and SAP S/4HANA Cloud, managing teams and aligning delivery with clients across regions. “My typical day involves managing project teams, aligning delivery plans with clients, resolving cross-functional issues, and ensuring that SAP solutions are implemented effectively and on time.” Right now, he’s leading a multi-country SAP Fieldglass solution implementation project for a financial institution in the UAE, from planning to post-go-live support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With cloud adoption accelerating, Yasir saw the need to deepen his knowledge, even after 22 years in the field. He chose the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-implementation-consultant-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Implementation Consultant - SAP S/4HANA Cloud (Public Edition)&lt;/A&gt; Certification to align his hands-on expertise with the latest innovations, and to strengthen his ability to meet client expectations in a cloud-first world. “Although I had extensive experience managing SAP projects, I wanted to update my knowledge to match SAP’s evolving cloud-first strategy,” he explained. “I also wanted to show that at 49, it’s never too late to reinvest in your skills — a message I hope can inspire others in the industry.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1664921594"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning That Connects Directly to Work&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learning something new while managing live client projects wasn’t easy. But Yasir embraced the challenge. “Balancing active client delivery with late-night study sessions required discipline, but the structure of &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;the free SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and the relevance of the learning content made it easier to stay motivated.” The learning paid off immediately — not just in knowledge, but in practical application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“One of the most energizing aspects was applying new knowledge immediately in my real-world projects, for example connecting cloud configuration concepts to actual client discussions.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1468408089"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Projects, New Purpose&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Completing the certification exam brought both professional and personal rewards. It enhanced Yasir’s credibility with clients, created new career opportunities, and reminded him of why he loves what he does. “It gave me a renewed sense of professional purpose, and reaffirmed my belief that learning is a lifelong journey,” he shares. "It also sparked a desire to give back, to contribute more to the SAP community, and mentor younger professionals."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this stage of his career, Yasir sees continued learning as essential — not just for growth, but for relevance. “Staying relevant, sharing knowledge, and proving that learning has no age barrier are most important to me.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you ready to begin your SAP journey? &amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Explore the SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and take the first step to transform your future.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/reigniting-purpose-through-sap-certification/ba-p/14125140"/>
    <published>2025-06-11T12:49:27.897000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/greater-vancouver-blog-posts/benefits-of-contributing-to-the-sap-community/ba-p/14163065</id>
    <title>Benefits of Contributing to the SAP Community</title>
    <updated>2025-07-26T07:08:08.868000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>garshen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491625</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Builds Your Personal Brand&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Sharing insights, answering questions, and writing blog posts showcases your expertise and positions you as a thought leader in the SAP ecosystem.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Increases Visibility to Recruiters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Many recruiters and hiring managers look for active contributors in niche communities. Your profile and contributions can make you stand out.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expands Your Network&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Engaging with others in the community can lead to connections with SAP professionals, consultants, and even hiring managers.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Demonstrates Communication Skills&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Employers value candidates who can explain complex topics clearly. Your posts and answers are proof of your ability to do just that.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Keeps You Updated&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Staying active in the community helps you stay current with SAP trends, tools, and best practices—something employers appreciate.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tips to Maximize Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Focus on High-Value Topics: Share insights on trending SAP modules (e.g., S/4HANA, BTP, Fiori, ABAP RESTful).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Be Consistent: Regular contributions build momentum and credibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Engage with Others: Comment on posts, ask thoughtful questions, and thank others for their insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Link to Your Work: Include your SAP Community profile on your resume and LinkedIn.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/greater-vancouver-blog-posts/benefits-of-contributing-to-the-sap-community/ba-p/14163065"/>
    <published>2025-07-26T07:08:08.868000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/advance-your-career-as-a-certified-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/14179600</id>
    <title>Advance Your Career as a Certified SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Project Manager</title>
    <updated>2025-08-13T18:31:41.947000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter_Voll</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/620</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.idc.com/2025/02/05/ten-trends-that-shaped-the-cloud-market-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Around 60% of cloud buyers told IDC’s Cloud Pulse Survey in October 2024&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; that their business’ IT or digital infrastructure currently requires major transformation, and 82% said their cloud also requires modernization. In response to these pressing industry needs, effective project management has become essential, particularly for navigating complex cloud-based initiatives. The new certification for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-managing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-projects" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Certified Associate - Managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;(C_S4PM2)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; provides a unique opportunity for professionals to become certified project managers, equipping them to lead transformative digital efforts with expertise and strategic insight.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Designed for Project Managers, Consultants, and Technical Leads, this certification empowers you to excel in managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition implementations, positioning you to become a strategic leader in your organization's digital strategy, providing direction and specialist knowledge in project execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to prepare for this certification&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can prepare for the exam in your own pace, by completing the "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/managing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-projects" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;" learning journey, designed to provide comprehensive insight into SAP S/4HANA Cloud project management. With free access to the learning journey, you can deepen your expertise of managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition projects, spotlighting SAP tools and strategic implementation &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;methodologies. Among these, the RISE with SAP Methodology stands out as a vital, holistic approach tailored for cloud transformation journeys.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additionally, SAP Community blog posts provide some supporting information to deepen your understanding and preparation:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/12-things-that-sap-implementation-methodology-sap-activate-tells-you-to-do/ba-p/13925363" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;12 Things that SAP implementation methodology SAP Activate tells you to do&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-your-system-conversion-to-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/13953362" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Planning your System Conversion to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition following SAP Activate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-activate-for-rise-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-now-available/ba-p/14039787" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Activate for RISE with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition now available by Deployment Journey&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/2b87656c4eee4284a5eb8976c0fe88fc/2023/en-US/CONV_OP2023.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Conversion Guide for SAP S/4HANA 2023 for SAP S/4HANA and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2023&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Review the SAP Activate Minute videos in this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?playlist_id=1_qr9ddkdl" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;playlist&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can also explore more insights about &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/roadmapviewer/group/658F507A-D6F5-4B78-9EE1-0300C5F1E40F/roadmapoverviewpage/79a834b21da74941bb3dedf553200a44" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Activate for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition on SAP for Me,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and take a look at the release notes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a prerequisite, candidates should possess project management experience, preferably in ERP implementation, especially SAP Cloud-related projects. Additionally, hands-on experience with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition solutions, knowledge of SAP Cloud ALM, and experience managing cloud-based SAP projects are beneficial.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get started today&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Achieving the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition certification allows you to become a crucial asset in driving your organization's growth and innovation. This certification validates your&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;competency in integrating business goals with technical solutions, enhancing your leadership role in cloud project management.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Certified learners must regularly update their skills and keep certifications valid by &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/ba-p/13660165?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;completing mandatory annual assessments&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; before expiration. With an SAP Learning Hub subscription, you can take these assessments anytime during your certification's validity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build the skills you need on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and get inspired by reading &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/bg-p/learner-stories?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;learner stories on SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, ask questions and connect with fellow learners. When you’re ready, take your certification exam and start shaping your industry's future! &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/advance-your-career-as-a-certified-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/14179600"/>
    <published>2025-08-13T18:31:41.947000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
