<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Careers-qa.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Careers</title>
  <updated>2025-09-11T11:10:26.330893+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Careers/pd-p/724690177700823984208969627109459" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Careers Q&amp;A in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/career-consultation/qaq-p/12764295</id>
    <title>Career Consultation</title>
    <updated>2023-10-29T14:10:12+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>abbas11</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/904984</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;
  &lt;P&gt;I need guidance for my masters. Currently i am at completion of my bachelors in Economics and Finance. With my background in finance , i have recently initiated my career path in SAP FICO module and i look forward not only mastering this module but aligning myself with relevant modules pertaining in to finance and costing. I have found my interest in ERP and aligning it with functional objects. I require suggestions on options available for fields in masters along with desirable institutes and what qualifications are available to hone my expertise in erp sap/fico/ career path?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/career-consultation/qaq-p/12764295"/>
    <published>2023-10-29T14:10:12+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/switching-from-d365-fo-consultant-to-sap-s-4-hana-functional-consultant/qaq-p/12815245</id>
    <title>Switching from D365 FO Consultant to SAP S/4 Hana Functional Consultant Possible?</title>
    <updated>2023-12-23T06:22:03+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rainchong7401</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1240392</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, All &lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I have 5 years + of experience in Microsoft Dynamics 365 FinOps (Aka Microsoft Dynamics AX). &lt;BR /&gt;I am specialized into SCM module as a functional consultant.&lt;BR /&gt;It is quite difficult to look for a D365 FO Consultant role nowadays in Malaysia (Since Ringgit is weak, very costly for upgrade.) yet MNC they will have lot of opportunity. (Very competitive to join MNC. It is because I am competing with talents/elites around the world)&lt;BR /&gt;Recently, I have been thinking to give a shot into SAP product. In terms of the paid, demand &amp;amp; opportunities in the market.&lt;BR /&gt;Been trying to submit application to few SAP partner companies or End-user companies. They do not put me into consideration. Since I do not have any SAP experience but even though, I do have Supply Chain knowledge.&lt;BR /&gt;I really want to switch to SAP from the bottom of my hearth. &lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If anyone has the same experience as I do. Please feel free to reply.&lt;BR /&gt;Or you have any tips to get into SAP product, you may share to me too.&lt;BR /&gt;I hope to hear from you all.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Br.&lt;BR /&gt;Rain Chong&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/switching-from-d365-fo-consultant-to-sap-s-4-hana-functional-consultant/qaq-p/12815245"/>
    <published>2023-12-23T06:22:03+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/career-transformation/qaq-p/12813167</id>
    <title>career transformation</title>
    <updated>2023-12-25T17:18:44+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>satyam_bhatt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/570020</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;hello team,&lt;/P&gt;
  &lt;P&gt;my self is satyam bhatt and have 8+ years of technology. Now I want to move my career to SAP ABAP technology.&lt;/P&gt;
  &lt;P&gt;So can someone help me to how to move step by step in future and which module I have to learn and practice &lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/career-transformation/qaq-p/12813167"/>
    <published>2023-12-25T17:18:44+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/career-path-co-or-brim/qaq-p/13598832</id>
    <title>Career path (CO or BRIM)</title>
    <updated>2024-02-08T05:59:07.027000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Coaspe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1393192</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;I'm a junior ABAP developer and I'm thinking of changing my career to a consultant in the future.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I recently got an opportunity to choose between CO or BRIM modules, but I'm having a hard time choosing because of the lack of information about BRIM modules.&amp;nbsp;Please advise which of these two modules would be wiser to choose.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/career-path-co-or-brim/qaq-p/13598832"/>
    <published>2024-02-08T05:59:07.027000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/confused-how-to-start-a-career-in-sap-sd-mm/qaq-p/13602921</id>
    <title>Confused how to start a Career in SAP SD, MM</title>
    <updated>2024-02-12T20:13:31.274000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MGD</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1396016</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi, I have been immigrating to Germany for three years. I have worked in marketing and sales for many years in mostly small companies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I want to work in SAP Sales &amp;amp; Distribution, I have never worked with SAP. How can I find free resources to learn by myself and take exams? I cannot afford the expensive SAP courses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My first question: Can I learn by myself and then take an exam?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is the SAP in Germany job market in demand?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are there free courses for refugees?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would really appreciate any help&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/confused-how-to-start-a-career-in-sap-sd-mm/qaq-p/13602921"/>
    <published>2024-02-12T20:13:31.274000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/starting-career-in-sap-hcm-ecc-6-0-in-2023/qaq-p/13632291</id>
    <title>Starting Career in SAP HCM ECC 6.0 in 2023</title>
    <updated>2024-03-08T13:14:36.933000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vikas_gupta281</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/833820</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts !!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have started career in SAP HCM ECC 6.0 in starting month of 2023, and worked till 1 year on support projects now i am not working because of less job opportunity with 1 yr experience, mostly opportunities are for 3-5 years &amp;amp; above with implementation exp.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now I am worried about future in SAP HCM on premises system, due to very less job opportunities in entry level jobs, and SAP also goes to stop provide support services after 2027 for ECC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) should I continue with SAP HCM or move to another could based technologies like SuccessFactors , workday etc.?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) what if I got job on support SAP HCM Consultant role for gov. client should I work?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;your opinion will really help me to get out from this complexity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vikas&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/starting-career-in-sap-hcm-ecc-6-0-in-2023/qaq-p/13632291"/>
    <published>2024-03-08T13:14:36.933000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/career-development-plan-notification-to-manager/qaq-p/13701449</id>
    <title>Career Development Plan- notification to manager</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T23:57:21.466000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JaneC</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1412872</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We need a notification to the manager when an employee creates and saves their Career Development Plan.&amp;nbsp; Any ideas?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/career-development-plan-notification-to-manager/qaq-p/13701449"/>
    <published>2024-05-14T23:57:21.466000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/view-all-available-jobs-as-default-in-career-opportunities/qaq-p/13755699</id>
    <title>view all available jobs as default in career opportunities</title>
    <updated>2024-07-09T14:09:54.226000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>WiktoriaD</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124092</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Experts&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is it possible to set up view in career opportunities for internal jobs, to view all jobs available as a default?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because now employee has to filter to see anything. Is it possible to set up view that once page is loaded all available jobs are visible?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wiktoria&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/view-all-available-jobs-as-default-in-career-opportunities/qaq-p/13755699"/>
    <published>2024-07-09T14:09:54.226000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-post-a-job-in-multiple-cities/qaq-p/13797409</id>
    <title>How to post a job in multiple cities</title>
    <updated>2024-08-16T15:18:26.053000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Adam_S1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/47322</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi -&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have job postings that we would like to show as available in different cities &lt;EM&gt;(eg: a remote Sales role that we can post in multiple major cities)&lt;/EM&gt; on the map within our external Careers site.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The postings that show on the map on our Careers site is currently driven by the Location object in EC. The values in the Location object only contain our actual work sites. We don't want to create Location values for every city/state combination to support this need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, when our Careers site is scraped by LinkedIn, Indeed, etc., we would like the different cities where the job should be posted to be scraped as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone else been able to solve this issue? Curious to hear what others are doing....&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/how-to-post-a-job-in-multiple-cities/qaq-p/13797409"/>
    <published>2024-08-16T15:18:26.053000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/prevent-search-engines-from-indexing-whole-csb-site-jobs/qaq-p/13859288</id>
    <title>Prevent search engines from indexing whole CSB site + jobs</title>
    <updated>2024-09-09T10:50:39.333000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LukasLoe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40146</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi guys,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;currently i am implementing CSB for a new customer. Long story short: My customer wants to use an external career site with CSB, but it should be prevented from appearing on any search engine.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I know that there is the possiblity to use SEO Settings within CSB (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_SUCCESSFACTORS_RECRUITING/8477193265ea4172a1dda118505ca631/b7a7264fca58464a817aa924895a2a55.html?q=Using%20Search%20Engine%20Optimization%20Settings&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using Search Engine Optimization Settings | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;). But also i know practically and from other colleagues that this is not enough to prevent the CSB career site from being indexed. Neither me nor any other expert i know has an idea on how to make this work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We also focused on robots.txt, meta-tags, robots no-index, http-header and cononical-tags - but i do not find a stimulating solution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does any one of you have experience on that and an "easy" way to reach the goal?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you so much in advance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lukas&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/prevent-search-engines-from-indexing-whole-csb-site-jobs/qaq-p/13859288"/>
    <published>2024-09-09T10:50:39.333000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/career-guide/qaq-p/13930627</id>
    <title>Career Guide</title>
    <updated>2024-11-07T01:40:42.741000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Gokul_Aasath</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1737697</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is Goku, and I am a Supply Chain and Operations management student. I have over year of internship experience working as Production Coordinator in a Aerospace Industry. I have learning Business process and little bit of end user experience in SAP Production Planning. Currently I am 3rd year of my college and I am learing advanced business process in SAP. As of now, I found out that I am interested in SAP and consulting sounds interesting to me what I have researched so far. I need help with finding good course or how can I start my career in SAP functional consulting? Please if you have any hints or guidance would be helpful. I googled how to become a SAP Functional consutant, and most the finding I got was need degree in IT and related field.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It would be helpful if someone provide with certification information or how to become a SAP consultant?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I found the course below in SAP certification website but I am not sure if it will be useful or not? Please guide!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-business-process-integration-with-sap-s-4hana" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-business-process-integration-with-sap-s-4hana&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/career-guide/qaq-p/13930627"/>
    <published>2024-11-07T01:40:42.741000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/is-it-a-good-decision-for-someone-without-an-it-background-to-learn-sap/qaq-p/13957282</id>
    <title>Is it a good decision for someone without an IT background to learn SAP Security GRC?</title>
    <updated>2024-12-06T13:27:37.658000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KSridharReddy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1904039</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have 5.3 years of experience working in an MNC in a non-IT role (BPO), and I am now looking to shift my career towards IT, specifically in SAP Security GRC, for better growth opportunities. I am not interested in programming languages, and have found limited opportunities in my current field.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would greatly appreciate insights from individuals who have transitioned into SAP Security GRC from non-IT backgrounds or from those currently working in this domain. Is it a good decision to pursue SAP Security GRC for long-term career growth?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, I would like to know:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. What is the average salary package for someone with 3 to 3.5 years of experience in SAP Security GRC?&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Are there any current job openings for candidates with this level of experience? What is the demand for&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; SAP Security GRC professionals in the market?&lt;BR /&gt;2. Are there opportunities for freshers in this field?&lt;BR /&gt;3. Could you recommend any reputable training institutes in Hyderabad for SAP Security GRC with contacts?&lt;BR /&gt;4. Is certification required after completing the course, and if so, what is the cost?&lt;BR /&gt;5. Is any programming knowledge (like Java, Python, etc.) required to learn SAP Security GRC? Is it a "no&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; coding" field?&lt;BR /&gt;6. Is certification necessary to get job calls and Interviews? If so, what is the certification fee?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Looking forward to your valuable feedback.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Sridhar.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/is-it-a-good-decision-for-someone-without-an-it-background-to-learn-sap/qaq-p/13957282"/>
    <published>2024-12-06T13:27:37.658000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/selling-projects-to-leaders/qaq-p/14028308</id>
    <title>Selling projects to leaders</title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T15:14:35.547000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TomBarney</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1473010</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Let’s start with one thing, if you struggle to sell the benefits of a good E-Commerce strategy to your Senior Leadership Team, you should quit your job, as the company won’t last long. However, there are some ways to enhance the role that E-Commerce can play in your business by getting the full backing of your superiors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s no secret that Directors and Executives are interested in two major factors; Return on Investment and Client Satisfaction. E-Commerce professionals are very lucky that a well-developed strategy will cater for both of these in bucket loads. Automating your interactions with clients can cut the cost of transaction by up to two thirds, whilst also improving your clients’ experience of trading with you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If I could offer one piece of advice, it would be to develop your skills in writing and presenting business cases. There is a lot to be said for taking the time to create a well prepared slide deck with all the relevant stats, expected ROI and time frames. Also, if the recent UK General Election has taught us anything, it’s that we need to fully cost our proposals before presenting them! Nothing is going to cut your presentation to a CEO or President short like not being able to directly answer their question. Do your research, prepare your slides, then present positively and confidently. Passion and exuberance are contagious and a vital part of your armory when requesting budget. Mentoring can also provide valuable input when preparing a business case. Is there someone you look up to within your company or a former boss that you maintain a great relationship with? If so, use them as a sounding board. Sometimes, there is no substitute for experience and great leaders love nothing more than having the opportunity to share that experience to help others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Returning to my earlier point, Client Satisfaction goes hand in hand with ROI. The former can have a hugely positive impact on the latter if it’s done right. One phrase should be at the forefront of any good E-Commerce strategy; ‘How can I remove all obstacles to my clients’ ability to purchase?’ We only get two chances to impress prospective clients. Just two negative experiences will lead to you losing the client, probably forever. This is a small margin of error, so put yourself in your clients’ shoes from day one. Your customers need to be central to your thinking when designing and developing your E-Commerce offerings. Don’t forget that one of your best marketing tools is satisfied clients spreading word of your value. A successful leadership team will value and appreciate this methodology, making them far more likely to buy in to your way of thinking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You also have one major advantage when approaching your bosses for a new E-Commerce project. Automating client experience reduces the cost and time of transaction, allowing your sales teams more time to be productive. E-Commerce teams typically run very lean and can deliver tangible benefits which are plain for all to see. Clients who integrate their ERPs with your business are also more patient if you make mistakes. A typical integration project can take up to three months (more for a large global client). This isn’t a cycle that businesses like to go through more often than they have to. Treat these clients well and you should be able to expand your sales portfolio with them, over a relationship lasting years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ultimately, you need to accept a leadership role yourself by driving E-Commerce within your business. Senior leaders rely on subject matter experts to steer their decision making. Guide them well, then deliver on your commitments!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before approaching your leadership team with new ideas, keep the below in mind:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;· Practice writing business cases&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;· Prepare and know your subject&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;· Be passionate&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;· Remove all the client’s obstacles&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;· Provide ROI&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;· Follow up and deliver&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/selling-projects-to-leaders/qaq-p/14028308"/>
    <published>2025-02-26T15:14:35.547000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/career-roadmap-for-a-fresher-in-scm-amp-logistics-need-guidance/qaq-p/14061319</id>
    <title>Career Roadmap for a Fresher in SCM &amp; Logistics – Need Guidance</title>
    <updated>2025-03-30T21:25:25.858000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lewis_Arun</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2064978</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Hello SAP Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I am transitioning into the Supply Chain Management (SCM) and Logistics domain and am eager to build a strong foundation. Since I am a fresher in this field, I would appreciate your guidance on the key concepts, tools, and SAP modules I should focus on to kickstart my career.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Some specific questions I have:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;What are the essential SAP modules for SCM &amp;amp; Logistics that I should start learning?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Are there any recommended learning paths, certifications, or free resources for beginners?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;What practical skills or industry knowledge should I develop to improve my job prospects?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Any advice on how to gain hands-on experience as a fresher in this domain?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I would be grateful for any insights, roadmaps, or advice from experienced professionals in this community. Looking forward to your suggestions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Thanks in advance!&lt;BR /&gt;Lewis Arun&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/career-roadmap-for-a-fresher-in-scm-amp-logistics-need-guidance/qaq-p/14061319"/>
    <published>2025-03-30T21:25:25.858000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/restart-my-career-in-sap-after-2-years-gap/qaq-p/14068315</id>
    <title>Restart my career in SAP after 2 years Gap</title>
    <updated>2025-04-07T12:45:57.306000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sapnaveen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1444206</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Members,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I worked in SAP projects for almost 8+years and due to some personal reason I couldn’t continue to work in IT for past 2 years , but now again I planning to restart my career in SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Basically I was MM consultant also worked in SD, TM and Security modules widely. But unfortunately not in S/4 HANA projects.(Though I am certified in S/4 HANA MM &amp;amp; SD 2021 version now it got expired too )&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So could some experts please suggest me the present market situation &amp;amp; which modules/ skill I need to update in order to restart my career once again in SAP and the approach to continue as a professional ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Your suggestions are highly appreciated and helpful at this time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks in advance.&lt;BR /&gt;Naveenkumar G&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/restart-my-career-in-sap-after-2-years-gap/qaq-p/14068315"/>
    <published>2025-04-07T12:45:57.306000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/looking-for-sap-mm-trainee-entry-level-opportunities/qaq-p/14143982</id>
    <title>Looking for SAP MM Trainee/Entry-Level Opportunities</title>
    <updated>2025-07-03T20:11:42.893000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lewis_Arun</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2064978</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;BR /&gt;I have 7.5 years of experience in the US healthcare domain and am now transitioning into Supply Chain Management.&lt;BR /&gt;I've recently trained in SAP MM and SCM processes and am actively looking for opportunities in this field.&lt;BR /&gt;If anyone is aware of openings or can guide me further, I’d greatly appreciate your support.&amp;nbsp; Thank you so much.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;***REMOVED BY MODERATION***&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/looking-for-sap-mm-trainee-entry-level-opportunities/qaq-p/14143982"/>
    <published>2025-07-03T20:11:42.893000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/looking-for-sap-fico-project-work-freelance-low-cost-even-free/qaq-p/14162215</id>
    <title>Looking for SAP FICO Project Work (Freelance/Low Cost/Even Free)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T09:06:22.067000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anuj23</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2066810</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hi everyone &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I’m currently learning SAP FICO (S/4HANA) and truly want to get real-time project experience to apply what I’ve been upskills my self— whether it’s in support, configuration, testing, or documentation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I’m open to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Freelance or remote projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Low budget or even unpaid work&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Assisting any consultant, company, or team who needs support&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Right now, gaining practical experience matters more to me than payment. I just want an opportunity to work, learn, and contribute.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you have anything where I can support — even small tasks — I’d be really grateful.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please feel free to message me or tag someone who might be looking for support in SAP FICO.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks in advance for reading and supporting! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition+Finance/pd-p/66233466-fcd6-45d2-a9ae-2cba38c72e19" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="232-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Finance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/looking-for-sap-fico-project-work-freelance-low-cost-even-free/qaq-p/14162215"/>
    <published>2025-07-25T09:06:22.067000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/query-enterprise-application-and-platform-solutions-sap-workflow-6355/qaq-p/14166153</id>
    <title>Query: enterprise application and platform solutions-SAP WORKFLOW 6355 certification</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T19:51:47.524000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sanju112233</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1836245</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am planning to appear for "enterprise application and platform solutions-SAP WORKFLOW 6355 certification". I got this name from my organization portal and wish to know if this is&lt;STRONG&gt; BTP based new workflow or S4HANA SAP Flexible workflow? &lt;/STRONG&gt;Actually, I am very strong with ECC workflow and would like to do the certification somewhere closure to it. Kindly help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sanjay&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/query-enterprise-application-and-platform-solutions-sap-workflow-6355/qaq-p/14166153"/>
    <published>2025-07-29T19:51:47.524000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/from-mechanical-engineering-to-sap-my-journey-challenges-and-the-next-step/qaq-p/14169802</id>
    <title>From Mechanical Engineering to SAP: My Journey, Challenges, and the Next Step to a PhD</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T18:43:15.357000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RACHID_AITBOUALE</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2203644</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1994337671"&gt;The Spark That Led Me to SAP&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;It all started with a fascination for systems—the kind that drive industries, make businesses run efficiently, and enable people to work smarter, not harder. As a Mechanical Engineering student, I was trained to optimize processes and troubleshoot problems. But when I stumbled upon SAP during my Master's degree in Industrial Systems Management, I realized this was the tool I had been looking for all along.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I still remember the first time I saw SAP in action. It was during a project on supply chain optimization, where SAP S/4HANA MM was used to streamline inventory and procurement processes. The complexity and potential of the system fascinated me. I was immediately hooked. The transition from mechanical systems to ERP systems like SAP S/4HANA MM wasn’t just an academic shift; it was a career-defining moment. SAP’s ability to manage procurement, inventory, and maintenance processes sparked a passion for digital transformation in industries that had yet to unlock their full potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1797824166"&gt;Why SAP? The Game-Changer in Business Processes&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Throughout my academic journey, I always sought ways to make processes more efficient. In Mechanical Engineering, it was about optimizing physical systems; in SAP, it was about optimizing digital systems that connect an entire organization’s operations. As an SAP S/4HANA MM certified consultant, I dove into procurement cycles, inventory management, and maintenance processes. One of the most rewarding moments was when I applied my SAP knowledge in a real-world simulation, extracting data from SAP and designing workflow processes that mimicked real business scenarios. The experience sharpened both my technical and analytical skills.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But what excites me most is not just the theory behind these processes—it’s the tangible, real-world impact. I’ve seen firsthand how the integration of SAP can elevate businesses, creating a seamless, efficient workflow that improves everything from stock management to procurement strategies. For instance, during my internship at OCP Group, I had the chance to help streamline their procurement process using SAP S/4HANA MM, which resulted in a 10% reduction in inventory holding costs over six months. This is where SAP truly becomes a transformation engine for businesses, driving measurable improvements in efficiency and cost savings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1601310661"&gt;The Shift: From Consultant to Scholar&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;As I reflect on my journey, I find myself at a crossroads. I’ve honed my skills in SAP and project management, but my academic curiosity is pushing me toward a deeper exploration. This is where the PhD dilemma comes into play.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m contemplating two distinct paths for my PhD:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exploring the Impact of SAP in Digital Transformation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This would allow me to combine my expertise in SAP S/4HANA MM with my passion for process optimization, diving deeper into how SAP can drive change in the procurement and maintenance sectors. I’d explore how ERP systems, like SAP, can be fully leveraged to improve supply chain efficiency, reduce costs, and enable smarter decision-making across industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Innovations in Systems Management and Reliability&lt;/STRONG&gt;: With my background in Industrial Systems Management and FMEA analysis, this route would allow me to continue to focus on engineering systems, but with a heavy emphasis on how emerging technologies like ERP systems, AI, and IoT can improve reliability and reduce failure in industrial processes. This would combine my engineering background with my interest in digital systems and process optimization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1404797156"&gt;The Tough Decision: Which Path Should I Choose?&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where I need your help. As I stand at this academic crossroads, I’m torn between these two exciting directions for my PhD. Should I dig deeper into the world of SAP, expanding its impact on businesses and industries? Or should I return to my engineering roots and explore how technology can improve reliability and innovation in industrial systems?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’d love to hear from fellow professionals, academics, and SAP experts. What path would you choose, and why? How have your experiences shaped your decision-making when it comes to advancing your career and academic goals?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For anyone who's walked a similar path, what resources or strategies helped you as you navigated this transition from hands-on application to academic research? Any tips or advice would be greatly appreciated!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1208283651"&gt;Conclusion: The Journey Continues&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every career is an ongoing journey, and mine is no different. From discovering SAP to contemplating a PhD, each step has been a learning experience. With every project I take on, I find myself more inspired to explore the full potential of SAP and its role in shaping the future of industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As I continue to seek knowledge and push the boundaries of what I can achieve, I look forward to engaging with the SAP community and drawing inspiration from the diverse experiences shared here. Your stories, insights, and feedback are what motivate me to keep pushing forward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1011770146"&gt;Let’s Connect!&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're an SAP expert or someone who's just started your journey, I’d love to hear about your experiences. What was your "aha" moment when you first discovered SAP? How has SAP transformed the way you approach process optimization? Let's share our stories and keep learning from each other.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+SuccessFactors+Career+and+Talent+Development/pd-p/bbf62c74-ac6d-4c50-86f1-9b23032e09d2" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1255-1"&gt;SAP SuccessFactors Career and Talent Development&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Careers/pd-p/724690177700823984208969627109459" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1148-1"&gt;Careers&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/from-mechanical-engineering-to-sap-my-journey-challenges-and-the-next-step/qaq-p/14169802"/>
    <published>2025-08-01T18:43:15.357000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/applicant-privacy-notice-questions/qaq-p/14170372</id>
    <title>Applicant Privacy Notice Questions</title>
    <updated>2025-08-03T16:49:35.173000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>re_sap</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/130212</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;My client has a few questions regarding Recruiting and the applicant privacy notice, can anyone please answer the questions below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;what &lt;STRONG&gt;usage data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is collected (meaning automatically collected data about how users use and navigate the system)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;what &lt;STRONG&gt;technical data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is collected (meaning automatically collected device information such as IP address, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;what &lt;STRONG&gt;cookies &lt;/STRONG&gt;and similar technologies are used to collect the above data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;whether users have any &lt;STRONG&gt;choice &lt;/STRONG&gt;about the application of those cookies (e.g. are they presented with a cookie preference tool)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;whether we as the client have any &lt;STRONG&gt;choice &lt;/STRONG&gt;about the application of those cookies/collection of that data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;what &lt;STRONG&gt;information &lt;/STRONG&gt;is given to users about the cookies (e.g. are they presented with a cookie notice specific to the system)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-q-a/applicant-privacy-notice-questions/qaq-p/14170372"/>
    <published>2025-08-03T16:49:35.173000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
