<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Certification-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Certification</title>
  <updated>2025-11-23T12:10:26.950685+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Certification/pd-p/222877341567121072788807155782117" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Certification blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/advance-your-career-as-a-certified-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/14179600</id>
    <title>Advance Your Career as a Certified SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Project Manager</title>
    <updated>2025-08-13T18:31:41.947000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter_Voll</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/620</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.idc.com/2025/02/05/ten-trends-that-shaped-the-cloud-market-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Around 60% of cloud buyers told IDC’s Cloud Pulse Survey in October 2024&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; that their business’ IT or digital infrastructure currently requires major transformation, and 82% said their cloud also requires modernization. In response to these pressing industry needs, effective project management has become essential, particularly for navigating complex cloud-based initiatives. The new certification for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-managing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-projects" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Certified Associate - Managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;(C_S4PM2)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; provides a unique opportunity for professionals to become certified project managers, equipping them to lead transformative digital efforts with expertise and strategic insight.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Designed for Project Managers, Consultants, and Technical Leads, this certification empowers you to excel in managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition implementations, positioning you to become a strategic leader in your organization's digital strategy, providing direction and specialist knowledge in project execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to prepare for this certification&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can prepare for the exam in your own pace, by completing the "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/managing-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-projects" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition Projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;" learning journey, designed to provide comprehensive insight into SAP S/4HANA Cloud project management. With free access to the learning journey, you can deepen your expertise of managing SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition projects, spotlighting SAP tools and strategic implementation &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;methodologies. Among these, the RISE with SAP Methodology stands out as a vital, holistic approach tailored for cloud transformation journeys.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additionally, SAP Community blog posts provide some supporting information to deepen your understanding and preparation:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/12-things-that-sap-implementation-methodology-sap-activate-tells-you-to-do/ba-p/13925363" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;12 Things that SAP implementation methodology SAP Activate tells you to do&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-your-system-conversion-to-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/13953362" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Planning your System Conversion to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition following SAP Activate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-activate-for-rise-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition-now-available/ba-p/14039787" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Activate for RISE with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition now available by Deployment Journey&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/2b87656c4eee4284a5eb8976c0fe88fc/2023/en-US/CONV_OP2023.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Conversion Guide for SAP S/4HANA 2023 for SAP S/4HANA and SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition 2023&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Review the SAP Activate Minute videos in this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?playlist_id=1_qr9ddkdl" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;playlist&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can also explore more insights about &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/roadmapviewer/group/658F507A-D6F5-4B78-9EE1-0300C5F1E40F/roadmapoverviewpage/79a834b21da74941bb3dedf553200a44" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Activate for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition on SAP for Me,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and take a look at the release notes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a prerequisite, candidates should possess project management experience, preferably in ERP implementation, especially SAP Cloud-related projects. Additionally, hands-on experience with SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition solutions, knowledge of SAP Cloud ALM, and experience managing cloud-based SAP projects are beneficial.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get started today&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Achieving the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition certification allows you to become a crucial asset in driving your organization's growth and innovation. This certification validates your&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;competency in integrating business goals with technical solutions, enhancing your leadership role in cloud project management.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Certified learners must regularly update their skills and keep certifications valid by &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/sap-certification-transformation-how-you-can-get-and-stay-certified/ba-p/13660165?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;completing mandatory annual assessments&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; before expiration. With an SAP Learning Hub subscription, you can take these assessments anytime during your certification's validity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build the skills you need on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and get inspired by reading &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/bg-p/learner-stories?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-certification" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;learner stories on SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, ask questions and connect with fellow learners. When you’re ready, take your certification exam and start shaping your industry's future! &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/advance-your-career-as-a-certified-sap-s-4hana-cloud-private-edition/ba-p/14179600"/>
    <published>2025-08-13T18:31:41.947000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/your-step-by-step-guide-to-sap-sales-cloud-v2-certification/ba-p/14183218</id>
    <title>Your Step-by-Step Guide to SAP Sales Cloud V2 Certification</title>
    <updated>2025-08-21T02:43:19.693000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DeepaliJohnson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124577</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-implementation-consultant-sap-sales-cloud-version-2" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Certified Associate - Implementation Consultant - SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; exam is designed for professionals who want to demonstrate their ability to configure, implement, and use the&amp;nbsp; new SAP Sales Cloud solution. With organizations increasingly relying on cloud-based sales tools, this credential sets you apart as someone who can deliver value through modern, intelligent sales processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re planning to pursue this certification, here’s a structured roadmap using the official resources available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737834800"&gt;Step 1: Start with the Learning Journey&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your first stop should be the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/implementing-sap-sales-cloud-version-2" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning Journey: Implementing SAP Sales Cloud V2&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/A&gt; This guided path introduces you to the fundamentals and provides structured exercises to practice key business user and configuration skills.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Learning Journey covers the essentials:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Daily workflows for sales representatives and managers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Core capabilities and navigation of Sales Cloud V2&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Machine learning fundamentals and generative AI overview&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integration with Microsoft Teams and mobile app functionality&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By following it through, you’ll gain both conceptual understanding and practical hands-on experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541321295"&gt;Step 2: Join the “Get Certified” Live Session Series&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, enroll in the &lt;STRONG&gt;“&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/get-certified-sap-certified-associate-implementation-consultant-sap-sales-cloud-version-2" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Get Certified&lt;/A&gt;: SAP Certified Associate – Implementation Consultant – SAP Sales Cloud V2”&lt;/STRONG&gt; live session series&lt;SPAN&gt;. These structured, expert-led sessions are designed to complement your independent study with:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;Kickoff session&lt;/STRONG&gt; (1 hour), which walks through exam format, question types, preparation strategies, and sample questions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A series of &lt;STRONG&gt;five additional 1-hour sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, each focusing on key Learning Journey units&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By participating, you gain direct guidance from certified trainers, reinforce your understanding of the most exam-relevant content, and practice with realistic sample questions—all of which are invaluable for aligning study with exam demands.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344807790"&gt;Step 3: Optional Microlearning Videos for Just-in-Time Insights&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;If you’d like to reinforce particular areas or learn on the go, consider exploring the &lt;STRONG&gt;bite-sized &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/videos?page=1&amp;amp;lsc_product_category=CRM+and+Customer+Experience&amp;amp;lsc_product=SAP+Sales+Cloud+Version+2" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;microlearning videos&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; in the Sales Cloud V2 category. &lt;SPAN&gt;These videos are concise, accessible, and perfect for filling knowledge gaps just when you need it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1148294285"&gt;Step 4: Hands-on Practical Test (Required to Unlock Exam Booking)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before you can book the certification exam, SAP requires proof of hands-on competence. This is fulfilled by the &lt;STRONG&gt;“&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/implementing-sap-sales-cloud-version-2/hands-on/demonstrating-the-value-of-sap-sales-cloud-version-2" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Demonstrating the Value of SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/A&gt;”&lt;/STRONG&gt; practical test within your Learning Journey.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have gone through the Learning Journey exercises, this step should be straightforward. The tasks in the test are based on what you’ve already practiced, making it a natural extension of your preparation. Once passed, the &lt;STRONG&gt;“Schedule Exam”&lt;/STRONG&gt; button becomes available, allowing you to book your certification exam.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-951780780"&gt;Step 5: Prepare for the Certification Exam&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, focus your preparation on the exam content itself:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implementation basics and clean-core principles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Master data management (accounts, contacts, products, pricing)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales processes including leads, opportunities, contracts, quotations, and orders&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User management, personalization, and security&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use this framework to guide your revision and ensure full coverage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-755267275"&gt;Step 5: Practice and Review&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;After completing the learning resources, reinforce your knowledge through practice:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Revisit exercises in the Learning Journey&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Test yourself with sample exam questions, if available&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consistent review will help you move from memorization to confident application of concepts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-558753770"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The path to &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-implementation-consultant-sap-sales-cloud-version-2" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud V2 certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; is clear when you use the right resources. Start with the Learning Journey, take advantage of quarterly expert sessions and study according to the exam guide. By combining structured learning with consistent practice, you’ll be ready to validate your expertise and move forward as a trusted SAP Sales Cloud consultant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/your-step-by-step-guide-to-sap-sales-cloud-v2-certification/ba-p/14183218"/>
    <published>2025-08-21T02:43:19.693000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-movie-theater-to-global-stage-how-a-quot-gully-boy-quot-moment-changed/ba-p/14185324</id>
    <title>From Movie Theater to Global Stage: How a "Gully Boy" Moment Changed Everything</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T16:10:06.098000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arabella</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145342</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In a darkened movie theater in Amsterdam, Nagesh Polu made a decision that would seem absurd to most people. Fifteen minutes into the film, he'd already guessed the ending (he is an avid movie goer, so this happens often). So, he did what any dedicated learner would do—he pulled out his phone and started studying SAP SuccessFactors materials instead.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"That's probably the weirdest place I've ever studied," Nagesh laughs, "but it perfectly captures who I am. I can't waste a moment when there's something new to learn."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Nagesh's story begins in Chirala, India, where he earned his bachelor's degree. His parents had instilled in him what he calls a "do-or-die mindset"—a philosophy that would prove prophetic.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Nagesh Polu_Preferred Picture.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303011i1828511F49F41F69/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Nagesh Polu_Preferred Picture.jpeg" alt="Nagesh Polu_Preferred Picture.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;"My father taught me that success isn't just about personal achievement," Nagesh reflects. "It's about lifting your family and extended family along with you. Living simply, staying cheerful, standing by our people—these weren't just values, they were survival strategies.” Those early years built something invaluable: resilience. Little did he know that this small-town foundation would eventually support a career spanning continents and transforming global enterprises.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Starting as a sales trainee, Nagesh eventually found himself at YASH Technologies, working with traditional SAP HCM presales teams and constantly hitting walls. During one particularly frustrating project estimations discussions, a senior consultant delivered advice that would change everything: "If you really want to shape the future, learn SAP—it's where the biggest challenges and opportunities are."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But it was SAP's acquisition of SuccessFactors that created Nagesh's true "lightbulb moment." While others saw a complex transition, he saw infinite possibility. What happened next was nothing short of extraordinary. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning Hub became Nagesh's compass—his "go-to resource for quickly building knowledge and completing prerequisites." The comprehensive training, hands-on exercises, and certification preparation materials became the foundation of his transformation. The breakthrough came during a late-night session in his Amsterdam home office. He was trying to build a complex report. Hours of trial and error had left him exhausted and frustrated. Then, using the detailed training materials and practical examples from SAP Learning Hub, it clicked. "I sat there thinking, 'I can build anything with this.' The rush was incredible”, he remembers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here's where Nagesh's story takes a surprising turn. He expected SAP learning to be purely technical—a skills upgrade to advance his career. Instead, it transformed something he never anticipated: his ability to think like a business leader. The intensive learning journey wouldn't have been possible without key support. Nagesh credits his wife as his anchor, whose unwavering support at home enabled his relentless pursuit of learning without interruption and his mentors across his journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Colleagues began noticing that Nagesh brought both big-picture strategy and hands-on expertise to projects. He wasn't just solving technical problems; he was solving business problems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As Nagesh accumulated SAP Certifications— through rigorous study with SAP Learning Hub—each one became what he calls "another layer of armor."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Every SAP Certification reinforced my ability not only to tackle complex projects but also to lead others through them," he shares. "They weren't just credentials—they were confidence multipliers."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Certifications opened doors to high-impact global assignments and helped him earn client trust more quickly. But the real transformation was internal: from a small-town graduate to a leader who could walk into any boardroom with complete confidence.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Then came the career-defining moment that validated years of relentless learning. A global client was facing a high-stakes SAP SuccessFactors implementation with a brutal deadline. Their previous attempts had failed. The pressure was immense. Nagesh delivered.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"When their CHRO told me that our solution had transformed how they manage talent worldwide, all those years of learning—including those movie theater study sessions—suddenly made perfect sense," he recalls. Today, Nagesh's learning journey continues to impact others in unexpected ways. He's mentored colleagues through their first SAP Certifications, elevated his entire team's capabilities, and regularly shares insights through blogs that help the wider SAP community.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;"My learning journey has been consistent, persistent, and purpose-driven," he notes. "It should be as natural as checking your messages or having your morning coffee."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When asked what movie would capture his learning journey, Nagesh's answer is immediate: "Gully Boy—Apna time aayega" (Our time will come). It perfectly captures his philosophy: that with persistent learning and unwavering commitment, anyone from anywhere can rise to extraordinary heights. From a movie theater in Amsterdam to global boardrooms, from a small coastal town to becoming a trusted advisor to multinational corporations, Nagesh's story proves a simple truth: learning isn't just about acquiring skills—it's about transforming your entire life.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to start your own transformation?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Benefit from tailored and self-paced learning opportunities that meet you when and where you learn best on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LSC-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Get certified to demonstrate your expertise and boost your career.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-movie-theater-to-global-stage-how-a-quot-gully-boy-quot-moment-changed/ba-p/14185324"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T16:10:06.098000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-blog-posts/prep-for-your-first-certification-with-a-sap-business-suite-bootcamp/ba-p/14213250</id>
    <title>Prep for your first Certification with a SAP Business Suite Bootcamp</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T13:40:25.439000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>David_Chaviano1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/113</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you're a student aspiring to break into the tech world, a career-driven professional, or an SAP partner looking to elevate your skills, &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-positioning-sap-business-suite" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;a new SAP Business Suite certification&lt;/A&gt; is a great first certification to begin adding SAP credentials to your CV.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/get-ready-for-your-first-sap-business-certification-positioning-sap-business-suite" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register for the September 30th bootcamp&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Understanding the SAP Business Suite is crucial for those looking to carve out a niche in the SAP ecosystem. If you already have access to a SAP Learning Hub subscription, &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/get-ready-for-your-first-sap-business-certification-positioning-sap-business-suite" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;sign up here for our expert-led bootcamp&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expert Guidance:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Work through your learning journey with insights from a renowned SAP University Alliances professor. Benefit from tailored coaching and practical advice that will be instrumental in passing your certification exam on the first go.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comprehensive Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Understand SAP Business Suite's structure and functionalities from a high level. Get familiarized with the need to identify client requirements and configuring SAP solutions tailored to addressing their infrastructure problems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical Knowledge:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Equip yourself with the skills to initiate meaningful conversations with potential interviewers and while growing your network - explain how SAP Business Suite adds both technical and business value across varied industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is the SAP Business Suite certification?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-blog-posts/how-students-can-get-certified-free-and-fast-in-sap-less-than-7-hours/ba-p/14116467" target="_blank"&gt;Check out my blog introducing the topic here.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is what you need to study:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/discovering-sap-1" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Discovering SAP for Students&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/positioning-sap-business-suite" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Positioning SAP Business Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How can I access this bootcamp and certification for free?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is free for all students and faculty across the world. &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-blog-posts/free-sap-certification-and-practice-systems-for-students-amp-lecturers/ba-p/14052493" target="_blank"&gt;You first need to sign up for SAP Learning Hub, student edition&lt;/A&gt; to access this free of charge. Commercial SAP Learning Hub subscribers can register in the same way as they would for any other Live Sessions on offer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Best of luck with your exam!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;David&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/beginner-corner-blog-posts/prep-for-your-first-certification-with-a-sap-business-suite-bootcamp/ba-p/14213250"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T13:40:25.439000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/certification-as-a-catalyst-how-minsait-drives-sap-excellence-in-brazil/ba-p/14203274</id>
    <title>Certification as a Catalyst: How Minsait Drives SAP Excellence in Brazil</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T13:36:39.559000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christine13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our partner Minsait, a company of the Indra Group, has established itself as a benchmark in digital transformation and SAP operations in Brazil. In this exclusive interview, the company shares how its long-standing commitment to SAP certifications has shaped its strategy, strengthened customer trust, and positioned it uniquely in the market. From pioneering SAP BTP operations in Brazil to driving innovation with AI, sustainability, and data-driven solutions, Minsait explains how it helps customers unlock the full potential of the SAP ecosystem — and what strategic priorities will guide the next chapter of its growth.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;We highly appreciate our enduring collaboration with Minsait and their openness in sharing valuable insights and experiences as a trusted SAP-certified operations partner.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Would you like to start by telling us about your company and the services MINSAIT offers?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Minsait, a company of the Indra Group, is a leader in new digital environments and disruptive technologies, with a global presence and strong operations in Brazil. Our portfolio covers everything from strategic consulting to the implementation and management of mission-critical solutions, with a focus on delivering tangible business results. We operate across the entire value chain, offering consulting, systems integration, custom development, cybersecurity, automation, artificial intelligence, and application management services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the SAP ecosystem, we support companies through end-to-end journeys — from defining the strategy, implementing digital transformation projects, migrating to SAP S/4HANA, and operating complex environments, to leveraging innovations such as SAP BTP, AI, Industry 4.0, and sustainability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Quote_1.jpg" style="width: 621px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307492i6E0C55384DDE8373/image-dimensions/621x190?v=v2" width="621" height="190" role="button" title="Quote_1.jpg" alt="Quote_1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Minsati joined the certification program for operations partner in 2010 - what was the deciding factor behind this decision? &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the beginning, we understood that SAP certification was not just a label, but a competitive differentiator to reinforce our customers’ trust. By joining the program in 2010, our goal was to prove — with SAP’s endorsement — the quality and maturity of our SAP operations and support processes. The certification was also seen as a public commitment to global best practices, aligning our operations with the highest standards in the market.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;To what extent has this certification been helpful in your marketing efforts and in your communication with customers?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The certification is a powerful tool in building credibility. In the sales process, it serves as concrete proof that we follow SAP-recognized standards and have proven capabilities to deliver high-quality services. It also differentiates Minsait in competitive bids and RFPs, strengthening our position as a trusted partner for strategic projects and mission-critical operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Quote_3.jpg" style="width: 615px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307491i2E2742660C7AB26A/image-dimensions/615x195?v=v2" width="615" height="195" role="button" title="Quote_3.jpg" alt="Quote_3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MINSAIT has recently received certification for SAP BTP operations in Brazil for the first time. What significance does SAP BTP hold for MINSAIT and its customers? And to what extent did the audit support your SAP BTP strategy?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BTP is far more than a technical platform — it is a central pillar of our digital transformation strategy for customers. It enables us to create extensions, intelligent integrations, automations, and advanced data and analytics solutions, enhancing the value of the SAP core while keeping it clean (clean core). In practice, this means transforming ERP systems into intelligent, scalable platforms ready for continuous innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The importance of this achievement is even greater because Minsait is only the second company in Brazil to obtain the SAP BTP operations certification. This reinforces our position as a trusted partner frequently recommended to support customers in complex and strategic BTP projects. This trust is no coincidence — it is the result of a solid track record of more than 180 SAP BTP developments and success stories, covering integration, automation, extension, and analytics scenarios for clients across various industries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When combined with other high-profile certifications such as CMMI, TMMi, SAP BTP Operations, and SAP S/4HANA Solutions Operations, this achievement places Minsait in a unique position: we are the only Brazilian company with this set of certifications, demonstrating our unmatched strength in development quality, testing, and SAP operations management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The audit played a key role in further strengthening our BTP strategy. It validated practices, highlighted our strengths, and pointed to areas for improvement — such as test automation, observability, and standardization of operations across multiple environments. We have incorporated these recommendations into our roadmap, enabling us to further raise our maturity level and ensure every BTP delivery is a benchmark for quality and innovation in the market.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Minsait and SAP team at the audit in July 2025" style="width: 903px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307479i350013391A6FAA52/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture2.jpg" alt="Minsait and SAP team at the audit in July 2025" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Minsait and SAP team at the audit in July 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP consistently aligns its strategy with the cloud and encourages partners to actively support customers during their migration journey. What distinguishes your company in this regard, and how do you support your customers in their digital transformation?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our differentiator lies in the combination of experience, proximity to our customers’ business, and multidisciplinary technical expertise. We work with agile methodologies, proprietary tools, and accelerators that reduce project time and migration risks. Furthermore, we don’t just migrate systems to the cloud — we ensure that this move delivers real business value, integrating data, artificial intelligence, automation, and clean core practices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This consultative, results-oriented approach enables us to accelerate SAP innovation adoption, ensuring that each customer gets the most from their cloud investment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Quote_2.jpg" style="width: 622px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307487i826151F5848DC60F/image-dimensions/622x184?v=v2" width="622" height="184" role="button" title="Quote_2.jpg" alt="Quote_2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How do your SAP certifications reflect your strategy and position in the Brazilian market?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The achievement of SAP BTP Operations certification in Brazil, along with the renewal of our SAP S/4HANA Solutions Operations certification, is not just a technical milestone — it is a symbol of our continuous evolution and the trust we have earned from SAP and our customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since joining the certification program in 2010, our strategy has been clear: align our processes with the most demanding global standards while maintaining the agility and proximity required by the Brazilian market. Over the years, this approach has established us as a reference in SAP application management and the execution of high-complexity projects, always focusing on quality, security, and business results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The fact that we are the only Brazilian company to hold certifications such as CMMI, TMMi, and the certifications for SAP BTP operations and SAP S/4HANA solutions Operations reinforces our robustness and organizational maturity. This allows us to consistently deliver value, whether in complex implementations, cloud migrations, critical integrations, or the ongoing management of mission-critical environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our commitment for the coming years is to continue innovating, anticipating trends, and helping our customers get the most out of the SAP ecosystem — always with the security of having a certified, experienced, and results-driven partner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Looking ahead, what are your strategic priorities in your partnership with SAP? Are there specific areas within SAP’s portfolio – such as AI, sustainability, industry cloud, or further expansion in SAP BTP – where you see growth opportunities or plan to invest? &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our strategic priorities are focused on six major pillars:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, we are &lt;STRONG&gt;expanding our SAP BTP expertise&lt;/STRONG&gt;, using it as a platform for innovation, automation, and seamless data integration.&amp;nbsp;We are also applying &lt;STRONG&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt; directly to business processes, leveraging SAP AI Core and AI Hub capabilities as well as partnerships with leading technology providers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sustainability and ESG&lt;/STRONG&gt; are deeply embedded in our portfolio, with solutions that enable customers to measure, reduce, and report their environmental and social impact.&amp;nbsp;At the same time, we support the responsible and fast &lt;STRONG&gt;adoption of SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring that customers who have not yet migrated can make the transition securely and with clear added value.&amp;nbsp;Another key focus is the &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; (BDC), which rein&lt;SPAN&gt;forces our commitment to transforming our customers’ data into strategic and monetizable assets.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finally, through&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent AMS&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we combine advanced monitoring, automation, and predictive analytics to reduce incidents and maximize performance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Information on the certification program for operations partners and an overview of all certified partners can be found in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/opc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Operations Partner Guide&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;OPC&amp;nbsp;at&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/partners/partner-program/certify-my-solution.html#outsourcing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/certification-as-a-catalyst-how-minsait-drives-sap-excellence-in-brazil/ba-p/14203274"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T13:36:39.559000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/get-certified-in-sap-sales-cloud-v2-a-prep-live-session-series-starting-oct/ba-p/14227292</id>
    <title>Get Certified in SAP Sales Cloud V2 - A prep live session series starting Oct 7th 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T23:32:12.378000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DeepaliJohnson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124577</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Are you ready to take your career in sales technology to the next level? Do you want to become a go-to expert in implementing one of the most innovative sales solutions on the market? Then mark your calendars!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Learning is thrilled to announce another 6 part live session series &lt;STRONG&gt;starting Oct 7th&lt;/STRONG&gt; designed to help you ace the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Certified Associate - Implementation Consultant - SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/STRONG&gt; exam!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://tinyurl.com/ykmtjtzj" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here to explore the full series and register&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890124950"&gt;Why SAP Sales Cloud Version 2?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today's fast-paced sales environment, businesses need more than just basic CRM. SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 is a game-changer, empowering sales teams with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI and Machine Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Predictive analytics, intelligent recommendations, and automated insights to help reps prioritize leads and close deals faster.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless Integration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Connects effortlessly with the broader SAP ecosystem (ERP, S/4HANA, etc.) for a truly end-to-end business process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Modern User Experience:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Intuitive, mobile-first design built on SAP Fiori for enhanced usability and adoption.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexibility &amp;amp; Extensibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Low-code/no-code options and an API-first approach for easy customization and integration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This isn't just about managing customer data; it's about driving intelligent engagement and accelerating business growth. As more companies adopt this powerful solution, the demand for skilled implementation consultants is skyrocketing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693611445"&gt;Why Get Certified?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Earning your "SAP Certified Associate - Implementation Consultant - SAP Sales Cloud Version 2" certification demonstrates your foundational knowledge and in-depth skills in implementing and administering this cutting-edge solution. It validates that you:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Possess a comprehensive understanding of SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 fundamentals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Can actively participate in project teams focusing on Sales Cloud V2 implementations in a mentored role.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are equipped to configure key sales-specific capabilities, manage master data, and understand extensibility options.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Understand critical areas like Lead and Opportunity Management, Activities Management, Mobile App capabilities, and the integration of Machine Learning and Generative AI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This certification is your badge of excellence, differentiating you in the job market and opening doors to exciting career opportunities!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497097940"&gt;What You'll Get from These Live Sessions:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This exclusive series of live sessions, led by an SAP expert, is quite simply your best shot at prepping for success. You'll walk away with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comprehensive Coverage:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This is a &lt;STRONG&gt;6-part live session series, each about an hour long&lt;/STRONG&gt;, designed to take you through the entire content of the learning journeys.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deep Dives:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Expert-led sessions covering the key topics and modules you'll need to master for the certification exam. You'll get an &lt;STRONG&gt;"expert's eye" on what's truly important&lt;/STRONG&gt; for both the exam and real-world application.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical Insights:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Get a feel for actual implementation scenarios and pick up best practices you can use right away.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Interactive Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Chat directly with SAP experts and get your burning questions answered live.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;True Confidence:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Step into your certification exam feeling completely ready and sure of your abilities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Seriously, don't let this incredible chance to boost your skills and validate your expertise in SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 slip by!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Check out the link below for the full schedule, all the session details, and make sure to register today:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/get-certified-sap-certified-associate-implementation-consultant-sap-sales-cloud-version-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/get-certified-sap-certified-associate-implementation-consultant-sap-sales-cloud-version-2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Invest in yourself and become the SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 implementation wizard everyone needs. Your next big career move is waiting!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/get-certified-in-sap-sales-cloud-v2-a-prep-live-session-series-starting-oct/ba-p/14227292"/>
    <published>2025-09-24T23:32:12.378000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/step-into-the-future-sap-business-ai-operations-certification-for-partners/ba-p/14228667</id>
    <title>Step Into the Future: SAP Business AI Operations Certification for Partners</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T07:08:43.137000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christine13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP partners are driving the next wave of enterprise innovation, and artificial intelligence is at the center of it all. As organizations look to unlock new efficiencies and smarter business outcomes, the ability to operate and manage SAP Business AI solutions is becoming a true differentiator.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s why we’re thrilled to introduce the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business AI solutions operations certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a new credential designed for partners who want to prove their expertise in running, integrating, securing, and extending SAP Business AI. This certification has just been launched, giving early adopters the chance to stand out as pioneers in the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Certification Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI isn’t just a buzzword anymore. It’s powering real change in how businesses operate, innovate, and serve their customers. But with new technology comes new expectations. Customers want partners who can do more than just deploy AI - they want experts who can keep it running smoothly, securely, and in line with best practices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s where this certification comes in. It’s your chance to show the market that your team knows how to deliver reliable, secure, and high-value SAP Business AI operations. Whether you’re supporting customers, building custom AI solutions, or managing complex integrations, this credential sets you apart.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Inside the Certification?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This isn’t just a technical badge - it's a comprehensive validation of your operational know-how. The certification covers everything from setting up and managing SAP Business AI scenarios and SAP Joule, to integrating AI with business processes and ensuring security, ethics, and compliance. You’ll demonstrate your ability to manage service desks, handle incidents, drive continual improvement, and manage change processes. The program also validates your skills in delivering custom AI development and integration on SAP BTP and applying SAP’s methodologies for project management. You’ll also demonstrate your skills in quality management, knowledge transfer, event management, and more - covering the full spectrum of what it takes to keep SAP Business AI solutions running at their best.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who Should Consider This?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re an SAP partner helping customers adopt, operate, or extend SAP Business AI, this certification is for you. It’s especially valuable for teams providing managed services, custom development, or integration support. If your clients rely on you to keep their AI solutions humming, this is your next step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ready to Take the Leap?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Curious about the details? Want to know how to get started? Reach out to us at SAPOperationsPartners@sap.com or visit &lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/opc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;www.sap.com/opc&lt;/A&gt; for all the info.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI is changing the game. Make sure your team is ready to play - and win. Get certified, get noticed, and help your customers unlock the full power of SAP Business AI.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/step-into-the-future-sap-business-ai-operations-certification-for-partners/ba-p/14228667"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T07:08:43.137000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-abap-to-the-world-daniel-s-journey-of-growth-and-resilience/ba-p/14232471</id>
    <title>From ABAP to the World: Daniel’s Journey of Growth and Resilience</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T11:31:41.422000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arabella</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145342</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you meet Daniel Mateo Perez outside work, you'll likely find him by the ocean. On Saturday mornings, he's barefoot on the beach with tea or planning his next trip—he's visited over 60 countries. Travel shapes his curious, adaptable, and open perspective—traits vital for SAP projects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Daniel didn’t plan a career working with SAP technology. A Chemical Engineering graduate in Barcelona, he began his professional journey as an ABAP developer at a consulting firm. But he quickly realized his real passion was in connecting technology with business. A manager advised him: &lt;EM&gt;“If you really want to grow, learn Finance and Logistics with SAP.”&lt;/EM&gt; That moment changed everything.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Daniel Mateo cover photo.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321942iC6E4C3790FE8D405/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Daniel Mateo cover photo.png" alt="Daniel Mateo cover photo.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;His first SAP classroom training in Supply Chain Management sparked a powerful realization. “For the first time, I saw how procurement, inventory, and finance all connected. It blew my mind—this was the solution that runs companies.” That moment didn’t just build knowledge; it gave him a surge of confidence and set a clear direction for his professional journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Two decades later, SAP certifications have propelled his career and unlocked new opportunities. Today, he proudly holds &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate Project Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA for Financial Accounting&lt;/STRONG&gt; certifications and is already reaching higher, working toward more in SAP S/4HANA Cloud. Each one, Daniel says, has been “a credibility booster,” fueling his ongoing professional growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“SAP Certifications gave me more than technical skills,” he explains. “They gave me trust. With clients, with colleagues, and with myself. When you’re certified, people know you can deliver.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That trust opened doors. Daniel has led multi-country SAP S/4HANA rollouts across various industries, including pharmaceuticals and media, co-authored a book on rollout strategies in Spanish, and mentored younger consultants as they navigate their careers. He’s also become known as the calm presence during stressful go-lives—someone who can translate between IT and finance and keep projects moving.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It hasn’t always been easy. Switching from development to finance consulting nearly made him quit. “I remember leaving a workshop convinced I’d never understand finance,” he admits. But curiosity—and the structure of SAP learning materials—kept him going. Step by step, SAP Certification by SAP Certification, he built both expertise and resilience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking back, he says the biggest surprise is that SAP learning never ends. “At first it felt overwhelming, but now I see it as the reason my career has stayed exciting.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If he could give advice to his younger self—or anyone considering starting—Daniel would keep it simple: &lt;EM&gt;“Don’t wait until you feel ready. Nobody knows everything. Just start, get certified, and grow from there.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From backpacking buses in Asia, where he studied for certifications, to global boardrooms where he delivers enterprise transformations, Daniel’s story showcases the real power of SAP Certification: it doesn’t just unlock opportunities—it gives you the confidence and credibility to walk through them.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Take your next step&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: visit the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/get-certified?url_id=text-sapcom-prdteng-Certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, choose your certification, and start shaping your future today.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-abap-to-the-world-daniel-s-journey-of-growth-and-resilience/ba-p/14232471"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T11:31:41.422000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/one-hour-one-habit-one-champion-kunal-bansal-s-lifelong-learning-story/ba-p/14238286</id>
    <title>One Hour, One Habit, One Champion: Kunal Bansal’s Lifelong Learning Story 🏆</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T14:53:14.971000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>margherita_gallucci34</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ask Kunal Bansal what the most powerful skill in his career has been, and he won’t say coding, consulting, or communication - he’ll say consistency. Every single day, no matter where he is, he dedicates one hour to learning. That one habit has not only shaped his expertise but also inspired hundreds of others to start their own learning journeys.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: Paint us a picture of who you are beyond work. What would we find you doing on a Saturday morning? What’s something about you that might surprise your colleagues?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Saturday mornings start with badminton with friends and afternoons mentoring rural students. Supporting underprivileged learners keeps me grounded and reminds me why learning matters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I spend at least an hour daily learning. It’s as natural as breathing, but far more rewarding. Mentoring isn’t just a hobby; it’s my passion. Networking and talking to people across industries taught me business processes, the foundation that made SAP technology click for me.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: Take us inside a typical business day. What makes you excited to get up in the morning, and what frustrates you?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My day begins with a workout at the gym. My favorite and happiest hour. After that come leadership calls on people and skill management for our SAP CX practice, followed by client project calls.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tea, lunch, and walks with colleagues mix jokes, work talk, and wisdom.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What frustrates me?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Seeing colleagues stuck in a non-learning, non-growth mindset.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What excites me?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Helping them flip the switch and grow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: Tell us about the moment you decided to learn SAP. What sparked that decision?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I started my career in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://jobs.sap.com/content/sap-star/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Student Training and Rotation program&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; - clueless, wide-eyed, and wondering how to survive in this massive ocean. My mentor,&lt;/SPAN&gt; Ramakrishna, told me something that shaped my entire journey:&amp;nbsp;“&lt;I&gt;Start with basics and learn business processes, not systems.&lt;/I&gt;”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: What was your biggest ‘aha!’ moment?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Back in 2016, I was working on SAP CRM and SAP Marketing Cloud. When I finally understood the CRM business process, the dots connected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I realized that technology wasn’t just moving data. It was orchestrating the heartbeat of a business. That shift turned me into a trusted advisor to customers and the go-to person for technical and business challenges.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: What was the hardest part of your learning journey?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Opening &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/training-certification/learning-hub.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning Hub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for the first time felt like entering a massive library without a map - overwhelming!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I remembered my mentor’s advice: start from basics, learn business processes first. Once I did, the chaos turned into clarity. That persistent learning turned me from a rookie into a recognized community voice.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: What surprised you most about the learning process?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Answering Q&amp;amp;A and writing blogs on SAP Community accelerated my learning more than I expected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Contributing consistently for over seven years helped me become a community influencer and built my personal brand as a subject matter expert which eventually led to my selection as an SAP Champion. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: What’s something you can do now that you couldn’t before?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Previously, I used to explain SAP technology in dense technical jargon, regardless of the audience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now, I adapt my speech according to the target audience as below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Developers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: features, APIs, and architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consultants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: flows, modules, and configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Executives&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: business impact and how the Intelligent Enterprise helps companies run smarter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This shift makes me more effective in stakeholder discussions, project planning, and skill development.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: Looking back, what advice would you give your younger self or someone just starting their SAP journey?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To my younger self, I’d say: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Start with basics, business processes, then explore SAP modules.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To newcomers: first understand real-world business challenges and processes, then learn Intelligent Enterprise concepts and SAP Business Suite flows. Everything else falls into place.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: How has your learning impacted others at work or beyond?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My journey has inspired juniors, peers, and even seniors to seek guidance for their SAP learning.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Outside work, this led to invitations to podcasts, panels, and SAP events as a speaker. It also strengthened my credibility and reinforced my position as a thought leader in the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At this point, friends and colleagues joke: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Just Google his name, you’ll find him.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Learner Story - Kunal Bansal.png" style="width: 267px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324669i275F11989068541E/image-dimensions/267x334/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="267" height="334" role="button" title="Learner Story - Kunal Bansal.png" alt="Learner Story - Kunal Bansal.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Q: What’s been your proudest moment?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Being recognized as one of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Champions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; worldwide was surreal and humbling. But I’m equally proud of helping colleagues grow, guiding careers, and creating a culture of continuous learning within my practice.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: Bonus question: what’s the weirdest place you’ve ever studied SAP?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Definitely old bookshops on Bangalore’s streets, while hunting for novels. They gave me strange looks but for me, learning can happen anywhere.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: And if your SAP learning journey were a movie?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learning Is Lifelong.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;” The moment you think you’ve mastered it all, the technology changes and you realize you’re still a student.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kunal’s advice to every SAP learner:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Start with what businesses need, not what buttons to click. SAP understanding, certifications and success will follow.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to carve out your own daily hour? Explore &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;learning journeys and certifications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; and see how far curiosity can take you. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/one-hour-one-habit-one-champion-kunal-bansal-s-lifelong-learning-story/ba-p/14238286"/>
    <published>2025-10-08T14:53:14.971000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-supply-chain-management-certification-increase-your-expertise-and/ba-p/14167288</id>
    <title>SAP Supply Chain Management Certification: Increase Your Expertise and Credibility</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T07:18:59.688000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ledwards19</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3980</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Running sustainable, resilient supply chains amid disruptions has become a driving force in many organizations. While supply chains have historically prioritized efficiency and cost reduction, digital technologies are delivering incredible gains to achieve even greater outcomes, while connecting processes and enabling faster insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In these times of rapid innovation, it’s becoming increasingly more critical to stay informed of the latest positioning guidance for SAP Supply Chain solutions. SAP has addressed this need by offering a &lt;EM&gt;non-technical certification&lt;/EM&gt; option:&lt;STRONG&gt; Positioning SAP Business Suite via SAP Supply Chain Management Solutions.&lt;/STRONG&gt; The non-technical certifications options are designed to be completed in a matter of few hours, thus making it a great option for individuals who are new to certification, looking to replace an expired certification, or simply interested in cultivating expertise in selling SAP Supply Chain solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Becoming certified in SAP Supply Chain Management solutions will prepare you to gain the confidence and trust in your biggest stakeholder, the Chief Operating Officer (“COO”).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The self-paced learning content will cover these key areas:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The end-to-end solution portfolio and how it addresses key priorities for the COO&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to position Supply Chain Management solutions in the context of SAP Business Suite&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How AI is being used today in modern business settings as well as how it fits into the SAP’s Business AI strategy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Selling SAP Supply Chain Management solutions to the COO through qualification, discovery, and packaging.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upon completing the digital learning, your certification attainment is achieved by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Submission of one of the following hands-on exercises:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Articulating the value of SAP Supply Chain solutions through an executive pitch&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Demonstrating the value of SAP Supply Chain solution by performing a demo.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Successful completion of a one-hour exam that will include thirty questions derived from the self-paced learning content.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t Delay—take advantage of this opportunity to establish your credibility in SAP Supply Chain Management and showcase your accomplishment. With around 5 hours of self-paced learning, this certification option is achievable for any busy professional and will provide tangible value in your field of expertise. Visit the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/products/customer-experience" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning Site&lt;/A&gt; to review the available certifications and select &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-positioning-sap-business-suite-via-sap-supply-chain-business-network-solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Positioning SAP Business Suite via SAP Supply Chain Management&lt;/A&gt; so you can start expertly positioning SAP’s Supply Chain Management solutions to solve your customer’s key challenges and deliver real-world results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lauren Edwards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Industries &amp;amp; Experience, Partner Solution Enablement, SAP Supply Chain Management&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-supply-chain-management-certification-increase-your-expertise-and/ba-p/14167288"/>
    <published>2025-10-09T07:18:59.688000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/announcing-the-sap-sales-cloud-version-2-classroom-training/ba-p/14240791</id>
    <title>Announcing the SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 Classroom Training</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T20:32:07.583000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DeepaliJohnson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124577</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The sales landscape is evolving at a breakneck pace, driven by AI, cloud transformation, and the demand for ultimate sales productivity. To meet this change head-on, we are thrilled to announce the official release of our foundational classroom training: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/c4h470-sap-sales-cloud-version-2-classroom-052-de-en/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;C4H470: SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This in-depth, instructor-led course is not just a review of new features—it is a comprehensive deep dive designed to elevate the skills of every professional involved in the SAP Sales Cloud ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1891768259"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Why You Can’t Afford to Miss This Course&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 is a massive leap forward, and this training is your guided path to mastering its power. Designed for both business users and administrators, C4H470 focuses on practical, hands-on application:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1824337473"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;1. Harness the Power of AI and Intelligent Sales&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Dive into the future of sales by leveraging &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Machine Learning and Gen AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; capabilities. You will learn the applications of the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;CX AI Toolkit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Lead Intelligence&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to automate and optimize decision-making, ensuring smarter lead scoring and a decisive competitive advantage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1627823968"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2. Hands-On Mastery of Productivity Tools&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Empower yourself and your sales teams with advanced tactics for opportunity management and pipeline execution. You will gain hands-on experience with:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Guided Selling App:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Utilizing playbooks to manage opportunity progression and ensure adherence to sales methodology.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Pipeline Manager:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Optimizing pipeline performance and identifying critical sales trends.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Forecast Tracker:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Improving forecast accuracy and monitoring sales performance effectively.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Digital Selling Workspace:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Organizing and prioritizing sales actions with enhanced task management features.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1431310463"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;3. Core System Proficiency and Administration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The course provides the confidence needed to navigate the system's new architecture and configuration. Key modules include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Comprehensive Configuration:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Tailoring core components like Leads, Opportunities, Quotes, Sales Orders, and Visits to reflect your business-specific processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Effective Administration:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Mastering the daily workflow, including user setup, advanced configurations, and data management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Seamless Collaboration:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Configuring and leveraging communication tools, such as &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Microsoft Teams Integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Relationship Intelligence&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, to streamline sales execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105714239"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Who Needs This Essential Training?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Whether you are a key decision-maker or on the front lines of sales technology, this course is essential.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Audience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="197px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="196.2px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;System Administrators&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="196.2px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Application Consultants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="196.2px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Business Users&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="196.2px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Super/Key Power Users&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This is your opportunity to elevate your skills, secure your expertise in the latest SAP release, and actively drive business growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Elevate your skills and stay ahead in the ever-evolving sales landscape. Register now for C4H470 to secure your spot!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/announcing-the-sap-sales-cloud-version-2-classroom-training/ba-p/14240791"/>
    <published>2025-10-10T20:32:07.583000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/learning-with-heart-and-structure-patrizia-rossi-s-story/ba-p/14240258</id>
    <title>Learning with Heart and Structure: Patrizia Rossi’s Story</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:57:44.817000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>margherita_gallucci34</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In 2020, Patrizia Rossi welcomed a tiny puppy into her life in Rome. “He was so small and tender that just looking at him made me feel better,” she recalls. What began as playful walks and teaching simple commands soon grew into something more substantial. By combining instinct with structured training, Patrizia discovered a whole new world. In time, she and her dog even became &lt;STRONG&gt;agility champions,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;something she never imagined at the beginning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Patrizia and her puppy training" style="width: 176px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325491i8A4444BC9A3854B4/image-dimensions/176x311/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="176" height="311" role="button" title="Agility.jpg" alt="Patrizia and her puppy training" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Patrizia and her puppy training&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;That joyful chapter came during a challenging time, after the loss of her younger brother and her mother. The puppy became more than a companion. He was a source of comfort and a reminder that growth often comes from pairing passion with structure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For Patrizia, the parallel with her SAP-related career was clear. Twenty years earlier, she began her career as an ABAP developer in Turin, learning by doing. Over the years, she specialized in SAP Fiori and SAP Business Technology Platform. Like with her dog, instinct and practice alone weren’t enough for her full potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“To really grow, I needed structured learning, a path that combined hands-on experience with theory,” she explains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That approach shaped her career. Until 2024, Patrizia was an SAP consultant, supporting clients on backend and frontend solutions. Recently, she joined the &lt;STRONG&gt;European Space Agency&lt;/STRONG&gt; as an SAP Solution Architect. Her role now demands concrete, reliable solutions, and SAP Certifications give her that foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="sappress.jpg" style="width: 195px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325502i0497913479774538/image-dimensions/195x260/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="195" height="260" role="button" title="sappress.jpg" alt="sappress.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;She recently earned the &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP BTP Solution Architect certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;, adding to several certifications. For her, certifications aren’t just credentials; they build confidence. "When you know the theory, you don’t just work better, you become an added value. You support colleagues, propose stronger solutions, and solve problems faster."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That difference was clear when she activated &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Work Zone Advanced Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Since she was also preparing for the SAP Build Work Zone certification, she was able to solve issues quickly that practicing alone wouldn’t have prepared her for.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Those are the moments when you feel like you’ve won the lottery,” she laughs. “After banging your head against a problem, you run a test and… it works!”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Patrizia remembers a colleague who encouraged her. Every time she cracked a tough problem, he would laugh and shout: "MONSTER!" Though he is no longer here, Patrizia keeps the tradition. "Whenever I solve something impossible, I still whisper: ‘MONSTERRR!’"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For Patrizia, certifications and structured learning turned her from a consultant who once relied on instinct to a solution architect trusted at the highest levels. Just like in dog training, practice matters—but theory and structure make you unstoppable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Want to become the next “monster” problem solver?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Explore structured learning paths and certifications at the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/learning-with-heart-and-structure-patrizia-rossi-s-story/ba-p/14240258"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:57:44.817000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/strengthening-security-on-sap-btp-neo-environment-with-digicert-global-root/ba-p/14246784</id>
    <title>Strengthening Security on SAP BTP Neo Environment with DigiCert Global Root G3</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T10:00:41.951000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LyuboslavL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2135273</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="LyuboslavL_0-1760688028101.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328882iE92DCA25D73CD590/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="LyuboslavL_0-1760688028101.png" alt="LyuboslavL_0-1760688028101.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, keeping your data and applications secure is always a top priority.&lt;BR /&gt;To further strengthen the security of the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Neo environment&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we are migrating to the “&lt;STRONG&gt;DigiCert Global Root G3&lt;/STRONG&gt;” Public Key Infrastructure (PKI). This update ensures long-term trust, improved encryption, and compliance with the latest international security standards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Do You Need to Do Anything&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For most customers,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;no action is required&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Modern web browsers (like Google Chrome and Mozilla Firefox) and up-to-date operating systems already trust the new DigiCert Global Root G3 certificate automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, if your organization manages certificates manually or maintains its own trust store, your technical team should add the new G3 certificate before the March 2026 deadline.&lt;BR /&gt;This ensures continued, secure access to SAP BTP services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Do not remove the existing G2 certificate — both should remain active during the transition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This change is part of SAP’s ongoing commitment to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keep your data and applications secure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Align with the latest global and national security standards&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure continued compatibility with modern browsers and systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By making this upgrade, SAP is helping customers stay protected and ready for the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Timeline&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;full migration to DigiCert Global Root G3&lt;/STRONG&gt; will take effect in &lt;STRONG&gt;March 2026&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Until then, both the G2 and G3 certificates will remain active to ensure a smooth transition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Add the DigiCert Global Root G3 Certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you manage your own trust stores, please follow these steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visit the DigiCert root certificate page: &lt;A href="https://www.digicert.com/kb/digicert-root-certificates.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.digicert.com/kb/digicert-root-certificates.htm&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Locate &lt;STRONG&gt;“DigiCert Global Root G3.”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Download the appropriate certificate format for your environment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify the certificate fingerprint using your preferred tool (for example, with OpenSSL:&lt;BR /&gt;openssl x509 -noout -text -in ./DigiCertGlobalRootG3.crt.pem -fingerprint)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Follow your trust store’s instructions to add the certificate.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For guidance on managing trusted certificates for SAP BTP, see the &lt;A href="https://github.com/sap-software/btp-trust-store/blob/main/README.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;BTP Trust Store on GitHub&lt;/A&gt;. To streamline future updates, we recommend applying the BTP Trust Store regularly or automating this process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Affected Domains&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This update applies to the following platform domains in the SAP BTP Neo environment:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.dispatcher.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.cert.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.static.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.vms.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.netweaver.ondemand.com&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;connectivitynotification.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;connectivitytunnel.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For a full overview of regions and domain hosts, see the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-btp-neo-environment/regions-and-hosts-available-for-neo-environment" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Domains&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-owned custom domains are &lt;STRONG&gt;not affected&lt;/STRONG&gt; by this change until &lt;STRONG&gt;March 2026&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;After this date, all new automated certificate renewals will use the DigiCert Global Root G3 certificate. New SAP-owned custom domains created after March 2026 will also use G3 by default.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Staying secure is a shared effort — and we’re making it easier for you.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;With the DigiCert Global Root G3 upgrade, SAP BTP continues to offer a trusted, reliable, and compliant cloud environment for your business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/strengthening-security-on-sap-btp-neo-environment-with-digicert-global-root/ba-p/14246784"/>
    <published>2025-10-17T10:00:41.951000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/save-your-spot-live-sessions-with-an-sap-sales-cloud-v2-expert-nov-10-12/ba-p/14254592</id>
    <title>Save your spot! Live Sessions with an SAP Sales Cloud V2 Expert – Nov 10-12, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T21:44:08.369000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DeepaliJohnson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124577</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Product Learning team is excited to run the series of live sessions focused on our new product, SAP Sales Cloud V2. These sessions will take place over three 1-hour segments, led by a product expert and are designed to provide a comprehensive understanding of SAP Sales Cloud V2's functionality and configuration.&lt;BR /&gt;During these sessions, we will offer valuable insights into the latest features and provide practical knowledge to help you maximize the benefits of this new product. Whether you're already familiar with SAP Sales Cloud V2 or considering its integration into your operations, these sessions will deliver the in-depth information needed to enhance your proficiency. This is also a fantastic opportunity to learn directly from an expert and ask questions in real-time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a brief agenda:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Session 1 – Overview of the solution from a functional perspective&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Session 2 - Deep Dive Part 1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Onboarding&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales Cloud Version 2 set-up&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fundamentals including Global Search, Extensibility, User&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Control etc.Session&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Session 3 - Deep Dive Part 2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Guided Selling&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Digital Sales Engagement&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Pipeline Management&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Forecasting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;MS Team integration and Autoflow&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As many of you know, SAP Sales Cloud V2 offers a wide range of features aimed at improving your sales processes. It is a cloud-native solution designed to boost productivity, manage customer relationships more effectively, and gain better insights from your data.&lt;BR /&gt;Don't miss out—secure your spot by signing up. We look forward to seeing you there!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: These sessions require a login with &lt;STRONG&gt;learning.sap.com&lt;/STRONG&gt; or an &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Learning Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; License.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/sap-sales-cloud-version-2-overview-and-deep-dive" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here to register&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sales+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100700002221" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="811-1"&gt;SAP Sales Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Training/pd-p/676305042803066886656318788802663" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1167-1"&gt;Training&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Customer+Experience/pd-p/cae17fd6-917e-483d-881a-502155cade3c" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1152-1"&gt;Customer Experience&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/save-your-spot-live-sessions-with-an-sap-sales-cloud-v2-expert-nov-10-12/ba-p/14254592"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T21:44:08.369000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/preparing-for-sap-c-cpe-here-s-how-i-m-studying-each-section-without/ba-p/14259621</id>
    <title>Preparing for SAP C_CPE? Here’s How I’m Studying Each Section Without Feeling Overwhelmed</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T15:23:22.635000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chahat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1574359</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Whenever I start learning something new, I like to have everything in order.&lt;BR /&gt;Before I even open the first tutorial, I plan what I’ll study first, what comes next, and how I’ll track it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently, I started preparing for the SAP C_CPE (SAP Certified Associate - Backend Developer -&amp;nbsp;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model) certification. Since this exam covers a mix of BTP architecture, SAP BAS, CAP, Side by side extensions, Cloud Foundry &amp;amp; Kyma Runtime&amp;nbsp; it can easily feel like too much at once. So I created a simple structure to move step by step without feeling lost.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I began with the learning about BTP, and doing hands on by following SAP Learning Journeys, creating subaccount and adding entitlements and services (It gave me a very clear understanding of BTP architecture) and then Developing appliaction using high productivity tools of SAP BAS, Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP) because it’s the foundation of most topics in this certification. I’m spending around two weeks learning about CDS models, service layers and how everything connects in a CAP project. I’m following the official SAP Learning Journey&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-backend-developer-sap-cloud-programming-model" href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-backend-developer-sap-cloud-programming-model" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-backend-developer-sap-cloud-program…...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My next focus is Cloud Foundry. I’ll spend about a week learning how to efficiently develop, run, and manage cloud-native applications on SAP BTP, Cloud Foundry Runtime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After that, I’ll move to Side by side extention on BTP.&amp;nbsp; This will cover&amp;nbsp;deploying&amp;nbsp; extension and integrating the app into SAP Build Work Zone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next stage is Developing Appliactions in Kyma Environment. I’ll take about two weeks to explore&amp;nbsp;a comprehensive understanding of Kubernetes and&amp;nbsp;to orchestrate the deployment of the applications in the cloud.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, I’ll study Advanced Extensions with SAP Cloud SDK for about two more weeks. These are slightly advanced topics but very useful for understanding&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;develop and integrate Java, JavaScript, and TypeScript extension applications for SAP solutions like SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So in short, this will be my roadmap-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommended Study Sequence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s the order I suggest, from foundational to more advanced :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exploring SAP Business Technology Platform 5hrs (link :&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-business-technology-platform" href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-business-technology-platform" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-business-technology-platform)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This gives you a broad overview of the entire platform (services, architecture, what BTP is). Good for building your base understanding.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;So start here.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.Develop Full‑Stack Applications Using Productivity Tools in SAP Business Application Studio 8hrs (&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-full-stack-applications-using-productivity-tools-in-sap-business-application-studio" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-full-stack-applications-using-productivity-tools-in-sap-business-application-studio" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-full-stack-applications-using-productivity-tools-in-sap-business-application-studio)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.Develop Applications on SAP BTP, Cloud Foundry Runtime 4hrs(&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-on-sap-btp-cloud-foundry-runtime" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-on-sap-btp-cloud-foundry-runtime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-on-sap-btp-cloud-foundry-runtime)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Cloud Foundry runtime is a major runtime environment in BTP. Understanding how to build and deploy there is critical.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4.Build Side‑by‑Side Extensions on SAP BTP 8hrs (&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/build-side-by-side-extensions-on-sap-btp" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/build-side-by-side-extensions-on-sap-btp" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/build-side-by-side-extensions-on-sap-btp)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After tooling and platform basics, you dive into extension scenarios (for example side-by-side extensions of S/4HANA using CAP). This aligns closely with CAP certification topics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5.Developing Applications in SAP BTP, Kyma Runtime 8hrs(&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-in-sap-btp-kyma-runtime" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-in-sap-btp-kyma-runtime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-in-sap-btp-kyma-runtime)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Kyma Runtime is more advanced (Kubernetes, microservices, event-mesh) and often sits on top of foundational knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6.Develop Advanced Extensions with SAP Cloud SDK 11hrs (&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-advanced-extensions-with-sap-cloud-sdk" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-advanced-extensions-with-sap-cloud-sdk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-advanced-extensions-with-sap-cloud-sdk)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is relatively specialized/advanced (SAP Cloud SDK, perhaps custom libraries, integrations). Once you’ve mastered the fundamentals above, you go here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By the end of this plan, I’ll go through a short revision period with mock questions and quick notes from my learning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This structured approach keeps my study plan clear and prevents me from feeling overwhelmed.&lt;BR /&gt;I study for two to four hours a day which feels realistic, and the small milestones make it easier to stay consistent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re also preparing for C_CPE, it really helps to make your own sequence instead of jumping randomly between topics. The Learning Journeys are excellent resources, but having a personal roadmap makes a big difference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’d love to hear how others are preparing for this certification too.&lt;BR /&gt;What topics are you finding most challenging so far and how are you managing the learning&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/preparing-for-sap-c-cpe-here-s-how-i-m-studying-each-section-without/ba-p/14259621"/>
    <published>2025-11-04T15:23:22.635000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/ba-p/14261141</id>
    <title>Reimagining Certification for the Way We Work Today</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T11:21:05.659000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DianaRoesner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10529</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For decades, certifications&amp;nbsp;exams&amp;nbsp;have&amp;nbsp;followed the same pattern:&amp;nbsp;silent rooms, strict proctors, and no access to the tools&amp;nbsp;you’d&amp;nbsp;normally use to get work done. The goal was to&amp;nbsp;test&amp;nbsp;what you knew (or could remember)&amp;nbsp;in that moment, not what you could&amp;nbsp;actually do.&amp;nbsp;But work&amp;nbsp;doesn’t&amp;nbsp;happen that way. And learning certainly&amp;nbsp;doesn’t&amp;nbsp;either.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today, projects are fast paced, connected, and collaborative. When&amp;nbsp;you’re&amp;nbsp;solving a problem, you&amp;nbsp;don’t&amp;nbsp;sit in silence — you look for information, consult with teammates, and use the tools available to you. With AI now woven into how we all work,&amp;nbsp;it’s&amp;nbsp;time for certification to evolve too.&amp;nbsp;That’s&amp;nbsp;why&amp;nbsp;we’re&amp;nbsp;reimagining SAP Certification.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From memory to mastery&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Certification&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;shifting from proctored, multiple-choice tests to&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;performance-based, practical, open-book&amp;nbsp;assessments&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;that&amp;nbsp;mirror real work.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Instead of answering theoretical questions,&amp;nbsp;you’ll&amp;nbsp;complete&amp;nbsp;realistic&amp;nbsp;challenges that&amp;nbsp;show&amp;nbsp;how you&amp;nbsp;actually&amp;nbsp;apply&amp;nbsp;your SAP knowledge — configuring systems, building applications, solving problems, or advising&amp;nbsp;customers&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;solutions.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are two types of practical exams:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System-based:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;You’ll&amp;nbsp;perform time-boxed tasks directly in SAP systems.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scenario-based:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;You’ll&amp;nbsp;interact with an AI avatar to respond to real customer or project situations.&amp;nbsp;(For&amp;nbsp;learners who&amp;nbsp;don’t&amp;nbsp;want to&amp;nbsp;use AI,&amp;nbsp;we&amp;nbsp;provide&amp;nbsp;an alternative&amp;nbsp;option to upload a&amp;nbsp;video&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;human review.)&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These&amp;nbsp;‘open-book’&amp;nbsp;exams allow access to&amp;nbsp;resources&amp;nbsp;like&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-CERT-Reimagined" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-CERT-Reimagined" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-CERT-Reimagined" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community, or&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-assistant/sap-consulting-capability.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-CERT-Reimagined" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Joule for Consultants&amp;nbsp;— just as you would use in your daily work.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learning that feels real&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This transformation&amp;nbsp;makes certification more meaningful and consistent with how you already learn. The types of&amp;nbsp;practical&amp;nbsp;exercises and scenarios you complete on the SAP Learning site now continue into the exam, so preparation and assessment feel like part of one experience.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Each exam is time-boxed and focused on proving you can do the work, not just recall facts.&amp;nbsp;There’s&amp;nbsp;no live proctoring; instead, identity is confirmed through SAP Universal ID,&amp;nbsp;reflecting trust in how professionals really work.&amp;nbsp;You’ll&amp;nbsp;still have to think critically and manage your time, but&amp;nbsp;you’ll&amp;nbsp;do so in a context that mirrors your day-to-day work, not an artificial testing environment.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A phased rollout for all certifications&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beginning in&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;November 2025&lt;SPAN&gt;, the first practical certifications,&amp;nbsp;including&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-professional-solution-architect-sap-btp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution Architect for SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-generative-ai-developer?source=contentsynd-global-bigdatainsider-prdteng" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Generative AI Developer&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-low-code-no-code-developer-sap-build" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Developer&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-btp-administrator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP System Administrator&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(new) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-rise-with-sap-methodology-and-experience" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;RISE&amp;nbsp;with&amp;nbsp;SAP Methodology&amp;nbsp;and Experience&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(new,)&amp;nbsp;will go live.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;By&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;2026,&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;all&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Certifications will shift to this new, practical format. That means everyone – consultants, developers, administrators,&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;sales professionals – will&amp;nbsp;validate&amp;nbsp;their&amp;nbsp;expertise&amp;nbsp;in ways that reflect how work&amp;nbsp;actually gets&amp;nbsp;done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why&amp;nbsp;this matters&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At its core, this transformation is about trust that SAP Certification accurately&amp;nbsp;represents&amp;nbsp;real capability. For learners, it means your credential truly reflects your skills. For employers, it means confidence that a certified professional can perform from day one.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When we launch&amp;nbsp;at SAP TechEd&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;Berlin,&amp;nbsp;we’re&amp;nbsp;not just&amp;nbsp;transforming&amp;nbsp;certification;&amp;nbsp;we’re&amp;nbsp;redefining what it means to be skilled in the AI era.&amp;nbsp;And for learners everywhere, that means your effort&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;experience&amp;nbsp;now matter&amp;nbsp;more than ever.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To learn more about our reimagined certification model, visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/training-certification/sap-certification.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Certification&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and read the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/helpcenter/certification-support/practical-exam?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-CERT-Reimagined" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FAQ&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/ba-p/14261141"/>
    <published>2025-11-05T11:21:05.659000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tri%C3%A2ngulo-mineiro-blog-posts/certifica%C3%A7%C3%B5es-sap-mudan%C3%A7a-para-formato-pr%C3%A1tico-e-open-book/ba-p/14266954</id>
    <title>Certificações SAP: mudança para formato prático e open-book</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T14:37:54.068000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Renato_Baracca</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/527140</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Certificação SAP: novo formato prático em implementação&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A SAP está transformando o formato das certificações para refletir melhor a forma como trabalhamos atualmente.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;O que muda:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ao invés de questões teóricas de múltipla escolha, o novo formato inclui:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tarefas práticas em sistemas SAP reais&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cenários simulados com avatares de IA representando situações de clientes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Acesso a recursos como SAP Help, Community e Joule durante o exame&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A proposta é alinhar a certificação com o ambiente de trabalho real: colaborativo, conectado e com IA integrada.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Mais informações: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/ba-p/14261141" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/ba-p/14261141&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tri%C3%A2ngulo-mineiro-blog-posts/certifica%C3%A7%C3%B5es-sap-mudan%C3%A7a-para-formato-pr%C3%A1tico-e-open-book/ba-p/14266954"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T14:37:54.068000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-prepare-for-sap-s-new-certification/ba-p/14268066</id>
    <title>How to Prepare for SAP’s New Certification</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:00:18.140000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SuyashVerma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1593598</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For years, SAP certification relied on multiple-choice questions and memorized answers. That approach no longer fits the realities of modern SAP work, where professionals configure systems, solve business problems, and increasingly collaborate with AI-driven tools. Simply recalling information isn’t enough.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new SAP certification model shifts the focus from “knowing SAP” to “doing SAP,” i.e., applying skills in real-world scenarios, navigating tools, and demonstrating practical competence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re planning to get certified soon, your preparation needs to evolve with it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764764095"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Changing and What It Means for Your Preparation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s new practical certification exams introduce a more authentic and performance-oriented approach to skill validation. Instead of testing whether you can recall a configuration detail, the new exams examine whether you can complete tasks, solve problems, and make decisions in situations that resemble real project environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;They use two primary formats: System-based assessment and Scenario-based assessment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;System-based assessment &lt;/STRONG&gt;is&amp;nbsp;where learners work inside a time-limited SAP system simulation. You are required to perform actual tasks, such as configuring components, building processes, developing artifacts, or resolving issues, just as you would in a project environment. The assessment measures your fluency in SAP tools, your ability to execute steps accurately, and your ability to apply best practices in a live system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario-based assessment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;places you in time-limited role-play situations with an AI avatar. In these scenarios, you must pitch SAP solutions, advise on architecture, justify design choices, respond to stakeholder concerns, and guide the conversation toward appropriate outcomes. Rather than executing system tasks, this format evaluates how you think, communicate, analyse requirements, and represent SAP’s capabilities in a business context.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each certification will use &lt;STRONG&gt;only one format&lt;/STRONG&gt;, either system-based or scenario-based, depending on the nature of the role being assessed. Technical roles emphasise hands-on execution, while consulting and architecture roles prioritise analytical and advisory depth. This creates a more precise and meaningful measurement of job readiness.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The exams are also now &lt;STRONG&gt;open-book&lt;/STRONG&gt;, allowing access to documentation, help portals, and AI-assisted guidance during the assessment. This change reflects how professionals actually work. They consult resources, verify information, test assumptions, and use intelligent tools like SAP Joule to support decision-making. The exam rewards the ability to locate, interpret, and apply information under realistic constraints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is rolling out this new model in phases. The first six certifications are already live and have received a strong response from the ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/get-certified/reimagining-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click this link to access the SAP Certifications featuring practical exams.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568250590"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Prepare for SAP's New Certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Train on SAP Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hands-on experience is now the most important part of certification readiness. Since the new exams rely heavily on real system usage or scenario execution, you must become comfortable navigating SAP environments directly. Spend time configuring components, building workflows, testing integrations, and troubleshooting issues in SAP BTP, &amp;nbsp;SAP Build, and other relevant tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Memorizing theory will not substitute for actual system familiarity, so create consistent practice sessions that mirror the tasks you expect to face in real projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adopt an Open-Book Learning Mindset&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because SAP’s new exams allow access to documentation and official resources, your success depends on how efficiently you can locate and apply information. Instead of trying to memorize every detail, shift your focus toward learning how SAP documentation is structured, where key topics are located, and how to interpret guidance quickly under time constraints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During preparation, challenge yourself to answer questions by navigating documentation rather than recalling facts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practise Scenario-Based Problem Solving&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new certification format rewards professionals who can think in end-to-end scenarios rather than isolated tasks. To build this skill, spend time working through full business situations that could appear in an exam.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine a client wants to automate approval workflows, integrate an external application, or modernize their analytics landscape. Break down how you would approach the requirement, which SAP tools you would use, what architecture makes sense, and what risks or trade-offs you would consider.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The more you practise this style of thinking, the more natural it becomes to articulate decisions and explain your reasoning during a scenario-based assessment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strengthen Your Architecture and Data Foundations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modern SAP work revolves around cloud services, data modeling, integration patterns, event-driven design, and automation. To prepare for the new certifications, make time to revisit these fundamentals. Understanding how components fit together will help you make informed decisions, whether you are configuring a system or advising a simulated stakeholder. This broader technical foundation also enables you to respond effectively during role-plays that require architectural justification or strategic recommendations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build a Continuous Learning Habit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The redesigned certification model encourages professionals to keep their skills active rather than rely on one-time exam success. As SAP continues to evolve its tools and expand its AI-driven capabilities, staying connected to the ecosystem, whether through hands-on practice, learning content, or experimentation with new features, will help you remain prepared for renewals and future certifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371737085"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What These Changes Mean for Your Career&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new certification format narrows the gap between being certified and being project-ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the assessments test actual capability, credentials earned under this model will carry greater weight with employers seeking professionals who can contribute immediately. It also shifts the ecosystem toward continuous learning, where staying certified means staying active, hands-on, and connected to SAP’s evolving technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The certifications also mark an important milestone in SAP’s broader commitment to equip 12 million people worldwide with AI-ready skills by 2030.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you approach your learning with the mindset of becoming truly project-ready rather than simply exam-ready, you will not only succeed in the new certification format but also build a stronger, more sustainable foundation for your SAP career.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The exam has evolved, and your preparation needs to evolve with it, too.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-prepare-for-sap-s-new-certification/ba-p/14268066"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:00:18.140000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/certified-excellence-how-cognizant-sets-the-benchmark-for-driving-real-sap/ba-p/14269012</id>
    <title>Certified Excellence: How Cognizant Sets the Benchmark for Driving Real SAP Transformation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T16:40:08.041000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christine13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our longstanding partner Cognizant sheds light on how it is redefining SAP services for a cloud-first, AI-powered world.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In this interview, &lt;U&gt;Sivakumar Varadananjayan&lt;/U&gt;, Assistant Vice President and Delivery Head – SAP Cloud &amp;amp; SAP GGM Product and Resources (Global Growth Market) at Cognizant Technology Solutions, shares insights about Cognizant's&amp;nbsp;Path from ERP to AI-Powered, Industry-Focused Innovation. As the leader of Cognizant’s SAP Certification initiative and its Validation Partner status, Sivakumar also shares his perspective on Cognizant’s renewed global certifications, the evolution of their SAP certification journey, and how they plan to further expand their SAP competencies to support customers. The conversation was conducted during Cognizant’s SAP Certification process, together with Christophe André, SAP Auditor and Partner Manager, who led the audit at Cognizant, and Hossam Saad, SAP Partner Manager and Cognizant’s main point of contact.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar outlines how they have evolved from traditional ERP implementations to a transformation model centered on automation, intelligence, and industry specificity. He also discusses their role as a RISE with SAP Validated Partner, its commitment to SAP Best Practices, and how cloud migrations are accelerated through clean-core principles and end-to-end governance. With renewed global SAP certifications, expanded security capabilities, and deep DevOps integration, Cognizant positions itself as a pioneer in secure, future-ready SAP transformation. Looking ahead, Sivakumar shares how continued investment in talent, co-innovation, and industry-focused solutions will shape the next chapter of intelligent enterprise modernization.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Christophe: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cognizant is globally known for providing SAP-related services. How have you been adapting your services to ever-changing customer needs and technology innovations?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Adaptability is at the heart of Cognizant’s SAP strategy. Over the past decade, we’ve transitioned from traditional ERP implementations to cloud-first, AI-enabled, and automation-driven models. Our approach focuses on three pillars:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Enablement:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We leverage &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to deliver scalable, resilient architectures that support rapid innovation and business agility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Automation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Through SAP Business AI, Joule Agents, and Cognizant’s Automation Fabric, we integrate robotic process automation and generative AI into SAP workflows, reducing manual effort and improving accuracy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer-Centric Design:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We co-innovate with clients using SAP’s cloud solutions and industry accelerators, ensuring transformation aligns with their business priorities and delivers measurable outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation is embedded in every stage – from &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP S/4HANA Conversions&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt; like SAP-Certified &lt;STRONG&gt;Case Management AI Agent for SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Finance4U®&lt;/STRONG&gt; for industry-specific needs. These capabilities enable real-time insights, predictive analytics, and continuous modernization, helping clients thrive in a rapidly changing digital economy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Christophe: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cognizant positions itself as a pioneer in leveraging SAP Business Suite, cloud ERP, and Business AI. How do you tailor your SAP services to address industry-specific challenges, and what role does innovation play?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cognizant tailors its SAP services through a deep industry-in-context approach - combining process expertise, data intelligence, and AI-driven automation to address the unique challenges of each sector. Our strategy integrates SAP Business Suite, cloud ERP, and Business AI with domain accelerators, industry templates, and pre-built integration frameworks that shorten time-to-value and enhance business agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation is embedded in every stage - from co-innovation with SAP and hyperscale cloud platforms to leveraging SAP Business AI, developing digital twins, and advanced analytics for continuous transformation. This ensures that clients don’t just modernize their ERP landscape but also unlock new business models, improve decision velocity, and stay future-ready in an AI-enabled economy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;A strong example of this innovation-led, industry-tailored approach is reflected in Cognizant’s &lt;STRONG&gt;Utegration &lt;/STRONG&gt;portfolio&amp;nbsp;for utilities and energy enterprises:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance4U® Extended Asset Accounting:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enhances SAP property accounting with regulatory-compliant, utility-specific asset management capabilities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance4U® Regulatory Accounting and Reporting:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Streamlines regulated financial reporting, improving data accuracy and audit readiness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Utility4U™:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A RISE with SAP-based cloud accelerator that modernizes and simplifies the utility ERP landscape while embedding industry best practices.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MeterData4U®:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Unlocks the value of Advanced Metering Infrastructure (AMI) by integrating and operationalizing meter data within SAP environments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, these offerings demonstrate how Cognizant combines deep domain experience with SAP innovation to deliver measurable outcomes across industries - from operational efficiency to intelligent, data-driven growth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hossam: &lt;/STRONG&gt;As a “RISE with SAP Validated Partner,” what has been your experience in leading SAP customers’ migration to cloud? How are your services modeled around SAP Best Practices?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a RISE with SAP Validated Partner, our experience in leading SAP customers’ migration to the cloud has been extensive and transformative. We have successfully delivered large-scale migrations for global enterprises using SAP’s validated methodology, ensuring predictable timelines, reduced risks, and accelerated time-to-value. Our approach emphasizes &lt;STRONG&gt;clean core principles&lt;/STRONG&gt; with embedded quality gates, supported by SAP Cloud ALM for governance and compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our services are modelled around &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Best Practices&lt;/STRONG&gt;, integrating SAP’s ecosystem tools such as Cloud ALM, LeanIX, Signavio, Business Technology Platform (BTP), Joule, and Tricentis Test Automation. This toolchain enables automation, collaboration, and robust governance throughout the migration journey. Additionally, all key roles - Project Managers, Architects, Developers, and Consultants - are SAP-certified and trained on the latest cloud and AI innovations, ensuring customers are positioned for continuous innovation post-migration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, we focus on delivering &lt;STRONG&gt;customer-centric outcomes&lt;/STRONG&gt; by accelerating cloud transformation with minimal disruption and ensuring smooth migration from ECC or on-premise systems to SAP S/4HANA Cloud. By leveraging SAP Best Practices and validated frameworks, we provide transparent, milestone-driven projects that reduce risk and deliver predictable results. Our engagements consistently achieve high satisfaction scores, reflecting our commitment to quality, innovation, and long-term customer success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Christophe: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cognizant recently renewed global certifications for SAP Business Suite and SAP S/4HANA services and achieved its first global certification for SAP security operations. How do your competencies in DevOps, Security, and Business AI add value?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cognizant’s renewed global certifications for SAP Business Suite and SAP S/4HANA services, along with its first global certification for SAP Security Operations, reinforce our ability to deliver secure, agile, and intelligent SAP transformations. These credentials validate our expertise in modernizing SAP landscapes while ensuring compliance and resilience for mission-critical environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our DevOps competency accelerates SAP delivery through automated CI/CD pipelines, enabling rapid release cycles, improved quality, and seamless integration with RISE with SAP and cloud platforms. In parallel, our Security Operations capability provides proactive threat management, robust identity governance, and real-time monitoring - critical for industries with stringent regulatory requirements. Internally, Cognizant leverages a DevOps for a Unified Competency Management model across SAP competencies to bring people, process, and knowledge together around the work we do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, Business AI brings intelligence into SAP workflows by embedding predictive analytics, generative AI, and automation. This drives faster decision-making, reduces manual effort, and unlocks new business models across sectors. Together, these strengths position Cognizant as a trusted partner for enterprises seeking secure, automated, and AI-powered SAP transformations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hossam: &lt;/STRONG&gt;How has your SAP certification journey evolved - from your first global certification in 2011 to today? What motivated you initially, and how has your approach changed?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As you have rightly pointed out, Cognizant’s SAP global certification journey began in &lt;STRONG&gt;2011&lt;/STRONG&gt;, when we became one of the earliest partners to achieve &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;. At that time, our motivation was clear: to build client &lt;STRONG&gt;confidence&lt;/STRONG&gt;, demonstrate &lt;STRONG&gt;market leadership&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and align with our vision of driving &lt;STRONG&gt;enterprise modernization through cloud-first strategies&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This milestone positioned us ahead of industry trends and validated our ability to deliver secure, scalable SAP solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since then, our approach has evolved from meeting compliance standards to driving continuous innovation. Today, certifications are part of a broader strategy focused on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA, SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, integrating AI, automation, and sustainability into transformation programs. We’ve expanded from core ERP to end-to-end digital solutions, strengthened partnerships with SAP and hyperscale cloud providers, and invested heavily in talent development through role-based certifications. For us, certification is no longer a one-time achievement - it’s a continuous journey to deliver measurable business outcomes and stay ahead of client needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hossam: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Looking ahead, how do you plan to grow your SAP competency and services to support customers?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cognizant plans to deepen its SAP competency by focusing on next-generation technologies such as&lt;STRONG&gt; SAP Business AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;and industry-specific solutions developed and integrated leveraging &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;. We are investing in advanced capabilities around &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA transformations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring clients can accelerate their cloud journeys with agility and resilience. Our strategy includes embedding &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-driven automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;predictive analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;sustainability frameworks&lt;/STRONG&gt; into SAP landscapes, enabling customers to unlock new business models and achieve measurable outcomes. These innovations will be supported by strong partnerships with SAP and hyperscale cloud providers to deliver integrated, multi-cloud architectures tailored to client needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Information on the certification program for operations partners and an overview of all certified partners can be found in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/opc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Operations Partner Guide&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;OPC&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/partners/partner-program/certify-my-solution.html#outsourcing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;or on the &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/partnership/services/co-innovation/opc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Partner Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/certified-excellence-how-cognizant-sets-the-benchmark-for-driving-real-sap/ba-p/14269012"/>
    <published>2025-11-14T16:40:08.041000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/fast-amp-curious-the-making-of-an-sap-champion/ba-p/14272116</id>
    <title>Fast &amp; Curious: The Making of an SAP Champion</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T12:53:30.851000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>margherita_gallucci34</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;On a Saturday morning in Hyderabad, Ruthvik Chowdary might be cruising towards a new destination with his playlist ready or volunteering at an SAP Inside Track event. Whether navigating winding roads or meeting fellow tech enthusiasts, Ruthvik thrives on exploring places, ideas, and opportunities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That same spirit of discovery led him to SAP technology.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inspired by his uncle, an experienced SAP Solution Architect, Ruthvik’s curiosity sparked during college. “He would discuss the problems he solved and SAP’s impact on businesses. It made him want to dive in.” And with his growing interest in manufacturing, it became the perfect starting point.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Guided by mentors and managers, Ruthvik soon broadened his expertise across the entire supply chain. He earned SAP Certifications spanning &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-s-4hana-quality-management?url_id=text-learnerstoryprdteng-LSC" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Quality Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; to &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-extended-warehouse-management-in-sap-s-4hana?url_id=text-global-learnerstory-prdteng-LSC" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Extended Warehouse Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and now, as a Supply Chain Manager at Deloitte, confidently designs and optimizes end-to-end processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;His breakthrough came during a training with a simulated supply bottleneck where he applied his knowledge to solve it. “That was when everything clicked. I understood not just the ‘how,’ but the ‘why.’ It was empowering.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The path, however, was not without challenges. Ruthvik wrestled with complex configurations and moments of self-doubt early in his journey. “I wondered if I was really suited for SAP products.” Encouragement from his mentor, manager, and uncle reminded him that every expert starts as a beginner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Ruthvik Photo 3.jpg" style="width: 340px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342407i29BC2C3946FD785D/image-dimensions/340x311/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="340" height="311" role="button" title="Ruthvik Photo 3.jpg" alt="Ruthvik Photo 3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;What continues to amaze him is SAP’s vastness and the constant innovation in cloud technologies. “It’s like an ocean. There’s always something new to learn.” Along the way, he developed unexpected strengths in communication and client engagement, becoming a trusted problem solver and mentor to others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of his proudest moments was being recognized as an SAP Champion for his contributions to the community. “Knowing my blogs helped others, even in interviews, is incredibly rewarding.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From shadow consultant to SAP Champion, Ruthvik’s story is one of persistence, passion, and purpose. His advice to new learners is simple: “Dive in, stay curious, and do not be afraid to ask for help. The rewards are worth it.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ready to begin your own adventure? Explore structured learning journeys and certifications on the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and discover where curiosity can take you.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/fast-amp-curious-the-making-of-an-sap-champion/ba-p/14272116"/>
    <published>2025-11-19T12:53:30.851000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
