<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Certification-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Certification</title>
  <updated>2025-12-19T00:10:22.929442+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Certification/pd-p/222877341567121072788807155782117" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Certification blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/step-into-the-future-sap-business-ai-operations-certification-for-partners/ba-p/14228667</id>
    <title>Step Into the Future: SAP Business AI Operations Certification for Partners</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T07:08:43.137000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christine13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP partners are driving the next wave of enterprise innovation, and artificial intelligence is at the center of it all. As organizations look to unlock new efficiencies and smarter business outcomes, the ability to operate and manage SAP Business AI solutions is becoming a true differentiator.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s why we’re thrilled to introduce the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business AI solutions operations certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a new credential designed for partners who want to prove their expertise in running, integrating, securing, and extending SAP Business AI. This certification has just been launched, giving early adopters the chance to stand out as pioneers in the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Certification Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AI isn’t just a buzzword anymore. It’s powering real change in how businesses operate, innovate, and serve their customers. But with new technology comes new expectations. Customers want partners who can do more than just deploy AI - they want experts who can keep it running smoothly, securely, and in line with best practices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s where this certification comes in. It’s your chance to show the market that your team knows how to deliver reliable, secure, and high-value SAP Business AI operations. Whether you’re supporting customers, building custom AI solutions, or managing complex integrations, this credential sets you apart.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Inside the Certification?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This isn’t just a technical badge - it's a comprehensive validation of your operational know-how. The certification covers everything from setting up and managing SAP Business AI scenarios and SAP Joule, to integrating AI with business processes and ensuring security, ethics, and compliance. You’ll demonstrate your ability to manage service desks, handle incidents, drive continual improvement, and manage change processes. The program also validates your skills in delivering custom AI development and integration on SAP BTP and applying SAP’s methodologies for project management. You’ll also demonstrate your skills in quality management, knowledge transfer, event management, and more - covering the full spectrum of what it takes to keep SAP Business AI solutions running at their best.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who Should Consider This?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re an SAP partner helping customers adopt, operate, or extend SAP Business AI, this certification is for you. It’s especially valuable for teams providing managed services, custom development, or integration support. If your clients rely on you to keep their AI solutions humming, this is your next step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ready to Take the Leap?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Curious about the details? Want to know how to get started? Reach out to us at SAPOperationsPartners@sap.com or visit &lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/opc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;www.sap.com/opc&lt;/A&gt; for all the info.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI is changing the game. Make sure your team is ready to play - and win. Get certified, get noticed, and help your customers unlock the full power of SAP Business AI.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/step-into-the-future-sap-business-ai-operations-certification-for-partners/ba-p/14228667"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T07:08:43.137000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-abap-to-the-world-daniel-s-journey-of-growth-and-resilience/ba-p/14232471</id>
    <title>From ABAP to the World: Daniel’s Journey of Growth and Resilience</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T11:31:41.422000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arabella</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/145342</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you meet Daniel Mateo Perez outside work, you'll likely find him by the ocean. On Saturday mornings, he's barefoot on the beach with tea or planning his next trip—he's visited over 60 countries. Travel shapes his curious, adaptable, and open perspective—traits vital for SAP projects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Daniel didn’t plan a career working with SAP technology. A Chemical Engineering graduate in Barcelona, he began his professional journey as an ABAP developer at a consulting firm. But he quickly realized his real passion was in connecting technology with business. A manager advised him: &lt;EM&gt;“If you really want to grow, learn Finance and Logistics with SAP.”&lt;/EM&gt; That moment changed everything.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Daniel Mateo cover photo.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321942iC6E4C3790FE8D405/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Daniel Mateo cover photo.png" alt="Daniel Mateo cover photo.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;His first SAP classroom training in Supply Chain Management sparked a powerful realization. “For the first time, I saw how procurement, inventory, and finance all connected. It blew my mind—this was the solution that runs companies.” That moment didn’t just build knowledge; it gave him a surge of confidence and set a clear direction for his professional journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Two decades later, SAP certifications have propelled his career and unlocked new opportunities. Today, he proudly holds &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Activate Project Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA for Financial Accounting&lt;/STRONG&gt; certifications and is already reaching higher, working toward more in SAP S/4HANA Cloud. Each one, Daniel says, has been “a credibility booster,” fueling his ongoing professional growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“SAP Certifications gave me more than technical skills,” he explains. “They gave me trust. With clients, with colleagues, and with myself. When you’re certified, people know you can deliver.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That trust opened doors. Daniel has led multi-country SAP S/4HANA rollouts across various industries, including pharmaceuticals and media, co-authored a book on rollout strategies in Spanish, and mentored younger consultants as they navigate their careers. He’s also become known as the calm presence during stressful go-lives—someone who can translate between IT and finance and keep projects moving.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It hasn’t always been easy. Switching from development to finance consulting nearly made him quit. “I remember leaving a workshop convinced I’d never understand finance,” he admits. But curiosity—and the structure of SAP learning materials—kept him going. Step by step, SAP Certification by SAP Certification, he built both expertise and resilience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Looking back, he says the biggest surprise is that SAP learning never ends. “At first it felt overwhelming, but now I see it as the reason my career has stayed exciting.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If he could give advice to his younger self—or anyone considering starting—Daniel would keep it simple: &lt;EM&gt;“Don’t wait until you feel ready. Nobody knows everything. Just start, get certified, and grow from there.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From backpacking buses in Asia, where he studied for certifications, to global boardrooms where he delivers enterprise transformations, Daniel’s story showcases the real power of SAP Certification: it doesn’t just unlock opportunities—it gives you the confidence and credibility to walk through them.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Take your next step&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: visit the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/get-certified?url_id=text-sapcom-prdteng-Certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, choose your certification, and start shaping your future today.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/from-abap-to-the-world-daniel-s-journey-of-growth-and-resilience/ba-p/14232471"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T11:31:41.422000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/one-hour-one-habit-one-champion-kunal-bansal-s-lifelong-learning-story/ba-p/14238286</id>
    <title>One Hour, One Habit, One Champion: Kunal Bansal’s Lifelong Learning Story 🏆</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T14:53:14.971000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>margherita_gallucci34</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ask Kunal Bansal what the most powerful skill in his career has been, and he won’t say coding, consulting, or communication - he’ll say consistency. Every single day, no matter where he is, he dedicates one hour to learning. That one habit has not only shaped his expertise but also inspired hundreds of others to start their own learning journeys.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: Paint us a picture of who you are beyond work. What would we find you doing on a Saturday morning? What’s something about you that might surprise your colleagues?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Saturday mornings start with badminton with friends and afternoons mentoring rural students. Supporting underprivileged learners keeps me grounded and reminds me why learning matters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I spend at least an hour daily learning. It’s as natural as breathing, but far more rewarding. Mentoring isn’t just a hobby; it’s my passion. Networking and talking to people across industries taught me business processes, the foundation that made SAP technology click for me.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: Take us inside a typical business day. What makes you excited to get up in the morning, and what frustrates you?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My day begins with a workout at the gym. My favorite and happiest hour. After that come leadership calls on people and skill management for our SAP CX practice, followed by client project calls.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tea, lunch, and walks with colleagues mix jokes, work talk, and wisdom.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What frustrates me?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Seeing colleagues stuck in a non-learning, non-growth mindset.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What excites me?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Helping them flip the switch and grow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: Tell us about the moment you decided to learn SAP. What sparked that decision?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I started my career in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://jobs.sap.com/content/sap-star/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Student Training and Rotation program&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; - clueless, wide-eyed, and wondering how to survive in this massive ocean. My mentor,&lt;/SPAN&gt; Ramakrishna, told me something that shaped my entire journey:&amp;nbsp;“&lt;I&gt;Start with basics and learn business processes, not systems.&lt;/I&gt;”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: What was your biggest ‘aha!’ moment?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Back in 2016, I was working on SAP CRM and SAP Marketing Cloud. When I finally understood the CRM business process, the dots connected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I realized that technology wasn’t just moving data. It was orchestrating the heartbeat of a business. That shift turned me into a trusted advisor to customers and the go-to person for technical and business challenges.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: What was the hardest part of your learning journey?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Opening &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/training-certification/learning-hub.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning Hub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for the first time felt like entering a massive library without a map - overwhelming!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I remembered my mentor’s advice: start from basics, learn business processes first. Once I did, the chaos turned into clarity. That persistent learning turned me from a rookie into a recognized community voice.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: What surprised you most about the learning process?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Answering Q&amp;amp;A and writing blogs on SAP Community accelerated my learning more than I expected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Contributing consistently for over seven years helped me become a community influencer and built my personal brand as a subject matter expert which eventually led to my selection as an SAP Champion. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: What’s something you can do now that you couldn’t before?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Previously, I used to explain SAP technology in dense technical jargon, regardless of the audience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now, I adapt my speech according to the target audience as below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Developers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: features, APIs, and architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consultants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: flows, modules, and configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Executives&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: business impact and how the Intelligent Enterprise helps companies run smarter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This shift makes me more effective in stakeholder discussions, project planning, and skill development.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: Looking back, what advice would you give your younger self or someone just starting their SAP journey?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To my younger self, I’d say: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Start with basics, business processes, then explore SAP modules.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To newcomers: first understand real-world business challenges and processes, then learn Intelligent Enterprise concepts and SAP Business Suite flows. Everything else falls into place.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: How has your learning impacted others at work or beyond?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My journey has inspired juniors, peers, and even seniors to seek guidance for their SAP learning.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Outside work, this led to invitations to podcasts, panels, and SAP events as a speaker. It also strengthened my credibility and reinforced my position as a thought leader in the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At this point, friends and colleagues joke: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Just Google his name, you’ll find him.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Learner Story - Kunal Bansal.png" style="width: 267px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324669i275F11989068541E/image-dimensions/267x334/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="267" height="334" role="button" title="Learner Story - Kunal Bansal.png" alt="Learner Story - Kunal Bansal.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Q: What’s been your proudest moment?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Being recognized as one of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Champions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; worldwide was surreal and humbling. But I’m equally proud of helping colleagues grow, guiding careers, and creating a culture of continuous learning within my practice.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: Bonus question: what’s the weirdest place you’ve ever studied SAP?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Definitely old bookshops on Bangalore’s streets, while hunting for novels. They gave me strange looks but for me, learning can happen anywhere.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Q: And if your SAP learning journey were a movie?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learning Is Lifelong.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;” The moment you think you’ve mastered it all, the technology changes and you realize you’re still a student.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kunal’s advice to every SAP learner:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Start with what businesses need, not what buttons to click. SAP understanding, certifications and success will follow.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to carve out your own daily hour? Explore &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;learning journeys and certifications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; and see how far curiosity can take you. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/one-hour-one-habit-one-champion-kunal-bansal-s-lifelong-learning-story/ba-p/14238286"/>
    <published>2025-10-08T14:53:14.971000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-supply-chain-management-certification-increase-your-expertise-and/ba-p/14167288</id>
    <title>SAP Supply Chain Management Certification: Increase Your Expertise and Credibility</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T07:18:59.688000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ledwards19</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3980</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Running sustainable, resilient supply chains amid disruptions has become a driving force in many organizations. While supply chains have historically prioritized efficiency and cost reduction, digital technologies are delivering incredible gains to achieve even greater outcomes, while connecting processes and enabling faster insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In these times of rapid innovation, it’s becoming increasingly more critical to stay informed of the latest positioning guidance for SAP Supply Chain solutions. SAP has addressed this need by offering a &lt;EM&gt;non-technical certification&lt;/EM&gt; option:&lt;STRONG&gt; Positioning SAP Business Suite via SAP Supply Chain Management Solutions.&lt;/STRONG&gt; The non-technical certifications options are designed to be completed in a matter of few hours, thus making it a great option for individuals who are new to certification, looking to replace an expired certification, or simply interested in cultivating expertise in selling SAP Supply Chain solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Becoming certified in SAP Supply Chain Management solutions will prepare you to gain the confidence and trust in your biggest stakeholder, the Chief Operating Officer (“COO”).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The self-paced learning content will cover these key areas:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The end-to-end solution portfolio and how it addresses key priorities for the COO&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How to position Supply Chain Management solutions in the context of SAP Business Suite&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;How AI is being used today in modern business settings as well as how it fits into the SAP’s Business AI strategy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Selling SAP Supply Chain Management solutions to the COO through qualification, discovery, and packaging.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upon completing the digital learning, your certification attainment is achieved by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Submission of one of the following hands-on exercises:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Articulating the value of SAP Supply Chain solutions through an executive pitch&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Demonstrating the value of SAP Supply Chain solution by performing a demo.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Successful completion of a one-hour exam that will include thirty questions derived from the self-paced learning content.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don’t Delay—take advantage of this opportunity to establish your credibility in SAP Supply Chain Management and showcase your accomplishment. With around 5 hours of self-paced learning, this certification option is achievable for any busy professional and will provide tangible value in your field of expertise. Visit the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/products/customer-experience" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning Site&lt;/A&gt; to review the available certifications and select &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-positioning-sap-business-suite-via-sap-supply-chain-business-network-solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Positioning SAP Business Suite via SAP Supply Chain Management&lt;/A&gt; so you can start expertly positioning SAP’s Supply Chain Management solutions to solve your customer’s key challenges and deliver real-world results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lauren Edwards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Industries &amp;amp; Experience, Partner Solution Enablement, SAP Supply Chain Management&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-supply-chain-management-certification-increase-your-expertise-and/ba-p/14167288"/>
    <published>2025-10-09T07:18:59.688000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/announcing-the-sap-sales-cloud-version-2-classroom-training/ba-p/14240791</id>
    <title>Announcing the SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 Classroom Training</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T20:32:07.583000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DeepaliJohnson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124577</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The sales landscape is evolving at a breakneck pace, driven by AI, cloud transformation, and the demand for ultimate sales productivity. To meet this change head-on, we are thrilled to announce the official release of our foundational classroom training: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/c4h470-sap-sales-cloud-version-2-classroom-052-de-en/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;C4H470: SAP Sales Cloud Version 2&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This in-depth, instructor-led course is not just a review of new features—it is a comprehensive deep dive designed to elevate the skills of every professional involved in the SAP Sales Cloud ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1891768259"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Why You Can’t Afford to Miss This Course&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP Sales Cloud Version 2 is a massive leap forward, and this training is your guided path to mastering its power. Designed for both business users and administrators, C4H470 focuses on practical, hands-on application:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1824337473"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;1. Harness the Power of AI and Intelligent Sales&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Dive into the future of sales by leveraging &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Machine Learning and Gen AI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; capabilities. You will learn the applications of the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;CX AI Toolkit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Lead Intelligence&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to automate and optimize decision-making, ensuring smarter lead scoring and a decisive competitive advantage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1627823968"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2. Hands-On Mastery of Productivity Tools&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Empower yourself and your sales teams with advanced tactics for opportunity management and pipeline execution. You will gain hands-on experience with:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Guided Selling App:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Utilizing playbooks to manage opportunity progression and ensure adherence to sales methodology.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Pipeline Manager:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Optimizing pipeline performance and identifying critical sales trends.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Forecast Tracker:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Improving forecast accuracy and monitoring sales performance effectively.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Digital Selling Workspace:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Organizing and prioritizing sales actions with enhanced task management features.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1431310463"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;3. Core System Proficiency and Administration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The course provides the confidence needed to navigate the system's new architecture and configuration. Key modules include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Comprehensive Configuration:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Tailoring core components like Leads, Opportunities, Quotes, Sales Orders, and Visits to reflect your business-specific processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Effective Administration:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Mastering the daily workflow, including user setup, advanced configurations, and data management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Seamless Collaboration:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; Configuring and leveraging communication tools, such as &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Microsoft Teams Integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Relationship Intelligence&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, to streamline sales execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105714239"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Who Needs This Essential Training?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Whether you are a key decision-maker or on the front lines of sales technology, this course is essential.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Audience&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="197px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="196.2px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;System Administrators&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="196.2px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Application Consultants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="196.2px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Business Users&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="196.2px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Super/Key Power Users&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This is your opportunity to elevate your skills, secure your expertise in the latest SAP release, and actively drive business growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Elevate your skills and stay ahead in the ever-evolving sales landscape. Register now for C4H470 to secure your spot!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/announcing-the-sap-sales-cloud-version-2-classroom-training/ba-p/14240791"/>
    <published>2025-10-10T20:32:07.583000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/learning-with-heart-and-structure-patrizia-rossi-s-story/ba-p/14240258</id>
    <title>Learning with Heart and Structure: Patrizia Rossi’s Story</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T12:57:44.817000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>margherita_gallucci34</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In 2020, Patrizia Rossi welcomed a tiny puppy into her life in Rome. “He was so small and tender that just looking at him made me feel better,” she recalls. What began as playful walks and teaching simple commands soon grew into something more substantial. By combining instinct with structured training, Patrizia discovered a whole new world. In time, she and her dog even became &lt;STRONG&gt;agility champions,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;something she never imagined at the beginning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Patrizia and her puppy training" style="width: 176px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325491i8A4444BC9A3854B4/image-dimensions/176x311/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="176" height="311" role="button" title="Agility.jpg" alt="Patrizia and her puppy training" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Patrizia and her puppy training&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;That joyful chapter came during a challenging time, after the loss of her younger brother and her mother. The puppy became more than a companion. He was a source of comfort and a reminder that growth often comes from pairing passion with structure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For Patrizia, the parallel with her SAP-related career was clear. Twenty years earlier, she began her career as an ABAP developer in Turin, learning by doing. Over the years, she specialized in SAP Fiori and SAP Business Technology Platform. Like with her dog, instinct and practice alone weren’t enough for her full potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“To really grow, I needed structured learning, a path that combined hands-on experience with theory,” she explains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That approach shaped her career. Until 2024, Patrizia was an SAP consultant, supporting clients on backend and frontend solutions. Recently, she joined the &lt;STRONG&gt;European Space Agency&lt;/STRONG&gt; as an SAP Solution Architect. Her role now demands concrete, reliable solutions, and SAP Certifications give her that foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="sappress.jpg" style="width: 195px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325502i0497913479774538/image-dimensions/195x260/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="195" height="260" role="button" title="sappress.jpg" alt="sappress.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;She recently earned the &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP BTP Solution Architect certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;, adding to several certifications. For her, certifications aren’t just credentials; they build confidence. "When you know the theory, you don’t just work better, you become an added value. You support colleagues, propose stronger solutions, and solve problems faster."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That difference was clear when she activated &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Work Zone Advanced Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Since she was also preparing for the SAP Build Work Zone certification, she was able to solve issues quickly that practicing alone wouldn’t have prepared her for.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Those are the moments when you feel like you’ve won the lottery,” she laughs. “After banging your head against a problem, you run a test and… it works!”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Patrizia remembers a colleague who encouraged her. Every time she cracked a tough problem, he would laugh and shout: "MONSTER!" Though he is no longer here, Patrizia keeps the tradition. "Whenever I solve something impossible, I still whisper: ‘MONSTERRR!’"&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For Patrizia, certifications and structured learning turned her from a consultant who once relied on instinct to a solution architect trusted at the highest levels. Just like in dog training, practice matters—but theory and structure make you unstoppable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Want to become the next “monster” problem solver?&lt;/STRONG&gt; Explore structured learning paths and certifications at the &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-learnerstory" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/learning-with-heart-and-structure-patrizia-rossi-s-story/ba-p/14240258"/>
    <published>2025-10-13T12:57:44.817000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/strengthening-security-on-sap-btp-neo-environment-with-digicert-global-root/ba-p/14246784</id>
    <title>Strengthening Security on SAP BTP Neo Environment with DigiCert Global Root G3</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T10:00:41.951000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LyuboslavL</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2135273</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="LyuboslavL_0-1760688028101.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328882iE92DCA25D73CD590/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="LyuboslavL_0-1760688028101.png" alt="LyuboslavL_0-1760688028101.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP, keeping your data and applications secure is always a top priority.&lt;BR /&gt;To further strengthen the security of the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Neo environment&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we are migrating to the “&lt;STRONG&gt;DigiCert Global Root G3&lt;/STRONG&gt;” Public Key Infrastructure (PKI). This update ensures long-term trust, improved encryption, and compliance with the latest international security standards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Do You Need to Do Anything&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For most customers,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;no action is required&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Modern web browsers (like Google Chrome and Mozilla Firefox) and up-to-date operating systems already trust the new DigiCert Global Root G3 certificate automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, if your organization manages certificates manually or maintains its own trust store, your technical team should add the new G3 certificate before the March 2026 deadline.&lt;BR /&gt;This ensures continued, secure access to SAP BTP services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Do not remove the existing G2 certificate — both should remain active during the transition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This change is part of SAP’s ongoing commitment to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Keep your data and applications secure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Align with the latest global and national security standards&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure continued compatibility with modern browsers and systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By making this upgrade, SAP is helping customers stay protected and ready for the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Timeline&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;full migration to DigiCert Global Root G3&lt;/STRONG&gt; will take effect in &lt;STRONG&gt;March 2026&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Until then, both the G2 and G3 certificates will remain active to ensure a smooth transition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Add the DigiCert Global Root G3 Certificate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you manage your own trust stores, please follow these steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visit the DigiCert root certificate page: &lt;A href="https://www.digicert.com/kb/digicert-root-certificates.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.digicert.com/kb/digicert-root-certificates.htm&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Locate &lt;STRONG&gt;“DigiCert Global Root G3.”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Download the appropriate certificate format for your environment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Verify the certificate fingerprint using your preferred tool (for example, with OpenSSL:&lt;BR /&gt;openssl x509 -noout -text -in ./DigiCertGlobalRootG3.crt.pem -fingerprint)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Follow your trust store’s instructions to add the certificate.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For guidance on managing trusted certificates for SAP BTP, see the &lt;A href="https://github.com/sap-software/btp-trust-store/blob/main/README.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;BTP Trust Store on GitHub&lt;/A&gt;. To streamline future updates, we recommend applying the BTP Trust Store regularly or automating this process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Affected Domains&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This update applies to the following platform domains in the SAP BTP Neo environment:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.dispatcher.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.cert.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.static.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.vms.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;*.netweaver.ondemand.com&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;connectivitynotification.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;connectivitytunnel.&amp;lt;Region.Domain&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For a full overview of regions and domain hosts, see the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-btp-neo-environment/regions-and-hosts-available-for-neo-environment" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Domains&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-owned custom domains are &lt;STRONG&gt;not affected&lt;/STRONG&gt; by this change until &lt;STRONG&gt;March 2026&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;After this date, all new automated certificate renewals will use the DigiCert Global Root G3 certificate. New SAP-owned custom domains created after March 2026 will also use G3 by default.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Staying secure is a shared effort — and we’re making it easier for you.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;With the DigiCert Global Root G3 upgrade, SAP BTP continues to offer a trusted, reliable, and compliant cloud environment for your business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/strengthening-security-on-sap-btp-neo-environment-with-digicert-global-root/ba-p/14246784"/>
    <published>2025-10-17T10:00:41.951000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/save-your-spot-live-sessions-with-an-sap-sales-cloud-v2-expert-nov-10-12/ba-p/14254592</id>
    <title>Save your spot! Live Sessions with an SAP Sales Cloud V2 Expert – Nov 10-12, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T21:44:08.369000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DeepaliJohnson</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124577</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Product Learning team is excited to run the series of live sessions focused on our new product, SAP Sales Cloud V2. These sessions will take place over three 1-hour segments, led by a product expert and are designed to provide a comprehensive understanding of SAP Sales Cloud V2's functionality and configuration.&lt;BR /&gt;During these sessions, we will offer valuable insights into the latest features and provide practical knowledge to help you maximize the benefits of this new product. Whether you're already familiar with SAP Sales Cloud V2 or considering its integration into your operations, these sessions will deliver the in-depth information needed to enhance your proficiency. This is also a fantastic opportunity to learn directly from an expert and ask questions in real-time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a brief agenda:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Session 1 – Overview of the solution from a functional perspective&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Session 2 - Deep Dive Part 1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Onboarding&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales Cloud Version 2 set-up&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fundamentals including Global Search, Extensibility, User&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Control etc.Session&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Session 3 - Deep Dive Part 2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Guided Selling&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Digital Sales Engagement&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Pipeline Management&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Forecasting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;MS Team integration and Autoflow&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As many of you know, SAP Sales Cloud V2 offers a wide range of features aimed at improving your sales processes. It is a cloud-native solution designed to boost productivity, manage customer relationships more effectively, and gain better insights from your data.&lt;BR /&gt;Don't miss out—secure your spot by signing up. We look forward to seeing you there!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: These sessions require a login with &lt;STRONG&gt;learning.sap.com&lt;/STRONG&gt; or an &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Learning Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; License.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/sap-sales-cloud-version-2-overview-and-deep-dive" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here to register&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Sales+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100700002221" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="811-1"&gt;SAP Sales Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Training/pd-p/676305042803066886656318788802663" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1167-1"&gt;Training&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Customer+Experience/pd-p/cae17fd6-917e-483d-881a-502155cade3c" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1152-1"&gt;Customer Experience&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/save-your-spot-live-sessions-with-an-sap-sales-cloud-v2-expert-nov-10-12/ba-p/14254592"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T21:44:08.369000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/preparing-for-sap-c-cpe-here-s-how-i-m-studying-each-section-without/ba-p/14259621</id>
    <title>Preparing for SAP C_CPE? Here’s How I’m Studying Each Section Without Feeling Overwhelmed</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T15:23:22.635000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chahat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1574359</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Whenever I start learning something new, I like to have everything in order.&lt;BR /&gt;Before I even open the first tutorial, I plan what I’ll study first, what comes next, and how I’ll track it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recently, I started preparing for the SAP C_CPE (SAP Certified Associate - Backend Developer -&amp;nbsp;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model) certification. Since this exam covers a mix of BTP architecture, SAP BAS, CAP, Side by side extensions, Cloud Foundry &amp;amp; Kyma Runtime&amp;nbsp; it can easily feel like too much at once. So I created a simple structure to move step by step without feeling lost.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I began with the learning about BTP, and doing hands on by following SAP Learning Journeys, creating subaccount and adding entitlements and services (It gave me a very clear understanding of BTP architecture) and then Developing appliaction using high productivity tools of SAP BAS, Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP) because it’s the foundation of most topics in this certification. I’m spending around two weeks learning about CDS models, service layers and how everything connects in a CAP project. I’m following the official SAP Learning Journey&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-backend-developer-sap-cloud-programming-model" href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-backend-developer-sap-cloud-programming-model" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-backend-developer-sap-cloud-program…...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My next focus is Cloud Foundry. I’ll spend about a week learning how to efficiently develop, run, and manage cloud-native applications on SAP BTP, Cloud Foundry Runtime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After that, I’ll move to Side by side extention on BTP.&amp;nbsp; This will cover&amp;nbsp;deploying&amp;nbsp; extension and integrating the app into SAP Build Work Zone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next stage is Developing Appliactions in Kyma Environment. I’ll take about two weeks to explore&amp;nbsp;a comprehensive understanding of Kubernetes and&amp;nbsp;to orchestrate the deployment of the applications in the cloud.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, I’ll study Advanced Extensions with SAP Cloud SDK for about two more weeks. These are slightly advanced topics but very useful for understanding&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;develop and integrate Java, JavaScript, and TypeScript extension applications for SAP solutions like SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So in short, this will be my roadmap-&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommended Study Sequence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s the order I suggest, from foundational to more advanced :&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exploring SAP Business Technology Platform 5hrs (link :&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-business-technology-platform" href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-business-technology-platform" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/courses/exploring-sap-business-technology-platform)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This gives you a broad overview of the entire platform (services, architecture, what BTP is). Good for building your base understanding.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;So start here.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.Develop Full‑Stack Applications Using Productivity Tools in SAP Business Application Studio 8hrs (&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-full-stack-applications-using-productivity-tools-in-sap-business-application-studio" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-full-stack-applications-using-productivity-tools-in-sap-business-application-studio" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-full-stack-applications-using-productivity-tools-in-sap-business-application-studio)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.Develop Applications on SAP BTP, Cloud Foundry Runtime 4hrs(&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-on-sap-btp-cloud-foundry-runtime" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-on-sap-btp-cloud-foundry-runtime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-on-sap-btp-cloud-foundry-runtime)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Cloud Foundry runtime is a major runtime environment in BTP. Understanding how to build and deploy there is critical.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4.Build Side‑by‑Side Extensions on SAP BTP 8hrs (&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/build-side-by-side-extensions-on-sap-btp" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/build-side-by-side-extensions-on-sap-btp" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/build-side-by-side-extensions-on-sap-btp)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After tooling and platform basics, you dive into extension scenarios (for example side-by-side extensions of S/4HANA using CAP). This aligns closely with CAP certification topics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5.Developing Applications in SAP BTP, Kyma Runtime 8hrs(&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-in-sap-btp-kyma-runtime" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-in-sap-btp-kyma-runtime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/developing-applications-in-sap-btp-kyma-runtime)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Kyma Runtime is more advanced (Kubernetes, microservices, event-mesh) and often sits on top of foundational knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6.Develop Advanced Extensions with SAP Cloud SDK 11hrs (&lt;A class="" title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-advanced-extensions-with-sap-cloud-sdk" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-advanced-extensions-with-sap-cloud-sdk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/develop-advanced-extensions-with-sap-cloud-sdk)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is relatively specialized/advanced (SAP Cloud SDK, perhaps custom libraries, integrations). Once you’ve mastered the fundamentals above, you go here.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By the end of this plan, I’ll go through a short revision period with mock questions and quick notes from my learning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This structured approach keeps my study plan clear and prevents me from feeling overwhelmed.&lt;BR /&gt;I study for two to four hours a day which feels realistic, and the small milestones make it easier to stay consistent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re also preparing for C_CPE, it really helps to make your own sequence instead of jumping randomly between topics. The Learning Journeys are excellent resources, but having a personal roadmap makes a big difference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’d love to hear how others are preparing for this certification too.&lt;BR /&gt;What topics are you finding most challenging so far and how are you managing the learning&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/preparing-for-sap-c-cpe-here-s-how-i-m-studying-each-section-without/ba-p/14259621"/>
    <published>2025-11-04T15:23:22.635000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/ba-p/14261141</id>
    <title>Reimagining Certification for the Way We Work Today</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T11:21:05.659000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DianaRoesner</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10529</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For decades, certifications&amp;nbsp;exams&amp;nbsp;have&amp;nbsp;followed the same pattern:&amp;nbsp;silent rooms, strict proctors, and no access to the tools&amp;nbsp;you’d&amp;nbsp;normally use to get work done. The goal was to&amp;nbsp;test&amp;nbsp;what you knew (or could remember)&amp;nbsp;in that moment, not what you could&amp;nbsp;actually do.&amp;nbsp;But work&amp;nbsp;doesn’t&amp;nbsp;happen that way. And learning certainly&amp;nbsp;doesn’t&amp;nbsp;either.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today, projects are fast paced, connected, and collaborative. When&amp;nbsp;you’re&amp;nbsp;solving a problem, you&amp;nbsp;don’t&amp;nbsp;sit in silence — you look for information, consult with teammates, and use the tools available to you. With AI now woven into how we all work,&amp;nbsp;it’s&amp;nbsp;time for certification to evolve too.&amp;nbsp;That’s&amp;nbsp;why&amp;nbsp;we’re&amp;nbsp;reimagining SAP Certification.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From memory to mastery&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Certification&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;shifting from proctored, multiple-choice tests to&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;performance-based, practical, open-book&amp;nbsp;assessments&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;that&amp;nbsp;mirror real work.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Instead of answering theoretical questions,&amp;nbsp;you’ll&amp;nbsp;complete&amp;nbsp;realistic&amp;nbsp;challenges that&amp;nbsp;show&amp;nbsp;how you&amp;nbsp;actually&amp;nbsp;apply&amp;nbsp;your SAP knowledge — configuring systems, building applications, solving problems, or advising&amp;nbsp;customers&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;solutions.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are two types of practical exams:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System-based:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;You’ll&amp;nbsp;perform time-boxed tasks directly in SAP systems.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scenario-based:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;You’ll&amp;nbsp;interact with an AI avatar to respond to real customer or project situations.&amp;nbsp;(For&amp;nbsp;learners who&amp;nbsp;don’t&amp;nbsp;want to&amp;nbsp;use AI,&amp;nbsp;we&amp;nbsp;provide&amp;nbsp;an alternative&amp;nbsp;option to upload a&amp;nbsp;video&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;human review.)&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These&amp;nbsp;‘open-book’&amp;nbsp;exams allow access to&amp;nbsp;resources&amp;nbsp;like&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-CERT-Reimagined" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-CERT-Reimagined" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-CERT-Reimagined" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community, or&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/ai-assistant/sap-consulting-capability.html?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-CERT-Reimagined" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Joule for Consultants&amp;nbsp;— just as you would use in your daily work.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learning that feels real&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This transformation&amp;nbsp;makes certification more meaningful and consistent with how you already learn. The types of&amp;nbsp;practical&amp;nbsp;exercises and scenarios you complete on the SAP Learning site now continue into the exam, so preparation and assessment feel like part of one experience.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Each exam is time-boxed and focused on proving you can do the work, not just recall facts.&amp;nbsp;There’s&amp;nbsp;no live proctoring; instead, identity is confirmed through SAP Universal ID,&amp;nbsp;reflecting trust in how professionals really work.&amp;nbsp;You’ll&amp;nbsp;still have to think critically and manage your time, but&amp;nbsp;you’ll&amp;nbsp;do so in a context that mirrors your day-to-day work, not an artificial testing environment.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A phased rollout for all certifications&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Beginning in&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;November 2025&lt;SPAN&gt;, the first practical certifications,&amp;nbsp;including&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-professional-solution-architect-sap-btp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution Architect for SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-generative-ai-developer?source=contentsynd-global-bigdatainsider-prdteng" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Generative AI Developer&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-low-code-no-code-developer-sap-build" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Developer&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-btp-administrator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP System Administrator&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(new) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-rise-with-sap-methodology-and-experience" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;RISE&amp;nbsp;with&amp;nbsp;SAP Methodology&amp;nbsp;and Experience&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(new,)&amp;nbsp;will go live.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;By&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;2026,&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;all&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Certifications will shift to this new, practical format. That means everyone – consultants, developers, administrators,&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;sales professionals – will&amp;nbsp;validate&amp;nbsp;their&amp;nbsp;expertise&amp;nbsp;in ways that reflect how work&amp;nbsp;actually gets&amp;nbsp;done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why&amp;nbsp;this matters&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At its core, this transformation is about trust that SAP Certification accurately&amp;nbsp;represents&amp;nbsp;real capability. For learners, it means your credential truly reflects your skills. For employers, it means confidence that a certified professional can perform from day one.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When we launch&amp;nbsp;at SAP TechEd&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;Berlin,&amp;nbsp;we’re&amp;nbsp;not just&amp;nbsp;transforming&amp;nbsp;certification;&amp;nbsp;we’re&amp;nbsp;redefining what it means to be skilled in the AI era.&amp;nbsp;And for learners everywhere, that means your effort&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;experience&amp;nbsp;now matter&amp;nbsp;more than ever.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To learn more about our reimagined certification model, visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/training-certification/sap-certification.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Certification&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and read the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/helpcenter/certification-support/practical-exam?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-CERT-Reimagined" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FAQ&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/ba-p/14261141"/>
    <published>2025-11-05T11:21:05.659000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tri%C3%A2ngulo-mineiro-blog-posts/certifica%C3%A7%C3%B5es-sap-mudan%C3%A7a-para-formato-pr%C3%A1tico-e-open-book/ba-p/14266954</id>
    <title>Certificações SAP: mudança para formato prático e open-book</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T14:37:54.068000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Renato_Baracca</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/527140</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Certificação SAP: novo formato prático em implementação&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A SAP está transformando o formato das certificações para refletir melhor a forma como trabalhamos atualmente.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;O que muda:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ao invés de questões teóricas de múltipla escolha, o novo formato inclui:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tarefas práticas em sistemas SAP reais&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cenários simulados com avatares de IA representando situações de clientes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Acesso a recursos como SAP Help, Community e Joule durante o exame&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A proposta é alinhar a certificação com o ambiente de trabalho real: colaborativo, conectado e com IA integrada.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Mais informações: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/ba-p/14261141" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-blog-posts/reimagining-certification-for-the-way-we-work-today/ba-p/14261141&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tri%C3%A2ngulo-mineiro-blog-posts/certifica%C3%A7%C3%B5es-sap-mudan%C3%A7a-para-formato-pr%C3%A1tico-e-open-book/ba-p/14266954"/>
    <published>2025-11-12T14:37:54.068000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-prepare-for-sap-s-new-certification/ba-p/14268066</id>
    <title>How to Prepare for SAP’s New Certification</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T14:00:18.140000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SuyashVerma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1593598</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For years, SAP certification relied on multiple-choice questions and memorized answers. That approach no longer fits the realities of modern SAP work, where professionals configure systems, solve business problems, and increasingly collaborate with AI-driven tools. Simply recalling information isn’t enough.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new SAP certification model shifts the focus from “knowing SAP” to “doing SAP,” i.e., applying skills in real-world scenarios, navigating tools, and demonstrating practical competence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re planning to get certified soon, your preparation needs to evolve with it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764764095"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Changing and What It Means for Your Preparation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s new practical certification exams introduce a more authentic and performance-oriented approach to skill validation. Instead of testing whether you can recall a configuration detail, the new exams examine whether you can complete tasks, solve problems, and make decisions in situations that resemble real project environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;They use two primary formats: System-based assessment and Scenario-based assessment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;System-based assessment &lt;/STRONG&gt;is&amp;nbsp;where learners work inside a time-limited SAP system simulation. You are required to perform actual tasks, such as configuring components, building processes, developing artifacts, or resolving issues, just as you would in a project environment. The assessment measures your fluency in SAP tools, your ability to execute steps accurately, and your ability to apply best practices in a live system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario-based assessment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;places you in time-limited role-play situations with an AI avatar. In these scenarios, you must pitch SAP solutions, advise on architecture, justify design choices, respond to stakeholder concerns, and guide the conversation toward appropriate outcomes. Rather than executing system tasks, this format evaluates how you think, communicate, analyse requirements, and represent SAP’s capabilities in a business context.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each certification will use &lt;STRONG&gt;only one format&lt;/STRONG&gt;, either system-based or scenario-based, depending on the nature of the role being assessed. Technical roles emphasise hands-on execution, while consulting and architecture roles prioritise analytical and advisory depth. This creates a more precise and meaningful measurement of job readiness.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The exams are also now &lt;STRONG&gt;open-book&lt;/STRONG&gt;, allowing access to documentation, help portals, and AI-assisted guidance during the assessment. This change reflects how professionals actually work. They consult resources, verify information, test assumptions, and use intelligent tools like SAP Joule to support decision-making. The exam rewards the ability to locate, interpret, and apply information under realistic constraints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is rolling out this new model in phases. The first six certifications are already live and have received a strong response from the ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/get-certified/reimagining-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click this link to access the SAP Certifications featuring practical exams.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568250590"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Prepare for SAP's New Certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Train on SAP Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hands-on experience is now the most important part of certification readiness. Since the new exams rely heavily on real system usage or scenario execution, you must become comfortable navigating SAP environments directly. Spend time configuring components, building workflows, testing integrations, and troubleshooting issues in SAP BTP, &amp;nbsp;SAP Build, and other relevant tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Memorizing theory will not substitute for actual system familiarity, so create consistent practice sessions that mirror the tasks you expect to face in real projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adopt an Open-Book Learning Mindset&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because SAP’s new exams allow access to documentation and official resources, your success depends on how efficiently you can locate and apply information. Instead of trying to memorize every detail, shift your focus toward learning how SAP documentation is structured, where key topics are located, and how to interpret guidance quickly under time constraints.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During preparation, challenge yourself to answer questions by navigating documentation rather than recalling facts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practise Scenario-Based Problem Solving&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new certification format rewards professionals who can think in end-to-end scenarios rather than isolated tasks. To build this skill, spend time working through full business situations that could appear in an exam.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine a client wants to automate approval workflows, integrate an external application, or modernize their analytics landscape. Break down how you would approach the requirement, which SAP tools you would use, what architecture makes sense, and what risks or trade-offs you would consider.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The more you practise this style of thinking, the more natural it becomes to articulate decisions and explain your reasoning during a scenario-based assessment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strengthen Your Architecture and Data Foundations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modern SAP work revolves around cloud services, data modeling, integration patterns, event-driven design, and automation. To prepare for the new certifications, make time to revisit these fundamentals. Understanding how components fit together will help you make informed decisions, whether you are configuring a system or advising a simulated stakeholder. This broader technical foundation also enables you to respond effectively during role-plays that require architectural justification or strategic recommendations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Build a Continuous Learning Habit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The redesigned certification model encourages professionals to keep their skills active rather than rely on one-time exam success. As SAP continues to evolve its tools and expand its AI-driven capabilities, staying connected to the ecosystem, whether through hands-on practice, learning content, or experimentation with new features, will help you remain prepared for renewals and future certifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371737085"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What These Changes Mean for Your Career&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new certification format narrows the gap between being certified and being project-ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the assessments test actual capability, credentials earned under this model will carry greater weight with employers seeking professionals who can contribute immediately. It also shifts the ecosystem toward continuous learning, where staying certified means staying active, hands-on, and connected to SAP’s evolving technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The certifications also mark an important milestone in SAP’s broader commitment to equip 12 million people worldwide with AI-ready skills by 2030.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you approach your learning with the mindset of becoming truly project-ready rather than simply exam-ready, you will not only succeed in the new certification format but also build a stronger, more sustainable foundation for your SAP career.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The exam has evolved, and your preparation needs to evolve with it, too.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-prepare-for-sap-s-new-certification/ba-p/14268066"/>
    <published>2025-11-13T14:00:18.140000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/certified-excellence-how-cognizant-sets-the-benchmark-for-driving-real-sap/ba-p/14269012</id>
    <title>Certified Excellence: How Cognizant Sets the Benchmark for Driving Real SAP Transformation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T16:40:08.041000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christine13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our longstanding partner Cognizant sheds light on how it is redefining SAP services for a cloud-first, AI-powered world.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In this interview, &lt;U&gt;Sivakumar Varadananjayan&lt;/U&gt;, Assistant Vice President and Delivery Head – SAP Cloud &amp;amp; SAP GGM Product and Resources (Global Growth Market) at Cognizant Technology Solutions, shares insights about Cognizant's&amp;nbsp;Path from ERP to AI-Powered, Industry-Focused Innovation. As the leader of Cognizant’s SAP Certification initiative and its Validation Partner status, Sivakumar also shares his perspective on Cognizant’s renewed global certifications, the evolution of their SAP certification journey, and how they plan to further expand their SAP competencies to support customers. The conversation was conducted during Cognizant’s SAP Certification process, together with Christophe André, SAP Auditor and Partner Manager, who led the audit at Cognizant, and Hossam Saad, SAP Partner Manager and Cognizant’s main point of contact.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar outlines how they have evolved from traditional ERP implementations to a transformation model centered on automation, intelligence, and industry specificity. He also discusses their role as a RISE with SAP Validated Partner, its commitment to SAP Best Practices, and how cloud migrations are accelerated through clean-core principles and end-to-end governance. With renewed global SAP certifications, expanded security capabilities, and deep DevOps integration, Cognizant positions itself as a pioneer in secure, future-ready SAP transformation. Looking ahead, Sivakumar shares how continued investment in talent, co-innovation, and industry-focused solutions will shape the next chapter of intelligent enterprise modernization.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Christophe: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cognizant is globally known for providing SAP-related services. How have you been adapting your services to ever-changing customer needs and technology innovations?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Adaptability is at the heart of Cognizant’s SAP strategy. Over the past decade, we’ve transitioned from traditional ERP implementations to cloud-first, AI-enabled, and automation-driven models. Our approach focuses on three pillars:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Enablement:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We leverage &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to deliver scalable, resilient architectures that support rapid innovation and business agility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Automation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Through SAP Business AI, Joule Agents, and Cognizant’s Automation Fabric, we integrate robotic process automation and generative AI into SAP workflows, reducing manual effort and improving accuracy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer-Centric Design:&lt;/STRONG&gt; We co-innovate with clients using SAP’s cloud solutions and industry accelerators, ensuring transformation aligns with their business priorities and delivers measurable outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation is embedded in every stage – from &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP S/4HANA Conversions&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt; like SAP-Certified &lt;STRONG&gt;Case Management AI Agent for SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Finance4U®&lt;/STRONG&gt; for industry-specific needs. These capabilities enable real-time insights, predictive analytics, and continuous modernization, helping clients thrive in a rapidly changing digital economy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Christophe: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cognizant positions itself as a pioneer in leveraging SAP Business Suite, cloud ERP, and Business AI. How do you tailor your SAP services to address industry-specific challenges, and what role does innovation play?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cognizant tailors its SAP services through a deep industry-in-context approach - combining process expertise, data intelligence, and AI-driven automation to address the unique challenges of each sector. Our strategy integrates SAP Business Suite, cloud ERP, and Business AI with domain accelerators, industry templates, and pre-built integration frameworks that shorten time-to-value and enhance business agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation is embedded in every stage - from co-innovation with SAP and hyperscale cloud platforms to leveraging SAP Business AI, developing digital twins, and advanced analytics for continuous transformation. This ensures that clients don’t just modernize their ERP landscape but also unlock new business models, improve decision velocity, and stay future-ready in an AI-enabled economy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;A strong example of this innovation-led, industry-tailored approach is reflected in Cognizant’s &lt;STRONG&gt;Utegration &lt;/STRONG&gt;portfolio&amp;nbsp;for utilities and energy enterprises:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance4U® Extended Asset Accounting:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enhances SAP property accounting with regulatory-compliant, utility-specific asset management capabilities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance4U® Regulatory Accounting and Reporting:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Streamlines regulated financial reporting, improving data accuracy and audit readiness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Utility4U™:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A RISE with SAP-based cloud accelerator that modernizes and simplifies the utility ERP landscape while embedding industry best practices.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MeterData4U®:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Unlocks the value of Advanced Metering Infrastructure (AMI) by integrating and operationalizing meter data within SAP environments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, these offerings demonstrate how Cognizant combines deep domain experience with SAP innovation to deliver measurable outcomes across industries - from operational efficiency to intelligent, data-driven growth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hossam: &lt;/STRONG&gt;As a “RISE with SAP Validated Partner,” what has been your experience in leading SAP customers’ migration to cloud? How are your services modeled around SAP Best Practices?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As a RISE with SAP Validated Partner, our experience in leading SAP customers’ migration to the cloud has been extensive and transformative. We have successfully delivered large-scale migrations for global enterprises using SAP’s validated methodology, ensuring predictable timelines, reduced risks, and accelerated time-to-value. Our approach emphasizes &lt;STRONG&gt;clean core principles&lt;/STRONG&gt; with embedded quality gates, supported by SAP Cloud ALM for governance and compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our services are modelled around &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Best Practices&lt;/STRONG&gt;, integrating SAP’s ecosystem tools such as Cloud ALM, LeanIX, Signavio, Business Technology Platform (BTP), Joule, and Tricentis Test Automation. This toolchain enables automation, collaboration, and robust governance throughout the migration journey. Additionally, all key roles - Project Managers, Architects, Developers, and Consultants - are SAP-certified and trained on the latest cloud and AI innovations, ensuring customers are positioned for continuous innovation post-migration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, we focus on delivering &lt;STRONG&gt;customer-centric outcomes&lt;/STRONG&gt; by accelerating cloud transformation with minimal disruption and ensuring smooth migration from ECC or on-premise systems to SAP S/4HANA Cloud. By leveraging SAP Best Practices and validated frameworks, we provide transparent, milestone-driven projects that reduce risk and deliver predictable results. Our engagements consistently achieve high satisfaction scores, reflecting our commitment to quality, innovation, and long-term customer success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Christophe: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cognizant recently renewed global certifications for SAP Business Suite and SAP S/4HANA services and achieved its first global certification for SAP security operations. How do your competencies in DevOps, Security, and Business AI add value?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cognizant’s renewed global certifications for SAP Business Suite and SAP S/4HANA services, along with its first global certification for SAP Security Operations, reinforce our ability to deliver secure, agile, and intelligent SAP transformations. These credentials validate our expertise in modernizing SAP landscapes while ensuring compliance and resilience for mission-critical environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our DevOps competency accelerates SAP delivery through automated CI/CD pipelines, enabling rapid release cycles, improved quality, and seamless integration with RISE with SAP and cloud platforms. In parallel, our Security Operations capability provides proactive threat management, robust identity governance, and real-time monitoring - critical for industries with stringent regulatory requirements. Internally, Cognizant leverages a DevOps for a Unified Competency Management model across SAP competencies to bring people, process, and knowledge together around the work we do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, Business AI brings intelligence into SAP workflows by embedding predictive analytics, generative AI, and automation. This drives faster decision-making, reduces manual effort, and unlocks new business models across sectors. Together, these strengths position Cognizant as a trusted partner for enterprises seeking secure, automated, and AI-powered SAP transformations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hossam: &lt;/STRONG&gt;How has your SAP certification journey evolved - from your first global certification in 2011 to today? What motivated you initially, and how has your approach changed?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; As you have rightly pointed out, Cognizant’s SAP global certification journey began in &lt;STRONG&gt;2011&lt;/STRONG&gt;, when we became one of the earliest partners to achieve &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;. At that time, our motivation was clear: to build client &lt;STRONG&gt;confidence&lt;/STRONG&gt;, demonstrate &lt;STRONG&gt;market leadership&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and align with our vision of driving &lt;STRONG&gt;enterprise modernization through cloud-first strategies&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This milestone positioned us ahead of industry trends and validated our ability to deliver secure, scalable SAP solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since then, our approach has evolved from meeting compliance standards to driving continuous innovation. Today, certifications are part of a broader strategy focused on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA, SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, integrating AI, automation, and sustainability into transformation programs. We’ve expanded from core ERP to end-to-end digital solutions, strengthened partnerships with SAP and hyperscale cloud providers, and invested heavily in talent development through role-based certifications. For us, certification is no longer a one-time achievement - it’s a continuous journey to deliver measurable business outcomes and stay ahead of client needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hossam: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Looking ahead, how do you plan to grow your SAP competency and services to support customers?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sivakumar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cognizant plans to deepen its SAP competency by focusing on next-generation technologies such as&lt;STRONG&gt; SAP Business AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;and industry-specific solutions developed and integrated leveraging &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;. We are investing in advanced capabilities around &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA transformations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring clients can accelerate their cloud journeys with agility and resilience. Our strategy includes embedding &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-driven automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;predictive analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;sustainability frameworks&lt;/STRONG&gt; into SAP landscapes, enabling customers to unlock new business models and achieve measurable outcomes. These innovations will be supported by strong partnerships with SAP and hyperscale cloud providers to deliver integrated, multi-cloud architectures tailored to client needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Information on the certification program for operations partners and an overview of all certified partners can be found in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/opc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Operations Partner Guide&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;OPC&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/partners/partner-program/certify-my-solution.html#outsourcing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;or on the &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/partnership/services/co-innovation/opc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Partner Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/certified-excellence-how-cognizant-sets-the-benchmark-for-driving-real-sap/ba-p/14269012"/>
    <published>2025-11-14T16:40:08.041000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/fast-amp-curious-the-making-of-an-sap-champion/ba-p/14272116</id>
    <title>Fast &amp; Curious: The Making of an SAP Champion</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T12:53:30.851000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>margherita_gallucci34</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2235654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;On a Saturday morning in Hyderabad, Ruthvik Chowdary might be cruising towards a new destination with his playlist ready or volunteering at an SAP Inside Track event. Whether navigating winding roads or meeting fellow tech enthusiasts, Ruthvik thrives on exploring places, ideas, and opportunities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That same spirit of discovery led him to SAP technology.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inspired by his uncle, an experienced SAP Solution Architect, Ruthvik’s curiosity sparked during college. “He would discuss the problems he solved and SAP’s impact on businesses. It made him want to dive in.” And with his growing interest in manufacturing, it became the perfect starting point.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Guided by mentors and managers, Ruthvik soon broadened his expertise across the entire supply chain. He earned SAP Certifications spanning &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-s-4hana-quality-management?url_id=text-learnerstoryprdteng-LSC" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Quality Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; to &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-extended-warehouse-management-in-sap-s-4hana?url_id=text-global-learnerstory-prdteng-LSC" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Extended Warehouse Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and now, as a Supply Chain Manager at Deloitte, confidently designs and optimizes end-to-end processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;His breakthrough came during a training with a simulated supply bottleneck where he applied his knowledge to solve it. “That was when everything clicked. I understood not just the ‘how,’ but the ‘why.’ It was empowering.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The path, however, was not without challenges. Ruthvik wrestled with complex configurations and moments of self-doubt early in his journey. “I wondered if I was really suited for SAP products.” Encouragement from his mentor, manager, and uncle reminded him that every expert starts as a beginner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Ruthvik Photo 3.jpg" style="width: 340px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342407i29BC2C3946FD785D/image-dimensions/340x311/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="340" height="311" role="button" title="Ruthvik Photo 3.jpg" alt="Ruthvik Photo 3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;What continues to amaze him is SAP’s vastness and the constant innovation in cloud technologies. “It’s like an ocean. There’s always something new to learn.” Along the way, he developed unexpected strengths in communication and client engagement, becoming a trusted problem solver and mentor to others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of his proudest moments was being recognized as an SAP Champion for his contributions to the community. “Knowing my blogs helped others, even in interviews, is incredibly rewarding.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From shadow consultant to SAP Champion, Ruthvik’s story is one of persistence, passion, and purpose. His advice to new learners is simple: “Dive in, stay curious, and do not be afraid to ask for help. The rewards are worth it.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ready to begin your own adventure? Explore structured learning journeys and certifications on the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and discover where curiosity can take you.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/fast-amp-curious-the-making-of-an-sap-champion/ba-p/14272116"/>
    <published>2025-11-19T12:53:30.851000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/sap-certification-is-changing-what-you-need-to-know-about-the-new-format/ba-p/14274190</id>
    <title>SAP Certification Is Changing: What You Need to Know About the New Format</title>
    <updated>2025-11-25T12:29:58.456000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DheerajHJ</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2197618</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you’ve been following SAP’s certification updates, you’ll know things are changing in a big way. The traditional multiple-choice exams are being replaced with a much more practical approach. I recently went through all the latest materials and sessions about the new SAP certification format, especially for SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC), and I want to share what I learned and how you can prepare.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1894652219"&gt;Why Is SAP Changing Its Certification Format?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP wants certifications to mean more than just passing a test. The new format is designed to make sure certified professionals can actually do the work required on real SAP projects. Instead of just memorizing theory, you’ll be asked to solve problems and perform tasks that you’d encounter in your day-to-day job. This shift is great news for both candidates and employers. Companies can trust that certified consultants are ready for hands-on work, and candidates can show they’re truly job-ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698138714"&gt;What’s Different About the New Exams?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The biggest change is the move to performance-based assessments. You’ll be asked to complete tasks in a simulated SAP system, or respond to real-world scenarios, sometimes interacting with an AI avatar or submitting a video response. You can use SAP Help Portal, SAP Learning, and even SAP Joule (the AI tool) during the exam, just like you would on a real project. This open-book style makes the exam feel much more like actual work.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You also get to choose how you want to be assessed for some parts: either through an AI role-play or by uploading a video. After you finish, you’ll receive instant feedback, including analytics on your technical depth and communication skills.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501625209"&gt;Role-Based Certifications and Staying Certified&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP certifications are now tailored to specific job roles, such as developer, administrator, or architect. This means the exam content is more relevant to what you’ll actually do in your role. Certifications aren’t permanent anymore. You’ll need to complete a “stay-certified” assessment each year to keep your credential active. This helps ensure everyone stays up to date with the latest SAP technology and best practices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1305111704"&gt;Timeline for the New Format&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The rollout starts in November 2025 for selected exams, including SAP BTP Administrator, SAP Build Developer, Solution Architect – SAP BTP, SAP Business Data Cloud, and SAP Generative AI Developer. By 2026, all SAP certifications will use this new practical format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108598199"&gt;What Hasn’t Changed?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ll still get a digital badge when you pass, and the registration process is the same as before. If you already have a certification, it remains valid, but you’ll need to follow the renewal process to keep it active.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912084694"&gt;How Should You Prepare?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Focus on building practical SAP skills. Spend time working in SAP simulation environments, and practice explaining SAP solutions clearly and simply. Get comfortable with timed tasks and AI evaluation, and make sure your laptop, internet, webcam, and audio all meet SAP’s technical requirements before exam day.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715571189"&gt;Spotlight on SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) Certification&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The BDC certification is a great example of the new approach. It covers foundational knowledge and practical skills in SAP Business Data Cloud. The assessment includes technical knowledge of BDC, integration with SAP Business Warehouse, SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Datasphere, and SAP Databricks. To earn the badge, you’ll need to complete the recommended SAP Learning Journey and pass the C_BCBDC exam. Remember to renew your badge every year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exam questions breakdown from my attempt:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Knowledge of BDC (40%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration with SAP Business Warehouse (15%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Knowledge of SAP Analytics Cloud (15%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Knowledge of SAP Datasphere (15%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Knowledge of SAP Databricks (15%)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-519057684"&gt;Tips for Success&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Take your time and use the pause button to think before you answer. Break your responses into clear chunks, and don’t worry about giving too much information, there’s no penalty for being thorough. Read the feedback you get and use it to improve before your next attempt. And don’t rush; you have plenty of time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-322544179"&gt;Useful Links&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are some resources that helped me:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/training-certification/sap-certification.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Certification Overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/get-certified/reimagining-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Certification in the Age of AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/exploring-sap-business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BDC Learning Journey&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Certification BDC&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-126030674"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s new certification format is a big step forward. It’s designed to make sure credentials really mean something and that certified professionals are ready for real project work. If you’re preparing for the SAP Business Data Cloud certification, focus on practical skills, clear communication, and continuous learning. The future of SAP certification is here, and it’s all about being ready for the real world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have questions or want to share your experience with the new SAP certification, I’d love to hear from you in the comments.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/learner-stories/sap-certification-is-changing-what-you-need-to-know-about-the-new-format/ba-p/14274190"/>
    <published>2025-11-25T12:29:58.456000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/westernacher-achieves-sap-s-4hana-operations-certification-a-benchmark-in/ba-p/14275752</id>
    <title>Westernacher Achieves SAP S/4HANA Operations Certification: A Benchmark in Cloud-Ready Excellence</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T17:13:20.780000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christine13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our longstanding SAP partner, Westernacher Business Management Consulting GmbH, was recently certified for the first time for SAP S/4HANA solution operations. In this interview, Martin Espenschied, Global Practice Lead Continuous Improvement &amp;amp; AMS at Westernacher, reflects on their motivation for pursuing the certification, their experience during the audit, and how the achievement strengthens their global positioning within the SAP ecosystem. He also shares how they support customers across the full SAP transformation lifecycle - from strategy and implementation to operations and continuous improvement. As a globally active SAP consulting leader, Westernacher discusses its evolving 30-year partnership with SAP and the milestones that have shaped its journey. A key focus is the company’s expanding role in cloud transformation, including S/4HANA Cloud migrations, process optimization with SAP Signavio, lifecycle management with SAP Cloud ALM, and innovation enablement via SAP BTP. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Could you start by telling us about your company and the services you offer?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Westernacher Consulting is an internationally operating consulting group for business and information technologies. Since 1969, we have been supporting well-known businesses globally and locally in realizing their vision. We help achieve business and SAP strategies through established experience in a variety of industries, as well as proven competency in the areas of Digital Transformation, Warehouse, Yard and Transport Logistics, Enterprise Management, Supply Chain Planning, Industry 4.0 &amp;amp; Internet of Things, Business Analytics, and Client Engagement &amp;amp; Commerce.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today, Westernacher operates as one of the leading SAP partners worldwide and is fully owned by its employees. We focus on quality, sustainability, and long-term relationships with our business partners.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Westernacher’s core strengths are best-practice processes and SAP consulting, combining innovative technologies with integrated solutions that enable clients to execute their business strategy holistically.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our service portfolio spans the entire lifecycle of SAP-driven transformation - from early strategy to daily operations. This includes pre-project assessments and feasibility studies, global rollouts and SAP implementations (including custom developments), process consulting and enterprise architecture, as well as project and change management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At Westernacher, Application Management Services (AMS) and Continuous Improvement form a comprehensive, forward-looking framework that supports and enhances SAP S/4HANA and connected landscapes. Our AMS offering goes far beyond traditional support. We provide end-to-end SAP operations for SAP S/4HANA and connected landscapes, covering incident, request, and problem management supported by proactive monitoring. We ensure safe and efficient change cycles through structured release and test management. In addition, our continuous improvement approach connects operational insights with business KPIs and clean-core principles to deliver measurable value. Governance and SLA-driven service delivery are supported by SAP Cloud ALM as a central platform for transparency, automation, and lifecycle management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As an SAP partner for almost 30 years, how has your partnership evolved, and what have been the most significant milestones or highlights in your collaboration with SAP?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Westernacher has been an SAP partner for almost three decades, and this collaboration has evolved from early ERP implementations to delivering next-generation cloud solutions and managed services. Some of the most significant milestones include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1990s – Early SAP ERP Expertise&lt;BR /&gt;We began with SAP R/3 implementations, transforming the IT landscape of big German companies, and building deep process knowledge in Finance, Logistics, and Supply Chain.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2000s – Global Expansion &amp;amp; Industry Leadership&lt;BR /&gt;Westernacher grew internationally, supporting complex global rollouts and becoming recognized for best-practice process consulting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2010s – Innovation &amp;amp; Digital Transformation&lt;BR /&gt;We embraced SAP HANA, took part in the very first EWM implementation, and pioneered in EWM, TM, and YL across the globe, helping customers modernize operations and integrate advanced automation into their SAP solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2020s – Cloud &amp;amp; Continuous Improvement&lt;BR /&gt;Today, we are an SAP Gold Partner delivering S/4HANA cloud solutions leveraging SAP Signavio for process mining and optimization and LeanIX for enterprise architecture transparency and impact analysis, ensuring controlled change and innovation. All supported by our Application Management Services (AMS) with a strong focus on continuous improvement and clean-core principles. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Certifications &amp;amp; Recognitions&lt;BR /&gt;We achieved SAP Partner Center of Expertise (PCoE) certification and SAP Operations Partner Certification for SAP S/4HANA, validating our ability to run and improve SAP landscapes at scale.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is strongly focusing on the cloud and encourages partners to support customers in their migration journey. Do you plan to further expand your cloud-related services, and how are you already helping customers in this area?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cloud is at the center of our strategy, and we are continuously expanding our cloud-related services to help customers accelerate their transformation journey. Our approach combines technical expertise, governance, and business process optimization to ensure migrations deliver real business value - not just infrastructure change.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In practice, we are already supporting customers in multiple areas of their cloud transformation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We accompany organizations through &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud (Private Edition) migrations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, guiding them with readiness assessments, clean-core strategies, and end-to-end transition roadmaps as part of RISE with SAP programs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A key pillar of our support is &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud ALM for Lifecycle Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;. We implement SAP Cloud ALM to manage projects, operations, and continuous improvement in a cloud-native environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In parallel, we offer &lt;STRONG&gt;Process Optimization with SAP Signavio&lt;/STRONG&gt; to help customers analyze, optimize, and redesign their processes before migration, ensuring fit-to-standard and reducing unnecessary custom code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For &lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Architecture Transparency and Impact Assessment, we leverage LeanIX&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling &lt;SPAN&gt;controlled and predictable cloud transitions&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our &lt;STRONG&gt;Application Management Services also extend fully to Cloud Landscapes&lt;/STRONG&gt; - whether hybrid, private, or public cloud - where we provide proactive monitoring, automation, and structured release management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, we &lt;STRONG&gt;Enable Innovation by integrating SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt; for extensibility and new capabilities, ensuring customers can adopt innovations without compromising clean-core principles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For the future we are investing in automation, AI-driven monitoring, and advanced testing for cloud environments, as well as expanding our global delivery model to support multi-region migrations and post-go-live optimization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With Westernacher delivering services across 25 countries, how do you address the different customer expectations and requirements related to SAP Cloud solutions?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Operating in more than 25 countries means we encounter different regulatory environments, cultural nuances, and business priorities. We address these variations through a globally consistent framework combined with local flexibility:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Global Standards, Local presence and adaptation:&amp;nbsp;We apply a standardized delivery model based on SAP best practices (Activate, Cloud ALM, Signavio, LeanIX) while adapting to local compliance, language, and operational requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regional Expertise &amp;amp; Local Consultants:&amp;nbsp;Our delivery teams include local consultants who understand cultural and legal specifics, ensuring smooth communication and adherence to country-specific regulations (e.g., data residency, GDPR).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Flexible Service Design:&amp;nbsp;We tailor SLAs, governance models, and reporting to match customer expectations, whether they prioritize speed, cost efficiency, or innovation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Industry-Specific Templates:&amp;nbsp;Using SAP Signavio process mining and LeanIX architecture mapping, we create migration and optimization templates that reflect both global standards and local business processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Continuous Improvement Across Regions:&amp;nbsp;Our AMS practice runs a global CI backlog but prioritizes regional needs, ensuring enhancements benefit all our clients while focusing on local priorities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You were recently certified for the first time for SAP S/4HANA solutions operations. What motivated you to pursue this certification at this stage of your company’s journey?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We were motivated by two key factors: the imperative to build customer trust and the importance of ensuring strategic alignment with SAP’s vision.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customer Confidence in Operational Excellence:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;As more of our clients move to SAP S/4HANA and cloud landscapes, they expect partners who can guarantee stable, secure, and continuously optimized operations. Certification validates that our AMS practice meets SAP’s highest standards for lifecycle management, monitoring, and proactive improvement. We’ve always positioned AMS as more than “keeping the lights on.” This certification reinforces our ability to deliver predictable service quality, structured governance, and continuous improvement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alignment with SAP’s Cloud Strategy:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is driving RISE with SAP, Cloud ALM, and clean-core principles. By certifying now, we demonstrate readiness to support customers in hybrid and cloud-native environments, leveraging tools like SAP Cloud ALM, SAP Signavio, and SAP LeanIX for process optimization and lifecycle transparency. The certification sets us apart as a partner who not only implements SAP solutions but also runs and improves them sustainably - a critical differentiator for global AMS engagements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How would you describe your experience with the audit? Did it provide any valuable insights or ideas for further improvement?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The audit was a highly structured and collaborative process, and we viewed it as more than a compliance exercise. It was an opportunity to benchmark our AMS operations against SAP’s best practices. Several noteworthy findings emerged from the audit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Validation of Strengths: The audit confirmed that our governance model, SLA framework, and continuous improvement approach are aligned with SAP’s standards for S/4HANA operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tooling Excellence: Our use of SAP Cloud ALM, SAP Signavio, and SAP LeanIX for lifecycle management and process optimization was highlighted as a differentiator.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Knowledge Management &amp;amp; Documentation: The review reinforced the importance of maintaining centralized, audit-ready documentation for processes, KPIs, and improvement initiatives - something we already prioritize but will continue to refine.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The audit also provided several valuable insights that will guide our further improvements:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automation Opportunities: The audit encouraged us to accelerate test automation and proactive automated monitoring to reduce manual effort and improve predictability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Global Consistency: While our regional teams perform strongly, we identified opportunities to standardize across all delivery centers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhanced Use of SAP Cloud ALM Analytics: Leveraging deeper analytics in Cloud ALM for predictive insights and trend-based improvement was a key takeaway.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Overall, the audit validated our “run and improve” philosophy and gave us actionable ideas to make our AMS practice even more efficient, scalable, and future-ready.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="The Westernacher team together with the SAP auditor during the S/4HANA operations certification audit, October 2025" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/344251i22086AD3CD4E9467/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Westernacher_1.jpg" alt="The Westernacher team together with the SAP auditor during the S/4HANA operations certification audit, October 2025" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;The Westernacher team together with the SAP auditor during the S/4HANA operations certification audit, October 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do you expect the certification to support your marketing activities and strengthen communication with your customers?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Yes, absolutely. The SAP S/4HANA Operations Certification is more than a technical achievement. It is a trust signal for our customers and prospects. It demonstrates that Westernacher meets SAP’s highest standards for operational excellence, lifecycle management, and continuous improvement, and supports marketing and communication by:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Differentiation in the Market: The certification positions us as a partner who not only implements SAP solutions but also runs and optimizes them sustainably, which is a key decision factor for AMS and cloud engagements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer Confidence: It reinforces our credibility when discussing RISE with SAP, cloud migrations, and AMS services, making conversations more persuasive and value-driven.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Co-Marketing Opportunities with SAP: The certification opens doors for joint success stories, webinars, and campaigns, leveraging SAP’s ecosystem to amplify our reach.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New Market Focus: With this certification, we will actively market AMS not only as a natural extension of our implementation projects but also as a standalone service for external clients where we did not perform the SAP implementation. This expands our reach and positions AMS as a strategic offering for any SAP customer seeking operational excellence and continuous improvement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In short, the certification strengthens our brand promise and helps us communicate a clear message: Westernacher delivers SAP operations at a globally recognized standard, backed by continuous improvement and cloud readiness.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Information on the certification program for operations partners and an overview of all certified partners can be found in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/opc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Operations Partner Guide&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;OPC&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/partners/partner-program/certify-my-solution.html#outsourcing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP.com&lt;/A&gt; or on the &lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/partnership/services/co-innovation/opc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Partner Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/westernacher-achieves-sap-s-4hana-operations-certification-a-benchmark-in/ba-p/14275752"/>
    <published>2025-11-26T17:13:20.780000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/my-experience-with-the-new-sap-exam-format-2026/ba-p/14289994</id>
    <title>My Experience with the New SAP Exam Format (2026)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-14T11:52:49.009000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VictorHo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/65578</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1895732387"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Starting from &lt;STRONG&gt;November 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP officially introduced a significant change to its certification journey: an &lt;STRONG&gt;open-book, scenario-based exam format&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This new approach is currently in pilot for selected certifications, including the &lt;EM&gt;SAP BTP Solution Architect&lt;/EM&gt; exam.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Details about format here: &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/get-certified/reimagining-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Reimagining certification in the age of AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Last week, I had the chance to take this new exam for the certificate “SAP BTP Solution Architect” and I want to share my honest experience, especially for those preparing for it soon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;After reading the new update from SAP (above link), I learn some more details in a blog in SAP community:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-prepare-for-sap-s-new-certification/ba-p/14268066#:~:text=Instead%20of%20testing%20whether%20you,assessment%20and%20Scenario%2Dbased%20assessment." target="_blank"&gt;How to Prepare for SAP’s New Certification — SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;However, it’s still not very clear for me how it looks like in the actual exam. So I gave it a try. For the “SAP BTP Solution Architect”, it’s a “scenario-based” exam format, where you need to play the role of a solution architect, designing the solution for a use case, then pitch the solution to AI avatar, or record a video and upload for expert review.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Unlike the previous exam format, where you need to setup some software (private browser) to take a prottor-monitored multiple-choice exam, in this new format, you will start directly from SAP learning website. This is the first look at the new exam format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(To have this view, you must have purchased the SAP Certification Subcription; I will share in another post)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorHo_0-1765709167091.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351820i55EDE7857F6AF1F7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorHo_0-1765709167091.png" alt="VictorHo_0-1765709167091.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Certificate landing page, where you can start the&amp;nbsp;exam&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;After pressing on the “Go to Certification Exam”, the website will open a wizard like dialog to guide you through the process, which is quite user friendly:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorHo_1-1765709165225.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351821iC50DBC3B12BF7A7D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorHo_1-1765709165225.png" alt="VictorHo_1-1765709165225.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Certification Exam — Scenario Based Assessment — AI&amp;nbsp;Roleplay&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;For the exam of “Solution Architect”, you will be assigned to a use case, where you play the architect role to propose a solution to project stakeholders. The use case resembles the actual use case in one project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;For example, in my exam, I need to design a soluton for Field Service Maintainance Engineer to efficiently get and update data with S/4 systems, while they’re working at customer site.&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;After reading the use case, once you’re ready, you can choose 1 out of 2 options to proceed with the pitching part.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;For the next step, you will have 2 options to join the xam:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI Roleplay with AI Guidance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Record Video with Human Review.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I tried both, and share my experience as below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1699218882"&gt;1. A Fresh Concept: Scenario-Based + AI&amp;nbsp;Roleplay&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The most exciting part of the new format is the &lt;STRONG&gt;“Roleplay with AI”&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature. Instead of answering static questions, you interact with an &lt;STRONG&gt;AI avatar acting as your stakeholder&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and you must propose and justify your architecture on SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This idea is &lt;EM&gt;brilliant&lt;/EM&gt; — it mimics real project work and tests your ability to think, design, and explain like a true architect.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;However… the reality wasn’t as smooth as expected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1502705377"&gt;2. Technical Issues: The AI Mode Was Not&amp;nbsp;Stable&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Despite an impressive concept, the AI roleplay mode repeatedly failed during my attempts. I tried everything:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Company laptop and personal MacBook&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Corporate network, home Wi-Fi, mobile hotspot&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Multiple browsers and system setups&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Yet the final step always returned the same message:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;“An error occurred. Please refresh the page and try again. If the issue persists, contact the support team for assistance.”&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorHo_2-1765709165112.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351822i5F8CBB71F2A180AB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorHo_2-1765709165112.png" alt="VictorHo_2-1765709165112.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;AI Roleplay option — error&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The other option with Human review also didn’t work:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorHo_3-1765709165222.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351824i9ABE32136B7FAB3C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorHo_3-1765709165222.png" alt="VictorHo_3-1765709165222.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Human review option — error&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Since SAP requires exam submission within &lt;STRONG&gt;24 hours&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the pressure was real. I opened a support ticket, but even after a full working day, there was &lt;STRONG&gt;no response&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1306191872"&gt;3. The Backup Plan: Human&amp;nbsp;Review&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fortunately, late in the day, one of my setups finally allowed me to switch to the &lt;STRONG&gt;“Traditional Assessment”&lt;/STRONG&gt; option, with human review my recording. This required me to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Record and upload a video explaining my architecture&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Wait for a &lt;STRONG&gt;manual evaluation by an SAP expert&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;For this option, things are very “generic”. SAP does not provides any details on the expectation of the video. All you can do is to prepare the best solution, and present it, during the 2 hours period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;After submitting your video, you will get the result immediately with the AI Roleplace approach. But with the human review approach, you will need to wait for a long time to get the result. During this period, if you enter the certification page again, you will get the “In Review” status:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VictorHo_4-1765709164987.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351823i36B9F5513567088B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VictorHo_4-1765709164987.png" alt="VictorHo_4-1765709164987.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The downside?&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;The waiting time for results is now 20 days.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;This delay is a huge gap in the expectation of exam taker in this fast-paced world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1109678367"&gt;4. Final Thoughts: Great Idea, but Needs Stability&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I truly appreciate SAP’s direction. A scenario-based, open-book exam that simulates real project challenges is the right way forward. It evaluates real skills — not memorization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;But the &lt;STRONG&gt;instability of the AI mode&lt;/STRONG&gt; currently holds back the full potential of this format. When candidates must fall back to manual review, the process becomes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Slow&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Costly&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Frustrating&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uncertain&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;For exam takers, waiting nearly a month for results is a painful experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-913164862"&gt;5. Looking&amp;nbsp;Ahead&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I hope SAP can quickly stabilize the AI roleplay feature. When it works, it will elevate the certification experience and set a new benchmark for professional exams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The concept is powerful.&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;The execution just needs more refinement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;And once it’s stable, I believe this format will truly &lt;STRONG&gt;redefine how SAP professionals prove their expertise in the future.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/my-experience-with-the-new-sap-exam-format-2026/ba-p/14289994"/>
    <published>2025-12-14T11:52:49.009000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-learning-group-blog-posts/sap-datasphere-the-cloud-based-data-warehouse-data-fabric-solution/ba-p/14289054</id>
    <title>SAP Datasphere – The Cloud-Based Data Warehouse / Data Fabric Solution</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T14:33:41.658000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexandergregor_scivos</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/335268</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Datasphere plays a major role within SAP Business Data Cloud, our new data analytics platform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexandergregor_scivos_0-1765482013788.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351329iB8B04FBF3CEFB754/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexandergregor_scivos_0-1765482013788.png" alt="alexandergregor_scivos_0-1765482013788.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Datasphere is also a full-grown powerful data fabric / data warehouse solution on its own.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexandergregor_scivos_1-1765482013800.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351330iB010F4A0FD55A0A6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexandergregor_scivos_1-1765482013800.png" alt="alexandergregor_scivos_1-1765482013800.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It provides graphical and pro-code options for data harmonization and integration. It is SAP’s strategic solution for this purpose.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexandergregor_scivos_2-1765482013818.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351331i6E79C05AB3CACE2E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexandergregor_scivos_2-1765482013818.png" alt="alexandergregor_scivos_2-1765482013818.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can even integrate native SAP HANA models (For details about these models, read&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-learning-group-blog-posts/what-is-hana-calculation-view-modeling-and-is-it-for-me/ba-p/14283984" target="_blank"&gt;Jan ZWICKEL’s blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; about SAP HANA Calculation views).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this community, you will find blogs and other resources on SAP Datasphere. As this is a highly dynamic topic with a new wave every 2 weeks, please check regularly for updates. Feel free to ask questions. Please feel free to use this new community and connect with us and other learners.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your feedback on these resources is highly welcome. Also let us know about topics you would like to have covered in future live sessions and blogs, so that we can make our content even more suited to your needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, how can you take up knowledge about SAP Datasphere and prove it?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning about SAP Datasphere &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you want to find a &lt;STRONG&gt;short overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the 3 hour online course &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/explore-sap-datasphere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Exploring SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt; suits you best. Search for DSPE01 on &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you need information about the cloud-based SAP BW/4HANA tenant called &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere, SAP BW bridge&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we offer the 4 hour online course &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/sap-datasphere-sap-bw-bridge" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere, SAP BW Bridge&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexandergregor_scivos_3-1765482013827.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351333i46B567657982569B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexandergregor_scivos_3-1765482013827.png" alt="alexandergregor_scivos_3-1765482013827.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;What if you want to practice?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here again, we have nice courses for you!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/dsp-overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere Overview&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp;(online tour offers a complementary system. (Search for TRIAL_INT_DSP_OVERVIEW on &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexandergregor_scivos_4-1765482013834.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351332i6ED5FA8836468B77/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexandergregor_scivos_4-1765482013834.png" alt="alexandergregor_scivos_4-1765482013834.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you want to &lt;STRONG&gt;dive deeper&lt;/STRONG&gt; and ask questions, book the instructor-led &lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/dsp01-introduction-to-sap-datasphere-classroom-012-g-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DSP01 - Introduction to SAP Datasphere | SAP Training&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Create&lt;/SPAN&gt; your own models in several hands-on exercises based on 3 typical scenarios: file upload for self-service, fuzzy data matching, data harmonization from 3 different sources. (Search for DSP01 on &lt;A href="https://training.sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://training.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexandergregor_scivos_5-1765482013848.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351334i6ED1F7A6A2FB288B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexandergregor_scivos_5-1765482013848.png" alt="alexandergregor_scivos_5-1765482013848.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Live Sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition to courses and practice systems, the SAP Learning portal offers live sessions that are useful to go keep learning, ask questions, deepen your knowledge on specific topics. These sessions are delivered by subject-matter-experts (SMEs), either from SAP Training, SAP Partners or other experts at SAP such as Product Managers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The sessions come under five categories:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get Started&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Expert Deep Dive&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What's New&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get Certified&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stay Certified&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some of the live sessions are available for free, some require a subscription. This is visible in the example below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/search?access=free&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;query=live+session+SAP+Datasphere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere Live Session catalog sample on SAP Learning&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, we offer topics on &lt;STRONG&gt;Graphical Modeling for SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Performance Optimization for Backend Modelling and SAC Stories&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Want to prove your knowledge and increase your value?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you feel prepared enough, you should take the certification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Datasphere is part of the AI-based practice certification &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-sap-business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;C_BDCBC&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="alexandergregor_scivos_6-1765482013854.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/351335iC2270948A4B1CB1B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="alexandergregor_scivos_6-1765482013854.png" alt="alexandergregor_scivos_6-1765482013854.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Happy learning with SAP!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-learning-group-blog-posts/sap-datasphere-the-cloud-based-data-warehouse-data-fabric-solution/ba-p/14289054"/>
    <published>2025-12-15T14:33:41.658000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-golden-certificate-as-a-benchmark-kpn-s-commitment-to-quality/ba-p/14290362</id>
    <title>SAP’s Golden Certificate as a Benchmark: KPN’s Commitment to Quality</title>
    <updated>2025-12-16T07:40:29.867000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christine13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP’s Golden Certificate has been awarded to our partner KPN B.V. following the certification of its SAP operations and services for the tenth consecutive time. This milestone reflects more than two decades of a continuous journey with SAP, driven by a strong commitment to quality, trust, and innovation. We deeply value our enduring partnership and appreciate KPN’s willingness to share their insights and experiences on how certification has played a central role in strengthening customer confidence and shaping KPN’s service portfolio. From early SAP HANA adoption to today’s cloud solutions such as SAP S/4HANA, RISE with SAP, and SAP BTP, KPN has continuously expanded its SAP capabilities.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--2140419930"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1958033861"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Could you start by telling us about your company and the services you offer?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;At KPN, we’re proud to be the Netherlands’ leading provider of telecommunications and IT services. Our unique combination of a secure, nationwide network and privately owned data centers empowers us to deliver critical SAP environments for both national and international clients. For nearly 30 years, our dedicated SAP team has been at the forefront, offering expert consultancy, managed services, and 24/7 support. Our customers benefit from our proven track record and deep expertise, ensuring their SAP systems are secure, stable, and ready for the future. As cloud solutions like SAP BTP become increasingly vital, we guide our customers through every step of their digital transformation, acting as a trusted advisor and technical partner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1761520356"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;As an SAP partner for more than 24 years, how has your partnership evolved, and what have been the most significant milestones or highlights in your collaboration with SAP?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our partnership with SAP is a story of continuous innovation and shared success. For over two decades, we’ve been one of the most consistently certified SAP service providers in the Netherlands, a testament to our commitment and expertise. Highlights include our early adoption of SAP HANA, the integration of certified disaster recovery across multiple data centers, and our expansion into SAP Cloud services. Each achievement has enabled our customers to innovate with confidence and resilience. Our recent certification as an SAP BTP Operations Partner marks another proud milestone, reflecting our dedication to supporting our customers’ evolving needs. Looking ahead, we’re excited to deepen our expertise in SAP Cloud security and AI, ensuring our customers remain at the cutting edge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1565006851"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What inspired your decision to seek your first service certification in 2001, and how do you assess that choice today?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking back, our decision to pursue SAP certification in 2001 was driven by a passion for excellence and a desire to earn our customers’ trust. We recognized early on that independent validation was essential, not just for us, but for our customers’ peace of mind. Today, we’re proud that this commitment continues to set us apart. Maintaining our certifications remains crucial, reassuring our customers, strengthening our reputation, and often making the difference in competitive bids. This commitment to quality and trust forms the foundation of our success, and we value the confidence it brings to our customers every day.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Handover of the golden certificate, November 2025" style="width: 595px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/352001iCBF14302D3DC43FC/image-dimensions/595x803?v=v2" width="595" height="803" role="button" title="IMG_1289_mod.jpg" alt="Handover of the golden certificate, November 2025" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Handover of the golden certificate, November 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP is strongly focusing on the cloud and encourages partners to support customers in their migration journey. Do you plan to further expand your cloud-related services, and how are you already helping customers in this area?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Absolutely! As cloud adoption accelerates, we’re investing heavily in expertise, solutions, and tooling to help our customers make a safe and successful transition. We guide customers through end-to-end migrations to SAP S/4HANA and RISE with SAP, delivering managed cloud services, including security, monitoring, and seamless integration with our robust network infrastructure. Our unique position as both a connectivity and SAP services provider ensures our customers enjoy secure, future-ready cloud journeys. Looking ahead, we’re excited to expand our offerings in cloud security and AI-driven automation, empowering our customers to achieve even greater success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1368493346"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;You were recently certified for the first time for SAP BTP operations. What experiences have you gained with SAP BTP in recent years, and what motivated you to pursue this certification at this point in your company’s evolution?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;We saw that many of our customers were eager to unlock the full potential of SAP BTP, but often found it challenging to manage the platform’s complexity, especially around monitoring, security, and operational excellence. By investing in SAP BTP expertise and achieving official certification, we ensure our customers can rely on us for secure, reliable, and optimized BTP operations. This milestone reflects our ambition to stay ahead of technological developments and our commitment to supporting our customers’ innovation journeys. Together, we embrace every step forward in making SAP BTP a powerful asset for our clients.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1171979841"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How would you describe your experience with the audits? Do they provide any valuable insights or ideas for further improvement?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;We welcome the audit process as a valuable opportunity to reflect, improve, and benchmark our services against the highest standards. While preparing for an audit is demanding, the thoroughness and professionalism of SAP’s auditors always lead to constructive feedback and fresh ideas. We carefully review every audit report and translate recommendations into concrete actions, ensuring we continuously raise the bar for our customers. These audits not only strengthen our partnership with SAP but also motivate us as a team to take pride in our achievements and strive for continuous improvement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Information on the certification program for operations partners and an overview of all certified partners can be found in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/opc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Operations Partner Guide&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;OPC&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/partners/partner-program/certify-my-solution.html#outsourcing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;or on the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/partnership/services/co-innovation/opc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Partner Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-golden-certificate-as-a-benchmark-kpn-s-commitment-to-quality/ba-p/14290362"/>
    <published>2025-12-16T07:40:29.867000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/capgemini-chosen-to-pilot-sap-s-newly-launched-sap-business-ai-solutions/ba-p/14292555</id>
    <title>Capgemini Chosen to Pilot SAP’s Newly Launched SAP Business AI Solutions Operations Certification</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T09:19:41.966000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Christine13</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4840</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;When SAP introduced its new SAP Business AI solutions operations certification, it signaled a new differentiator for partners driving the next wave of enterprise AI innovation. At the intersection of readiness and opportunity, Capgemini was selected as pilot partner - reflecting years of trust, operational maturity, and leadership in SAP Business AI. In this story, SAP and Capgemini share their perspectives on how co-creation, real-world rigor, and precise timing helped shape a new standard for AI operations. Together, they highlight what it takes to turn innovation into trusted, enterprise-grade reality.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP’s Perspective&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;In the rapidly evolving landscape of enterprise AI, operational excellence is no longer a back-office concern, it’s a strategic imperative. That’s why SAP launched its new certification “SAP-certified in SAP Business AI solutions operations”, designed to validate and elevate the operational capabilities of partners delivering services and AI-powered operations for SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;For this initiative, SAP chose&amp;nbsp;Capgemini&amp;nbsp;as its first&amp;nbsp;pilot partner. The decision was rooted in trust, history, and proven excellence and some fortunate timing. Capgemini was due to recertify its operations certifications, and the timing aligned with SAP’s desire to pilot a new certification for SAP Business AI operations. Capgemini’s maturity in the SAP Business AI space made them an ideal pilot partner. Their defined offerings, mature KPIs, and well-managed AI operations gave SAP the confidence to move forward with the certification launch.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“As we scale Business AI across the enterprise, trust in the operations behind it is just as critical as the technology itself. Having Capgemini as our pilot partner for this certification was a deliberate choice; their operational maturity and candid feedback helped elevate our new standards for the entire ecosystem.”,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;said Marc-Oliver Klein,&amp;nbsp;VP, Head of Partner Product Management SAP Business AI, SAP SE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;What made this collaboration truly special was Capgemini’s&amp;nbsp;active role in shaping the certification itself. Their feedback helped refine the final form of the certification. Their thoughtful feedback helped turn it into something that truly mirrors real-world operational needs. It’s another milestone in a long-standing partnership between SAP and Capgemini.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Capgemini’s Perspective&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;When SAP approached Capgemini to recertify its operations scope, they were already deep into their AI journey, with a strong posture in SAP AI operations and a desire to further validate their capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Participating in the pilot wasn’t just about earning a badge, it was about&amp;nbsp;co-creating a standard&amp;nbsp;that would define operational excellence in AI for years to come. Capgemini’s willingness to engage, provide feedback, and iterate with SAP reflects its commitment to being a&amp;nbsp;trusted, forward-thinking partner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;"Partnering with SAP on this new certification allowed us to go beyond validation. It enabled us to help define what excellence in AI operations truly looks like. It’s a proud moment that reflects our shared commitment to shaping the future with our clients, making it real.",&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;said Gianluca Simeone, VP &lt;SPAN&gt;- Global SAP CTIO and Gen-AI Leader at Capgemini&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;This certification now stands as a symbol of Capgemini’s leadership in the space and its dedication to robust, scalable, and high-performing AI operations. It also reinforces Capgemini’s role in helping shape the future of enterprise AI alongside SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Information on the certification program for operations partners and an overview of all certified partners can be found in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://www.sap.com/opc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Operations Partner Guide&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;OPC&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/partners/partner-program/certify-my-solution.html#outsourcing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;or on the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/partnership/services/co-innovation/opc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Partner Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/capgemini-chosen-to-pilot-sap-s-newly-launched-sap-business-ai-solutions/ba-p/14292555"/>
    <published>2025-12-18T09:19:41.966000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
