<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-09-16T05:00:12.542834+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Cloud/pd-p/431932400353955532628433796433200" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/let-s-talk-transformation-interactive-sessions-small-groups-of-customers-to/ba-p/13986679</id>
    <title>LET´S TALK Transformation: Interactive sessions, small groups of customers to share and learn</title>
    <updated>2025-01-15T20:30:41.376000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VaneA_Transformation</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20125</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trying to succeed on a cloud journey?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You're in for an exciting ride! But let's face it, aligning strategies, teams, and investments can be a real challenge. Collaboration is key to nailing your project and driving business value. Migrating to the cloud isn't just about software; it's about evolving processes to stay competitive and meet customer demands. Tech is a powerful enabler, but it's not the transformation itself. That's where you come in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the past year, we've chatted with over 300 customers about their transformation strategies. We've found that while many organizations have a vision, they struggle to align internally and make it a reality.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Sounds familiar? Guess what? We've taken insights from those conversations with more mature customers, the ones that have managed to achieve results from the cloud (and some great research from SAP) to build a transformation framework to guide our customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Transformation Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt; is made up of &lt;U&gt;11 elements&lt;/U&gt; across three key areas:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1)&lt;/STRONG&gt;Business Area Strategy&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2)&lt;/STRONG&gt;Transformation Tactical Components&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3)&lt;/STRONG&gt;Technology Enablement.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Want to dive deeper? Join our 1:Few Sessions! Our Solution Value Advisory experts will lead interactive discussions on the most relevant topics within our &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Transformation Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Sessions repeat monthly, so pick the topics and dates that work best for you. Ready to transform your transformation? We can't wait to see you there!&amp;nbsp; Link to review available sessions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/dqazTCD/1_Fews_H1_2025_ClientFacing%20%28including%20APJ%29_PDF.pdf?inline=true&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1164079" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click to review global calendar for H2_2025&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/rNuHFir/1_Fews_H1_2025_ClientFacing%20LATAM1.pdf?inline=true&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1195540" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here for LAC sessions calendar (in spanish)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/let-s-talk-transformation-interactive-sessions-small-groups-of-customers-to/ba-p/13986679"/>
    <published>2025-01-15T20:30:41.376000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-bw-4hana-the-grey-panther-of-data-warehousing/ba-p/13997639</id>
    <title>SAP BW/4HANA: The Grey Panther of Data Warehousing</title>
    <updated>2025-01-27T09:42:37.658000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Phil_from_Madrid</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1886</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP BW/4HANA: The Grey Panther of Data Warehousing&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“And some things that should not have been forgotten were lost. History became legend. Legend became myth. And for twenty years, the BW passed out of all knowledge.”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(Adapted from Galadriel’s famous words)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cloud-native&amp;nbsp;data management solutions dominate the presence in many discussions and strategies about data management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Despite its evolution from BW to BW/4HANA and the significant functional improvements it brought, the solution’s 25-year history— evident in many of its functional corners—makes it difficult for BW/4HANA to be perceived as a modern data warehousing solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But there are many concepts in BW that are functionally strong and beneficial, and on which in the last decades many foundations of large and very large BW platforms for many customers of SAP were built.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BW/4HANA addresses challenges that, in the past, &lt;STRONG&gt;may not have been fully recognized as strengths by those who used it&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but which are now worth remembering in the discussion about the “modern data stack”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This article revisits some of these strengths in metadata management, governance, orchestration, and automation—highlighting its utility for (classical) well-structured, large-scale EDWs with a focus on SAP systems as the source of data. This short article concludes by exploring how SAP Datasphere inherits and modernizes some of BW’s proven concepts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deep Integration of Metadata Management and Business Semantics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BW/4HANA (within its own functionality) offers unparalleled rich metadata, its management and semantic integration. Its Info Objects always provided rich semantics, time-dependencies, hierarchies, multilingual support, and reusability, hiding a table-oriented view in favor of a more object-oriented perspective. Info Objects embed business semantics directly into data models, eliminating the need for external interventions for that purpose. Features like well-defined amount-to-currency relationships and unit conversions are natively extracted from the source in an automated way, ensuring semantic precision throughout the data chain without having to create additional bespoke logic or external tools to enforce system-wide consistency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In contrast, many modern cloud platforms often depend on third-party tools for advanced metadata management and lineage, particularly in heterogeneous environments with multiple data warehouse solutions. While these tools can offer benefits in multi-platform setups, they also introduce additional licensing costs and integration complexity. By comparison, BW/4HANA’s integrated approach streamlines unified yet complex data landscapes (of structured data).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Master Data Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BW/4HANA Info objects of type characteristic have always been an excellent support for master data design and management. Info Objects ensure system-wide uniqueness and consistency, managing time-dependent attributes and hierarchies with minimal developer intervention.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multilingual support for master data and standard hierarchy containers and operations for even complex, time-dependent hierarchical structures further enhance the utility of Info Objects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Handling slow-changing dimensions and other master data management tasks are homogeneous across all master data in their application and treatment, reflecting one of BW’s long-standing strengths.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Orchestration and Automation with Process Chains&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Process Chains in BW/4HANA automate ETL workflows, ensuring tasks are executed in sequence with built-in error handling, scheduling, and logging. In contrast, cloud platforms often rely on external orchestration tools like Apache Airflow or AWS Step Functions, adding tool complexity to data pipeline design and orchestration. BW/4HANA’s native orchestration has proven to simplify large workflows and to reduce maintenance and monitoring overhead. It also has its effects in the application lifecycle management which is deeply integrated in BW.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Logical Scalability and Dependency Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BW/4HANA’s previously discussed object-oriented approach enables logical scalability and robust dependency management for complex data landscapes. While cloud platforms like Snowflake focus on elastic scalability, managing interrelated data tables often requires additional tools for cataloguing dependencies. BW/4HANA’s integrated design handles these challenges natively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While this list highlights key features, it is by no means exhaustive. BW/4HANA offers additional strengths that have made it a robust solution, though they are omitted here for brevity. The point here is that plenty of currently discussed topics and challenges in the use of the “modern data stack”&lt;A href="#_ftn1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; have been resolved many years ago in BW and that for SAP data a solid BW infrastructure still is an asset not to be underestimated in its value when it comes to thoughts about substituting it just for doing something “new”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere: Modernizing BW’s Strengths&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Datasphere is now showing clear signs of including some of the above-mentioned conceptual strengths of BW/4HANA features. We can find the following concepts in the more recent SAP Datasphere releases:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Multilingual Support: Adapts datasets and reports to user preferences, ensuring global consistency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Currency Conversion: Replicates BW’s standardized functionality for seamless ERP-DW integration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Time-Dependent Attributes: Maintains historical master data changes with business semantics like “Valid from” and “Valid to”.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hierarchies: Incorporates parent-child hierarchies with expanded functionality for modern cloud environments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigation Attributes: Enables logically easy to understand aggregations of fact data by natural “business objects” without duplicating data, ensuring model flexibility and expressiveness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Non-Cumulative Measures: Supports scenarios like stock levels and balances, leveraging delta records for precision.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BW-Style Measure Types: Includes calculated, restricted, and currency conversion measures, maintaining analytic rigor.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Variables: Enhances interactivity and flexibility through dynamic parameter settings with a standardized behavior.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BW/4HANA’s integrated approach included solutions for many challenges in metadata management, governance, and scalability, reducing complexity and homogeneous solution patterns in large-scale deployments. While cloud platforms necessitate often third-party tools for similar capabilities, BW/4HANA offers a cohesive solution which his not easily found anywhere else. Despite being labelled as a ‘legacy’ system, BW/4HANA remains and will remain relevant for many organizations for years. Transitioning its proven solutions to a “modern data stack” would require significant effort, discipline, re-skilling and governance, making BW/4HANA a practical choice for the foreseeable future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Datasphere represents a powerful evolution, blending modern cloud-native architecture with some of the proven concepts of BW/4HANA. It not only supports seamless SAP data integration but also accommodates diverse data sources, offering enterprises a balance of innovation and reliability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="#_ftnref1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; A name which implicitly includes the multi-tool nature of it&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-bw-4hana-the-grey-panther-of-data-warehousing/ba-p/13997639"/>
    <published>2025-01-27T09:42:37.658000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/comparing-uipath-impact-analysis-and-tricentis-livecompare-key-differences/ba-p/13997350</id>
    <title>Comparing UiPath Impact Analysis and Tricentis LiveCompare: Key Differences</title>
    <updated>2025-01-30T09:33:45.112000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vikasini</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1678881</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1209490808"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview of UiPath Impact Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;UiPath Heatmap for SAP is a feature of the UiPath Test Suite designed to optimize test prioritization based on real-time SAP system usage. It leverages data-driven insights to identify automation opportunities and align test efforts with critical business processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1142060022"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-Time Process Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Visualizes SAP transactions and their usage frequency to prioritize testing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Coverage Visualization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Displays test coverage through color-coded indicators:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Gray: No test case exists or has been executed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Red: Test case exists but has failed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Green: Test case exists and has passed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immediate Results&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Requires minimal setup, offering instant insights to identify gaps in test coverage and critical risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Compatible with SAP ECC, S/4HANA, and SAP EWM.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-945546517"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strengths&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prioritizes test cases based on real system usage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Simple and intuitive visualization for test management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Seamless integration with UiPath’s low-code automation platform.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Focus on test optimization and automation scalability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-619950293"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Overview of Tricentis LiveCompare&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tricentis LiveCompare is a comprehensive impact analysis and testing tool designed specifically for SAP environments. It provides AI-driven insights into system changes, helping organizations minimize risks and optimize testing efforts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-552519507"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Change Impact Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Uses AI-powered analytics to identify SAP objects at risk from transports, support packs, or change requests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Continuous Configuration Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Automatically identifies configuration-related changes affecting master data and functional testing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Code Quality Monitoring&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Monitors and analyzes custom ABAP code for quality and dependency issues.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart Project Guides&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Guides SAP teams through quality activities at each stage of a project, aligned with SAP Activate.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role-Based UI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Provides tailored analytics and reports based on user roles.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-356006002"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strengths&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Comprehensive impact analysis for SAP system updates.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Focus on risk minimization and testing efficiency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Advanced AI and analytics for deep insights into changes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Detailed reports for test prioritization and audit readiness.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-30409778"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. UiPath Platform vs. Tricentis Tosca&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--37021008"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature Comparison&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UiPath Platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tricentis Tosca&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process Library&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Strong capabilities (9.6), offering efficient test management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Equally rated at 9.6, focusing on managing test cases effectively.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Execution Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Superior (9.5), excelling in automated workflow management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Slightly behind, with less emphasis on execution management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Delivers actionable insights (9.2) for automation testing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Provides valuable insights (8.3), though less detailed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Highly flexible (9.3) for tailored solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Limited flexibility (8.0) for customization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ease of Use&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Streamlined bot creation process (9.3).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;User-friendly visual editor (9.1).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quality of Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Strong support (8.8), offering responsive assistance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Decent support (8.3), less robust.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extensive pre-built connectors (9.2) for seamless app integration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;API Designer rated lower (8.0) and seen as somewhat limited.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--362617232"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Key Differences Between UiPath Heatmap and Tricentis LiveCompare&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UiPath Heatmap for SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tricentis LiveCompare&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Primary Focus&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Real-time test prioritization and coverage visualization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Change impact analysis and risk identification for SAP systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visualization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Heatmap with color-coded indicators for test coverage and transaction usage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Detailed impact analysis dashboards and reports.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technology Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data-driven insights from system usage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI and dependency-based analysis of system changes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Setup and Usability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Minimal setup with immediate results.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Requires configuration for change analysis.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Part of the UiPath ecosystem for automation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Standalone tool integrated with Tricentis Tosca.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Audience&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Test teams looking to optimize automation coverage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Organizations focused on minimizing risk and managing change impacts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Prioritization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Based on real-time system usage and transaction relevance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Based on changes in code, configuration, and dependencies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scope&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Optimizes ongoing testing efforts with actionable insights.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Focuses on preparing for SAP upgrades and major changes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--559130737"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Which Tool Should You Choose?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1124278618"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Choose UiPath Heatmap for SAP if&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You prioritize visual, data-driven test optimization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You already use UiPath’s automation tools and want seamless integration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your focus is on enhancing automation efficiency and real-time prioritization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You need a tool that delivers immediate insights without complex setup.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1320792123"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Choose Tricentis LiveCompare if&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You require a robust solution for managing SAP system changes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your organization prioritizes risk mitigation during SAP upgrades and migrations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You need detailed impact analysis to identify high-risk areas.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You are looking for advanced AI-driven insights and reporting capabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1223902621"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1420416126"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6. Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Both UiPath Heatmap for SAP and Tricentis LiveCompare provide valuable functionalities to support SAP testing and change management. The UiPath Platform shines in its execution management and actionable feedback, while Tricentis Tosca excels in visual editing and ease of use. Meanwhile, UiPath Heatmap excels in real-time test prioritization, and Tricentis LiveCompare offers advanced change impact analysis and risk-based recommendations. Organizations should assess their specific testing needs, existing tools, and long-term goals to select the most suitable solution for their SAP landscape.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/comparing-uipath-impact-analysis-and-tricentis-livecompare-key-differences/ba-p/13997350"/>
    <published>2025-01-30T09:33:45.112000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/daniel-mateo/ba-p/14006541</id>
    <title>Daniel Mateo</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T11:00:32.483000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KatherineKenneally</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/328</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/266870" target="_blank"&gt;More about Daniel Mateo in SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Daniel Mateo circular.png" style="width: 152px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/221647iD422DB3DB3AF42A2/image-dimensions/152x160?v=v2" width="152" height="160" role="button" title="Daniel Mateo circular.png" alt="Daniel Mateo circular.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;First Name, Last Name:&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;Daniel Mateo&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Location (City, Country): &lt;/STRONG&gt;Barcelona, Spain&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Occupation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP Finance Project Manager&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="People_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51216i6B6C3041A74CC074/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="People_pictogram.png" alt="People_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Daniel, tell us about yourself.&lt;BR /&gt;Who are you, what do you like to do, what is important to you?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hey there! I am a big SAP enthusiast with over 18 years of experience in this sector, focused on international projects in finance and management accounting. I love diving into all SAP innovations and Cloud implementations, but when I am not working, you will probably find me out exploring new places. Traveling, cycling, swimming and hiking are some of my favorite ways to unplug and recharge. Whether it is tackling a mountain trail or discovering new cities, I am always up for an adventure!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Desktop_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51217iF7FFD39907D24E76/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="Desktop_pictogram.png" alt="Desktop_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What is your area of expertise?&lt;BR /&gt;What does a usual day at work look like for you?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an SAP Project Manager specialized in finance and management accounting, I bring over 18 years of experience in driving and managing complex international projects. My expertise lies in implementing and optimizing SAP solutions for finance, controlling and reporting. My deep understanding of SAP’s finance modules and related Cloud solutions, enables me to lead teams and stakeholders effectively while ensuring project success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My day usually starts with reviewing the progress of ongoing SAP implementations and addressing any project roadblocks. Meetings with stakeholders or project teams are a regular part of my schedule, where I review requirements, ensure alignment with business objectives, and prioritize tasks. If needed, I step in to resolve any project issues, from resource management to stakeholder communication. My role also includes reporting on the project’s status, tracking milestones, and providing leadership to ensure the smooth transition from kick-off to go-live.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Overall, my day is dynamic, combining strategic planning, problem-solving, and client management to drive successful SAP international projects in the finance and controlling areas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="inspiration_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51218i2605363EFF68DD34/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="inspiration_pictogram.png" alt="inspiration_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What inspired you to become an SAP Champion in SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My inspiration to become an SAP Champion in the esteemed SAP Community originated from my passion for SAP and sharing knowledge about the latest trends that may impact business processes, especially in finance and controlling.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Becoming an SAP Champion allows me to not only deepen my understanding but also to share my expertise with others, learn from the diverse community, and be part of the ongoing evolution of SAP solutions. It is incredibly rewarding to help fellow professionals understand the cutting-edge SAP functionalities, and in doing so, help them unlock the full potential of their SAP systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="bullet_list_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51219i2905480F1FCC6AE2/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="bullet_list_pictogram.png" alt="bullet_list_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;How do you learn in SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is your daily/weekly routine in SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the SAP Community, I learn by actively reading discussions and exploring new content related to my areas of interest, such as SAP Finance and Cloud solutions. I make it a point to stay engaged with the latest topics and interact with other SAP professionals to exchange insights and best practices. This learning process not only enhances my expertise but also helps me stay at the forefront of SAP innovations, ensuring that I can contribute effectively to ongoing projects and discussions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My daily routine includes checking for updates on forums, reviewing any new posts in the groups I follow, and engaging in conversations where I can share my knowledge or gain new insights. On a weekly basis, I make time to attend webinars and read blog posts to stay up to date with the latest SAP trends and best practices. Additionally, I participate in SAP Inside Track events, such as Fortaleza and Barcelona, as a speaker or participant, which provide valuable opportunities to network, share knowledge, and learn from others in the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="circles_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51220i73C820D745D17725/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="circles_pictogram.png" alt="circles_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is your suggestion to get the most out of SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I highly recommend engaging actively by joining discussions, asking questions, and sharing your experiences. Make sure to follow relevant tags or groups related to your expertise, such as Finance or Supply Chain, to stay updated on the latest trends and best practices. Contributing to forums, webinars, or even blogs allows you to network with SAP professionals, learn from their insights, and help others by offering your expertise. The more you interact, the more valuable knowledge you will gain, and you will establish connections that can support your career growth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Arrow_pictogramm_new.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51221i1EA57128883E9979/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="Arrow_pictogramm_new.png" alt="Arrow_pictogramm_new.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Daniel's question to you:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How do you see AI transforming SAP financial and controlling processes in the next 5 years? Share your thoughts and let's discuss how emerging technologies will shape the future of SAP finance.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/daniel-mateo/ba-p/14006541"/>
    <published>2025-02-04T11:00:32.483000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/beyond-the-data-silo-the-convergence-of-sap-systems-and-modern-data-lake/ba-p/14011954</id>
    <title>Beyond the Data Silo: The Convergence of SAP Systems and Modern Data Lake Technologies</title>
    <updated>2025-02-10T04:53:39.311000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>rugved88</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/842167</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In today's enterprise landscape, a fascinating transformation is underway. While SAP systems continue to serve as the backbone of business operations, organizations are discovering that traditional approaches to data management no longer meet the demands of our rapidly evolving digital economy. The challenge isn't just about managing data – it's about turning it into actionable intelligence at the speed of business.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1702688267"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Evolution of SAP Data Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP ecosystem has long been the backbone of enterprise operations, housing critical business data across its various modules. However, today's digital economy demands more than just robust transaction processing – it requires seamless integration of internal and external data sources, real-time analytics, and AI-driven insights.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The current state of enterprise data presents an intriguing paradox. Consider a typical global manufacturing Company X: Multiple SAP instances span continents, each running critical modules like FI/CO, MM, SD, and PP. In Europe, teams work with one set of customizations and configurations, while their Americas counterparts operate with different chart of accounts and business rules. What seems like a simple question about global inventory levels can spiral into a days-long exercise involving multiple teams, countless Excel sheets, and lengthy email threads.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="system-architecture_.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/223916iA3D5AA05D3AD969A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="system-architecture_.png" alt="system-architecture_.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Traditional-architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These challenges extend beyond just SAP systems. The integration of external data sources – IoT sensors, market data feeds, social media analytics – adds layers of complexity to an already intricate landscape. The time lag between data creation and insight generation has become a critical bottleneck for business agility.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1506174762"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Promise of Modern Data Lakes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Modern data lake technologies represent a paradigm shift in how enterprises can manage and utilize their data. These platforms bring transformative capabilities through their support for industry-standard formats, enabling seamless data exchange across the enterprise. Their flexible schema management adapts to changing business needs, while enterprise-grade reliability is ensured through ACID transactions. The ability to access and restore historical data states, combined with unified processing for both batch and streaming workloads, creates a robust foundation for next-generation enterprise data management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1309661257"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Convergence: A New Enterprise Data Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The future lies in architectures that bring together the best of both worlds – SAP's robust business processes and the flexibility of modern data lakes. This next-generation architecture reimagines how enterprise data flows and interacts:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Untitled diagram-2025-02-09-090222.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/223917i91AFA408420F800C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Untitled diagram-2025-02-09-090222.png" alt="Untitled diagram-2025-02-09-090222.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Future-architecture&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;This convergence enables a new approach to data governance, where metadata management, data quality rules, and lineage tracking are centralized across both SAP and non-SAP data. Organizations can achieve zero-latency access to operational data with instant synchronization across systems, while performing real-time analytics without impacting transaction systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Perhaps most importantly, this convergence creates an AI-ready data foundation. By standardizing data formats for AI/ML workloads and enabling the integration of structured and unstructured data, organizations can fully leverage the power of large language models and generative AI across their enterprise data landscape.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1113147752"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical Implementation Strategies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Organizations looking to modernize their SAP data architecture should begin with a focus on high-value scenarios that require integrated data, particularly in areas where real-time insights drive business value. Projects that combine SAP and external data often yield the most significant returns and provide valuable learning experiences for teams. The foundation of this modernization requires implementing modern data lake capabilities alongside existing systems, while establishing unified governance frameworks. Creating semantic layers that abstract technical complexity enables broader adoption across the organization. Organizations must also prepare their data structures for AI workloads, implementing robust data quality measures and building pipelines for continuous data refreshes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-916634247"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion: Preparing for Tomorrow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The convergence of SAP systems with modern data lake technologies isn't just a technical evolution – it's a business imperative. Organizations that successfully navigate this transformation will find themselves better positioned to accelerate innovation through integrated data access, improve decision-making with real-time insights, enable AI-driven business processes, and maintain competitive advantage in the digital economy.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The question isn't whether to embrace this transformation, but how to implement it in a way that maximizes business value while minimizing disruption. As technology leaders, our role is to guide our organizations through this evolution, ensuring we build data architectures that are not just modern, but future-ready.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What steps is your organization taking to modernize its enterprise data architecture? The journey toward unified, AI-ready data platforms is just beginning, and the decisions we make today will shape our ability to compete tomorrow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/beyond-the-data-silo-the-convergence-of-sap-systems-and-modern-data-lake/ba-p/14011954"/>
    <published>2025-02-10T04:53:39.311000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-metadata-behind-sap-data-products-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14016947</id>
    <title>The Metadata behind SAP Data Products in SAP Business Data Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-02-17T16:44:25.629000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SimonHeimler</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/172928</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;On February 13th, 2025, we introduced&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Data+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100700003531" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1249-1"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(BDC) to help enterprises unlock value from their data, using it to power analytics, AI, and automation. Fundamental to BDC are&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_product" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Data Products&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: curated datasets that are accessible, self-describing, discoverable, and understandable. The value and usability of any data partly depends on the availability and quality of metadata, which is also true for the Data Products of BDC. This blog post provides a &lt;STRONG&gt;deep dive into the metadata for SAP Data Products&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, SAP uses open metadata standards&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;to describe Data Products. The API / data model of Data Products is described in &lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/csn-interop-specification/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Core Schema Notation Interoperability Specification&lt;/A&gt; (CSN Interop). The high-level information about Data Products, their taxonomy and relationships are described in &lt;A href="https://open-resource-discovery.github.io/specification/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Open Resource Discovery&lt;/A&gt; with a focus on taxonomy and connecting Data Products with development, integration, and business-oriented concepts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1573754475"&gt;High-Level Metadata&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP developed a metadata discovery standard for describing and publishing various types of APIs and events: &lt;A href="https://open-resource-discovery.github.io/specification/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Open Resource Discovery&lt;/A&gt; (ORD). ORD is part of the &lt;A href="https://apeirora.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Apeiro Reference Architecture&lt;/A&gt; and is&amp;nbsp;contributed as &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/open-resource-discovery-a-protocol-for-decentralized-metadata-discovery-is/ba-p/13579190" target="_self"&gt;open source&lt;/A&gt; to the European &lt;A href="https://www.8ra.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;IPCEI-CIS&lt;/A&gt; initiative as a standard for interoperability. It was a natural step to leverage this existing standard rather than to create another isolated metadata standard that only covers the Data Product and platform aspects. So, we extended ORD to include the &lt;A href="https://open-resource-discovery.github.io/specification/spec-v1/concepts/data-product" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Product&lt;/A&gt; concept and connected it with other existing developer-focused concepts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This also helps with avoiding the typical problem of siloed and fragmented metadata graphs. We believe there is huge value in connecting the various metadata concepts that are relevant to developers, architects, data scientists, and business persona. Our strategy is to bring all these aspects together and aggregate the metadata into central repositories.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="2025-02-14 09_52_52-data-product-model.drawio.svg - open-resource-discovery-specification - Visual S.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/225838i2574D60A1E3E6523/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-02-14 09_52_52-data-product-model.drawio.svg - open-resource-discovery-specification - Visual S.png" alt="2025-02-14 09_52_52-data-product-model.drawio.svg - open-resource-discovery-specification - Visual S.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In our model, the Data Product is a grouping concept that carries the relevant metadata to describe the dataset and its data qualities. A Data Product itself is not directly consumable, but it exposes data through output ports, which can be implemented as APIs or events. In the first iteration &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;of BDC, the primary Data Products expose a single output port as delta-sharing API. In principle, there can be multiple output ports of various API and/or event types. To understand data ingestion, lineage, and dependencies, Data Products can also have input ports which are the equivalent of an ORD Integration Dependency that lists the APIs and events that are used to ingest or process the data. Most of the concepts have relations to Entity Type, which represents business objects / domain objects / &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/harnessing-half-a-century-of-knowledge-sap-s-journey-of-enriching-apis-with/ba-p/13578364" target="_self"&gt;ODM&lt;/A&gt; entities&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;as semantic taxonomy terms business experts would understand.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Right now, SAP uses the ORD protocol to streamline our own discovery and publishing processes, most notably to the &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Accelerator+Hub/pd-p/73555000100800001091" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1214-1"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Technology+Platform/pd-p/73555000100700000172" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1215-1"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(BTP) System Landscape,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/build.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build&lt;/A&gt; and to the BDC Cockpit.&amp;nbsp; This all happens behind the scenes, so customers are not exposed to it and can benefit from a better integrated experience. However, in our partnership with &lt;A href="https://www.databricks.com/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Databricks&lt;/A&gt;, we also use the ORD protocol to connect the Databricks Unity Catalog with the Data Products provided by BDC as well as the other way around, retrieving Data Products created in Databricks into BDC. Leveraging ORD as an open metadata standard is a very important part of our partnership. We are looking forward to growing the ecosystem around ORD in our partnerships.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information about Data Products in ORD, have a look at the &lt;A href="https://open-resource-discovery.github.io/specification/spec-v1/concepts/data-product" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;ORD Data Product page&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1377240970"&gt;Data Product API / Data Model&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data Products exposed by SAP applications will use the industry-standard &lt;A href="https://github.com/delta-io/delta-sharing/blob/main/PROTOCOL.md" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Delta Sharing protocol&lt;/A&gt;, but customers will also be able to expose Data Products via other types of APIs. In Delta Sharing, the Delta Table metadata format provides the basics for wider ecosystem interoperability. For many of our use cases, we need even richer metadata – more semantics and a model that is closer to our existing metadata models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many SAP products already support the SAP-specific &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/cds/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Core Data Services&lt;/A&gt; (CDS) metamodel, which may also be known to our customers as the metadata format for ABAP (RAP) and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Cloud+Application+Programming+Model/pd-p/9f13aee1-834c-4105-8e43-ee442775e5ce" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="100-1"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(CAP). Since we invested in rich metadata in CDS models for many years (sometimes decades), it made sense to leverage it also for Data Products, preserving and transferring the rich metadata and semantics we often&lt;EM&gt;&lt;I&gt; already have&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As CDS models can be exported in the &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/cds/csn" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CSN&lt;/A&gt; format in many variants and flavors, we created a public specification that focuses on an interoperable, machine-consumption-optimized format: &lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/csn-interop-specification/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Core Schema Notation Interoperability Specification&lt;/A&gt; (CSN Interop).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With CSN Interop, we describe the API / data model of the Data Products output port. The most relevant aspects are that we describe entities&lt;SPAN&gt; (tables / objects) and elements (fields, properties). By assigning entities to a service, we define (or imply) the protocol and &lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/csn-interop-specification/mappings" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;mapping&lt;/A&gt; how they are exposed as an API with a concrete data serialization format.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="2025-02-14 09_54_13-high-level-model.drawio.svg - csn-interop-specification - Visual Studio Code.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/225840i63A055A549FDF399/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-02-14 09_54_13-high-level-model.drawio.svg - csn-interop-specification - Visual Studio Code.png" alt="2025-02-14 09_54_13-high-level-model.drawio.svg - csn-interop-specification - Visual Studio Code.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since the CSN format is not well known outside of the SAP ecosystem, here are some interesting aspects:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CSN is well suited to describe “conceptual” models, which are more abstract than, e.g., JSON Schema. The same CSN model can be exposed through different API protocols and data serialization formats (via assignment to a Service). It can also be used as a persistency model for the database. The core entity model in CSN is therefore agnostic of protocol and serialization format. The final API / data interface is then decided by the chosen &lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/csn-interop-specification/mappings" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;mapping&lt;/A&gt;. In the case of the Delta Sharing APIs, we defined a mapping to the &lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/csn-interop-specification/mappings/apache-spark" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Apache Spark&lt;/A&gt; type system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, CSN already has extensive &lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/csn-interop-specification/annotations" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;annotation&lt;/A&gt; vocabularies, which can carry a lot of additional information like business semantics (&lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/csn-interop-specification/annotations/semantics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@Semantics&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/csn-interop-specification/annotations/odm" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;@ODM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;), relationships, and metadata that improve the &lt;EM&gt;semantic onboarding&lt;/EM&gt; experience. This means that there is no need to rebuild a rich, semantic metamodel from scratch, because we can carry over the information.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, have a look at the &lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/csn-interop-specification/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;CSN Interop page&lt;/A&gt; and its &lt;A href="https://sap.github.io/csn-interop-specification/primer" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Primer&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1180727465"&gt;Future Direction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We plan to extend the current scope of the metadata standards and further improve the data product metadata with more annotations and better coverage. We want to establish ORD as a de facto industry standard, being an intrinsic piece of our open ecosystem approach similar as we use ORD as the solid foundation of our partnership with Databricks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;If you have questions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;feedback&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; or &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;just &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;want to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;get in touch with&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; us, feel free to reach out!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-metadata-behind-sap-data-products-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14016947"/>
    <published>2025-02-17T16:44:25.629000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/creating-and-managing-databasehits-at-your-project-level-for-audit-logs-in/ba-p/14019969</id>
    <title>Creating and Managing DatabaseHits at your project level for Audit Logs in Cloud HANA</title>
    <updated>2025-02-18T13:28:50.095000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shariqueali2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/190389</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In SAP HANA CockPit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Search for the Auditing Service&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-150px" style="padding-left : 150px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shariqueali2_0-1739949531143.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/227579i88F49C8A1A8A46C1/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shariqueali2_0-1739949531143.png" alt="shariqueali2_0-1739949531143.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creating the new "DatabaseHits" Audit Policy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Navigate to Audit Policies&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Within the "Auditing" section, select "Audit Policies."&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create New Policy&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click "Create" to start defining a new audit policy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="farihakazi_4-1739877080690.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/227042iECC2CE9E5A08BD82/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="farihakazi_4-1739877080690.png" alt="farihakazi_4-1739877080690.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Policy Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Enter DatabaseHits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Provide a meaningful description, such as "Audit policy to track database hits and accesses for my project."&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define Audit Conditions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SELECT, INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Object Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;: TABLE.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Object Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Specify specific tables/objects.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-120px" style="padding-left : 120px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="farihakazi_5-1739877270233.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/227043i92B2A3554EA882E7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="farihakazi_5-1739877270233.png" alt="farihakazi_5-1739877270233.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure Audit Trails&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Define the retention period for audit logs.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="farihakazi_7-1739877335383.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/227045i3A80CA928EB9DE35/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="farihakazi_7-1739877335383.png" alt="farihakazi_7-1739877335383.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the relevant schema after checking in DB explorer&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-90px" style="padding-left : 90px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="farihakazi_1-1739880020103.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/227055iF15BAAD6A318FC3B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="farihakazi_1-1739880020103.png" alt="farihakazi_1-1739880020103.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activate Policy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save the new audit policy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure the policy status is "Active.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;When you execute a query in DB explorer you can view the logs:&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="farihakazi_8-1739878700584.png" style="width: 712px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/227049i89F0D92E507494B4/image-dimensions/712x242?v=v2" width="712" height="242" role="button" title="farihakazi_8-1739878700584.png" alt="farihakazi_8-1739878700584.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;To integrate this logs in your Project - Create User and Role&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;CREATE USER ISUSUSER PASSWORD "Welcome1234" SET USERGROUP DEFAULT;

ALTER USER ISUSUSER DISABLE PASSWORD LIFETIME;

CREATE ROLE DBROLE;

GRANT SELECT, EXECUTE, SELECT METADATA ON SCHEMA "DBADMIN" TO DBROLE WITH GRANT OPTION;

GRANT DBROLE TO ISUSUSER WITH ADMIN OPTION;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bind the Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Use the Cloud Foundry CLI to create a user-provided service:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;cf cups DBCS_ACCESS -p "{\"user\":\"ISUSUSER\",\"password\":\"Welcome1234\",\"tags\":[\"hana\"],\"schema\":\"DBADMIN\"}"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Addition of grants file in project db/cfg path&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{

    "DBCS_ACCESS": {

      "object_owner" : {

        "roles" : ["DBROLE" ]

      },

      "application_user" : {

        "roles" : ["DBROLE" ]

      }

    }

  }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Addition of hdbsynonym file(audit_log.hdbsynonym) at db/src to expose the audit log table held in the Admin schema&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{

  "APP_INTERACTIONS_AUDIT_LOG": {

    "target": {

      "object": "AUDIT_LOG",

      "schema": "SYS"

    }

  }

}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Addition of the Audit_Log entity in .cds file with the annotation persistence.exists. Please refer to the screenshot below :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-120px" style="padding-left : 120px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="farihakazi_1-1739876911915.png" style="width: 444px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/227038i8275811D7B3E7690/image-dimensions/444x275?v=v2" width="444" height="275" role="button" title="farihakazi_1-1739876911915.png" alt="farihakazi_1-1739876911915.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finally exposing the entity as an ODATA service in the service catalog file interactions-srv.cds&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-120px" style="padding-left : 120px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="farihakazi_2-1739876951153.png" style="width: 440px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/227039iC51D1BC6E290842D/image-dimensions/440x273?v=v2" width="440" height="273" role="button" title="farihakazi_2-1739876951153.png" alt="farihakazi_2-1739876951153.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now this entity can be used in your UI application to view specific logs about your particular project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For e.g we created a Auditlog tile and used the oData :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="farihakazi_2-1739881125241.png" style="width: 692px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/227063i5F42EFB1BB575648/image-dimensions/692x215?v=v2" width="692" height="215" role="button" title="farihakazi_2-1739881125241.png" alt="farihakazi_2-1739881125241.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/creating-and-managing-databasehits-at-your-project-level-for-audit-logs-in/ba-p/14019969"/>
    <published>2025-02-18T13:28:50.095000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/capm-basics-part-1/ba-p/14024871</id>
    <title>CAPM Basics - Part 1</title>
    <updated>2025-02-23T13:09:40.402000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>archisman92</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/679180</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hello Colleagues,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below blog will guide you on how to create a basic CAP application and deploy the application to a persistent SQLite DB.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sign in to your global account and launch BAS from your instances and subscriptions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_1-1740285112842.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229001iF1E4361DD326E6E3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_1-1740285112842.png" alt="archisman92_1-1740285112842.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a new Dev Space and select a "Full Stack Cloud Application". This will pre-install the necessary extensions/libraries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_2-1740296326258.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229015iCD2ECD2FE906571E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_2-1740296326258.png" alt="archisman92_2-1740296326258.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your new Dev Space is now created. Launch it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_3-1740296557031.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229016i7BAD378F7552D46B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_3-1740296557031.png" alt="archisman92_3-1740296557031.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Browse to the "projects" directory of your Dev Space and open the same.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_4-1740296673826.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229017i2A5A5DC64CB5D8C9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_4-1740296673826.png" alt="archisman92_4-1740296673826.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Projects directory, create a new CAP project as shown below. Open terminal and use the command "cds init &amp;lt;project_name&amp;gt;". A sample CAP application with the pre-defined folder structure is created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_5-1740297697967.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229024i5F3D4B44E42F50B2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_5-1740297697967.png" alt="archisman92_5-1740297697967.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the "db" folder, create a file named "data-model.cds" and paste the contents as below. This creates the entity "trainer" in the namespace "training".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_6-1740298293004.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229057iD88670165351383A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_6-1740298293004.png" alt="archisman92_6-1740298293004.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;namespace training;

using {cuid} from '@sap/cds/common';

define entity trainer : cuid {
    name        : String;
    location    : String;
    designation : String

}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the "srv" folder, create a file named "services.cds". This creates a OData V4 service exposes the entity as a view/projection.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_7-1740300921751.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229060iF93C1D5837DC5EC3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_7-1740300921751.png" alt="archisman92_7-1740300921751.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;using training as db from '../db/data-model';

@path: 'MyService'
service CatalogService {
    entity trainers  as projection on db.trainer;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use "cds add data" to add data feature to your project. This will be the sample mock data for testing our application in development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_8-1740301452353.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229063i4C2A61B22ADC0A54/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_8-1740301452353.png" alt="archisman92_8-1740301452353.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add some sample data to the csv file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_9-1740301584913.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229064iF547E251B8E8124B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_9-1740301584913.png" alt="archisman92_9-1740301584913.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the terminal, run "cds watch" and observe the logs. Our mock data is loaded from the csv file and deployed to in-memory database. This is the default configuration in CAP. Run the application by clicking on the highlighted URL.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_10-1740303431092.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229065i9A3CFB218C3AE80E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_10-1740303431092.png" alt="archisman92_10-1740303431092.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The default HTML page of your CAP application loads up. Click on the entity "trainers". A "GET" request is fired to fetch the data for the same entity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_11-1740307187505.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229073i79B2FAE1834952FD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_11-1740307187505.png" alt="archisman92_11-1740307187505.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_12-1740307605428.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229078i8928031B40616318/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_12-1740307605428.png" alt="archisman92_12-1740307605428.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now return to your CAP application, and create a "test.http" file in the root of your project as shown below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_13-1740307950144.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229080i183238F1CCFEEC59/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="archisman92_13-1740307950144.png" alt="archisman92_13-1740307950144.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Write a GET request as shown below and execute the same.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_14-1740309208136.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229082i04E5A4F55328E0AF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_14-1740309208136.png" alt="archisman92_14-1740309208136.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now write a POST request and execute the same. Hit the "GET all records" request again. Observe a new record is created with a guid assigned by CAP. This is because we used a &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/cds/common#aspect-cuid" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;cuid&lt;/A&gt; aspect for our entity which assigns a unique primary key to our entity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_15-1740309329200.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229083i3600AA231A48E78B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_15-1740309329200.png" alt="archisman92_15-1740309329200.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_16-1740309649397.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229084iA8C14523C0D613EE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_16-1740309649397.png" alt="archisman92_16-1740309649397.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now stop your CAP application (hit CTRL+C in your terminal), start it again (execute cds watch in your terminal) and execute the above "GET all records" once more. What happens? We only get the records from our csv file. The record that we posted in the previous step is lost. This is because we are using a default in-memory database (ephemeral database) as observed from our logs previously.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_17-1740309826780.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229085iD76AED4AFE75644A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_17-1740309826780.png" alt="archisman92_17-1740309826780.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To "fix" this, we will now shift to a persistent SQLite DB. To make CAP understand that we want to use a persistent DB instead of a in-memory DB, add the following lines in your package.json file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{ "cds": { "requires": {
   "db": {
      "kind": "sqlite",
      "credentials": { "url": "db.sqlite" } 
   }
}}}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_18-1740310418442.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229086iEEEE82EC9157FA2A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_18-1740310418442.png" alt="archisman92_18-1740310418442.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now execute the command "cds deploy --to sqlite" as shown below. A new file db.sqlite is created which is now our local persistent DB.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_19-1740310751096.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229087i05E06BD7B0C43572/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_19-1740310751096.png" alt="archisman92_19-1740310751096.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Execute "cds watch" to start the application again. Observe the logs. The application is now connected to our persistent SQLite DB instead of in-memory database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_20-1740311093777.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229089i629786A2C321B374/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_20-1740311093777.png" alt="archisman92_20-1740311093777.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now POST a new record, stop the application, start the application again and execute the "GET all records" request. What do you observe? The record that was posted is persisted even after restarting the application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_21-1740311337600.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229092i36C536536AFF12DB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_21-1740311337600.png" alt="archisman92_21-1740311337600.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_22-1740311405155.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229094i92B8DAC38EDEF530/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_22-1740311405155.png" alt="archisman92_22-1740311405155.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="archisman92_23-1740311596475.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/229095i360F91350EDF072F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="archisman92_23-1740311596475.png" alt="archisman92_23-1740311596475.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So now you have a fully capable CRUD application service with very minimum development. If you have any questions, please feel free to comment below.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/capm-basics-part-1/ba-p/14024871"/>
    <published>2025-02-23T13:09:40.402000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-btp-cloud-application-programming-model/ba-p/14032929</id>
    <title>SAP BTP: Cloud Application Programming Model</title>
    <updated>2025-03-04T07:09:41.141000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SekhuteTK</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15314</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming (CAP) Model exposes the ability to extend standard Cloud, on-premises and hybrid application functionality with flexible custom business logic scripted using the developer’s choice of programing language (SQL, SQL Script, Python, Node.js and JavaScript) and exposing the functionality to various user interfaces (UIs) e.g. Microsoft Power Bi, SAP Fiori, Dataiku and Google Big Query using various integration frameworks e.g. OData v4,JDBC/ODBC depending on the case study.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The developer takes pride in delivering a scalable extended functionality, embedding robust real-time monitoring capabilities to ensure a health life cycle and protecting the functionality with secure authentication protocols e.g. OAuth 2.0, JWT Bearer, SAML version 2.0 and RFC Specification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Furthermore, the developer ensures a reliable and robust solutions by implementing continuous integration and continuous delivery CI/CD pipelines that automates testing, building and deployment of code changes this strategy ensures a speedy development and delivery cycle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditionally developers extended business logic directly on-premises on the ABAP application server. With the ever-changing world of technology, digital transformation has become essential for organization to say afloat of competitors and therefore the programming model paradigms and capabilities of extending SAP solutions have evolved drastically and provides a seamless experience into the cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Programming model.png" style="width: 626px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/232631i560CE0B01EB4E6CB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Programming model.png" alt="Programming model.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 1: &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Architectural Paradigm Shift from Classic ABAP App server to CAP App server&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Source: Thomas Jung, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/sap-hana-extended-application-services/ba-p/12963426" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Extended Application Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; blog, URL: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/sap-hana-extended-application-services/ba-p/12963426/page/4" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/sap-hana-extended-application-services/ba-p/12963426/page/4&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;The SAP Cloud Application model comes with a rich set of languages, libraries, and tools for building enterprise-grade services and applications. It guides developers along a 'golden path' of proven&amp;nbsp;best practices&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;and a great wealth of&amp;nbsp;out-of-the-box solutions&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;to recurring tasks:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="cap.png" style="width: 626px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/232633i1EC9379A4BB0DAA1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="cap.png" alt="cap.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 2: &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Cloud Application Model Architecture&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Source &lt;A href="HTTPS://Cap.cloud.sap" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;HTTPS://Cap.cloud.sap&lt;/A&gt; , U&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;RL:&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/about/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/about/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The below diagram categories the skill set of SAP Cloud Developer based on the scope of the development either being ABAP or Non-ABAP. Each with its unique set of tools and methodologies:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ABAP VS NON.png" style="width: 626px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/232635i61C63058B7D72485/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ABAP VS NON.png" alt="ABAP VS NON.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 3:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Cloud Developer skill set&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Source: Building side-by-side extensions on SAP BTP, URL: &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/build-side-by-side-extensions-on-sap-btp/identifying-the-need-for-side-by-side-extensibility_f1e838f0-f02a-43b4-8896-cedc25a7d5d0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/build-side-by-side-extensions-on-sap-btp/identifying-the-need-for-side-by-side-extensibility_f1e838f0-f02a-43b4-8896-cedc25a7d5d0&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Cloud Application Programming model enables a collaboration of agile cross functional teams inclusive of but not limited, depending on the scope of the development: &amp;nbsp;citizen developers (low-code/no-code), Professional developers (Scripting, OOP), business analysts, data engineers and application specialists to model robust data models:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Cross functional.png" style="width: 626px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/232636i237D8D5BBD7CB069/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Cross functional.png" alt="Cross functional.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 4:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Agile cross functional team&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Source: &lt;STRONG&gt;Investigating the Impact of Cross-Functional Teams on Business Success&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;URL:&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.iienstitu.com/en/blog/cross-functional-teams" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.iienstitu.com/en/blog/cross-functional-teams&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming (CAP) Model enables a culture where people regardless of their title or background, work together to imagine, develop, deploy, and operate a solution. This strengthens the trust between employees and authentic healthy work relationships.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you all for taking a glimpse into the above Content. Please don’t for get to like, comment and share.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Abbreviations:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;APP: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Application&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CAP: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cloud Application Programing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CDS&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Core Data Services&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CI/CD:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;JWT&lt;/STRONG&gt;: JSON Web token&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OData: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Open Data Protocol&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RFC&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Remote Function Call&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAML&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Security Assertion Markup Language&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SQL:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Structured Query Language&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UIs:&lt;/STRONG&gt; User Interfaces&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-btp-cloud-application-programming-model/ba-p/14032929"/>
    <published>2025-03-04T07:09:41.141000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/hilal-kurt/ba-p/14060265</id>
    <title>Hilal Kurt</title>
    <updated>2025-03-28T16:01:19.774000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KatherineKenneally</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/328</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/162742" target="_blank"&gt;More about Hilal Kurt in SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Hilal Kurt circular 1.png" style="width: 186px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/244277iD53BC8711D0988BB/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Hilal Kurt circular 1.png" alt="Hilal Kurt circular 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;First Name, Last Name: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Hilal Kurt&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Location (City, Country): &lt;/STRONG&gt;Istanbul, Turkey&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Occupation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Sr. MM Consultant&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="People_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51216i6B6C3041A74CC074/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="People_pictogram.png" alt="People_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Hilal, tell us about yourself.&lt;BR /&gt;Who are you, what do you like to do, what is important to you?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hi there! As an SAP MM consultant, I have worked on various projects both domestically and internationally, providing process consultancy. I have a strong interest in new SAP products, especially SAP ALM, Joule, and cloud solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Being an active member of the SAP Community, I am passionate about organizing events and strengthening the SAP ecosystem. Contributing to SAP Inside Track, CodeJam and similar events excites me, as I love sharing knowledge and engaging with the community.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Outside of work, I have been actively practicing sports and yoga for many years. I believe maintaining both mental and physical balance has a positive impact on professional life. I continue to learn, share, and grow together with the SAP Community!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Desktop_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51217iF7FFD39907D24E76/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="Desktop_pictogram.png" alt="Desktop_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What is your area of expertise?&lt;BR /&gt;What does a usual day at work look like for you?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an SAP MM consultant, I specialize in sourcing and procurement and inventory management processes. Throughout my career, I have worked on both domestic and international projects, focusing on process optimization and system implementations. My expertise extends to SAP ALM, Joule, and cloud solutions, where I explore innovative ways to enhance business processes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A typical day for me involves analyzing business requirements, configuring SAP solutions, and collaborating with teams to ensure smooth operations. I spend time troubleshooting issues, optimizing workflows, and keeping up with the latest SAP innovations. Beyond project work, I actively contribute to the SAP Community, organize events, and engage in knowledge sharing to foster a collaborative learning environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="inspiration_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51218i2605363EFF68DD34/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="inspiration_pictogram.png" alt="inspiration_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What inspired you to become an SAP Champion in SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bringing people together, organizing events, and encouraging others to explore new things as a community has always been a passion of mine. This is not just something I do in my professional life, but also an integral part of my daily life. I strongly believe that those working within the SAP ecosystem must continuously adapt to emerging technologies. The ever-evolving solutions, new business models, and constantly changing processes keep us dynamic and energized.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP plays a significant role in our lives, and for me, being able to integrate what I love doing outside of work into my professional life is incredibly motivating. I truly love my job because SAP is such a dynamic industry where we encounter diverse and unique business cases every day. Each new case presents an opportunity to learn and grow, making the journey both exciting and rewarding.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is why I find the "pay it forward, pay it back" philosophy so valuable. I believe that fostering a culture of knowledge sharing within the SAP Community is essential for collective growth. Becoming an SAP Champion allows me to contribute to this vision by sharing my expertise, inspiring others, and strengthening our ecosystem. It’s not just about learning, it's about empowering others, creating opportunities for collaboration, and growing together as a community. That’s what makes this journey truly meaningful for me.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="bullet_list_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51219i2905480F1FCC6AE2/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="bullet_list_pictogram.png" alt="bullet_list_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;How do you learn in SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is your daily/weekly routine in SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I first discovered SAP Community when I started my career. While working on business processes, I often encountered errors and began searching for solutions. I found that the shared experiences and insights in SAP Community blogs provided valuable information. This process helped me realize that SAP Community is not just a knowledge base but also a collaborative learning environment where professionals share their experiences.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My learning process in SAP Community involves actively following forums and exploring new content related to my areas of interest. I focus on SAP MM, ALM, Joule, and cloud solutions, staying up to date with the latest developments. Since the SAP ecosystem is constantly evolving, exchanging ideas with other professionals and sharing best practices is a great way for me to learn.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of my daily routine, I read SAP Community blogs and forums to stay informed about current topics. On a weekly basis, I make sure to read SAP blogs and documentation to keep up with the latest updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="circles_pictogram.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51220i73C820D745D17725/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="circles_pictogram.png" alt="circles_pictogram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is your suggestion to get the most out of SAP Community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To get the most out of SAP Community, being an active participant is essential. Instead of just reading content, asking questions, engaging in discussions, and sharing your experiences helps you build a stronger connection within the community.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, following the right resources makes a significant difference. Regularly exploring SAP blogs, documentation, and forums ensures that you stay up to date with the latest information and continuously improve your knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another key aspect is attending events and building a professional network within the community. Participating in events like SAP Inside Track allows you to gain new insights and connect with other professionals in the industry. I also contribute by organizing community events and sharing content to help grow the SAP ecosystem.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lastly, SAP Community thrives on a culture of knowledge sharing. By embracing the "pay it forward" mindset, sharing what you learn and supporting others in their growth, you contribute to making the community even stronger. The more we share, the more we learn!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Arrow_pictogramm_new.png" style="width: 87px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/51221i1EA57128883E9979/image-dimensions/87x87?v=v2" width="87" height="87" role="button" title="Arrow_pictogramm_new.png" alt="Arrow_pictogramm_new.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hilal's question to you:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI is becoming an important part of modern enterprise solutions, including SAP. How do you see AI transforming supply chain, procurement, and enterprise resource planning in SAP over the next few years? What challenges and opportunities do you foresee in integrating AI-driven automation into sourcing and procurement and ALM processes?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/hilal-kurt/ba-p/14060265"/>
    <published>2025-03-28T16:01:19.774000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/new-customer-story-from-westwood/ba-p/14084557</id>
    <title>New customer story from Westwood</title>
    <updated>2025-04-23T13:51:46.432000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nadine_mildenberger</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/288742</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;It's always great to hear how customers are using the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition with the integrated product compliance solution to enable them to automate product safety workflows and help support international business growth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See the full Westwood story &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2025/03/d4d883b1-fd7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="See Westwood's story!" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/254081i7093520899A633B0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="WestWood Kunststofftechnik_social card_approved (1).jpg" alt="See Westwood's story!" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;See Westwood's story!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/new-customer-story-from-westwood/ba-p/14084557"/>
    <published>2025-04-23T13:51:46.432000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-retail-blogs/grow-with-sap-for-retail-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-retail-fashion/ba-p/14088617</id>
    <title>Grow with SAP for Retail: SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition retail, fashion, and vertical business</title>
    <updated>2025-05-05T09:29:33.331000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>annette_weidler</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/348580</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The evolution of SAP's retail systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Having dedicated 30 years to SAP and the retail industry, I have had the privilege of witnessing the remarkable evolution of SAP's retail systems. From the first version specifically designed for retail in a ECC system to the continuous improvements over the years, culminating in the sophisticated cloud private edition for retailers, the journey has been extraordinary. And with this cloud private edition, we are still not at the end of this evolution!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Begin of 2025, SAP proudly introduced the Retail Industry version of our multi-tenant SaaS ERP solution (general availability). This advanced system goes beyond the fundamentals of finance, procurement, and warehouse management to include specialized features such as store management, pricing, promotions, replenishment, allocations, and more. These processes are tailored to the retail sector, drawing on SAP's 50 years of experience collaborating with the world's leading retailers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/retail-fashion-and-vertical-business-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/13999385" target="_blank"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, retail, fashion, and vertical business&lt;/A&gt; empowers small and medium-sized enterprises to drive business growth and foster innovation. By standardizing retail-specific processes, this modern, agile, and scalable cloud ERP solution ensures the fastest time to value and the lowest total cost of ownership.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In simple terms, it’s a platform that allows retailers to focus on what they do best: delighting their customers. In an age where customer experience defines success, maintaining this focus is essential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Are&amp;nbsp;you ready to transform your retail business across the value chain?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Retailers are confronted with three significant challenges: consumers seeking personalized and instant experiences, competitors utilizing technology to drive innovation, and supply chains strained by global uncertainties. Within this crucible of challenges, I believe that Grow with SAP for Retail emerges as an essential lifeline for the contemporary retailer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, retail, fashion, and vertical business is, at its heart, a holistic cloud ERP solution tailored to the demands of retail businesses. Its goal is to empower retailers to thrive in times of disruption. This solution facilitates the streamlining of business processes, effective data utilization, and flexible scaling.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;How could it look like in practice? Let's explore some key aspects of this solution together&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;To provide a clearer picture, we will step into the shoes of different employees in a retail company and explore their unique challenges, needs, and how they gain advantages from SAP's Public Cloud. Moreover, I will share some example screenshots as a teaser to further illustrate this (the content was built by SAP and demonstrated on &lt;A class="" href="https://news.sap.com/2025/01/sap-nrf-2025-retail-public-cloud-erp-ai-shopping-assistant/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;NRF 2025&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Melanie, the Procurement Specialist&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Melanie, a Procurement Specialist, plays a key role in ensuring the profitability and customer satisfaction of her store by selecting the right products, negotiating prices, and keeping purchases within budget. She relies on sales data to identify products that are in demand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;However, her role comes with several challenges such as errors from manual data entry which lead to inaccuracies, disorganized vendor information increasing costs, limited visibility affecting inventory management, and difficulty in monitoring in-store customer demand for more accurate and timely decisions on stock replenishment and procurement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;To effectively manage these challenges, Melanie needs tools and strategies that allow her to monitor stock levels, assess product performance, handle delivery performance, manage supplier contracts, and analyze sales data for forecasting demand. Implementing solutions like setting automatic reorder points, optimizing purchase orders, and strategies to prevent stock-outs can maximize sales and enhance customer satisfaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Utilizing SAP Cloud Public Edition tailored for retail can significantly support Melanie in her role. SAP can help optimize inventory levels, reduce carrying costs through accurate sales forecasting, streamline invoice processing for better supplier compliance, and provide built-in tools for communication and approvals. This streamlines the entire purchasing process, making it more efficient and effective in meeting both the store's and customers' needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="(The procurement overview dashboard of Procurement Specialist Melanie provides pre-built reports, easy access to precise data)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255959iC732039A0987D8DA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-03-26 145844.png" alt="(The procurement overview dashboard of Procurement Specialist Melanie provides pre-built reports, easy access to precise data)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;(The procurement overview dashboard of Procurement Specialist Melanie provides pre-built reports, easy access to precise data)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="(The machine learning model for predicting delivery dates utilizes the company's data, incorporating factors such as transportation method, lead time, vendor history, and weather conditions)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255965i6019648A179FEFA0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-03-26 145954.png" alt="(The machine learning model for predicting delivery dates utilizes the company's data, incorporating factors such as transportation method, lead time, vendor history, and weather conditions)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;(The machine learning model for predicting delivery dates utilizes the company's data, incorporating factors such as transportation method, lead time, vendor history, and weather conditions)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Phil, the Store Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Phil, as the Store Manager, holds the responsibility for the store's smooth operation. He is dedicated to achieving sales targets, maintaining customer satisfaction, and effectively managing his team. His role encompasses strategic planning, team leadership, and operational know-how to propel the store towards success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;However, Phil faces a set of challenges that include balancing inventory to align with customer demands while also minimizing carrying costs, contending with slow restocking processes which can result in empty shelves and lost sales, and dealing with operational inefficiencies that create bottlenecks, impair productivity, and cause delays.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;To address these challenges, Phil's strategy requires developing and implementing methods to meet sales goals and enhance profitability, managing inventory levels to prevent stock-outs and ensure product availability, getting a clear perspective on short-term and long-term promotional activities, and using customer data to personalize recommendations and promotions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Utilizing the SAP Cloud Public Edition tailored for retail, Phil can gain a suite of benefits to streamline operations and boost efficiency. This includes integrated data facilitating quicker decision-making processes across sales, inventory, and customer operations; enhanced real-time collaboration with local suppliers, which helps in improving lead times and reducing restocking delays; and omnichannel integration that guarantees a consistent customer experience and synchronized inventory management across all platforms. This comprehensive approach not only aids in tackling existing challenges but also positions the store for lasting success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="(Phil opens his store overview page which gives him a snapshot of his daily store operations briefly)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255968i3FB2D34779CA5610/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-04-28 131335.png" alt="(Phil opens his store overview page which gives him a snapshot of his daily store operations briefly)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;(Phil opens his store overview page which gives him a snapshot of his daily store operations briefly)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="(Demand Forecast Run shows the expected demand for the coming weeks including seasonality)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255970i4102F22825CFD3A5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-03-26 164318.png" alt="(Demand Forecast Run shows the expected demand for the coming weeks including seasonality)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;(Demand Forecast Run shows the expected demand for the coming weeks including seasonality)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sarah, the Store Associate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sarah is a dedicated Store Associate with a flair for customer service and teamwork. She helps customers find the right products and ensures smooth transactions through the point-of-sale system. Her duties extend beyond the counter, as she restocks shelves, crafts appealing displays, and double-checks that price tags reflect current offers. The harmony and satisfaction in her workplace motivate her to contribute actively to the store's success, aiming to provide every customer with a pleasant shopping journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Despite her enthusiasm, Sarah faces several hurdles in her day-to-day operations. Inventory management can be sluggish and imprecise, leading to situations where products are either unavailable or unnecessarily abundant. This misalignment can make product location cumbersome and detract from customer satisfaction. Additionally, inefficient checkout processes can cause delays, leaving customers feeling frustrated. Her current tools also limit her ability to access insightful data, making it harder to make informed decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;With SAP Cloud Public Edition tailored for retail, Sarah's workflow can be optimized, leading to greater productivity.&amp;nbsp;Improved in-store pickup processes minimize revenue loss, ensuring customers receive their orders promptly. Real-time visibility into stock levels empowers her to update customers accurately, fostering trust and satisfaction. Optimized inventory management reduces unnecessary carrying costs, while smart restocking based on actual sales keeps shelves perfectly stocked.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;By integrating smart technology, Sarah can overcome her hurdles and elevate both her efficiency and customer satisfaction. Better inventory tracking, streamlined transactions, and comprehensive reporting provide Sarah with the tools she needs to thrive in her role. With SAP, she gains more control over her processes, fulfilling her responsibilities with newfound ease and confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="(BOPIS enables store associates like Sarah to prepare online orders for fast, convenient in-store pickup)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255976i7C10FF6CE9286445/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-04-28 131904.png" alt="(BOPIS enables store associates like Sarah to prepare online orders for fast, convenient in-store pickup)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;(BOPIS enables store associates like Sarah to prepare online orders for fast, convenient in-store pickup)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Natalie, the Chief Financial Officer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;CFO Natalie is responsible for monitoring the financial health of the company. Her primary role includes developing strategies to enhance profitability and sustain long-term growth while managing potential risks. She is also tasked with leading the financial reporting to provide precise insights into the company's performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;To effectively fulfill her duties, Natalie requires tools that offer real-time financial insights for accurate reporting and decision-making. She also needs integrated financial and operational data to gain a holistic view of business performance, scalable financial management to support operations across multiple locations seamlessly, and automated tools for compliance and tax reporting to minimize manual labor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;However, she faces challenges such as delayed strategic decisions caused by inadequate financial visibility, limited scalability which results in bottlenecks, time-consuming and error-prone consolidation processes, and a lack of real-time performance insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;By utilizing SAP Cloud Public Edition tailored for retail, Natalie can benefit significantly. SAP provides agile, real-time management with personalized dashboards, reports, and key performance indicators, enabling faster financial closings and smoother group reporting. Moreover, predictive analytics in SAP help with better cash flow management, budgeting, and profitability forecasting. Additionally, SAP's flexible, cloud-based financial management solutions scale with business growth and support omnichannel operations, overcoming previous limitations and driving efficiency in financial operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="(Example of a unified view of financial performance by product and merchandise category)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255978iFD5191F1DC6F1EC9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-03-26 171508.png" alt="(Example of a unified view of financial performance by product and merchandise category)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;(Example of a unified view of financial performance by product and merchandise category)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Takeaways&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/retail-fashion-and-vertical-business-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/13999385" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, retail, fashion, and vertical business&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; offers significant benefits for retailers of small and medium sizes. This user-friendly software delivers a clear return on investment by providing ready-to-use industry best practices. It enables cost-effective implementations and minimal capital investments, supporting retailers' growth objectives. The state-of-the-art Software-as-a-Service model ensures a seamless cloud experience with the convenience of a fully managed solution and easy onboarding, allowing retailers to focus on their core business activities and customer satisfaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Further Reading&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A great solution experience is SAP's innovative S.Mart Store in Walldorf! This cutting-edge shopping destination is redefining retail with the powerful combination of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, retail, fashion, and vertical business solutions, along with additional SAP and partner technologies. Check out this blog to learn more about it: &lt;A class="" href="https://blogs.one.int.sap/sapnews_en/2025/04/s-mart-store-an-innovative-shopping-experience/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;S.Mart Store in Walldorf, it delivers an innovating shopping experience&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;You are SAP Partner and interested in more information?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":double_exclamation_mark:"&gt;‼️&lt;/span&gt;SAP partners can discover valuable information on this dedicated SAP Partner Page:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/products/s4hanacld/public-edition/about/sap-s-4hana-cloud-solution-for-retail.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Explore SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, retail, fashion, and vertical business&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":double_exclamation_mark:"&gt;‼️&lt;/span&gt;The four personas I presented to you are integral to this &lt;A href="https://ivj-vx.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/journey/71d1384f-e656-4509-8dd2-7f411d4dac09/intro" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Interactive Value Journey&lt;/A&gt;. Please enter to view the complete E2E offline demo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-retail-blogs/grow-with-sap-for-retail-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-retail-fashion/ba-p/14088617"/>
    <published>2025-05-05T09:29:33.331000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/clean-core-as-foundation-for-your-cloud-journey/ba-p/14096608</id>
    <title>Clean Core as Foundation for Your Cloud Journey</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T23:32:26.016000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Michael_Blaschke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1822449</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At the DSAG Technology Days 2025 in Wiesbaden, I had the privilege of presenting alongside &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/234913"&gt;@michael_sokollek&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1579298"&gt;@Tobi_F&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Tobias Fischer) on &lt;STRONG&gt;“Clean Core as Foundation for Your Cloud Journey.”&lt;/STRONG&gt; The enthusiastic engagement from the DSAG&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="#_ftn1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;[1]&lt;/A&gt; community—representing over 4,000 companies across the DACH region—affirmed the relevance and timeliness of our enterprise architecture approach to cloud transformation. The presentation followed &lt;STRONG&gt;why, what, and how sections&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Michael_Blaschke_0-1746718653365.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/258875i3E2607457DCE0874/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Michael_Blaschke_0-1746718653365.jpeg" alt="Michael_Blaschke_0-1746718653365.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1581139637"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;WHY Clean Core is the Foundation for Cloud Success&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our presentation emphasized that a clean core is not merely a technical objective but a strategic imperative for sustainable innovation:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Continuous innovation enablement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Clean core systematically removes barriers to new software capabilities, allowing organizations to adopt emerging technologies and features&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Process agility through standardization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Companies operating with standardized systems consistently demonstrate superior process agility, underpinned by higher data quality and streamlined operations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reduced complexity and costs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: The clean core approach significantly reduces the complexity and costs associated with upgrades, maintenance, and overall system management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Strategic S/4HANA transformation foundation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: As an ongoing strategic activity rather than a one-time effort, clean core provides the essential groundwork for successful S/4HANA transformation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The audience response was particularly strong when we showcased the correlation between clean core principles and measurable business outcomes. As one CIO from a mid-sized manufacturing company commented: “We’ve been approaching modernization backward—focusing on features first rather than foundation.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Michael_Blaschke_1-1746718653387.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/258876i6335FE65D9C199D5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Michael_Blaschke_1-1746718653387.jpeg" alt="Michael_Blaschke_1-1746718653387.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1384626132"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;WHAT Our EA-RISE Framework Delivers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We explained how our enterprise architecture approach within RISE with SAP delivers comprehensive support throughout the transformation journey:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Structured implementation guidance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: RISE-EA provides clear pathways through established methods and pre-configured SAP solutions, eliminating guesswork and reducing implementation risk&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Complexity transformation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: The framework transforms architectural complexity into clear business insights, enabling effective decision-making at both strategic and operational levels&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerated cloud adoption&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: By providing specialized reference architectures, we create accelerated pathways for cloud adoption tailored to industry-specific needs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Strategic alignment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: RISE-EA ensures continuous alignment between business objectives and IT implementation across the entire journey, preventing drift between strategic intent and execution&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The detailed exploration of greenfield versus brownfield strategies resonated strongly with attendees facing these decisions, particularly our differentiation between “keep clean” strategies for new implementations and “make clean” approaches for system conversions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Michael_Blaschke_2-1746718653410.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/258877i8236D37E2F856B27/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Michael_Blaschke_2-1746718653410.jpeg" alt="Michael_Blaschke_2-1746718653410.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1188112627"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;HOW SAP’s Toolchain Supports Implementation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The demonstration section of our presentation showcased the practical implementation of clean core principles through:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrated planning ecosystem&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: SAP’s toolchain enables seamless planning from Enterprise Architecture Management (EAM) to Business Process Management (BPM), providing end-to-end visibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Collaborative modeling&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Process analysis fosters stakeholder alignment through structured modeling and governance frameworks that bring business and IT perspectives together&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Implementation standardization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Reference architectures establish consistent solution deployment standards, reducing variability and accelerating implementation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Continuous optimization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: The framework enables sustainable optimization across all five clean core dimensions (Extensibility, Data, Integrations, Processes, Operations) through structured feedback loops&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our live demonstration of the Clean Core Scoring Framework, including performance KPIs and governance maturity assessments, provided attendees with tangible tools to measure their progress toward clean core objectives.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-991599122"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Impact and Response&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The session attracted a diverse audience ranging from mid-sized business process owners to CIOs. The engagement level—particularly during our exploration of process deviation management practices—highlighted the DSAG community’s commitment to moving beyond technical approaches to embrace architectural thinking.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Several attendees approached us afterward to discuss how they could apply our five clean core principles within their specific transformation journeys. The most frequent questions concerned practical governance approaches for maintaining clean core principles in organizations with multiple business units and diverse process owners.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For colleagues who missed the session, the presentation materials are available below. I welcome further conversations about how we can apply these principles with your customers to accelerate their cloud journeys while establishing sustainable architectural foundations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Special thanks to Michael Sokollek and Tobias Fischer for their excellent collaboration, and to the DSAG organization for providing this platform to showcase SAP’s thought leadership in enterprise architecture.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;by Dr. Michael R. Blaschke&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="#_ftnref1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; The DSAG is one of the most influential SAP user associations in the world. Many dedicated members from over 4,000 companies form a strong network: from medium-sized businesses to DAX-listed corporations, from the specialist department to the CxO level, across all industries, in Germany, Austria, and Switzerland (DACH). The user association is organized into 200 working groups and committees.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/clean-core-as-foundation-for-your-cloud-journey/ba-p/14096608"/>
    <published>2025-05-15T23:32:26.016000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-application-programming-model-cap-customer-roundtable-june-2025/ba-p/14103224</id>
    <title>SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP) | Customer Roundtable | June 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T10:27:51.756000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TheSebastian</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/142742</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1730446659"&gt;Update: Slides &amp;amp; Recording&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/resources/events/SAP_CAP_Roundtable_June_2025.pdf" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Slides&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1HOA4neAj8HozB8-QCE-6blRv4c6I24Nk/view?usp=sharing" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Recording&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1533933154"&gt;Customer Roundtable&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;It's been some time since the last &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP Customer &amp;amp; Partner Roundtable&lt;/STRONG&gt;, so it's time for a new edition before our highlight of the year - &lt;A href="https://recap-conf.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;re&amp;gt;≡CAP 2025&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;in July.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As always we will go for a mix of recent announcements, demo, presentations as well as topics and questions raised by the CAP community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do you have CAP related insights, requirements, issues, challenges, topics… that you would like to share and discuss in the upcoming meeting?&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If yes, please reach-out to us so that we can add it to the agenda.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="CAP_Roundtable.png" style="width: 734px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261956i19B673F3858FB90E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="CAP_Roundtable.png" alt="CAP_Roundtable.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1337419649"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Agenda&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://recap-conf.dev/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;re&amp;gt;≡CAP&lt;/A&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;A href="https://code-connect.dev/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Code Connect&lt;/A&gt; 2025&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://recap-conf.dev/program.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Agenda&lt;/A&gt; is released!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Updates from CAP Team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CAP's new major release&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Improved UX with Draft Messages - Marc Becker&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fiori Tree Tables - David Kunz, Olena Timrova&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New CAP license - Michael Hellenschmidt, Sebastian Schmidt&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Task Queues (sneak peek) - David Kunz&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q&amp;amp;A / Topics by the Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1140906144"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Meeting Information&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;When:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Wednesday,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;June 04th&lt;/STRONG&gt;, 2025, 11 AM EST | 5 PM CE(S)T&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://teams.microsoft.com/l/meetup-join/19%3ameeting_MjhlMDRhZTAtOWEyYi00MzJmLThmOGItMDBkM2Q3YzY0Njhl%40thread.v2/0?context=%7b%22Tid%22%3a%2242f7676c-f455-423c-82f6-dc2d99791af7%22%2c%22Oid%22%3a%223d4d6882-45a1-41ce-9418-35a35744348f%22%7d" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Teams Meeting&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meeting Request Download&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/resources/events/CAP_Customer_Roundtable_June_2025.ics" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;link&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All interested&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;partners and stakeholders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;are invited to join: developers, enterprise architects, technical consultants…&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Anyone interested&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;in learning about the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and exchange your ideas and feedback with other users and the product team&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to seeing you there!&lt;BR /&gt;Check also out the new&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/resources/events" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Events&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;page in our&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and our&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/cloud-application-programming" target="_blank"&gt;Community page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for updates on upcoming events.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-application-programming-model-cap-customer-roundtable-june-2025/ba-p/14103224"/>
    <published>2025-05-16T10:27:51.756000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-heart-of-transformation-people-process-and-persistence/ba-p/14124154</id>
    <title>The Heart of Transformation: People, Process, and Persistence</title>
    <updated>2025-06-10T18:00:00.024000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Friederike</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46254</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H6 id="toc-hId--2046313796"&gt;(Blog 1 of the “Transformation in Field Service” series)&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1664891838"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we hear the word &lt;EM&gt;transformation&lt;/EM&gt;, our minds often jump to technology—shiny new tools, artificial intelligence, mobile apps, cloud platforms. But in my experience working in Field Service—and as a parent, gardener, and lifelong learner—I’ve found that successful transformation isn’t just digital.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s deeply human.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="282666_low_shutterstock_540575332.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/272481i5479649F6CD9BFED/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="282666_low_shutterstock_540575332.jpg" alt="282666_low_shutterstock_540575332.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1468378333"&gt;The Family Trip That Almost Didn’t Happen&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A few weekends ago, we planned a “short” hike as a family. With a three-year-old and a four-year-old in tow, I expected some negotiation. One wanted to stay and build a fort in the living room. The other had already left the house wielding a stick like an explorer on a mission. My partner and I were somewhere in the middle—juggling snacks, sunhats, and our sanity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What made the hike possible wasn’t the gear or the route. It was &lt;STRONG&gt;alignment, motivation, and compromise&lt;/STRONG&gt;. We adjusted expectations. Built excitement. Let the kids help plan the snack break. And eventually, we all made it to the top—tired, proud, and a little muddy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Honestly? That’s what transformation looks like.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1271864828"&gt;What It Means for Field Service&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The same lessons apply when transforming service operations. You might be rolling out new scheduling software or launching mobile tools for technicians. On paper, the plan looks perfect. But in reality, adoption lags. Resistance creeps in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why? Because &lt;STRONG&gt;technology alone doesn’t change behavior&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Successful transformation requires:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;People&lt;/STRONG&gt; who feel involved, heard, and capable&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Processes&lt;/STRONG&gt; that are redesigned—not just digitized&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Persistence&lt;/STRONG&gt; to navigate detours, doubts, and delays&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1204434042"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":blue_book:"&gt;📘&lt;/span&gt;Want a model? Try &lt;STRONG&gt;Kotter’s 8-Step Change Model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Dr. John Kotter’s framework is widely used in business transformation. It emphasizes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Creating urgency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Building a guiding coalition&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Forming a strategic vision&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enabling action by removing barriers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Celebrating short-term wins&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;And anchoring the changes in culture&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A target="_new" rel="noopener"&gt;Explore the full model →&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-878837818"&gt;Technology Is the Enabler, Not the Driver&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tech is powerful. But it’s like giving my kids high-end hiking gear. If they don’t know where they’re going—or why—the gear ends up in the mud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Field Service, this means:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Involving technicians when introducing mobile apps&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Listening to dispatchers when reimagining cloud-based workflows&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Aligning leadership KPIs to real-world service outcomes—not just feature checklists&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-811407032"&gt;🧠 Need a practical tool? Consider &lt;STRONG&gt;ADKAR&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have seen companies successfully applying the ADKAR model from Prosci that helps manage individual transitions across 5 stages:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A&lt;/STRONG&gt;wareness of the need for change&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;D&lt;/STRONG&gt;esire to participate in the change&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;K&lt;/STRONG&gt;nowledge of how to change&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A&lt;/STRONG&gt;bility to implement change&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;R&lt;/STRONG&gt;einforcement to sustain change&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A target="_new" rel="noopener"&gt;More on ADKAR from Prosci →&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-485810808"&gt;What’s Next in This Series&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the first post in a five-part series exploring key transformations in Field Service:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This Part 1: The Heart of Transformation: People, Process, and Persistence&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Part 2: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/embracing-ai-in-field-service-from-garden-tools-to-smart-assistance/ba-p/14146962" target="_self"&gt;Embracing AI in Field Service: From Garden Tools to Smart Assistance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Part 3: From Paper to Pocket: How Mobile Transformed the Technician’s Day&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Part 4: Migrating from on-premise solutions to cloud dispatching&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Part 5: Transitioning to S/4HANA&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;And throughout: putting &lt;STRONG&gt;people, process, and persistence&lt;/STRONG&gt; at the center.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-418380022"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":seedling:"&gt;🌱&lt;/span&gt;Book tip: &lt;EM&gt;Switch: How to Change Things When Change Is Hard&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;A highly readable book by Chip &amp;amp; Dan Heath, which uses the metaphor of the rider, the elephant, and the path. In Field Service, you often need to steer minds (rider), motivate hearts (elephant), and shape the environment (path).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A target="_new" rel="noopener"&gt;More on &lt;EM&gt;Switch&lt;/EM&gt; here →&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/the-heart-of-transformation-people-process-and-persistence/ba-p/14124154"/>
    <published>2025-06-10T18:00:00.024000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/custom-widgets-in-sap-analytics-cloud-increased-flexibility-for-reporting/ba-p/14132680</id>
    <title>Custom Widgets in SAP Analytics Cloud - Increased flexibility for Reporting and Planning</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T10:16:42.417000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tonio_Japing</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/121427</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is a SAC Custom Widget?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Analytics Cloud offers companies a powerful platform for business intelligence, planning and predictive analyses. SAC provides a large number of standard widgets - so-called basic widgets - with which reports and dashboards can be designed quickly and effectively. Even though these basic widgets cover many common requirements and support a total of 21 different chart types, users sometimes come up against limitations when it comes to more specific visualization requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is exactly where custom widgets come into play: these are individually developed visualization elements that go beyond what SAP offers as standard. A SAC custom widget is essentially a web component that consists of a JSON file for the description, JavaScript code for the behavior and optional additional resources such as CSS or images. This allows new chart types as well as customized user interface elements, interactions or even completely new functionalities to be implemented.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="GRAPHIC 1: EXAMPLE OF A CUSTOM WIDGET" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276692i2D26A337131710B4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tonio_Japing_0-1750404191201.png" alt="GRAPHIC 1: EXAMPLE OF A CUSTOM WIDGET" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;GRAPHIC 1: EXAMPLE OF A CUSTOM WIDGET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom widgets offer developers full control: they can design their own diagrams and visualizations from scratch that are perfectly tailored to the specific requirements of a company - be it an interactive network diagram, a dynamic map view or a customized user interface. Thanks to the integration in SAC Stories and the support of the script API, custom widgets fit seamlessly into the existing environment and can be conveniently integrated into Stories via drag &amp;amp; drop.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom widgets therefore allow the SAP Analytics Cloud to be expanded considerably - both in terms of visual design and functional depth. They are the ideal tool if the standard options are not sufficient and the focus is on individual visualization requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Application scenarios for custom widgets in the SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom widgets open up a wide range of possible applications in the SAP Analytics Cloud, especially when standard widgets are not sufficient to meet specific requirements. A key area of application is the development of tailor-made visualizations that go beyond the 21 chart types available in the standard system.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="GRAPHIC 2: CUSTOM WIDGETS ARE AS INDIVIDUAL AS YOUR COMPANY'S REQUIREMENTS" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276690i13AFFF95EC6A5181/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tonio_Japing_1-1750404191202.png" alt="GRAPHIC 2: CUSTOM WIDGETS ARE AS INDIVIDUAL AS YOUR COMPANY'S REQUIREMENTS" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;GRAPHIC 2: CUSTOM WIDGETS ARE AS INDIVIDUAL AS YOUR COMPANY'S REQUIREMENTS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For example, companies can create their own KPI tiles that contain numerical values as well as contextual information such as deviations or trend indicators. In addition, custom widgets enable the integration of interactive user interface elements such as calendars, date pickers or barcode generators that are required in specific business processes. The integration of SAPUI5 controls is also possible, allowing existing components to be reused and complex applications to be implemented efficiently.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Another scenario is the extension of the SAC functionality by integrating external data sources or APIs. For example, custom widgets can visualize data from third-party systems in real time or enable specific interactions that cannot be realized with standard widgets. This offers companies the flexibility to tailor their dashboards and analyses precisely to their individual needs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Overall, custom widgets in the SAP Analytics Cloud offer a powerful way to extend standard functionalities and efficiently implement individual requirements. They are particularly advantageous when specific visualizations, user interactions or data integrations are required that go beyond the standard.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom widgets in detail - how they work in the SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom widgets can be seamlessly integrated into SAP Analytics Cloud Stories and behave like any other standard widget. After successful deployment, they are automatically listed in the widget menu so that they can be dragged and dropped onto the canvas and placed there. Once inserted, custom widgets can be flexibly moved, resized and visually designed - just like native components in SAC.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="GRAPHIC 3: ADD CUSTOM WIDGETS" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276691i9224DAF8526D7DAB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tonio_Japing_2-1750404191204.png" alt="GRAPHIC 3: ADD CUSTOM WIDGETS" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;GRAPHIC 3: ADD CUSTOM WIDGETS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Developers and users benefit from a wide range of functions. Basic properties such as color, font or frame can be adjusted via the styling panel. What is particularly interesting is that in the “Additional properties” section, you can add your own options that have been specially defined for the respective custom widget. Additional settings and functions can be stored in the builder panel, for example for data binding or initializing interactions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom widgets also support direct data binding, which means that they can be connected to data sources - a key requirement for interactive and data-driven visualizations. In the widget structure within a SAC story, custom widgets appear like any other component and can therefore be easily organized and targeted.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Another powerful feature is the scripting capability: custom widgets can be addressed via the familiar SAC script API. In addition to the methods available as standard, you can also define and implement your own events - such as an onClick that triggers certain actions when the widget is clicked. This flexibility makes Custom Widgets a versatile tool that can be deeply integrated into SAC, both visually and functionally.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Technical requirements and authorizations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The development and use of custom widgets in the SAP Analytics Cloud requires specific technical prerequisites and authorizations. By default, SAP roles are restricted to read access. To create or update custom widgets, users must be assigned additional authorizations. These authorizations can either be set globally for all custom widgets or individually per widget. In particular, widget designers require the rights to create and update widgets.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Several files are required to create a custom widget, including a JSON file to define the metadata and a JavaScript file for the functionality. These files are packed into a ZIP file together with optional resources such as CSS files or images. This ZIP file is then uploaded directly to the SAC, eliminating the need for external hosting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The development environment for custom widgets includes tools such as Visual Studio Code, a free editor from Microsoft that is particularly suitable for editing HTML and JavaScript. To create complex charts, developers can integrate free chart libraries such as ECharts, D3.js or Chart.js to realize advanced visualization options.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="GRAPHIC 4: DEVELOPMENT ENVIRONMENT" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276694i93C4615DAE63BA6F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tonio_Japing_3-1750404191205.png" alt="GRAPHIC 4: DEVELOPMENT ENVIRONMENT" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;GRAPHIC 4: DEVELOPMENT ENVIRONMENT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, there are currently certain limitations when using custom widgets. For example, only Chromium-based browsers such as Google Chrome and Microsoft Edge are fully supported. In addition, the number of custom widgets that can be loaded into a single SAC tenant is limited to 50.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some features of the SAC are not supported by custom widgets. These include themes and CSS adjustments, pause refresh, commenting, scheduling, translations, data change insights and the “Search to Insight” function. Restrictions may also occur when exporting custom widgets to PDF, especially if certain chart libraries such as D3.js are used or if CSS settings are defined in the widget.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are numerous examples for references in the SAP Community and in SAP Help:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/0ac8c6754ff84605a4372468d002f2bf/75311f67527c41638ceb89af9cd8af3e.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;mt=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud Custom Widget Developer Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/analytics-cloud-datasphere-community-content/blob/main/SAC_Custom_Widgets/README.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Custom Widget examples on GitHub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-custom-widget-amp-widget-add-ons-samples-preview/ba-p/13585313" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Technology Blog: Custom Widgets &amp;amp; Widget Add-Ons&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://echarts.apache.org/examples/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Echarts library examples&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/35a443e276964981a85bf2b0cb58e180/10a922dc482448d7b2176cd22bbf7afd.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;mt=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud Widget Add-On Developer Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Your path to SAP Analytics Cloud Custom Widgets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The introduction of custom widgets in the SAP Analytics Cloud offers companies an outstanding opportunity to expand their analytics solutions individually and to tailor them visually and functionally to specific requirements. To maximize the benefits, we recommend a structured and proven approach.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;requirements analysis: In initial workshops, we work with you to analyze the technical, functional and content requirements for the planned custom widget. In this way, we ensure that all stakeholder needs are understood and taken into account - from IT to the specialist department.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;proof of concept: We then develop an initial minimum viable product (MVP) to demonstrate the technical feasibility. This PoC serves as the basis for further decisions and for internal coordination with relevant teams.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;implementation: Based on the PoC, we add the required functionalities to the widget, test it in your SAC environment and hand over the finished custom widget as part of a clean documentation and handover.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="GRAPHIC 5: EVALUATION" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276693i9D4A8851CB7A7383/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tonio_Japing_4-1750404191206.png" alt="GRAPHIC 5: EVALUATION" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;GRAPHIC 5: EVALUATION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Custom widgets are a modular building block for making a variety of advanced functions usable in SAC - from individual visualizations to complex interactions. They promote acceptance among end users and enable customized solutions for company-specific challenges. At the same time, you should consider the increased development effort compared to standard widgets and the possible training requirements for your team - because individual developments also require internal know-how in the long term.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/custom-widgets-in-sap-analytics-cloud-increased-flexibility-for-reporting/ba-p/14132680"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T10:16:42.417000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/steps-to-connect-solace-aem-advanced-event-mesh-with-sap-cloud-integration/ba-p/14137656</id>
    <title>Steps to Connect Solace AEM (Advanced Event Mesh) with SAP Cloud Integration (CPI)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-02T13:46:26.422000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SanalaTejaswini</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2117187</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Set Up the Solace Event Broker :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Before integrating with SAP Cloud Integration (CPI), ensure that your &lt;STRONG&gt;Solace Event Broker (Advanced Event Mesh)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is properly set up. The broker should be,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Running and operational,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accessible over the internet&lt;/STRONG&gt; with the necessary ports open for communication.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;New to Solace&lt;BR /&gt;Check out our blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="SolaceSetUp" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/solace-from-scratch-a-beginner-s-guide-to-setting-up-your-first-event/ba-p/14130557" target="_blank"&gt;Solace from Scratch: A Beginner’s Guide to Setting Up Your First Event Broker&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;before diving into the integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Log in to SAP Cloud Integration (CPI)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; via&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://account.hana.ondemand.com/#/home/welcome" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit Login&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to Design&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.Create/Configure an Integration Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open or create an &lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;Sender&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;Receiver&lt;/STRONG&gt; adapters depending on your flow:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To &lt;STRONG&gt;send messages to Solace&lt;/STRONG&gt;, use AEM adapter as &lt;STRONG&gt;Receiver&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To &lt;STRONG&gt;receive messages from Solace&lt;/STRONG&gt;, use the same as &lt;STRONG&gt;Sender&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, According to my requirement I Choose AEM Receiver adapter to send/ Store the data in the Solace event broker Queues.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture1.jpg" style="width: 624px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279160iB2627945CBFCC807/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture1.jpg" alt="Picture1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture2.jpg" style="width: 624px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279171i4494A9E0BC7D9514/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture2.jpg" alt="Picture2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture3.jpg" style="width: 624px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279175iC0F579EF30E46817/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture3.jpg" alt="Picture3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Gather Solace AEM Connection Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From your AEM &lt;STRONG&gt;Broker Console&lt;/STRONG&gt;, collect:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Broker hostname&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Client username&lt;/STRONG&gt; (from “Try Me!” or manually created)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Client password&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Queue/Topic name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can find these in the "Connect" or "Try Me!" sections of AEM's Console.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After Gathering The Connection Details,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make the Connectivity Test through TLS &amp;nbsp;for the Broker Hostname to ensure that we had a successful connection establishment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture4.jpg" style="width: 624px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279215iDAE0982AFBCFD0E6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture4.jpg" alt="Picture4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If it is a valid connection, we will get a response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5.Setup the CPI I flow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, we are triggering the payload through the Https adapter, based on the payload, the data is sent to different queues &amp;nbsp;which is acquired through “&lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic Routing&lt;/STRONG&gt;”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SanalaTejaswini_1-1751023962335.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279767i6483777D255E1BE0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SanalaTejaswini_1-1751023962335.png" alt="SanalaTejaswini_1-1751023962335.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Below is the Sample payload that I considered to work on.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Products&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;Product&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ProductID&amp;gt;P1001&amp;lt;/ProductID&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ProductName&amp;gt;Wireless Mouse&amp;lt;/ProductName&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Category&amp;gt;Electronics&amp;lt;/Category&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Price&amp;gt;25.99&amp;lt;/Price&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Currency&amp;gt;USD&amp;lt;/Currency&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;StockQuantity&amp;gt;150&amp;lt;/StockQuantity&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;UnitOfMeasure&amp;gt;EA&amp;lt;/UnitOfMeasure&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Supplier&amp;gt;LogiTech Inc.&amp;lt;/Supplier&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/Product&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/Products&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The below snippet is a Groovy script used for dynamic routing . It reads the root tag from the XML payload and sets the route name in the property routeTo based on the tag value.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import com.sap.gateway.ip.core.customdev.util.Message
import groovy.util.XmlSlurper

Message processData(Message message) {
    def body = message.getBody(String) // Get XML as a string
    def xml = new XmlSlurper().parseText(body) // Parse XML

    def targetRoute = ""

    // Check the root element or a specific tag (adjust as needed)
    if (xml.name() == "Products") {
        targetRoute = "publisher_solace_inbound_products_layer-2"
    } else if (xml.name() == "Suppliers") {
        targetRoute = "publisher_solace_inbound_suppliers_layer_2"
    } else {
        targetRoute = "publisher_solace_inbound_books_layer_2"
    }

    message.setProperty("routeTo", targetRoute) // Store the route in a property
    return message
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the Above sample data belongs to &lt;STRONG&gt;Products&lt;/STRONG&gt;, so it will be dynamically routed to the corresponding &lt;STRONG&gt;Products transaction layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SanalaTejaswini_2-1751024811701.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279776iC60D32ED1FC9FFFA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SanalaTejaswini_2-1751024811701.png" alt="SanalaTejaswini_2-1751024811701.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, AEM (Advanced event mesh) &amp;nbsp;acts as an adapter between SAP CPI and the Solace Event Broker, enabling seamless event-based communication.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After Confirming the Hostname connectivity in the connectivity tests add all the Gathered details as shown below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SanalaTejaswini_3-1751024978504.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279780iE52CA1334CB6387D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SanalaTejaswini_3-1751024978504.png" alt="SanalaTejaswini_3-1751024978504.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Password secure Alias are the credentials stored in Security Material, which are Client Name and Client Password&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SanalaTejaswini_4-1751025047880.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279781i1511EFC46D0F9A6B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SanalaTejaswini_4-1751025047880.png" alt="SanalaTejaswini_4-1751025047880.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Destination Name refers to Queue Name that we have created in the Solace Event Broker&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SanalaTejaswini_5-1751025122526.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279782iCD9C351B96525B93/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SanalaTejaswini_5-1751025122526.png" alt="SanalaTejaswini_5-1751025122526.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, we placed the name of the queue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SanalaTejaswini_6-1751025274989.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279784i81F9B6F39C06B64E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SanalaTejaswini_6-1751025274989.png" alt="SanalaTejaswini_6-1751025274989.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The above is the Queue created in the Solace, which acts as a median between the publisher and the subscriber.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the Subscriber End we will use the AEM Sender Adapter, to Share the data through Queues&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SanalaTejaswini_0-1751439434978.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281639iBC5691C3166D4082/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SanalaTejaswini_0-1751439434978.png" alt="SanalaTejaswini_0-1751439434978.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similar Details needs to be authenticated on the Subscriber side.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SanalaTejaswini_1-1751439490185.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281641iBB7009BE528432F5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SanalaTejaswini_1-1751439490185.png" alt="SanalaTejaswini_1-1751439490185.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SanalaTejaswini_2-1751439499136.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/281642iCC27BADEC15D3633/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SanalaTejaswini_2-1751439499136.png" alt="SanalaTejaswini_2-1751439499136.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"After deploying the above artifacts, you will be able to successfully retrieve the data stored in the Solace Event Broker"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/steps-to-connect-solace-aem-advanced-event-mesh-with-sap-cloud-integration/ba-p/14137656"/>
    <published>2025-07-02T13:46:26.422000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/connect-to-public-cloud-api-in-node-js-via-authorisation-code/ba-p/14158313</id>
    <title>Connect to Public Cloud API in Node.js via Authorisation Code</title>
    <updated>2025-07-22T13:54:57.292000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Egan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1504852</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Connecting to a Public Cloud API (from &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;) via Node.js CAP application can be challenging. I hope this blog helps others attempting the same task.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735214148"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Prerequisites&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;• SAP BTP subaccount (Cloud Foundry)&lt;BR /&gt;• Service key for the target Public Cloud API&lt;BR /&gt;• XSUAA instance bound to your CAP app&lt;BR /&gt;• SAP BTP Destination service instance&lt;BR /&gt;• Bruno installed for manual testing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1538700643"&gt;1. Confirm the API's Auth Options&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, check which authentication methods are available for the API you plan to consume.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my example I connect to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Specification Management API&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but the steps apply to any Public Cloud API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the &lt;EM&gt;OAuth 2.0 Access Code Flow&lt;/EM&gt; is listed under “Authentication Methods”, the API supports the authorization-code flow. That flow confirms a user context and usually grants wider authorisations, such as update and POST requests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(&lt;EM&gt;OAuth 2.0 Application Flow&lt;/EM&gt; corresponds to the client-credentials flow.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Auth-method screenshot" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289462iBE738F54BD94C2E9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Egan_0-1753113819867.png" alt="Egan_0-1753113819867.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1342187138"&gt;2. Connect manually with Bruno (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/data-export-api-getting-started-with-bruno/ba-p/14120240" target="_blank"&gt;Good blog on Bruno&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because our API supports the auth-code flow, we first prove we can log in by calling it via Bruno.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a new collection and paste the base URI of your Public Cloud API instance (you’ll find it in the service key in your service instance of the saas application your connecting to).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Service key showing URI" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289463iD5B5C161AD23500A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Egan_3-1753114108426.png" alt="Egan_3-1753114108426.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you send a test GET request you will probably receive an authorisation error. Configure OAuth 2.0 on the &lt;STRONG&gt;Auth&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select Grant type Authorisation Code&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then fill in the below fields using your service key from your service instance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Bruno auth settings" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289461i1BABC87E61152C2F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Egan_1-1753113819868.png" alt="Egan_1-1753113819868.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Callback URL: &amp;lt;your Public Cloud API hostname&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Auth URL:** https://&amp;lt;subdomain&amp;gt;.authentication.&amp;lt;region&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/authorize&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access-Token URL: https://&amp;lt;subdomain&amp;gt;.authentication.&amp;lt;region&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/token&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Client ID / Secret: from the uaa section of the service key&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Request the token, pick your identity provider, and Bruno will return an access token. Inspect the scopes there to see what you can do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1145673633"&gt;3. Connect to the API from Node.js&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the manual check we can now automate the flow in a Node.js service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1078242847"&gt;3.1 Destination setup&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a destination that points to the same API endpoint and bind it to your app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Destination configuration" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289460i1560E45388730B53/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Egan_2-1753113819869.png" alt="Egan_2-1753113819869.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The required scopes and the audience (aud) value are visible inside the Bruno access token.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;the Audience should start with the client id of your CAP application on BTP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the destination is saved, ensure your application is bound to the Destination service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-881729342"&gt;3.2 xs-security.json&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add every scope your service needs so the approuter, it will forward it in the user’s JWT: in my example i needed this scope.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "name": "$XSAPPNAME.Spc_Write",
  "description": "Allow modification of specifications."
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also reference the scope in authorities (and role templates, if used) and assign the resulting role collection to your user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-685215837"&gt;3.3 Connect in code&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now time to connect to the API in the code itself.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, obtain the user’s JWT. This helper below tries every possible source and falls back to LOCAL_USER_JWT in local development:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/** Try every source for a JWT and fall back to LOCAL_USER_JWT. */
function getJwt(capReq) {
  // CAP ≥ 7.3 keeps the raw token here
  if (capReq.user?.jwt) return capReq.user.jwt;

  // Plain HTTP / WebSocket headers
  const hdrs = capReq.http?.req?.headers || {};
  const token =
        hdrs['x-approuter-authorization'] ||   // CF WebSocket
        hdrs.authorization;                    // CF HTTP

  if (token) return token.replace(/^Bearer\s+/, '');
  // Last resort for local dev
  return process.env.LOCAL_USER_JWT;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-617785051"&gt;3.3.1 Testing locally&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;When testing locally we don't have access to the user JWT so we can add it manually to the environment file so we can still test locally, below is the process to get the JWT for user testing (each token lasts about 7 to 8 hours)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-550354265"&gt;Step 1 – Get an auth code&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://&amp;lt;instance&amp;gt;.eu10.authentication.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/authorize
?response_type=code
&amp;amp;client_id=&amp;lt;XSUAA client id of your deployed app&amp;gt;
&amp;amp;redirect_uri=http://localhost
&amp;amp;state=xyz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Paste your version into your browsers address bar, after login you will land on &lt;A href="http://localhost/?code=" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;http://localhost/?code=&lt;/A&gt;&amp;lt;AUTH_CODE&amp;gt;&amp;amp;state=xyz. Copy the value of AUTH_CODE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-353840760"&gt;Step 2 – Exchange the code for a JWT&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;I made the Curl Request inside BAS itself. it will return a number of tokens, we only need the first and biggest one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -v -X POST \
-u '&amp;lt;same client id&amp;gt;' \
--data-urlencode grant_type=authorization_code \
--data-urlencode code=&amp;lt;AUTH_CODE&amp;gt; \
--data-urlencode redirect_uri=http://localhost \
https://&amp;lt;instance&amp;gt;.eu10.authentication.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/token&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Save the token from the response into .env:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;LOCAL_USER_JWT=&amp;lt;paste JWT here&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--469472559"&gt;3.3.2 Call the destination with the JWT&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;const jwt = getJwt(req);
if (!jwt) req.reject(401, 'No user token found.');

const dest = await getDestination({
  destinationName: '&amp;lt;DestinationName&amp;gt;',
  jwt
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;await executeHttpRequest(dest, {
  method: 'POST',
  url: `/odata/v4/api/specification/v1/${EntityName}`,
  data: v
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you reach the destination but receive 401 Unauthorized, your JWT is missing the correct scope—ask the product team which one you need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other common pitfall is using the different XSUAA instances to get your JWT for the local run. use your applications XSUAA client since this is the same one your application will check the token against&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And that’s it! You should now be able to read from and write to the Public Cloud API. For read-only workloads the client-credentials flow is usually simpler.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If I missed anything or you’d like more details, please comment below—happy to help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;## Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;### What’s the difference between authorization-code and client-credentials flows?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The authorization-code flow runs in a user context, so it can carry user-level scopes (read, write, update). The client-credentials flow operates with a technical user—perfect for background jobs or read-only integrations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;### Why do I get “401 Unauthorized” after deployment?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Your user’s JWT is probably missing the required scope (e.g., `Spc_Write`). Make sure the scope is listed in &lt;STRONG&gt;xs-security.json&lt;/STRONG&gt;, mapped to a role template, and assigned via a role collection in the BTP cockpit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;### Which audience value belongs in my destination?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;client ID&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;of your CAP application’s XSUAA instance&lt;/STRONG&gt;; it usually starts with `sb-&amp;lt;appName&amp;gt;!t&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;`.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Node.js/pd-p/723714486627645412834578565527550" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="322-1"&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Cloud+Identity+Services/pd-p/67837800100800007337" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="155-1"&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/API/pd-p/b31da0dd-f79a-4a1e-988c-af0755c2d184" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="123-1"&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Authenticator/pd-p/73554900100700000789" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="435-1"&gt;SAP Authenticator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Fiori+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800000375" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="20-1"&gt;SAP Fiori Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Cloud+Application+Programming+Model/pd-p/9f13aee1-834c-4105-8e43-ee442775e5ce" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="100-1"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Application+Studio/pd-p/67837800100800007077" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="13-1"&gt;SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Technology+Platform/pd-p/73555000100700000172" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1215-1"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition+Extensibility/pd-p/270c4f37-c335-46e1-bfad-a256637d5e26" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="37-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Extensibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Accelerator+Hub/pd-p/73555000100800001091" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1214-1"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/JavaScript/pd-p/506421944534752500398156104608974" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="321-1"&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/API+Management/pd-p/67838200100800006828" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="358-1"&gt;API Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;!--    END BLOG FRAGMENT    --&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/connect-to-public-cloud-api-in-node-js-via-authorisation-code/ba-p/14158313"/>
    <published>2025-07-22T13:54:57.292000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/uploading-attachment-with-cap-js-attachment-plugins-but-via-external-app/ba-p/14147330</id>
    <title>Uploading attachment with cap-js/attachment plugins but via External App/Postman</title>
    <updated>2025-07-24T09:08:43.209000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chrisobar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/845878</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If anyone here are struggling uploading attachments via external app to &lt;STRONG&gt;cap-js/attachments&lt;/STRONG&gt;, I am writing this blog to showcase how to upload attachments on the plugins via external applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The blog shall include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Pre-requisites&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Example 1. via Postman&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Example 2. via External App (React)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Pre-requisites: cap-js/attachment&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You have extended your current entity for example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_0-1751980368296.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284030i3E65DD76A2FC1CE5/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_0-1751980368296.png" alt="chrisobar_0-1751980368296.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Attachment entity accepts the following field below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_1-1751980478628.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284031iD0E50B9FD39F02D2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_1-1751980478628.png" alt="chrisobar_1-1751980478628.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The fields above are important and to be used for your JSON Body parameters (can leave status as blank as it uses '&lt;STRONG&gt;Unscanned&lt;/STRONG&gt;' as default). See below sample scenarios on how we can upload attachment:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Example 1. (via Postman)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;**Other API tools are doable&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this case, we require an existing entry in our table/fiori app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are the steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Retrieve a single entry from your entity, copy the link and add /YourAttachmentEntity that you extended. (On my case, discount_attachment)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ex:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_3-1751981390255.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284056iBE13F1B966BBFC55/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_3-1751981390255.png" alt="chrisobar_3-1751981390255.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Follow the entity fields then replicate it, then attach your desired parameters on the body as raw - JSON format&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_4-1751981481494.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284061i18F93B46BA174AFC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_4-1751981481494.png" alt="chrisobar_4-1751981481494.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(Convert your file to base64. In my case I attached an image, png format)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Send the request, you will see that it responded successfully. Go back to your Fiori app to verify if the attachment reflected:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_5-1751981587156.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284062i392735186A50F1A7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_5-1751981587156.png" alt="chrisobar_5-1751981587156.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_8-1751981935102.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284070i0538D102CDCD1200/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_8-1751981935102.png" alt="chrisobar_8-1751981935102.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_7-1751981734557.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284064iA81690ED011DFFEC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_7-1751981734557.png" alt="chrisobar_7-1751981734557.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Example 2. (External App)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have developed a React App for POC purposes. In this scenario, the data should be created first, then update that same entry using the ID, then upload the attachment via HTTP POST.&amp;nbsp; Let's breakdown:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Upload attachment as input='file', bind it in form data including all the parameters:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_9-1751982052158.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284071iA0F0CE6822C0130A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_9-1751982052158.png" alt="chrisobar_9-1751982052158.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Build your logic for your initial creation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_10-1751982176378.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284073iE2AFE797AA5B9623/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_10-1751982176378.png" alt="chrisobar_10-1751982176378.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; My .ENV variable contains the base odata URL (/odata/v4/......, not the whole http url)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Convert the file from input='file' to base64 via JS logic, then bind the OData URL with your entity keys and the HTTP body parameters (refer to Attachment Entity fields and Postman example above).&amp;nbsp; then proceed OData call&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_15-1751982778767.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284082i20CC907D75921644/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_15-1751982778767.png" alt="chrisobar_15-1751982778767.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My form will display a successful message and it should reflect on the database/fiori app as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_13-1751982513662.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284080i196C2C1646A41D1A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_13-1751982513662.png" alt="chrisobar_13-1751982513662.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="chrisobar_14-1751982541889.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284081i48304E0EF638EEFE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="chrisobar_14-1751982541889.png" alt="chrisobar_14-1751982541889.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog demonstrates how SAP CAP can interface seamlessly with external apps to enhance attachment handling across varied use cases. By abstracting the upload and retrieval logic via an API layer, the approach supports modular features in both admin dashboards and customer-facing applications. Despite initial challenges around payload structuring and authorization, the solution remains scalable, secure, and adaptable to different frontend contexts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let me know if you have any further questions or wish to communicate, just comment below the comment section.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/uploading-attachment-with-cap-js-attachment-plugins-but-via-external-app/ba-p/14147330"/>
    <published>2025-07-24T09:08:43.209000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/webcast-series-sap-s-four-part-journey-through-architecting-modern-sap/ba-p/14162755</id>
    <title>Webcast Series: SAP's Four-Part Journey Through Architecting Modern SAP Landscapes</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T16:17:53.817000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Michael_Blaschke</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1822449</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Michael_Blaschke_5-1753449960935.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291599i10D2ED3567ACCD01/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Michael_Blaschke_5-1753449960935.png" alt="Michael_Blaschke_5-1753449960935.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In an era where digital transformation has evolved from competitive advantage to survival imperative, enterprise architects find themselves at the crossroads of unprecedented technological convergence. The traditional boundaries between artificial intelligence, cloud platforms, and business applications are dissolving, creating both immense opportunities and complex architectural challenges. To address this shifting landscape, SAP’s global &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Enterprise Architecture &amp;amp; Advisory&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; team recently delivered a four-part webcast series that charts a course through the most pressing architectural questions facing organizations today.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This series, "&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Architecture for Modern SAP Landscapes&lt;/STRONG&gt;," was developed at the invitation of the broader "&lt;STRONG&gt;Move to Cloud ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;" webcast series, powered by the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Global User Groups Organization&lt;/STRONG&gt; to serve the worldwide SAP community."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It represents more than just technical guidance—it's a strategic roadmap for navigating the fundamental transformation of how businesses architect, deploy, and govern their technology ecosystems. From debunking persistent myths that paralyze decision-making to realizing the promise of clean core principles, each session builds upon the others to create a holistic view of modern enterprise architecture, delivering the practical insights that user groups across the globe have been requesting for their digital transformation journeys.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DSC08021.jpg" style="width: 799px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291538i73A46FCB47FE885F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DSC08021.jpg" alt="DSC08021.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1606880174"&gt;Part 1: Debunking Enterprise Architecture Myths&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Michael_Blaschke_0-1753444131937.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291473iE9E93C53A913637F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Michael_Blaschke_0-1753444131937.png" alt="Michael_Blaschke_0-1753444131937.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date&lt;/STRONG&gt;: June 10, 2025 | &lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Dr. Michael Blaschke (&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1822449"&gt;@Michael_Blaschke&lt;/a&gt;), Enterprise Architect, SAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The series opens with perhaps the most critical challenge facing enterprise architects today: separating fact from fiction in SAP’s modern architecture paradigms. The opening session, “&lt;STRONG&gt;Debunking Enterprise Architecture Myths: Clean Core, SAP S/4HANA, and BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;,” tackles seven persistent misconceptions that continue to derail digital transformation initiatives across organizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These aren’t merely technical misunderstandings—they’re strategic barriers that cost organizations millions in project delays and suboptimal architectural decisions. The session demonstrates how clean core principles extend far beyond SAP S/4HANA implementation, enabling strategic custom development while maintaining upgrade safety and innovation velocity. Through architectural patterns and real-world case studies, attendees learn to counter myths with evidence-based approaches that accelerate rather than impede transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What makes this session particularly valuable is its focus on communication and stakeholder management. Enterprise architects often find themselves in the unenviable position of defending architectural decisions against deeply held misconceptions. This presentation equips them with the truths and techniques needed to lead evidence-based discussions in executive steering committees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1668532107"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/u/a/mew5Knq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Download PDF&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; | &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=chMdN8gHvl0&amp;amp;t=1947s" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Watch Replay&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1213853164"&gt;Part 2: Architecting Innovation-Platform Ecosystems&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Michael_Blaschke_1-1753444189108.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291474i1B378FF9605B0E80/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Michael_Blaschke_1-1753444189108.png" alt="Michael_Blaschke_1-1753444189108.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date&lt;/STRONG&gt;: June 17, 2025 | &lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Dr. Michael Blaschke (&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1822449"&gt;@Michael_Blaschke&lt;/a&gt;),&amp;nbsp;Enterprise Architect, SAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The second installment shifts focus to one of the most significant architectural transformations of our time: the evolution from traditional product-platform ecosystems to dynamic innovation-platform ecosystems. “&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Architecture for Transitioning from Product-platform to Innovation-platform Ecosystems&lt;/STRONG&gt;” explores how enterprise architects can design the foundational layers necessary for fostering co-creation and external innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session is grounded in rigorous academic research by &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1822449"&gt;@Michael_Blaschke&lt;/a&gt;, drawing from his peer-reviewed studies on platform ecosystem dynamics and digital transformation patterns. The presentation unveils the architectural building blocks required to create open, scalable innovation-platform ecosystems that support API-first strategies and platform economics while maintaining essential governance and security controls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The transition from product-platform to innovation-platform ecosystems represents a fundamental shift in how organizations create and capture value. Enterprise architects learn to design the organizational capabilities that enable ecosystem participation, support multi-sided marketplace dynamics, and unlock network effects—all while ensuring the organization doesn’t sacrifice operational stability for innovation velocity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1275505097"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=QUFFLUhqbE5OMzZQR2VZLUY4YUJXQnloT0d0ek9BUnl6QXxBQ3Jtc0tsNUNLSUFvWHVNSjZ4QTg1a01KNjFROTlGVzNkb0REOTlGeDJTc3ZlMllpYjhOei1rcEpaMFJ5dWtqU2VIYzM3YXhQRUt2TGxSS3lGQ2stV2wzYnNNRWgtR0pvNTctNjhmMndmU3A0SkVGRmFCdE03QQ&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Furl.sap%2Fcv7ic8&amp;amp;v=jWFNNmhH8zw" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Download PDF&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; | &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jWFNNmhH8zw&amp;amp;list=PLpQebylHrdh7WMU3RRilp-kdAkqmb8MQx&amp;amp;index=5" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch Replay&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supporting Research&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0960085X.2022.2136542#abstractlovers" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Dynamic capabilities for transitioning from product platform ecosystem to innovation platform ecosystem&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://aisel.aisnet.org/icis2018/service/Presentations/2/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Capabilities for Digital Platform Survival: Insights from a Business-to-Business Digital Platform&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-820826154"&gt;Part 3: AI-First and Suite-First Convergence&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Michael_Blaschke_3-1753444290445.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291477iCE70542A4B601C99/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Michael_Blaschke_3-1753444290445.png" alt="Michael_Blaschke_3-1753444290445.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date&lt;/STRONG&gt;: June 24, 2025 | &lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Dr. Michael Blaschke (&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1822449"&gt;@Michael_Blaschke&lt;/a&gt;),&amp;nbsp;Enterprise Architect, SAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The third session addresses perhaps the most complex architectural challenge of our time: orchestrating the convergence of AI-first capabilities with suite-first principles. “&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Architecture Convergence: AI-First and Suite-First Strategy for Modern Digital Landscapes&lt;/STRONG&gt;” explores how enterprise architects must evolve their frameworks to architect truly future-ready organizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This presentation goes beyond the typical AI integration discussion to examine the deeper architectural patterns required for pervasive AI adoption. The session demonstrates how to harmonize three critical elements: AI integration with Joule as the intelligent copilot, unified business data cloud capabilities for cross-portfolio insights, and consistent suite qualities that ensure security and performance at scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The convergence theme is particularly relevant as organizations struggle to integrate AI capabilities without fragmenting their existing architectural coherence. Dr. Blaschke provides practical guidance on designing landscapes that embrace AI-first thinking while maintaining the governance and integration integrity essential for enterprise-scale deployments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-882478087"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://d.dam.sap.com/a/cJDNuP6/Move_to_Cloud_ERP_Part_3_EA_Convergence.pdf?rc=10&amp;amp;inline=true&amp;amp;doi=SAP1218268" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Download PDF&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; | &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4hlN0Rc-nLM&amp;amp;list=PLpQebylHrdh7WMU3RRilp-kdAkqmb8MQx&amp;amp;index=4" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch Replay&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-427799144"&gt;Part 4: &lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Architecture View on&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Clean Core&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Michael_Blaschke_4-1753444320779.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291479iF36A331D62E813D9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Michael_Blaschke_4-1753444320779.png" alt="Michael_Blaschke_4-1753444320779.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date&lt;/STRONG&gt;: July 1, 2025 | &lt;STRONG&gt;Speaker&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Dr. Michael Blaschke (&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1822449"&gt;@Michael_Blaschke&lt;/a&gt;), Principal Enterprise Architect, SAP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The series concludes with “&lt;STRONG&gt;Realizing Clean Core using Cloud Extensibility: An Enterprise Architecture Perspective&lt;/STRONG&gt;,” which provides the practical implementation guidance necessary to transform architectural vision into operational reality. This session reveals how enterprise architects can maintain pristine core systems while enabling seamless cloud-based extensions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The clean core principle represents one of SAP’s most significant architectural innovations, but its implementation requires careful balance between standardization and customization. The presentation demonstrates how to establish architectural guardrails that prevent core pollution, leverage cloud-native extension patterns, and create flexible composition layers that enable innovation without compromising stability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This final session ties together themes from the entire series, showing how clean core principles enable the platform ecosystem transformations discussed earlier while providing the architectural foundation necessary for AI-first initiatives. The result is a comprehensive approach to enterprise architecture that balances the sometimes competing demands of standardization, innovation, and agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-489451077"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://url.sap/esomah" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Download PDF&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; | &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L_9lPJ-HX3I&amp;amp;t=2824s" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Watch Replay&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-34772134"&gt;The Global Enterprise Architecture &amp;amp; Advisory Impact&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;These sessions represent the expertise and experience of SAP’s global &lt;EM&gt;Enterprise Architecture &amp;amp; Advisory&lt;/EM&gt; team, part of the &lt;EM&gt;Premium Engagement &amp;amp; Advisory&lt;/EM&gt; practice. This specialized team serves as strategic business partners to regional enterprise architect teams, helping customers drive digital transformation initiatives across the globe. Their focus on board-mandated and critical customer situations positions them uniquely to understand and address the most complex architectural challenges facing modern organizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The team provides dedicated enterprise architecture expertise to enterprise-grade customers, partnering with senior executives to architect modern enterprises. This hands-on experience with strategic transformations informs every aspect of the webcast series, ensuring that the content reflects real-world implementation challenges and proven solution patterns.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--161741371"&gt;Charting Your Architectural Journey&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, these four sessions provide enterprise architects with a comprehensive framework for navigating the complexities of modern digital transformation. They address not just the technical aspects of architecture but the strategic, organizational, and governance challenges that determine transformation success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The series acknowledges that modern enterprise architecture requires more than technical expertise—it demands the ability to lead organizational change, communicate complex technical concepts to business stakeholders, and design solutions that balance competing priorities across multiple stakeholder groups.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the SAP Community's global audience of customers, partners, and practitioners, this webcast series offers both immediate practical value and strategic vision for the future of enterprise architecture. Whether you’re debunking myths in steering committee meetings, designing innovation-platform ecosystems, orchestrating AI-first transformations, or implementing clean core principles, these sessions provide the frameworks and insights necessary to succeed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The journey toward modern enterprise architecture is neither simple nor straightforward, but with the right guidance and frameworks, organizations can navigate this transformation successfully. This webcast series represents a valuable resource for anyone committed to architecting modern enterprises.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Special thanks to &lt;STRONG&gt;Larissa Brinkmann&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Krenar Kuqi &lt;/STRONG&gt;for their excellent collaboration, and to the SAP Global User Groups Organization&amp;nbsp;for providing this platform to showcase SAP’s thought leadership in enterprise architecture.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This series, "&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Architecture for Modern SAP Landscapes&lt;/STRONG&gt;," was developed at the invitation of the broader "&lt;STRONG&gt;Move to Cloud ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;" webcast series, powered by the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Global User Groups Organization&lt;/STRONG&gt; to serve the worldwide SAP community."&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;by Dr. Michael R. Blaschke&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/webcast-series-sap-s-four-part-journey-through-architecting-modern-sap/ba-p/14162755"/>
    <published>2025-07-25T16:17:53.817000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
