<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Data-and-Analytics-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Data and Analytics</title>
  <updated>2025-12-07T09:00:15.407707+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Data and Analytics/pd-p/87817424-f4e7-46f2-af14-88bf0f4ba034" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Data and Analytics blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/choosing-the-right-sap-analytics-tool-features-benefits-and-strategy/ba-p/14230016</id>
    <title>Choosing the Right SAP Analytics Tool: Features, Benefits, and Strategy</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T08:48:09.273000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GiriRaaj</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/153675</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Within an organization's data and analytics strategy, SAP provides a portfolio of analytics solutions, including SAP S/4HANA Embedded Analytics, SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC), and SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC), each with a specific function. To assist clients in selecting the best option for their requirements, a comparative analysis of their salient characteristics and advantages is provided below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890837768"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP S/4HANA Embedded Analytics&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This solution, which is directly integrated into the SAP S/4HANA ERP system, offers real-time analytics on operational data without requiring data replication.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GiriRaaj_0-1759127524684.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320922i4C4B404D79A8F548/image-dimensions/592x313?v=v2" width="592" height="313" role="button" title="GiriRaaj_0-1759127524684.png" alt="GiriRaaj_0-1759127524684.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Reporting in Real Time:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Get the most recent information straight from the ERP system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Views of Core Data Services (CDS):&lt;/STRONG&gt; For customizable reporting, use virtual data models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Predefined KPIs and Dashboards:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use unconventional content to gain rapid insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fiori-Based User Interface:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enhanced user experience through intuitive design.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immediate Decision-Making&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Facilitates quick actions based on current data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified Infrastructure&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Eliminates the need for separate data warehousing solutions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Embedded within the core ERP system, ensuring consistency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565241544"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497810758"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A cloud-based platform combining business intelligence, planning, and predictive analytics, SAC connects to various data sources, including SAP and non-SAP systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GiriRaaj_1-1759127661310.png" style="width: 575px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320924i99C5FE0993F046D8/image-dimensions/575x286?v=v2" width="575" height="286" role="button" title="GiriRaaj_1-1759127661310.png" alt="GiriRaaj_1-1759127661310.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Utilize AI-driven insights and predictive modelling.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Integrate financial planning and budgeting processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Collaboration Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Facilitate real-time discussions and decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mobile Accessibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Access analytics on-the-go through optimized dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comprehensive Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Consolidates data from multiple sources for holistic analysis.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Forecasting&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Improves accuracy in planning and budgeting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Cloud infrastructure supports growth and flexibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A fully managed SaaS solution that unifies and governs SAP and third-party data, enabling advanced analytics and AI-driven insights across the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GiriRaaj_3-1759128045141.png" style="width: 667px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320928i4140F05E2A3791CE/image-dimensions/667x375?v=v2" width="667" height="375" role="button" title="GiriRaaj_3-1759128045141.png" alt="GiriRaaj_3-1759128045141.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Connects disparate data sources into a unified platform.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI and ML Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Leverages machine learning for predictive analytics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prebuilt Applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Offers industry-specific solutions and dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ensures data quality and compliance across the organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerated Decision-Making&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Provides timely insights for informed decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reduced Complexity&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Simplifies data management and analytics processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Fosters cross-departmental data sharing and insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301297253"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104783748"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comparative Study&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GiriRaaj_0-1759126789879.png" style="width: 721px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320908i657DD56539F68920/image-dimensions/721x229?v=v2" width="721" height="229" role="button" title="GiriRaaj_0-1759126789879.png" alt="GiriRaaj_0-1759126789879.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommendation&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Choose SAP S/4HANA Embedded Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt; if your primary need is real-time, operational reporting directly within your ERP system, with minimal infrastructure overhead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Opt for SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; when you require advanced analytics, predictive modeling, and planning capabilities across various data sources, with a focus on scalability and collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consider SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; if your organization seeks a unified platform for data integration, governance, and AI-driven insights, encompassing both SAP and third-party data sources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your time.&amp;nbsp; Stay connected for further updates on Analytics !&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;-With Warm Regards :&amp;nbsp; GIRI&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/choosing-the-right-sap-analytics-tool-features-benefits-and-strategy/ba-p/14230016"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T08:48:09.273000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/full-page-fit-vs-scrollable-dashboards-in-sac-which-one-is-better/ba-p/14187381</id>
    <title>Full-Page Fit vs. Scrollable Dashboards in SAC which one is better?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T10:05:42.611000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Siva_Prakash_S</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1721011</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'd like to discuss a common dilemma developers face when it comes to designing a dashboard in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Should I design the dashboard such that it fits entirely within the browser window (Full-Page Fit)? or should I design the dashboard such that it has a scroll?&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Would the customer be okay with having to scroll up and down to see the contents of the dashboard?&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":face_with_rolling_eyes:"&gt;🙄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, the design process begins even before we decide to click Create Story.&lt;BR /&gt;To Tackle this problem, I will be elaborating both the scenarios for you to make an informed decision while designing your next dashboard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Difference between both the Dashboard Fit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assuming we are seeing the dashboard in a normal sized laptop screen [1366 x 768px] not a 1080p HD one. A&amp;nbsp;Full-Page Fit Dashboard&amp;nbsp;ensures all content is visible without scrolling, while a&amp;nbsp;Scrollable Dashboard&amp;nbsp;allows content to extend vertically or horizontally beyond the initial view, requiring user interaction to access additional information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This choice significantly impacts user experience and performance. Both has its own advantages and disadvantages. Let's dive deep to understand the pros and cons of each type.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Full-Page Fit Dashboard: (Everything visible in a single glance)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Full page.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317900i5A90E12A83002CEF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Full page.png" alt="Full page.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Here in the above screenshot, see how all the KPIs presented within a single screen and there is no scroll to the right and bottom of the dashboards. This means that it is well within the boundaries of our 1366 x 768 px canvas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advantages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All KPIs are visible at a single glance, enabling quick decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No need to scroll, which is ideal for users who prefer a single-screen overview.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Each KPI has less room, potentially less real estate and more congestion.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All widgets are triggered simultaneously, sending backend requests that can strain system resources.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Heavy widgets like tables may take longer to load, making the dashboard appear sluggish.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Performance Statistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the KPIs visible in viewport have triggered a backend request and rendered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;It's like going to a restaurant and saying bring me everything you have, even when you know you won't be able to eat everything they bring. Wasteful.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_down:"&gt;👎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Total render time ~9.5s&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Loading Full.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317904iE1D9BEA549328C60/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Loading Full.png" alt="Loading Full.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the visible KPIs have triggered a backend request and are rendered at Frontend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dashboard with Scroll (You gotta scroll to see what you want)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Scroll Section 1" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317901iE6AB518252E0B520/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Scroll1.png" alt="Scroll Section 1" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Scroll Section 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Scroll Section 2" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317902iED81895D82CF2D8D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Scroll2.png" alt="Scroll Section 2" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Scroll Section 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here in the above screenshot, see how we have a scroll to the right of the dashboard. This means that the KPIs are spaced out more and exceeds the page's default height of 768px, therefore the user would get a scroll when accessing the dashboard.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advantages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;More space per KPI allows for better viewability and detailed insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC’s viewport loading ensures only visible widgets are triggered, reducing initial load time and backend traffic.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Less frequently used or heavier components can be placed lower on the page.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users may miss the overall picture and need to scroll to compare KPIs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scrolling back and forth can hinder quick analysis and decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Performance Statistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the KPIs that has been viewed initially have triggered a backend request and rendered. The Un scrolled portion doesn't trigger any backend request neither doesn't render until we preview it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This is like going to the restaurant and placing an order and post eating the main course you get to decide if you want to take on dessert. Only what is required is being consumed here. Resourceful&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_up:"&gt;👍&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Total render time ~8s&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Scroll perfo.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317903i27DD3CCB64A6F510/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Scroll perfo.png" alt="Scroll perfo.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Only KPIs visible during initial preview has been rendered&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding the Middle Ground: Tab Strips&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To balance usability and performance, developers can use&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tab Strip. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These are&amp;nbsp;container widgets used within a SAC story to organize content into separate, switchable tabs.&amp;nbsp;They allow users to view different components, such as charts or tables, within a single application by providing a navigation area to select and display the content of each tab.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tab strip - summary section" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317905iC348C2D7822E0019/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tab1.png" alt="Tab strip - summary section" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Tab strip - summary section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tab strip - Table section" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317906i1CC36323DF17C5D5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tab2.png" alt="Tab strip - Table section" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Tab strip - Table section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here in the above screenshot, see how the dashboard is still fitted within the canvas and also having the benefits of loading what is required.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we have also bifurcated the components into summary and table section. The heavier/Less frequently viewed KPIs are places in the subsequent tab strips, therefore reducing the initial load.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits of Tab Strips&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Essential KPIs are displayed upfront, while heavier or less frequently accessed components (e.g., raw data tables) are placed in separate tabs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC’s default viewport loading ensures only visible components are triggered, reducing backend load and improving responsiveness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tabs offer a cleaner and better UI/UX.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Performance Statistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Only the Default tab strip KPIs have triggered a backend request and has been rendered. The heavier KPIs which hasn't been previewed is still untriggered and unrendered.&lt;BR /&gt;Total render time ~7.5s&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tab perf1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317907i2530B4084DEE5820/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tab perf1.png" alt="Tab perf1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Only the Default tab strip KPIs have triggered a backend request and has been rendered&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Principle: "What You See Is What Loads"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAC's viewport optimization&lt;/U&gt; means that only the visible components are loaded initially. This explains why Full-Page Fit dashboards can be performance intensive as everything is triggered at once. In contrast, scrollable dashboards and tab-based layouts defer loading of non-visible components, enhancing performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;However, it’s important to note that once a user navigates to hidden sections or tabs, those components will be triggered, potentially causing a brief delay.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Take away&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The choice between a Full-Page Fit and a Scrollable Dashboard should be guided by user requirements and usage patterns. Developers must engage with users' early phases in the design process to understand:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which KPIs are most frequently accessed?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is a single-screen overview preferred?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are users comfortable with scrolling or tab navigation?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this article was helpful. Which one do you prefer? Let me know your doubts and opinions in the comments below!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;References:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/managing-performance-in-sap-analytics-cloud/using-the-loading-optimization-setting-on-a-story-level" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using the Loading Optimization Setting on a Story Level&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/full-page-fit-vs-scrollable-dashboards-in-sac-which-one-is-better/ba-p/14187381"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T10:05:42.611000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-foundation-to-future-master-data-management-as-the-fuel-for-gen-ai/ba-p/14237459</id>
    <title>From Foundation to Future: Master Data Management as the Fuel for Gen AI</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T18:52:47.070000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Corrie</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/164966</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In today's fast-paced business landscape, the role of Master Data Management (MDM) has evolved significantly, transitioning from a fundamental process improvement tool to a critical enabler of advanced analytics and AI. Join us for an &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5071369/89EF715DACF727EA399DE330113B0340" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;interactive webinar&lt;/A&gt;, "From Foundation to Future: Master Data Management as the Fuel for Gen AI," where we delve into the evolution of MDM and its pivotal role in empowering next-generation AI technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What to Expect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Introduction to The Hackett Group and Their Latest MDM Study&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kickstarting our session, we will introduce The Hackett Group and share insights from their latest 2025 MDM study. This will set the tone for our detailed discussion on the evolution and impact of Master Data Management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditional Applications of MDM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will then explore the traditional applications of MDM, highlighting its role in business process improvement. Through line-of-business-specific examples, you'll gain a clear understanding of how MDM has been utilized to streamline operations and enhance efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Contemporary MDM Use Cases&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Diving deeper, we will examine more contemporary MDM use cases to illustrate how clean master data drives effective analytics, AI, and ultimately, improved decision-making. These examples will underscore the transformative potential of MDM in today's data-driven world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Master Data Governance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will weave in throughout the capabilities of SAP Master Data Governance, demonstrating its role in achieving operational excellence and accurate analytics. Moreover, we will discuss how AI within MDM is driving new value and accelerating business process excellence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet Our Speakers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bryan DeGraw, Market Intelligence Analyst&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Bryan DeGraw, Market Intelligence Analyst at The Hackett Group, is the author of their MDM Matrix Study. His insights and expertise in MDM will provide a comprehensive understanding of its past, present, and future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Andreas Seifried, SAP MDM Product Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Andreas Seifried, from SAP MDM Product Management, will share his knowledge on how SAP Master Data Governance can fuel enable businesses to stay ahead in the competitive marketplace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why Attend?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Insightful Perspectives: Gain valuable insights from industry experts on the evolution of MDM.&lt;BR /&gt;2. Practical Examples: Learn from real-world examples that demonstrate the impact of MDM on business processes and decision-making.&lt;BR /&gt;3. Future Trends: Understand how MDM is shaping the future of AI and how you can leverage it for your organization.&lt;BR /&gt;4. Interactive Session: Engage with our speakers through Q&amp;amp;A sessions and interactive discussions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register Now!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don't miss out on this opportunity to explore how Master Data Management is impacting the business landscape. &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5071369/89EF715DACF727EA399DE330113B0340" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register now&lt;/A&gt; to stay ahead of the curve and discover how MDM can be the fuel your organization needs to harness the power of Gen AI and secure operational excellence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We look forward to seeing you at the webinar!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-foundation-to-future-master-data-management-as-the-fuel-for-gen-ai/ba-p/14237459"/>
    <published>2025-10-07T18:52:47.070000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-news-in-september/ba-p/14235999</id>
    <title>SAP Datasphere News in September</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T06:00:00.038000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kpsauer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14110</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere News in September&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another month with two nice new release deliveries &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more in my short top features video in September 2025 on YouTube &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":television:"&gt;📺&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, explore the latest updates in our community news blogs and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slide9.PNG" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323393iAC5024206C279836/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Slide9.PNG" alt="Slide9.PNG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761912904"&gt;My top features in September&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1694482118"&gt;Input Parameters in Task Chains and Transformation Flows&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now define input parameters on the task level of task chains and also for transformation flows. &lt;/SPAN&gt;A scheduled transformation flow uses the default value of the input parameter. Input parameters defined in transformation flows can be used in operators within the transformation flow, except for the Python operation in Apache Spark runtime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A transformation flow executed as part of a task chain receives input parameters from the task chain. &lt;SPAN&gt;This will allow for more flexible usage of task chains and even nested task chains.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/f7161e6c20204672ac4a6d90c81762e4.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating a Transformation Flow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/c9906ec515f04fbd9589c59339b03c6c.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating Input Parameters in Task Chains&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497968613"&gt;Email notification in Replication Flows&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can setup email notifications to stay informed when individual replication objects fail in a running replication flow. From both the Replication Flow editor or the Flows monitor, you can setup an email notification for failures of an individual object in a replication flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/5dc4db23d3894b10aca6ade3c666554d.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configure Email Notification for Replication Flow Failure at Object Level&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/da62e1ee746448e8bc043e1be4377cbe.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Working With Existing Replication Flow Runs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301455108"&gt;Fiscal Time Dimension&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When creating a time dimension view, you now have the option for dimension type &lt;EM&gt;Standard&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;Fiscal Time&lt;/EM&gt;. You use the new Fiscal Time dimension type to model your fiscal time periods and the columns that define their starts and ends. When you add a fiscal time dimension to an analytic model, a Fiscal Variant variable is created for this dimension. The variable can then be handled like any other variable. Its data type is derived from the fiscal variance column from the fiscal time dimension.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/5aae0e95361a4a4c964e69c52eada87d.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;More information&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104941603"&gt;Structure Support for Analytic Models&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In order to create restrictions and calculations across all measures of an analytic model, you can create structures. Structures help you to save time and ensure consistency in your calculations, as you don’t need to create a formula/calculation for each measure. &lt;SPAN&gt;In the data preview, the structure members are displayed in their own section. When you use a structure member in the drill-down of a preview, the restriction and calculations defined in the structure member will be applied to each measure. Structures can also be used and enhanced&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;SAP Analytics Cloud. When the analytic model has measures&amp;nbsp;and at least one&amp;nbsp;structure you&amp;nbsp;need to&amp;nbsp;define how the calculations should be prioritized. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/de1ed4742dec44088236131e239df8b9.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;More information&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FkvIhMO5u3Jc%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DkvIhMO5u3Jc&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FkvIhMO5u3Jc%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="SAP Datasphere: Top New Features | September 2025" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779345379"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Getting Started Series&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="kpsauer_0-1759765981803.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323394i3A793FAD592A45FD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="kpsauer_0-1759765981803.jpeg" alt="kpsauer_0-1759765981803.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Starting September 10, the Getting Started Series kicks off with four modules &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Module 1: Build an Intelligent Application Grounded in Data Products (Sep 10, 2025)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Module 2: Fuel AI Innovation with SAP Databricks in Business Data Cloud (Sep 24, 2025)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Module 3: Create and Enrich an Analytical Model with SAP Datasphere (Oct 8, 2025)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Module 4: From Ingredients to Impact: How Döhler built a data fabric for data and AI (Oct 22, 2025)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sign up today on the &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5049141/155E33D499506054AF6FD5A553C2BD38/6298861" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;registration page&lt;/A&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Check out the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/step-by-step-guide-getting-started-with-the-sap-business-data-cloud-basic/ba-p/14172806" target="_blank"&gt;Step-By-Step Guide: Getting started with the SAP Business Data Cloud Basic Trial&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-582831874"&gt;More blogs about SAP BDC and Datasphere to check out &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_down:"&gt;👇&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/integrating-sap-datasphere-with-s-4hana-in-ecs/ba-p/14214268" target="_blank"&gt;Integrating SAP Datasphere with S/4HANA in ECS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/highlights-enterprise-architects-guide-on-sap-bw-modernization/ba-p/14226193" target="_blank"&gt;Highlights: Enterprise Architects Guide on SAP BW Modernization &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/from-rest-to-datasphere-a-cap-based-integration-approach/ba-p/14218922" target="_blank"&gt;From REST to Datasphere: A CAP-based Integration Approach&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/choosing-the-right-sap-analytics-tool-features-benefits-and-strategy/ba-p/14230016" target="_blank"&gt;Choosing the Right SAP Analytics Tool: Features, Benefits, and Strategy&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/archive-sac-change-docs-into-datasphere/ba-p/14229415" target="_blank"&gt;Archive SAC Change Docs into Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/unsupported-features-with-sap-datasphere-live-connections-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14228053" target="_blank"&gt;Unsupported Features with SAP Datasphere Live Connections in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/seeing-skills-before-they-matter-people-intelligence-in-sap-successfactors/ba-p/14226130" target="_blank"&gt;Seeing Skills Before They Matter: People Intelligence in SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/unleashing-creativity-with-cloud-based-ai-apps-2025-premium-hub-coe-high/ba-p/14195307" target="_blank"&gt;Unleashing Creativity with Cloud-Based AI Apps: 2025 Premium Hub CoE High School Summer Orientation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-custom-llm-agent-in-databricks-an-example-generating-ai-responses/ba-p/14223274" target="_blank"&gt;Building Custom LLM Agent in Databricks: An Example Generating AI Responses from Customer Review&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/fortaleza-blog-posts/o-que-%C3%A9-o-sap-datasphere/ba-p/14227147" target="_blank"&gt;O que é o SAP Datasphere?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-integration-with-sap-s-4hana-sap-cloud-connector-setup-guide/ba-p/14224459" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Datasphere Integration with SAP S/4HANA: SAP Cloud Connector Setup Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-amp-analytics-p-amp-a-is-an-essential-part-of-sap-business-data/ba-p/14223762" target="_blank"&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Analytics (P&amp;amp;A) is an essential part of SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/shanghai-blog-posts-%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2/sap-business-data-cloud%E4%B8%AD%E6%96%87%E5%85%A5%E9%97%A8%E5%90%AF%E5%8A%A8%E4%B9%8B%E6%97%85-%E8%A7%86%E9%A2%91%E8%AE%B2%E8%A7%A3/ba-p/14225129" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud中文入门启动之旅 视频讲解&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-from-provisioning-to-intelligent-applications/ba-p/14224669" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud - From Provisioning to Intelligent Applications&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sapinsider-emea-2025-in-three-easy-steps/ba-p/14224371" target="_blank"&gt;SAPinsider EMEA 2025 in Three Easy Steps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/build-a-data-driven-enterprise-with-sap-s-data-amp-analytics-advisory/ba-p/14224035" target="_blank"&gt;Build a Data-Driven Enterprise with SAP’s Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-enterprise-ready-data-products-with-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14223082" target="_blank"&gt;Building Enterprise Ready Data Products with SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/e-learning-sap-datasphere-security-amp-data-access-controls/ba-p/14213412" target="_blank"&gt;E-Learning: SAP Datasphere Security &amp;amp; Data Access Controls&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-blogs/unlocking-a-cleaner-and-greener-energy-future-with-ai/ba-p/14220956" target="_blank"&gt;Unlocking a Cleaner and Greener Energy Future with AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/e-learning-hybrid-integration-between-sap-analytics-cloud-and-sap/ba-p/14211207" target="_blank"&gt;E-Learning: Hybrid integration between SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP BusinessObjects BI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/using-technical-user-in-sap-datasphere-consumption-apis-client-credentials/ba-p/14218919" target="_blank"&gt;Using Technical User in SAP Datasphere Consumption APIs (Client Credentials)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/session-1-recap-amp-highlight-sap-bdc-the-future-of-intelligent-data/ba-p/14218631" target="_blank"&gt;Session 1 Recap &amp;amp; Highlight - SAP BDC The Future of Intelligent Data Architectures&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-add-bw-last-data-update-field-to-sap-analytics-cloud-datasphere-sap/ba-p/14220846" target="_blank"&gt;How to add BW Last Data Update field to SAP Analytics Cloud + Datasphere (SAP Note 2706430)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/erp-centric-planning-with-sap-analytics-cloud-and-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/14214876" target="_blank"&gt;ERP-Centric Planning with SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/ai-assisted-data-quality-screening-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14218695" target="_blank"&gt;AI Assisted Data Quality Screening in SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/e-learning-series-sap-datasphere-connectivity/ba-p/14211076" target="_blank"&gt;E-Learning series: SAP Datasphere Connectivity&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/enabling-the-business-data-fabric-of-sap/ba-p/14212271" target="_blank"&gt;Enabling the Business Data Fabric of SAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-overview-and-guide-to-further-learning-and/ba-p/14211212" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud – Overview and Guide to Further Learning and Resources&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-seguridad-reforzada-ia-aplicada-y-nuevas-alianzas/ba-p/14217615" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP Weekly: seguridad reforzada, IA aplicada y nuevas alianzas estratégicas&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/implementing-sap-emarsys-loyalty-management-part-1/ba-p/14216345" target="_blank"&gt;Implementing SAP Emarsys Loyalty Management - Part 1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/easier-integration-of-sap-cis-with-bdc-sac-dsp-bdcc-with-a-new-identity/ba-p/14165026" target="_blank"&gt;Easier Integration of SAP CIS with BDC (SAC, DSP, BDCC) with a new Identity Provider Administration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/architecting-your-sap-business-data-cloud-journey-from-data-to-intelligence/ba-p/14211958" target="_blank"&gt;Architecting Your SAP Business Data Cloud Journey – From Data to Intelligence!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/practical-guide-how-to-build-sap-analytics-cloud-stories-using-sap/ba-p/14213710" target="_blank"&gt;Practical Guide: How to build SAP Analytics Cloud stories using SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-september-11th-2025/ba-p/14215007" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Developer News September 11th, 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/master-data-management-via-business-data-cloud-datasphere-amp-seamless/ba-p/14197189" target="_blank"&gt;Master Data Management via Business Data Cloud: Datasphere &amp;amp; Seamless Planning in combination&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-sap-enterprise-architecture-amp-business-data-cloud-apac-event/ba-p/14213981" target="_blank"&gt;Join the SAP Enterprise Architecture &amp;amp; Business Data Cloud APAC Event!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-magic-of-attributes-in-sap-ias-default-vs-enrich-assertion/ba-p/14202929" target="_blank"&gt;The Magic of Attributes in SAP IAS: Default vs Enrich Assertion&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-blog-posts/e-learning-sap-datasphere-lifecycle-management/ba-p/14213493" target="_blank"&gt;E-Learning: SAP Datasphere Lifecycle Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tokyo-blog-posts/hotter-than-july-sap-bdc-databricks-jsug-ngb-%E3%82%A4%E3%83%99%E3%83%B3%E3%83%88%E5%8F%82%E5%8A%A0%E3%83%AC%E3%83%9D%E3%83%BC%E3%83%88/ba-p/14213309" target="_blank"&gt;Hotter Than July: SAP BDC × Databricks × JSUG NGB イベント参加レポート&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/partner-learning-managers-blog-posts/win-more-cloud-business-amp-enhance-your-services-with-sap-complementary/ba-p/14208572" target="_blank"&gt;Win more cloud business &amp;amp; enhance your services with SAP® complementary services built for partners&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-series-part-3-customer-managed-data-products/ba-p/14195545" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Series – Part 3: Customer-Managed Data Products&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/modernize-with-sap-business-data-cloud-using-the-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14212128" target="_blank"&gt;Modernize with SAP Business Data Cloud using the SAP Business Data Cloud Modernization Assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-weekly-practical-ai-enhanced-analytics-and-a-vision-for-the-future/ba-p/14211112" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP Weekly: Practical AI, Enhanced Analytics, and a Vision for the Future&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/same-code-different-results-obsolete-version-in-dsp-cache/ba-p/14209466" target="_blank"&gt;Same code, different results. Obsolete Version in DSP cache?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/portuguese-sap-business-data-cloud-sess%C3%B5es-de-expert-guided-implementation/ba-p/14208758" target="_blank"&gt;[Portuguese] SAP Business Data Cloud: Sessões de Expert-Guided Implementation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-partners-fast-track-your-sap-business-technology-platform-certification/ba-p/14194751" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Partners - Fast Track your SAP Business Technology Platform Certification Path&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/demystifying-sap-business-data-cloud-a-simplified-take/ba-p/14181755" target="_blank"&gt;Demystifying SAP Business Data Cloud, A Simplified Take&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-databricks-in-sap-business-data-cloud-a-typical-machine-learning/ba-p/14206612" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Databricks in SAP Business Data Cloud – a Typical Machine Learning Workflow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/restrict-access-of-oauth2-0-clients-with-the-technical-user-purpose/ba-p/14195095" target="_blank"&gt;Restrict Access of OAuth2.0 Clients with the Technical User purpose&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-datasphere-architecture-and-lessons-learned/ba-p/14189930" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Datasphere - Architecture and Lessons-Learned&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="kpsauer_0-1759766213581.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323395iC98529A585B85DFE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="kpsauer_0-1759766213581.png" alt="kpsauer_0-1759766213581.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find more information and related blog posts on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;topic page for SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. You will find further product information on our Community with various subpages about &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere/business-content" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Content&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere/bw-bridge" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BW Bridge&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; as well as content for&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere/best-practices-troubleshooting" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Best Practices &amp;amp; Troubleshooting&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. Also check out the new &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SUPPORT_CONTENT/datasphere/4181116697.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;support content for SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; on SAP Help for troubleshooting and analysis guides, how-to guides, technical details, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find out how to unleash the power of your business data with SAP’s free learning content on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journey/explore-sap-datasphere?source=social-meta-prdteng-ExploreSAPDatasphere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. It’s designed to help you enrich your data projects, simplify the data landscape, and make the most out of your investment. Check out even more role-based learning resources and opportunities to get certified in one place on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Learning site.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-news-in-september/ba-p/14235999"/>
    <published>2025-10-16T06:00:00.038000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sneak-peek-in-to-sap-analytics-cloud-release-for-q4-2025/ba-p/14249322</id>
    <title>Sneak Peek in to SAP Analytics Cloud release for Q4 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T12:51:14.365000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Orla_C</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sneak Peek Q4 2025.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330188i6A63D711CA776939/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Sneak Peek Q4 2025.png" alt="Sneak Peek Q4 2025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hard to believe we are at the final quarter of 2025 and what a year it has been. In this blog we give you a sneak peek into our Top 5 features in SAP Analytics Cloud for QRC4 2025. A full list of what is coming can be found on our&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q4%202025" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q4%202025" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Roadmap Explorer.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Let's dive in!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762949599"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Horizon Theme&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are excited to announce the introduction of the Horizon themes in SAP Analytics Cloud a modern, cohesive visual language aligned across SAP’s product suite. You will have access to Morning and Evening Horizon, the light and dark themes as well as to the high contrast white and black themes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SAC Home Page in Horizon Morning.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330192i9C4338490C950C35/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAC Home Page in Horizon Morning.png" alt="SAC Home Page in Horizon Morning.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more about this and other usability enhancement check out this great &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-horizon-themes-and-usability-enhancements-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14230129" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4718"&gt;@AnnaBurkhardt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566436094"&gt;My Metrics for KPIs Monitoring (formerly known as Watchlist)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A much anticipated new feature is the introduction of My Metrics (fka Watchlist).&amp;nbsp;My Metrics to create lists of metrics that you want to monitor, analyze, and share with other stakeholders. Add to a metrics list from a chart's context menu within a story. You can gain insights of the data changes and organize important metrics associated with your business in an intuitive way. With this new feature users can enjoy:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;New design that enables you to add and monitor your KPIs within SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ability to create, manage, and share your Metric Lists&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ability for viewers to add KPIs directly from stories&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customized comparisons and previews&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="My Metrics.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330194iB78C223A2EF7DDF8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="My Metrics.jpg" alt="My Metrics.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more check out this great &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-my-metrics-your-personalized-view-of-metrics-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14241430" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/719361"&gt;@marouferchichi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1369922589"&gt;Seamless Planning&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have two exciting additions to Seamless Planning this quarter,&amp;nbsp;SAP Datasphere fact view as a live version in a planning model and the ability to Scheduling a story based on a live SAP Datasphere solution connection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's start with the a&lt;SPAN&gt;bility to consume an existing SAP Datasphere fact view live using a separate version dimension element within a planning model:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Version element is available for consumption within stories (read-only in table)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Version element can be used as a source for planning operations, including copy and paste from an external version to a local version, or in batch operations, such as data actions, as a source or reference for copy and calculation operations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SeamlessPlanning_LiveVersions.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330198i5AC7E5B8231967E0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SeamlessPlanning_LiveVersions.jpg" alt="SeamlessPlanning_LiveVersions.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have also added the ability to schedule and deliver a story based on a live connection of SAP Datasphere to users over e-mail through SAP Analytics Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="DSP Scheduling.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330200i6A743A0FAC747D12/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DSP Scheduling.jpg" alt="DSP Scheduling.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;These are just 2 new features in the Seamless Planning story and there are many other in this great &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14553"&gt;@Max_Gander&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1173409084"&gt;Scheduling &amp;amp; Process Management: Factory Calendar&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Staying with planning we also introduce the ability to s&lt;SPAN&gt;chedule calendar tasks and publications based on working days. This includes the ability to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Define a custom property representing workdays as an attribute in a model time dimension&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;View working days within the calendar and Gantt view&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set task recurrence based on working days&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="FactoryCalendar.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330205i54F30E7DD9713268/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FactoryCalendar.jpg" alt="FactoryCalendar.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-976895579"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud Performance Content: Model and audit table sizes&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For administrators and system owners of SAP Analytics Cloud, maintaining a high-performing and stable environment is a top priority. As organizations expand their use of SAC, managing the underlying data volumes becomes increasingly important.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So in this release we are delivering a new Story in SAC Content designed to give you the transparency and control you need to manage your SAC tenant's data footprint effectively. This Story serves as a central overview for monitoring, analyzing, and then to be able to take an informed action on data volumes before they become a critical issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Model Sizes 2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330209i026912DC5B38F13D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Model Sizes 2.jpg" alt="Model Sizes 2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further details check out this great &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-model-size-analysis-in-sac/ba-p/14238307" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/259114"&gt;@thomas_fery&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;There are plenty more exciting deliverables coming your way this quarter and we will be taking a deeper dive into these items in our What’s New video and blog series so stay tuned. For a full list of all features coming in QRC3 2025 for SAP Analytics Cloud check out the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Roadmap Explorer&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/42e4f84a0e5e458792b1047eaf81c31a" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;What's New Viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Want to experience new and existing features for yourself? Take the leap and start your journey towards making data-driven decisions with confidence by signing up for a&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/cloud-analytics/trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;free trial&lt;/A&gt;, today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sneak-peek-in-to-sap-analytics-cloud-release-for-q4-2025/ba-p/14249322"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T12:51:14.365000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/maximize-the-value-of-hr-data-introducing-people-intelligence/ba-p/14252396</id>
    <title>Maximize the value of HR data – Introducing People Intelligence</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T15:28:50.402000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VenkatPS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14765</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;We are excited to introduce people Intelligence in SAP Business Data Cloud – People Intelligence in SAP Business Data Cloud is the new People Analytics solution from SAP based on the fully managed Business Data Cloud that unifies and governs data from SAP SuccessFactors, other SAP and non-SAP sources while preserving its original business context to enable analytics. Designed for HR leaders, HR Business Partners, Managers and many other personas, the solution helps answer some of the most important and critical business questions through prebuilt insight applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The problem&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Data is the new currency and HR data has even more potential but, the reality is that most of this data remains fragmented, scattered across silos, locked in incompatible formats, or inaccessible in real time. This fragmentation hinders agility, quick decision-making, and slows innovation. As HR landscapes evolve rapidly and competition intensifies, companies need more than just access to data—they need clarity, coherence, and the ability to act on insights with confidence and speed. Additional complexities arise when we want to make this data available for powering AI scenarios and enriching the data leveraging machine learning and Data Science capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;To address these data silos and solve these business challenges faced by HR Leaders, we’re introducing People Intelligence – A solution that transforms people, skills, Learning, Recruiting, and talent data into actionable, AI-driven insights. It is a collection of insight Applications around SuccessFactors Core HR, Skills, Recruiting, Learning and talent modules. Many of these insight apps have been built to showcase broad spectrum of insights from these modules and many more to be added covering the other modules as per the published roadmap.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Some of the key Insights that HR leaders can derive through people Intelligence are -&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Talent Flow Analytics,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Knowing if they are building Skills led future-ready organization?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Our investments in learning are improving skills proficiencies and how does it impact employee performance?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are we paying for performance and how is our ethnicity and gender pay gap?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;People Intelligence is built on SAP Business Data Cloud(BDC) &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;As stated earlier, BDC is a fully managed Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) solution designed to unify, govern, and make sense of data across the entire business landscape. It brings together SAP and non-SAP data into one trusted, business-ready foundation—enabling decision-makers access real-time insights with full context. By connecting siloed information through a powerful semantic layer and open data ecosystem, SAP BDC transforms raw data into a strategic asset. BDC brings this powerful functionality of SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, and SAP Business Warehouse, plus managed SAP Databricks, intelligent applications, and data products.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VenkatPS_0-1761292529321.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331896iDB96160E00842D09/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VenkatPS_0-1761292529321.png" alt="VenkatPS_0-1761292529321.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Data Products are curated data sets, the meta data that describes the data set and an API to exchange the data.&lt;BR /&gt;Data Products are then used in realising SAP Datasphere Analytic models that power SAP Analytic Cloud stories or Planning scenarios.&lt;BR /&gt;Each insight App that is part of People Intelligence is based on SAP curated semantic models, which provide customers with tailored insights and actionable recommendations out-of-the-box.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VenkatPS_1-1761292566304.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331897iE88351FBD6BE80D4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VenkatPS_1-1761292566304.png" alt="VenkatPS_1-1761292566304.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;List of Insight Apps delivered as part of People Intelligence GA:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workforce composition Insights&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Visualize workforce composition by role, location, demographics, and org structure, and track how talent flows through the organization by analysing movements, new-hires and terminations data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Skills Insights:&lt;/STRONG&gt; See current employee skills, identify role-level gaps (as-is vs. required proficiency), and track which skills are rising or declining across the organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workforce Compensation(EC based) Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Gain clear compensation visibility by viewing average salaries by role, grade, and location, analysing compa-ratio organization-wide, and comparing pay for terminated employees versus new hires.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recruiting Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Reduce time-to-hire and recruitment costs by uncovering the most effective talent sources and ensuring project success by filling open positions faster.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Drive agility across your teams through targeted trainings that closes essential Skills and Proficiency gaps.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Performance Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Drive productivity and fairness by connecting performance trends to compensation, promotion rate and turnover outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goals Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ensure goal-setting aligns with organizational strategy and includes progress tracking to completion.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Succession Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Build a stronger leadership pipeline by evaluating successor readiness, uncovering risk areas, by refining talent pool readiness and succession strategies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Career Development Planning(CDP) Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Enhance retention and engagement through tailored, actionable insights into employee development goals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Through all of these Insight Apps we have enabled access to Data Analyzer which helps the user with a predefined ready-to-run service for multidimensional, pivot styled ad-hoc analysis using our Datasphere models directly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VenkatPS_2-1761292588953.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331898i44BD95395ACAD3B8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VenkatPS_2-1761292588953.png" alt="VenkatPS_2-1761292588953.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Another notable feature that is made available in all of the Insight Apps is a A/B comparison utility which helps compare key measure values like headcount etc., by bringing them side by side and by selecting dimensions like location, organization unit, job classification etc., This helps the persona discover the headcount changes between the two locations or by the other selected dimensions in an intuitive manner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VenkatPS_3-1761292608395.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331899i6F6ADA58BC8E9B75/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="VenkatPS_3-1761292608395.png" alt="VenkatPS_3-1761292608395.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;People Intelligence – Product Capabilities:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access semantically rich Data Products across all SuccessFactors Modules provided by a scalable SAP managed Data Lake.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access to cross SAP Data Products comprising harmonized data across SAP LOBs discoverable via the central data product catalog.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate Data from non-SAP systems into Business Data Cloud.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Utilize ready to run insights with out-of-the-box analytical models and dashboards for SuccessFactors modules and cross LOB use-cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leverage the power of SAP Business Data Cloud stack to extend the pre-delivered content or create your own analytical application.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable your data engineers and data scientists to perform pro-code data engineering, data science, custom AI/ML and advanced analytics use-cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Close the action to insight gap by bringing analytics into the flow of your users in SuccessFactors via Joule.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;In summary, People Intelligence helps Drive better HR and business performance with proactively delivered, AI-driven insights and help them stay ahead by continually adapting and optimizing with agility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Watch this space for separate blog posts to cover the various insight Apps that we are delivering as part of People Intelligence, the business questions they answer etc.,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Please check the official&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73555000100800004851&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;BC=B9314318771A1EEFBFB783A4FC0A4458#Q4%202025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;BDC Roadmap&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;for a comprehensive overview of forthcoming features not just as part of People Intelligence but also BDC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Resources to know more about People Intelligence:&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Know more about &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/introducing-sap-business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Watch our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/connect/virtual/flow/sap/scv25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1754955548675001MVTr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Success Connect solution deep dive&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(registration required).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Register for our upcoming webinars on People Intelligence: &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-business-suite-webcast-series/en_us/hr.html?source=internal-glo-sapnewsletters-SeptTile#accordion-3553d78c72-item-79fcddbeb8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;"Drive Better Workforce Decisions with a New Approach to People Analytics"&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visit our Website to know more: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/people-intelligence" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/people-intelligence&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Know the potential of People Analytics: IDC Paper: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/protected/default-overlay.html?gated_asset_path=%2F%2Fwww.sap.com%2Fdocuments%2F2025%2F09%2F54fdb4b9-1f7f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.rc.html&amp;amp;pdf-asset=54fdb4b9-1f7f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b&amp;amp;page=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;"How AI-Driven Workforce Insights Unlock Value in the Talent Practice for HR Leaders"&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/maximize-the-value-of-hr-data-introducing-people-intelligence/ba-p/14252396"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T15:28:50.402000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-teched-sessions-in-berlin-and-sydney-2025-by-kp-sauer/ba-p/14251763</id>
    <title>SAP TechEd Sessions in Berlin and Sydney 2025 by KP Sauer</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T17:35:29.715000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kpsauer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14110</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763638761"&gt;SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;One more week to #SAPTechEd 2025.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I am super excited &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt; to speak at this year’s SAP TechEd in Berlin, and also in Sydney for SAP TechEd on Tour.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;🤩 Looking forward to meet and talk to all you data and analytics experts in Berlin or Sydney.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join me for a variety of sessions this year and gain a comprehensive understanding of our strategic direction and priorities with SAP Business Data Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567125256"&gt;SAP TechEd in Berlin&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1628777189"&gt;Deep Dive Sessions&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;DA204 | The impact of SAP Business Data Cloud on SAP Datasphere users&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session is for all users of SAP Datasphere to better understand the impact with SAP Business Data Cloud and the new options you get within such a new landscape. Rithivika Acharya will give you a demo and we will have some time for Q&amp;amp;A at the end&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753913915410001RQyH" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753913915410001RQyH&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DA204.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331601iCEA9ABE801466DB8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DA204.png" alt="DA204.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;DA203 | SAP Business Data Cloud: The path forward for SAP Business Warehouse&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session is for all users of SAP BW or BW/4HANA to better understand the impact with SAP Business Data Cloud and exploring the best practices for modernizing with such a new landscape. Domink Kurz will mainly talk here and we will have some time for Q&amp;amp;A at the end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753910209205001V1Vm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753910209205001V1Vm&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="kpsauer_0-1761224561237.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331602i4055646C57CAFD1F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="kpsauer_0-1761224561237.png" alt="kpsauer_0-1761224561237.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1432263684"&gt;Hands-on Workshop&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;DA264 | SAP Business Data Cloud: Explore the analytical components end to end&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This beginner hands-on workshop takes you through the analytical components of the SAP Business Data Cloud solution. Use the SAP Datasphere and SAP Analytics Cloud solutions to design and build custom scenarios from beginning to end. This session is ideal for technical users seeking to transform data into meaningful business insights. I will be hosting this together with Hannes Keil, Daniel Ingenhaag and Florian Neukirch.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754056240863001fO9w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754056240863001fO9w&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="kpsauer_1-1761224580227.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331603i908E9B49B0383441/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="kpsauer_1-1761224580227.png" alt="kpsauer_1-1761224580227.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are you ready? &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Register now: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977584741"&gt;SAP TechEd on Tour in Sydney&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Sydney I will be talking live about &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;DA806 | SAP Business Data Cloud Solution Road Map&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join me and gain a comprehensive understanding of our strategic direction and priorities with SAP Business Data Cloud. Find out about the product road map and ongoing development in key areas. Learn about our plans to continue to deliver innovation to aid in your data strategy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DA806.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331611iE0B2C1D3ABDBC63C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DA806.jpg" alt="DA806.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;DA100 | An Introduction to SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join us for an insightful overview of SAP Business Data Cloud. Discover the key capabilities including seamless integration of SAP and non-SAP data sources, the data product concept, and analytics-ready data across your organization. Learn how SAP Business Data Cloud supports agile decision-making, simplifies complex data challenges, and drives digital transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="DA100.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331613iAA8C010F4A4BB191/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="DA100.jpg" alt="DA100.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other than these sessions I will be around the show floor and support hands-on sessions too.&lt;BR /&gt;So please be welcome to talk to me as I’m happy to share my SAP experience during the three days &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":loudspeaker:"&gt;📢&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Passes to Mastering SAP Collaborate, an SAP TechEd on Tour event, are available online now – join me in Sydney on 12 – 14 November!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Program and passes at &lt;A href="http://sapteched.sydney/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;http://sapteched.sydney&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; and best of all you can use code SPEAKER5OFF to save 5% on a pass.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":spiral_calendar:"&gt;🗓&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; When: 12 - 14 November 2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":round_pushpin:"&gt;📍&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; Where: International Convention Centre, ICC, Darling Harbour, Sydney&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Related community &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;topic pages&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/business-data-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud | SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere | SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/cloud-analytics" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud | SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Looking forward to seeing you in Berlin and Sydney!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Now let’s hear from you&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What is your favorite feature in SAP Datasphere?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do you already have any plans for SAP Business Data Cloud or are you waiting to adopt?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Please add your thoughts as comments to this blog. Thanks!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-teched-sessions-in-berlin-and-sydney-2025-by-kp-sauer/ba-p/14251763"/>
    <published>2025-10-27T17:35:29.715000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/integration-between-sap-cpi-and-sap-datasphere-jdbc-connection/ba-p/14256236</id>
    <title>Integration Between SAP CPI and SAP DataSphere (JDBC Connection)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T08:17:01.679000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2190179</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration Between SAP CPI and SAP DataSphere (JDBC Connection)&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;JDBC – JAVA DATABASE CONNECTIVITY&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Why Recommendation for JDBC Over OData API :&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;JDBC is recommended over OData when consuming large-scale records (e.g., 100,000+) because JDBC streams data directly from the database with better performance and less overhead, while OData is optimized for lightweight, paginated, service-based access.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Problem statement: &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/en/3337495" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3337495 - OData API returns less records than expected due paging&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Pagination limits in OData and Ariba APIs can be handled in SAP CPI using a looping process call. I’ll cover this with a clear explanation in an upcoming post.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;G&lt;STRONG&gt;oal:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Connect CPI to a database used by DataSphere (JDBC) and run a simple read data from the (Analytical Model / Table /View). &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;For the Write / Delete / Update method, the attached SAP Help Portal Link has syntax in the reference section.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP DataSphere&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Subscribed account (⚠ Trial has limited features, JDBC not supported)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Subscribed or Trial (JDBC actions supported)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP DataSphere Step by Step Guide :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Action / Notes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Create a Space&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DataSphere → Space Management → &lt;EM&gt;New Space&lt;/EM&gt; → Name it → Create.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Create Table / Analytical Model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Builder → In your Space → &lt;EM&gt;New&lt;/EM&gt; → Table or Analytical Model → define fields &amp;amp; data types → Save &amp;amp; Publish.&lt;BR /&gt;*Verify Table/Model Deployed Successfully. *&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Prepare / Load Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Load data manually for testing cases. Otherwise load CSV/import to table via Data Builder/Data Integration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Note Schema &amp;amp; Object Names&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Record schema name, table name, and view names for JDBC SQL use.&lt;BR /&gt;* Created space name is the SCHEMA name and Collect Table / Model name *&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. Decide Where to Create DB User&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If HANA Cloud → use HANA Cockpit/DB Explorer. If on-prem DB → use DB admin tools or contact DB Admin.&lt;BR /&gt;* We are using the HANA cloud system for practical session*&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6. Create JDBC DB User&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DB admin tool → Security/Users → &lt;EM&gt;New User&lt;/EM&gt; → set username &amp;amp; strong password → Save.&lt;BR /&gt;*Check Active status of User*&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7. Grant Privileges for the DB user&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Assign only required privileges (e.g., &lt;STRONG&gt;SELECT&lt;/STRONG&gt; for read; add &lt;STRONG&gt;INSERT/UPDATE/DELETE&lt;/STRONG&gt; for CRUD). Best practice: create role &lt;/SPAN&gt;JDBC_ROLE&lt;SPAN&gt; and assign.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;8. Prepare JDBC Connection Details&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Gather JDBC URL (e.g. &amp;nbsp;sample URL from datasphere: z*********-abc.hana.prod-eu10.hanacloud.ondemand.com&lt;BR /&gt;Format for CPI JDBC Material:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;jdbc:sap://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;/?encrypt=true&amp;amp;validateCertificate=true&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite Step by Step Guide :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create a Package &amp;amp; Artifact&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In CPI → &lt;EM&gt;Design&lt;/EM&gt; → Create a new package → Add an integration flow artifact.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; Make sure your CPI user has the required roles to create and access design-time artifacts.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Go to Monitoring → JDBC Material&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In CPI → &lt;EM&gt;Monitor&lt;/EM&gt; → Integrations and APIs → Manage Security → JDBC Material&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_9-1761743104479.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333936i6D0241B617F00B77/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_9-1761743104479.png" alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_9-1761743104479.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;→ Add &lt;EM&gt;JDBC Data Source. &lt;/EM&gt;→ Select HANA cloud &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_10-1761743104489.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333937iE85BFA171AC5354A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_10-1761743104489.png" alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_10-1761743104489.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide JDBC URL in the correct format (e.g., jdbc:sap://&amp;lt;hana-host&amp;gt;:443/?encrypt=true&amp;amp;validateCertificate=true).&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_11-1761743104501.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333938i78679B85543ED506/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_11-1761743104501.png" alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_11-1761743104501.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter DB username and password (use the dedicated JDBC user created earlier in DataSphere).&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_12-1761743104508.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333940iFF24BD979E951623/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_12-1761743104508.png" alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_12-1761743104508.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save and deploy the JDBC material.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apply JDBC Material in iFlow&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your integration flow, configure the JDBC receiver adapter → select the JDBC data source created.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use SQL queries (SELECT) in the &lt;EM&gt;Processing tab&lt;/EM&gt; or provide XML query body. &lt;SPAN&gt;Here, I’m using SQL &lt;/SPAN&gt;SELECT * to&lt;SPAN&gt; fetch all records from the table.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_13-1761743104513.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333939i0C4A23EA2DD7435A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_13-1761743104513.png" alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_13-1761743104513.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Timer Start &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;In this iFlow, the Start Timer is configured with a Simple Schedule → None → On Deployment, which means the integration flow automatically triggers immediately after deployment.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_14-1761743104520.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333941iB3F7F36AA2A7DE16/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_14-1761743104520.png" alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_14-1761743104520.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Content Modifier&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Use this SQL query to fetch all records with the body operation.&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;SELECT * FROM "&amp;lt;Schema&amp;gt;"."&amp;lt;Model/TableName&amp;gt;"&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_15-1761743104527.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333943i58EEBA8EA1D3F197/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_15-1761743104527.png" alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_15-1761743104527.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Request Reply &amp;amp; JDBC Receiver Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;→ Use the deployed JDBC Data Source alias in the JDBC Material in the previous step and set Max records count based on your requirement.&lt;BR /&gt;→ JDBC Maximum Records per call:&amp;nbsp; 2,147,483,647&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_16-1761743104534.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333944i6290D296884CAE5A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_16-1761743104534.png" alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_16-1761743104534.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Sample data Response from JDBC Connection:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_17-1761743104538.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/333942iC7431EDC092521C8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_17-1761743104538.png" alt="MUGILAN_KANAGARAJ_17-1761743104538.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;References :&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;same blog by me for clear picture quality:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/integration-of-sap-cpi-and-sap-datasphere-using-jdbc/qaq-p/14256172" target="_blank"&gt;Integration of SAP CPI and SAP DataSphere using JD... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;CPI JDBC – XML Query in Body for CRUD Operations (Syntax Guide)&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;link:&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/payload-and-operation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/cloud-integration/sap-cloud-integration/payload-and-operation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/integration-between-sap-cpi-and-sap-datasphere-jdbc-connection/ba-p/14256236"/>
    <published>2025-10-31T08:17:01.679000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-news-in-october/ba-p/14258069</id>
    <title>SAP Datasphere News in October</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T06:30:00.036000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kpsauer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14110</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere News in October&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another month with a great new release delivery &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":sparkles:"&gt;✨&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more in my short top features video in October2025 on YouTube &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":television:"&gt;📺&lt;/span&gt; also including an outlook at SAP TechEd session this year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, explore the latest updates in our community news blogs and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="kpsauer_0-1761924309739.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334798i6A01E6965243EEBC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="kpsauer_0-1761924309739.png" alt="kpsauer_0-1761924309739.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763840577"&gt;My top features in October&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1696409791"&gt;Impact of Changes in the Source Objects of an Analytic Model&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Changing, saving, and re-deploying a data builder object again will trigger a status change of any analytic model that uses that object. The analytic model status will change to either “Changes to Deploy” or “Design Time Error”, depending on which change has been made (compatible or incompatible changes). This gives you better transparency in change control handling of your models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499896286"&gt;Converting a Data Flow Into a Replication Flow and/or Transformation Flow&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When your data flow is eligible to be converted into a transformation flow or a replication flow coupled with a transformation flow, a banner will be displayed in the data flow editor. Using a replication flow and/or a transformation flow will allow you to benefit from improved connectivity, access to delta load processing, and enhanced resiliency and scalability.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/34ae0a2ea6e94483b19f632a2843d56d.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;More information&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1303382781"&gt;Technical User to Manage Tasks via CLI&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can now use OAuth clients with the technical user purpose to manage tasks via the command line interface based on the roles and spaces you assign to the client.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/d4185d7d9a634d06a5459c214792c67e/2b26a31f197444dea314495bc0008eae.html?version=cloud&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;More information&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F-E6Ah1ZGCfA%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D-E6Ah1ZGCfA&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F-E6Ah1ZGCfA%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="SAP Datasphere: Top New Features | October 2025" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977786557"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are many sessions about SAP Business Data Cloud and also SAP Datasphere at SAP TechEd 2025. Some are part of the virtual TechEd and others like for instance the onsite hands-on sessions are exclusive for people attending in Berlin.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP BDC @Japan night__.gif" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334802iA58A71DDA358FF90/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP BDC @Japan night__.gif" alt="SAP BDC @Japan night__.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-781273052"&gt;My favorite blogs in October&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;My colleague &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14553"&gt;@Max_Gander&lt;/a&gt; wrote two nice blogs about the new feature with live versions in planning, which I think is a one of the best features I have seen all next to seamless planning itself:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/live-versions-from-an-sql-source-for-sap-analytics-cloud-planning/ba-p/14245675" target="_blank"&gt;Live Versions from an SQL Source for SAP Analytics Cloud Planning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864" target="_blank"&gt;Unlocking the Next Chapter of Seamless Planning in SAP Business Data Cloud with Live Versions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;People Intelligence is one of the latest applications offered as part of SAP Business Data Cloud.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/3843"&gt;@blberger&lt;/a&gt; has written a informative blog about its general availability and offers many useful links to further details about this offering:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/maximize-the-value-of-hr-data-introducing-people-intelligence/ba-p/14252396" target="_blank"&gt;Maximize the value of HR data – Introducing People Intelligence&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14765"&gt;@VenkatPS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;is looking at the same topic from a use case perspective and explains the problems which can be solved using this application:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/delivery-blog-posts/people-intelligence-in-sap-business-data-cloud-is-generally-available/ba-p/14240825" target="_blank"&gt;People Intelligence in SAP Business Data Cloud is Generally Available!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36635"&gt;@hozumi&lt;/a&gt;highlight another interesting capability we recently delivered as part of SAP BDC, which is called BDC Connect and it helps expand the zero copy delta sharing to external systems:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-bdc-connect-sap-elevates-bidirectional-zero-copy-data-sharing-with-game/ba-p/14244067" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BDC Connect: SAP elevates bidirectional zero-copy data sharing with game-changing partnerships&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Keep on brining these valuable blogs &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1410810"&gt;@FernandaFroelich&lt;/a&gt;. On the one hand she extend her blog series on SAP Databricks by looking more detailed on user and roles with Databricks:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/get-started-with-sap-databricks-users-and-roles/ba-p/14231027" target="_blank"&gt;Get started with SAP Databricks: Users and roles&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;On the other hand, she helps you to better understand the consumption monitoring in SAP BDC:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-monitor-consumption-for-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-and-its/ba-p/14257413" target="_blank"&gt;How to monitor consumption for SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) and its components?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-584759547"&gt;More blogs about SAP BDC and Datasphere to check out &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_down:"&gt;👇&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/integration-between-sap-cpi-and-sap-datasphere-jdbc-connection/ba-p/14256236" target="_blank"&gt;Integration Between SAP CPI and SAP DataSphere (JDBC Connection)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/bw-data-product-generator-to-databricks-enterprise-capability/ba-p/14251192" target="_blank"&gt;BW Data Product Generator to Databricks Enterprise Capability&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-monitor-consumption-for-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-and-its/ba-p/14257413" target="_blank"&gt;How to monitor consumption for SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) and its components?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-your-transition-paths-to-sap-business-data-cloud-data-architecture/ba-p/14257176" target="_blank"&gt;Planning your transition paths to SAP Business Data Cloud (data architecture miniseries)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/leading-sap-business-warehouse-modernization-as-a-solution-architect-data/ba-p/14256656" target="_blank"&gt;Leading SAP Business Warehouse modernization as a Solution Architect (data architecture miniseries)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/from-sap-datasphere-to-a-local-llm-llama-3-1-hands-on-tutorial/ba-p/14253357" target="_blank"&gt;From SAP Datasphere to a Local LLM (Llama 3.1) — Hands-On Tutorial&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/converting-fsv-financial-statement-version-into-a-flattened-structure-using/ba-p/14253164" target="_blank"&gt;Converting FSV (Financial Statement Version) into a Flattened Structure using Python&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-bridges-between-sap-and-databricks-a-dream-team-for-your-data-and/ba-p/14255167" target="_blank"&gt;Building Bridges Between SAP and Databricks: A Dream Team for Your Data and AI-Powered Analytics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unpacking-sap-business-data-cloud-for-solution-architects-data-architecture/ba-p/14255350" target="_blank"&gt;Unpacking SAP Business Data Cloud for Solution Architects (data architecture miniseries)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-maxattention-blog-posts/sap-maxattention-summit-2026-shaping-the-future-of-enterprise-innovation/ba-p/14252333" target="_blank"&gt;SAP MaxAttention Summit 2026: Shaping the Future of Enterprise Innovation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-sap/maximize-the-value-of-hr-data-introducing-people-intelligence/ba-p/14252396" target="_blank"&gt;Maximize the value of HR data – Introducing People Intelligence&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-teched-sessions-in-berlin-and-sydney-2025-by-kp-sauer/ba-p/14251763" target="_blank"&gt;SAP TechEd Sessions in Berlin and Sydney 2025 by KP Sauer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/human-capital-management-blog-posts-by-members/people-intelligence-for-successfactors-what-it-is-and-why-it-matters/ba-p/14252869" target="_blank"&gt;People Intelligence for SuccessFactors – What It Is and Why It Matters&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/launch-your-data-science-platform-with-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14250546" target="_blank"&gt;Launch your Data Science Platform with SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/developer-news/sap-developer-news-23rd-october-2025/ba-p/14251875" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Developer News 23rd October, 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-data-and-analytics-value-map-on-sap-community/ba-p/14249416" target="_blank"&gt;Join the Data and Analytics Value Map on SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-teched-virtual-business-data-cloud-session-recommendations/ba-p/14248738" target="_blank"&gt;SAP TechEd Virtual Business Data Cloud Session Recommendations&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-my-metrics-your-personalized-view-of-metrics-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14241430" target="_blank"&gt;Introducing My Metrics: Your Personalized view of Metrics in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-on-the-sap-analytics-cloud-homepage-2025-q4-qrc-enhancements/ba-p/14234040" target="_blank"&gt;What’s New on the SAP Analytics Cloud Homepage: 2025 Q4 QRC Enhancements!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sneak-peek-in-to-sap-analytics-cloud-release-for-q4-2025/ba-p/14249322" target="_blank"&gt;Sneak Peek in to SAP Analytics Cloud release for Q4 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-horizon-themes-and-usability-enhancements-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14230129" target="_blank"&gt;Introducing Horizon Themes and Usability Enhancements in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-bdc-connect-sap-elevates-bidirectional-zero-copy-data-sharing-with-game/ba-p/14244067" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BDC Connect: SAP elevates bidirectional zero-copy data sharing with game-changing partnerships&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/implementing-sap-emarsys-loyalty-management-part-2-technical-deep-dive/ba-p/14247872" target="_blank"&gt;Implementing SAP Emarsys Loyalty Management – Part 2 (Technical Deep Dive)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/re-wire-your-existing-sap-datasphere-tenant-from-sap-btp-to-sap-bdc/ba-p/14247423" target="_blank"&gt;Re-wire your existing SAP Datasphere Tenant from SAP BTP to SAP BDC&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-teched-berlin-2025-sap-business-data-cloud-data-products-master-data/ba-p/14246937" target="_blank"&gt;SAP TechEd Berlin 2025: SAP Business Data Cloud: Data products, master data, governance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-%E3%82%AB%E3%82%B9%E3%82%BF%E3%83%A0%E3%83%87%E3%83%BC%E3%82%BF%E3%83%97%E3%83%AD%E3%83%80%E3%82%AF%E3%83%88%E3%81%AE%E4%BD%9C%E6%88%90/ba-p/14235138" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud: カスタムデータプロダクトの作成&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/delivery-blog-posts/people-intelligence-in-sap-business-data-cloud-is-generally-available/ba-p/14240825" target="_blank"&gt;People Intelligence in SAP Business Data Cloud is Generally Available!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/parameterized-task-chains-what-you-can-and-can-t-do/ba-p/14245534" target="_blank"&gt;Parameterized Task Chains: What You Can and Can’t Do&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/live-versions-from-an-sql-source-for-sap-analytics-cloud-planning/ba-p/14245675" target="_blank"&gt;Live Versions from an SQL Source for SAP Analytics Cloud Planning&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-seamless-planning-model-design-principles-compared-to-sap-bw/ba-p/14242687" target="_blank"&gt;SAC seamless planning: Model design principles - compared to SAP BW&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-bdc-enhance-a-bw-data-product-with-sap-databricks/ba-p/14242606" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BDC - Enhance a BW Data product with SAP Databricks&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864" target="_blank"&gt;Unlocking the Next Chapter of Seamless Planning in SAP Business Data Cloud with Live Versions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/building-ai-ready-life-sciences-enterprise-with-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14242504" target="_blank"&gt;Building AI Ready Life Sciences Enterprise with SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/key-planning-amp-analytics-components-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc/ba-p/14238066" target="_blank"&gt;Key Planning &amp;amp; Analytics components of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/sap-business-data-cloud-create-a-custom-data-product-based-on-a-replication/ba-p/14238555" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud - Create a custom Data Product based on a replication Flow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/step-by-step-implementing-generative-ai-with-sap-hana-cloud/ba-p/14231548" target="_blank"&gt;Step-by-Step: Implementing Generative AI with SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-connect-to-sap-ibp-from-sap-datasphere-using-odata/ba-p/14233734" target="_blank"&gt;How to Connect to SAP IBP from SAP Datasphere using OData&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/provisioning-sap-business-data-cloud-connect-and-enrolling-with-existing/ba-p/14237512" target="_blank"&gt;Provisioning SAP Business Data Cloud Connect and Enrolling with Existing Databricks&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-foundation-to-future-master-data-management-as-the-fuel-for-gen-ai/ba-p/14237459" target="_blank"&gt;From Foundation to Future: Master Data Management as the Fuel for Gen AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-btp-q3-2025/ba-p/14235530" target="_blank"&gt;What's New in SAP BTP - Q3 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extend-existing-planning-scenarios-of-sap-bpc-bw-ip-in-sap-bdc/ba-p/14234247" target="_blank"&gt;Extend existing planning scenarios of SAP BPC/ BW-IP in SAP BDC&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-and-customer-updates/exciting-news-people-intelligence-is-now-generally-available/ba-p/14234867" target="_blank"&gt;Exciting News: People Intelligence is Now Generally Available!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-customer-onboarding-newsletter-october-2025/ba-p/14233774" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP Customer Onboarding Newsletter October 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-analytics-cloud-modeling-extensions-amp-integration-qrc4/ba-p/14208685" target="_blank"&gt;What's New in SAP Analytics Cloud Modeling Extensions &amp;amp; Integration QRC4 2025 Release&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/get-started-with-sap-databricks-users-and-roles/ba-p/14231027" target="_blank"&gt;Get started with SAP Databricks: Users and roles&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-maxattention-blog-posts/from-strategy-to-impact-tqm-multiplier-week-2025-highlights/ba-p/14230628" target="_blank"&gt;From Strategy to Impact: TQM Multiplier Week 2025 Highlights&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-data-and-analytics-forum-18-19-11-2025/ba-p/14232575" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Data and Analytics Forum 18.-19.11.2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-enterprise-support-academy-newsletter-october-2025/ba-p/14232476" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Academy Newsletter October 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/fast-track-your-transition-to-sap-business-data-cloud-%EF%B8%8F/ba-p/14232169" target="_blank"&gt;Fast Track Your Transition to SAP Business Data Cloud!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="kpsauer_0-1761924614923.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334799i9C6F5F225AE081E3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="kpsauer_0-1761924614923.png" alt="kpsauer_0-1761924614923.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find more information and related blog posts on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;topic page for SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. You will find further product information on our Community with various subpages about &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere/business-content" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Content&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere/bw-bridge" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BW Bridge&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; as well as content for&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/datasphere/best-practices-troubleshooting" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Best Practices &amp;amp; Troubleshooting&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. Also check out the new &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SUPPORT_CONTENT/datasphere/4181116697.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;support content for SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; on SAP Help for troubleshooting and analysis guides, how-to guides, technical details, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find out how to unleash the power of your business data with SAP’s free learning content on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journey/explore-sap-datasphere?source=social-meta-prdteng-ExploreSAPDatasphere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. It’s designed to help you enrich your data projects, simplify the data landscape, and make the most out of your investment. Check out even more role-based learning resources and opportunities to get certified in one place on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Learning site.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-datasphere-news-in-october/ba-p/14258069"/>
    <published>2025-11-04T06:30:00.036000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-becomes-agentic-introducing-discovery-agent-amp-data-agent/ba-p/14257394</id>
    <title>SAP HANA Cloud Becomes Agentic: Introducing Discovery Agent &amp; Data Agent</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T16:40:36.221000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shabana</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/38259</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="teched banners.gif" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336047i763DFACC5EDC6127/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="teched banners.gif" alt="teched banners.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Challenge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enterprises today work with massive volumes of data spread across tables, views, JSON collections, graphs, and text. Yet most users don’t know where that data lives or how to access it efficiently. Building a bridge between business questions and the underlying technical data model often requires deep schema knowledge and SQL expertise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the same time, users expect to “talk to their data”, to search, ask, and get answers without navigating complex structures. But creating such experiences has often been challenging. Data is often siloed, metadata is hard to navigate, and the context needed to connect insights is missing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Innovation: Discovery Agent and Data Agent in SAP HANA Cloud (planned QRC1 2026)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP HANA Cloud takes a major step forward by becoming &lt;STRONG&gt;agentic&lt;/STRONG&gt; and introducing a suite of agents designed to simplify how people discover and interact with data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, the focus will be on the &lt;STRONG&gt;Discovery Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;Together, they make it easier for agent users to find the right data objects, understand relationships, and generate the right queries, all without needing deep technical or SQL knowledge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="agents.png" style="width: 643px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336166iD48FFF346415F224/image-dimensions/643x304/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="643" height="304" role="button" title="agents.png" alt="agents.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discovery Agent: Exploring data context &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Discovery Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; helps users find and understand the data available in SAP HANA Cloud. It explores the HANA catalog using a Knowledge Graph that exposes how objects relate to one another, making it easy to locate relevant datasets without manually browsing schemas. When users describe what they need, like for example, project details or customer transactions, the Discovery Agent can identify the right data sources based on context, relationships, and annotations. Under the hood, the agent generates SPARQL queries on the RDF graph of HANA objects, revealing how data structures connect.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Agent: Turning intent into executable queries&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the relevant data objects are found, the &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; takes over.&lt;BR /&gt;It translates natural language intent into executable queries, such as SQL. Users can simply describe what they want to retrieve, for instance, “show my current projects with partner involvement” and the Data Agent generates and executes the corresponding query.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By combining discovery and query generation, these agents make data exploration seamless: the Discovery Agent provides context, while the Data Agent delivers answers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Powered by the SAP HANA Cloud Custom Database Objects Knowledge Graph (planned QRC1 2026)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the core of these agents lies the &lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Database Objects Knowledge Graph:&lt;/STRONG&gt; an RDF graph automatically built from system catalog that captures tables, columns, relationships, and annotations. It provides the semantic layer needed for exploration, AI grounding, and graph-based reasoning, forming the foundation for richer, AI ready data discovery in SAP HANA Cloud. What used to take days of manual modeling can now be done automatically in minutes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Create a custom database objects knowledge graph on SAP HANA Cloud Central" style="width: 807px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334838i47E5B2285039F439/image-dimensions/807x394/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="807" height="394" role="button" title="Create KG.jpg" alt="Create a custom database objects knowledge graph on SAP HANA Cloud Central" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Create a custom database objects knowledge graph on SAP HANA Cloud Central&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This Knowledge Graph allows agents to reason about data, to understand how entities connect, what relationships exist, and which attributes are relevant. It is the foundation that enables both discovery and querying to work contextually and at scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="agentic.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/336164iE4A2B83DEB5B047B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agentic.png" alt="agentic.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How It Works&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine a business user who doesn’t know the database schema or table names, they simply have a question in mind and want to “talk to the database.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, they might ask: &lt;EM&gt;“List all customers with their sales conversion probability and related details?”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s what happens behind the scenes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Discovery Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; searches the Database Objects Knowledge Graph to identify which tables and views contain the relevant data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; then uses that information to generate a query that retrieves the results without any manual lookup or SQL writing required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In a few seconds, the user receives a clear answer. The process feels conversational, even though the agents are performing complex discovery and query generation under the hood.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Ask a Natural Language Query on your database objects, via Joule in SAP HANA Cloud Central" style="width: 788px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334839i2BC1ECBBEE39420B/image-dimensions/788x388/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="788" height="388" role="button" title="Asking NLQ.jpg" alt="Ask a Natural Language Query on your database objects, via Joule in SAP HANA Cloud Central" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Ask a Natural Language Query on your database objects, via Joule in SAP HANA Cloud Central&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Explore insights built on the actual database objects and relationships in your SAP HANA Cloud instance." style="width: 812px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334840i3A29FE45C4D21714/image-dimensions/812x391/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="812" height="391" role="button" title="Asking NLQ 2.jpg" alt="Explore insights built on the actual database objects and relationships in your SAP HANA Cloud instance." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Explore insights built on the actual database objects and relationships in your SAP HANA Cloud instance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enables Data Discovery &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the Discovery and Data Agents, SAP HANA Cloud transforms metadata into a living semantic layer that spans its multi-model engines. The “agent users” can now query their data environment conversationally, explore hidden relationships, and even surface annotations and sample values to guide analytics. Together, these agents transform SAP HANA Cloud from a static data platform into a dynamic environment where users can reason, explore, and interact with data naturally.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Looking Ahead: Context and Memory for Agents (Product Vision)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The journey toward an agentic SAP HANA Cloud is just beginning. As these capabilities evolve, &lt;STRONG&gt;context and long-term memory&lt;/STRONG&gt; will play a key role in shaping the next generation of agents. Future agents will not only discover and query data but also retain context from previous interactions, remembering what was asked, which datasets were used, and what outcomes were returned. Over time, this could enable more natural and connected conversations with data, where insights evolve instead of starting from scratch each time.&lt;BR /&gt;This concept of &lt;STRONG&gt;Agentic Memory&lt;/STRONG&gt; will help create more continuous and connected user experiences, all while leveraging HANA Cloud’s trusted data management and governance foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, these agents make SAP HANA Cloud the foundation for a new generation of secure, context-aware, and agent-driven data experiences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For agent users, this means:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A unified way to access data and metadata.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Natural-language querying through familiar protocols (&lt;A href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/docs/getting-started/intro" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;MCP&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The potential for context persistence across multi-turn conversations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A path toward AI-grounded data exploration and graph-enhanced analytics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;With that, it’s certain: &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA Cloud is THE database for SAP’s AI-native software architecture.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;For additional updates and announcements from SAP TechEd 2025, check&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781"&gt;@thomashammer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;'s blogpost &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-next-with-sap-hana-cloud-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14258163" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-becomes-agentic-introducing-discovery-agent-amp-data-agent/ba-p/14257394"/>
    <published>2025-11-04T16:40:36.221000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/agentic-databases-for-data-scientists-sap-hana-cloud-will-equip-you-with-a/ba-p/14265823</id>
    <title>Agentic Databases for Data Scientists: SAP HANA Cloud Will Equip You with a Team</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T20:30:25.347000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel_Dukes</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/41370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;During my tenure as a data practitioner, I often preferred my own database to produce mission-critical calculations. The journey of such an analysis usually began with a single purpose, like informing a business process manager or a change of parameters to optimize a back-end process. Regardless of the original scope, the need to operationalize the logic often followed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="data professional in front of two monitors" style="width: 600px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338852i40DE60B899FA4844/image-dimensions/600x343/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="600" height="343" role="button" title="data_scientist_in_front_of_two_monitors.png" alt="data professional in front of two monitors" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;data professional in front of two monitors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Moonlighting as a DBA was nice, admittedly, because I could manage my databases with minimal process obstacles . However, the time lost searching documentation and stuck in trial-error loops of administrative commands only increased the delivery pressure, as deadlines are often unforgiving. I very quickly learned that while I was certainly capable of performing a dual role, I could not be great at both. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;The expectations of my job demanded data analysis excellence, while I desperately sought after administrative competency&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Last week at &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/A&gt;, the SAP HANA Cloud team made a few significant announcements. One very notable set of features is the introduction of the agentic database concept. Simply illustrated and grounded in my scenario, the use of AI agents could give me the best of both worlds – autonomy and scale. Applying the example, imagine the productivity benefits associated with giving every data science professional a dedicated team of agentic colleagues – administrator, data analyst, and a multi-model specialist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SAP HANA Cloud agents" style="width: 600px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/338897i8814662680CBEF1F/image-dimensions/600x369/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="600" height="369" role="button" title="sap_hana_cloud_agents.png" alt="SAP HANA Cloud agents" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud agents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;F&lt;SPAN&gt;or those who prefer the native use of a database, consider the upcoming agentic features of SAP HANA Cloud:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The discovery agent provides insight into the objects within the database using a knowledge graph for more efficient semantic lookups.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The multi-model agent augments with the specialist knowledge needed to use the advanced analysis engines.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The data agent supplements the need for SQL with natural language queries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The admin agent assists with the analysis and optimization of the database.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud enhances all data professionals with agentic teammates. Thanks additionally to in-memory speed, machine learning and AI libraries, access to multi-model engines, data-tiering, and the ability to scale, this cloud database provides the much-desired resources to build autonomous, intelligent, and responsive solutions that drive business process excellence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more about functionality and availability ...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(1) Be sure to watch these TechEd 2025 virtual session replays:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1751961515198001rK0r" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud: The Database for Business AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1753997962285001Bb2p" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Accelerating Your AI Strategy with SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1751961475046001rTWX" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s Next for SAP HANA Cloud: Road Map and Innovation Highlights&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(2) Make sure to read these blogs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-becomes-agentic-introducing-discovery-agent-amp-data-agent/ba-p/14257394" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Becomes Agentic: Introducing Discovery Agent &amp;amp; Data Agent&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-next-with-sap-hana-cloud-sap-teched-2025/ba-p/14258163" target="_blank"&gt;What’s Next with SAP HANA Cloud – SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unleashing-the-power-of-trusted-data-sap-2025-teched-announces-enhanced/ba-p/14263266" target="_blank"&gt;Unleashing the Power of Trusted Data: SAP 2025 TechEd Announces Enhanced Data Product Capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(3) Sign up for the free &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana/trial.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud basic trial&lt;/A&gt; for a hands-on experience that includes a tutorial of the multi-model and data science capabilities of the database.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/agentic-databases-for-data-scientists-sap-hana-cloud-will-equip-you-with-a/ba-p/14265823"/>
    <published>2025-11-11T20:30:25.347000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sailing-analytics-goes-open-source/ba-p/14268880</id>
    <title>Sailing Analytics Goes Open Source</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T12:34:25.402000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Fempel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/10046</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="stage_ec_17.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340548iBCCFA50F53D8F5EA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="stage_ec_17.jpg" alt="stage_ec_17.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;On October 20, 2025, SAP published the source code of the Sailing Analytics solution and its companion apps (Sailing Race Manager, Buoy Pinger, Sail Insight) on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/sailing-analytics" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GitHub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; under the Apache 2.0 license. This finally allows all interested parties to contribute to the solution, and optionally even host it themselves.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This was a logical next step for the project and remains in-line with SAP’s open source principles described in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/05/ec7cc67d-bf7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Open Source Manifesto.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; It lays out a vision where open source drives innovation through collaboration and empowers communities through openness.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="image (7).png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340565i39663271A3D9BAB5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image (7).png" alt="image (7).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2022937277"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Sailing Analytics Does&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sailing Analytics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; solution helps comment and analyze sailing regattas by combining data from satellite tracking, wind sensors, and decisions by the race committee into live results and analyses. As a cloud solution, it scales from small cost-efficient club-level events to the most visible regattas at the Olympic Summer Games in Tokyo (2020/2021) and Paris (2024), serving hundreds of thousands of concurrent viewers across several regions worldwide. It powers the world's largest sailing tracking database with wind data and proper score boards (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapsailing.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://sapsailing.com&lt;/A&gt;). See it in action, live from the upcoming Youth World Championships 2025 in Vilamoura, Portugal taking place December 12-20, 2025, at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://youthworlds2025.sapsailing.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://youthworlds2025.sapsailing.com&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While Sailing Analytics started in the domain of one-design dinghy sailing with a specific focus on Olympic classes, over time it has evolved into many other areas of the complex sport. This includes different handicap formats with support for handicap-based live rankings, and a variety of scoring systems.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Image preview (1).png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340555i407B8545C7E16219/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Image preview (1).png" alt="Image preview (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The solution can be configured to work with different systems for position tracking, wind sensors, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;external regatta management tools, and official scoring systems. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Through &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;i&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ts&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://sapsailing.com/sailingserver/webservices/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;REST&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;ful API&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;it is possible to integrate more external tools and components without a need to change the sources. For tighter integrations, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;such as&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; tracking systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; and administration &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;interface&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;, a connector architecture exists that allows developers to extend the solution accordingly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1826423772"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Collaboration Models&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the code base now being released under a permissive open-source license, several new collaboration opportunities have opened.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In particular:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sensor technology providers can implement connectivity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Federations, class associations and event hosts can work on new formats and scoring options to be supported&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Research institutions can extend the solution for their specific projects and in-depth analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Sailing enthusiasts with a background in IT or graphic design &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;can contribute&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; to all layers and aspects of the solution&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1629910267"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Find a Neutral Entity as&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;New Home&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the long run&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; we plan to move this project to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;a neutral entity, such as&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;foundation, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to collaborate &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;more &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;indiv&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;i&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;duals and teams&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; ensure neutral &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;governance.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;In a foundation, th&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;is solution will &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;benefit&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;from &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;established processes for running open-source projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; and&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;structures for&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; collaboration &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;that &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;allow&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; interested stakeholders &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to easily&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; shap&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;e&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; the project’s future&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; together.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="PPT image sailing.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/340553i0D8BBD2845ADC61B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PPT image sailing.jpg" alt="PPT image sailing.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Join Us for a Technical Webinar&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We plan a one-hour webcast on this subject for the beginning of 2026. There you will learn about the status of the project, the potential going forward, and the concrete ways for you to participate, contribute, and collaborate. Let us know if you are interested either in the comments or by using the email below. Please find more details &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/sailing-analytics/discussions/9" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For those who can’t wait, please also use the project’s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/sailing-analytics/discussions" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;discussion board&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; or send an e-mail to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="mailto:support@sapsailing.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;support@sapsailing.com&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to learn more.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sailing-analytics-goes-open-source/ba-p/14268880"/>
    <published>2025-11-14T12:34:25.402000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/slaying-the-s-4-hana-dual-maintenance-amp-interim-state-monster-palantir-s/ba-p/14271369</id>
    <title>Slaying the S/4 HANA Dual Maintenance &amp; interim State Monster: Palantir's Trick to Treat Your Budget</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T20:47:18.401000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>STALANKI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13911</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1636399246"&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Imagine trying to rebuild your entire house, from the foundations up, while still living in it and running your daily life! That's the scale of the challenge many global enterprises are embracing as they transition from SAP ECC to S/4HANA. It's not just a tech upgrade; it's arguably the most significant transformation they'll undertake this decade.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="BD.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/342034i8F8C881F05F82A97/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BD.png" alt="BD.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Given the sheer size, the intricate sap integration web of operations with other systems, and all those unique regional needs, no one wants to risk bringing their business to a standstill. That's why most organisations are wisely choosing a thoughtful, multi-year, phased rollout.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Migrating from&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ECC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is one of the most significant transformations many global enterprises will undertake this decade. Given the scale, complexity, and regional dependencies involved, most organizations opt for a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;multi-year, phased rollout to minimize business disruption.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;While this approach minimizes business disruption, it introduces a costly challenge:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;dual maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;the need to maintain, reconcile, and synchronize data and processes across both ECC and S/4 systems during the transition period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In this post, we’ll explore how&amp;nbsp;Palantir’s data integration and digital twin capabilities&amp;nbsp;can dramatically reduce those interim costs, streamline operations, and accelerate time-to-value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568968460"&gt;The Dual Maintenance Dilemma&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;During a staggered rollout, some business units run on ECC while others move to S/4HANA. This creates temporary but expensive complexity:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Duplicate data maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;across ECC and S/4 systems (e.g., master data, pricing conditions, bills of material)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parallel reporting landscapes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as analytics must draw from both systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration bridges&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;required to maintain end-to-end process continuity (order-to-cash, procure-to-pay, etc.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reconciliation overhead&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to ensure financial and operational consistency&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;These efforts can add millions in IT and business costs annually during the rollout.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="ember875" id="toc-hId-1372454955"&gt;What Palantir does differently for Interim State?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rapid Data Integration: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Foundry excels at ingesting and integrating vast amounts of disparate data (structured, unstructured, streaming) from various source systems (legacy databases, cloud applications, IoT devices, spreadsheets, etc.) into a single, coherent data asset. This significantly reduces the need for manual data manipulation or temporary data warehouses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic Data Models (Ontology):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Instead of static data models, Foundry builds a dynamic "ontology" , a living, interconnected representation of an organisation's real-world entities (e.g., customers, assets, products, events) and their relationships. This provides a unified, real-time "digital twin" of the organisation's operations. This eliminates the "interim state" of fragmented data views and manual reconciliation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Lineage and Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Foundry automatically tracks data lineage, providing transparency on where data comes from and how it's transformed. This builds trust in the data and reduces the need for manual validation steps often found in interim processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerated Application Development:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Users can build operational applications, dashboards, and analytical tools directly on top of this integrated ontology without needing to move data to separate systems. This bypasses the need for bespoke, temporary solutions that often characterise an interim state.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System of Engagement over System of Record":&lt;/STRONG&gt; Palantir often acts as a "system of engagement" or "system of analysis" that sits on top of existing "systems of record." It doesn't require organisations to immediately rip and replace their legacy systems. Instead, it integrates data from these systems, allowing them to continue functioning while providing a modern, unified operational layer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In essence, Palantir Foundry's unique value lies in its ability to rapidly integrate and harmonise data from across an enterprise into a dynamic, operational ontology. This provides a single, coherent source of truth and a platform for building applications, thereby eliminating the need for costly "interim states" and allowing organisations to strategically reduce or retire redundant systems, thus cutting "dual maintenance running costs".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175941450"&gt;Palantir: A Unified Data and Process Layer&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Palantir Foundry&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;offers a powerful solution: instead of forcing every application, report, and integration to connect separately to ECC and S/4HANA, organizations can use&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Palantir as a single harmonized data layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;across both systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This creates a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;“digital twin”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;of the enterprise that abstracts away the differences between ECC and S/4, providing unified access to operational and analytical data without redundant maintenance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108510664"&gt;How Palantir Helps Reduce Interim Dual Maintenance Costs&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-782914440"&gt;1. Unified Data Model for ECC and S/4&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Palantir can connect directly to both ECC and S/4HANA systems (via SAP connectors, OData services, or data extracts) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;harmonize the key master and transactional data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- customers, materials, vendors, G/L accounts into a single, consistent data model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Instead of maintaining customer hierarchies in both ECC and S/4, Palantir can ingest them from ECC and apply transformation logic that reflects the new S/4 model. Downstream systems (analytics, planning, compliance) can consume the Palantir layer directly, avoiding the need to replicate changes twice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reduces data duplication and manual harmonization efforts by up to 60–70% during migration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-586400935"&gt;2. Process Continuity Through Digital Twins&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Palantir’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Data Layer (ODL)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;enables enterprises to create a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;digital twin of critical business processes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; such as order-to-cash or supply chain flows&amp;nbsp; across ECC and S/4 boundaries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Imagine a company where Europe has migrated to S/4 but North America is still on ECC. Orders may flow from ECC customers to S/4 production plants. Instead of building and maintaining multiple custom SAP interfaces, Palantir can serve as the process bridge — integrating order, inventory, and delivery data in real-time to ensure seamless visibility and coordination.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Cuts custom integration and reconciliation costs while ensuring consistent KPIs across regions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-389887430"&gt;3. Harmonized Analytics Layer&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Reporting is one of the biggest pain points during phased migration. Palantir provides a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;centralized analytics layer&lt;/STRONG&gt; where ECC and S/4 data can be combined, transformed, and visualized using the same semantic logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Finance teams can view a consolidated P&amp;amp;L across both systems without reconciling chart of accounts manually. Palantir’s ontology layer standardizes financial attributes (cost centers, profit centers, etc.) across systems, enabling consistent reporting months&amp;nbsp; or years&amp;nbsp; before full migration completes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Eliminates need for maintaining dual SAP BW or SAC models during rollout.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-193373925"&gt;4. Accelerated Master Data Migration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;By connecting to both source (ECC) and target (S/4) systems, Palantir can&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;simulate and validate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;master data transformations in advance. This reduces rework during each migration wave.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; For materials management, Palantir can pre-map ECC material master attributes to S/4’s simplified data model, identify inconsistencies, and validate against business rules all without touching production systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reduces downtime and errors during each cutover, saving time and resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--3139580"&gt;5. Continuous Value Delivery During Transition&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Palantir’s modular architecture allows business users to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;build analytics and decision applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that remain valid even after the migration is complete. This protects investments in data products and dashboards, reducing re-implementation costs post-S/4 go-live.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-147601272"&gt;Illustrative Scenario: A Global Manufacturing Company&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Context:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A global manufacturer is migrating from ECC to S/4HANA over 4 years. Europe goes live first, while APAC and North America remain on ECC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenges:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Global financial consolidation required across mixed systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Duplicate master data maintenance in multiple systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Integration pain for global supply chain visibility&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Palantir Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Build a unified Palantir data model integrating ECC and S/4 data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Create operational dashboards for global supply chain using this harmonized data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Maintain a single master data governance workflow through Palantir’s ontology layer&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Outcome:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;50% reduction in IT maintenance costs during rollout&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Single version of truth for finance and operations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Seamless reporting continuity across systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;In essence, Palantir allows you to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;“run as one”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;even while you’re still&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;migrating to one.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;#SAP #S4HANA, #Palantir, #DigitalTransformation, #CloudTransformation, #DualMaintenance, #SAPMigration, #EnterpriseMigration, #ERPStrategy, #BusinessTransformation #ERPTraansformation&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/slaying-the-s-4-hana-dual-maintenance-amp-interim-state-monster-palantir-s/ba-p/14271369"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T20:47:18.401000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-rpt-1-context-model-vs-training-classical-models-the-models-battle/ba-p/14268507</id>
    <title>SAP RPT-1 Context Model vs. Training Classical Models: The Models Battle (Python Hands-on)</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T07:50:27.670000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nicolasestevan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1198632</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1764768715"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":collision:"&gt;💥&lt;/span&gt;The Models Battle&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_5-1763206328497.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341535i2A2C9A98D24BF43B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_5-1763206328497.png" alt="nicolasestevan_5-1763206328497.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predictive modeling is becoming a built-in capability across SAP, improving how teams handle forecasting, pricing, and planning. &lt;STRONG&gt;Many SAP professionals, however, aren’t machine-learning specialists&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and traditional models often demand extensive setup, tuning, and repeated training, which slows down new ideas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; offers a simpler path. It’s a pretrained model from SAP, also available in an OSS version, that lets developers and consultants produce predictions with far less technical effort, no deep ML background required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've explored SAP RPT-1 hands-on, comparing it with traditional regressors using Python and a real public vehicles price dataset.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Goal:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To see (as a non Data Scientist) how &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1&lt;/STRONG&gt; behaves in practice, what advantages and limits it shows, and when it could make sense in a predictive scenario.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Usually for real-world scenario, the right approach would be consume the SAP RPT-1 though the available and simplified API, but for studies proposal and fair comparision over othe traditional ML models, the &lt;STRONG&gt;OSS&lt;/STRONG&gt; fits perfectly for it:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1568255210"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thinking_face:"&gt;🤔&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP RPT-1 vs Traditional Machine Learning - Core Differences&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into the code, let’s quickly revisit how&lt;STRONG&gt; traditional ML&lt;/STRONG&gt; models work:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Training-based models like Random Forest, LightGBM, and Linear Regression learn patterns directly from data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;They require hundreds or thousands of examples to tune their internal parameters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Their performance depends heavily on data quantity and quality.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The more relevant examples they see, the smarter they get.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the other hand, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 f&lt;/STRONG&gt;ollows a different philosophy. It’s part of the RPT (Representational Predictive Transformer) family, pretrained on a wide variety of business and contextual data. This means:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You don’t "train" it in the traditional sense. Instead, it uses context embeddings to predict outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It can be used immediately, even with smaller datasets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The OSS version allows developers to experiment directly in Python.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No special SAP backend required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Outcome:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Traditional ML models learn from high amount of data. SAP RPT-1 already knows how to deal with small context amount of data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1371741705"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":desktop_computer:"&gt;🖥&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;The Experiment - Setup &amp;amp; Dataset&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-container"&gt;&lt;a class="lia-spoiler-link" href="#" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Spoiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;noscript&gt; (Highlight to read)&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-border"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-content"&gt;Don't worry on "playing puzzles" copying + pasting code below. The full version is available for download at end!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-container"&gt;&lt;div class="lia-spoiler-noscript-content"&gt;Don't worry on "playing puzzles" copying + pasting code below. The full version is available for download at end!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make this comparison tangible, I built a simple yet realistic Python experiment to predict vehicle selling prices using a public dataset containing car attributes like make, model, year, transmission, and mileage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Why vehicle pricing? Because it’s an intuitive example where both traditional machine learning and pretrained AI models can be applie, and it helps visualize how prediction quality evolves as the sample size grows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This entire analysis runs on a local Python environment&amp;nbsp;with the following stack:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import os
import gc
import warnings
import pandas as pd
import numpy as np
import matplotlib.pyplot as plt
from datetime import datetime
from sklearn.model_selection import train_test_split
from sklearn.metrics import r2_score
from sklearn.ensemble import RandomForestRegressor
from sklearn.preprocessing import LabelEncoder
from sklearn.linear_model import LinearRegression
from sap_rpt_oss import SAP_RPT_OSS_Regressor
import lightgbm as lgb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;pandas&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;numpy&lt;/STRONG&gt; for data manipulation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/STRONG&gt; for classical ML regressors (R&lt;STRONG&gt;andom Forest, Linear Regression&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;LightGBM&lt;/STRONG&gt; for gradient &lt;STRONG&gt;boosting&lt;/STRONG&gt; comparison&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;sap_rpt_oss&lt;/STRONG&gt; — the open-source Python version of &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP’s RPT-1 model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;matplotlib&lt;/STRONG&gt; for all &lt;STRONG&gt;visualizations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 OSS &lt;/STRONG&gt;can be downloaded installed following official Hugging Face:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://huggingface.co/SAP/sap-rpt-1-oss?library=sap-rpt-1-oss" href="https://huggingface.co/SAP/sap-rpt-1-oss?library=sap-rpt-1-oss" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://huggingface.co/SAP/sap-rpt-1-oss?library=sap-rpt-1-oss&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;. Python can be installed with executable download on Windows, or via &lt;STRONG&gt;Home Brew&lt;/STRONG&gt; for Mac and &lt;STRONG&gt;apt&lt;/STRONG&gt; commands for Linux. Libraries dependencies can be downloaded with &lt;STRONG&gt;pip&lt;/STRONG&gt; commands. Googling it may not be a road blocker.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;We use a sample&amp;nbsp;vehicle sales dataset. The complete file is about to 88Mb but for such experiment a restricted sample of 20k as it's more than enough to prove our the concept, still it's faster and consuming less computing resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="498px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;year&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Vehicle model year&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;make&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Brand (e.g., Toyota, Ford, BMW)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;model&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Specific model name&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;body&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Type (SUV, Sedan, etc.)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;transmission&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Gear type&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;odometer&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Vehicle mileage&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;color&lt;/CODE&gt;, &lt;CODE&gt;interior&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;Visual attributes&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="248.57px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;sellingprice&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="248.43px" height="30px"&gt;The target variable to predict&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Dataset Download:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/syedanwarafridi/vehicle-sales-data?resource=download" href="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/syedanwarafridi/vehicle-sales-data?resource=download" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/syedanwarafridi/vehicle-sales-data?resource=download&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The dataset is loaded and preprocessed in a few simple steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;df = pd.read_csv("car_prices.csv").sample(n=20000, random_state=42)

# Fill missing values for categorical columns
fill_defaults = {
    'make': 'Other', 'model': 'Other', 'color': 'Other',
    'interior': 'Unknown', 'body': 'Unknown', 'transmission': 'Unknown'
}
for col, val in fill_defaults.items():
    df[col] = df[col].fillna(val)

X = df[["year", "make", "model", "body", "transmission", "odometer", "color", "interior"]]
y = df["sellingprice"]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;At this point, the stage is set:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The data is clean.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The environment is ready.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All models, traditionals and SAP RPT-1, are ready to be tested under identical conditions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1175228200"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Training the Models - Three different ones&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the dataset ready, the &lt;STRONG&gt;next step&lt;/STRONG&gt; is to run each model under the same conditions: &lt;STRONG&gt;same features, same target, same train/test split and same random seed&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This ensures the comparison is fair and repeatable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We evaluate prediction performance using &lt;STRONG&gt;R² (coefficient of determination)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which indicates how much of the price variation the model can explain (1.0 = perfect prediction).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1107797414"&gt;Training Model #1 - Random Forest&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Random Forest is often the first model used in tabular ML. It works by creating &lt;STRONG&gt;many decision trees&lt;/STRONG&gt; and averaging their predictions. Before training, categorical variables need to be &lt;STRONG&gt;label-encoded&lt;/STRONG&gt; into numbers, a common requirement for classical ML models:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_random_forest(X, y):
    X = X.copy()
    cat_cols = ["make", "model", "body", "transmission", "color", "interior"]
    le = LabelEncoder()

    for col in cat_cols:
        X[col] = le.fit_transform(X[col].astype(str).fillna("Unknown"))

    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = RandomForestRegressor(
        n_estimators=150, max_depth=20, random_state=42, n_jobs=-1
    )

    try:
        model.fit(X_train, y_train)
        preds = model.predict(X_test)
        r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)
    except Exception as e:
        preds, r2 = np.zeros_like(y_test), 0

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-911283909"&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_3-1763206176248.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341502i82216AA724092E03/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_3-1763206176248.png" alt="nicolasestevan_3-1763206176248.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-714770404"&gt;Up to 7067 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_8-1763206511155.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341538iF2A25E0C0EBE0612/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_8-1763206511155.png" alt="nicolasestevan_8-1763206511155.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-518256899"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="RandomForest_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341551i3A2C874AFAF47388/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="RandomForest_20251115_092355.gif" alt="RandomForest_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-321743394"&gt;Training Model #2 - LightGBM&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;LightGBM is one of the most powerful models for tabular data. Unlike Random Forest (many independent trees), LightGBM builds trees &lt;STRONG&gt;sequentially&lt;/STRONG&gt;, each correcting the errors of the previous one. It supports categorical features natively, which simplifies preprocessing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_lightgbm(X, y):
    X = X.copy()
    cat_cols = ["make", "model", "body", "transmission", "color", "interior"]
    for col in cat_cols:
        X[col] = X[col].astype(str).fillna("Unknown").astype("category")

    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = lgb.LGBMRegressor(
        n_estimators=500, learning_rate=0.05, num_leaves=31,
        subsample=0.8, colsample_bytree=0.8, random_state=42
    )

    try:
        model.fit(X_train, y_train, categorical_feature=cat_cols)
        preds = model.predict(X_test)
        r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)
    except Exception:
        preds, r2 = np.zeros_like(y_test), 0

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-125229889"&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_2-1763205951324.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341474i1AAB214E2D01C2B2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_2-1763205951324.png" alt="nicolasestevan_2-1763205951324.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--146514985"&gt;Up to 7067 rows:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_7-1763206474860.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341537i0ACD453B96C87ADF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_7-1763206474860.png" alt="nicolasestevan_7-1763206474860.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--343028490"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="LightGBM_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341552i30BC4DE94C4988F6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="LightGBM_20251115_092355.gif" alt="LightGBM_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--539541995"&gt;Training Model #3 - Linear Regression&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not fancy and even not complex, Linear Regression provides a baseline that shows:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;“If the relationship between attributes and price is roughly linear, how well can a simple model perform?”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_linear_model(X, y):
    X = X.copy()
    cat_cols = ["make", "model", "body", "transmission", "color", "interior"]
    for col in cat_cols:
        X[col] = LabelEncoder().fit_transform(X[col].astype(str).fillna("Unknown"))

    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = LinearRegression()
    X_train = X_train.fillna(X_train.mean(numeric_only=True))
    X_test = X_test.fillna(X_test.mean(numeric_only=True))

    try:
        model.fit(X_train, y_train)
        preds = model.predict(X_test)
        r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)
    except Exception:
        preds, r2 = np.zeros_like(y_test), 0

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--736055500"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_1-1763205857765.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341472i81AFB2D0BE770F90/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_1-1763205857765.png" alt="nicolasestevan_1-1763205857765.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--932569005"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 7067 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_6-1763206428099.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341536iC708165AEAE11D46/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_6-1763206428099.png" alt="nicolasestevan_6-1763206428099.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1129082510"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="LinearModel_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341553i0849B4C842A417EE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="LinearModel_20251115_092355.gif" alt="LinearModel_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1032193008"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chequered_flag:"&gt;🏁&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP RPT-1 OSS: Context Model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where things get interesting. SAP RPT-1 does &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; rely on learning patterns from the dataset. Instead, it uses a pretrained transformer architecture to infer relationships directly through &lt;STRONG&gt;context embeddings&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Lean and simple, "for non-Data Science PhD":&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;def train_sap_rpt1(X, y):
    X_train, X_test, y_train, y_test = train_test_split(
        X, y, test_size=default_test_size, random_state=42
    )

    model = SAP_RPT_OSS_Regressor(max_context_size=8192, bagging=8)
    model.fit(X_train, y_train)

    preds = model.predict(X_test)
    r2 = r2_score(y_test, preds)

    return [preds, r2, y_test]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1522109520"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 50 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_0-1763205729558.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341471i4AC7007DCA5A0F76/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_0-1763205729558.png" alt="nicolasestevan_0-1763205729558.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1718623025"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Up to 2055 rows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="nicolasestevan_4-1763206228416.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341505i9ADE9D2D2B38C363/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="nicolasestevan_4-1763206228416.png" alt="nicolasestevan_4-1763206228416.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1915136530"&gt;Live view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SAP_RPT1_20251115_092355.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/341566i0BE0E0D666836951/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP_RPT1_20251115_092355.gif" alt="SAP_RPT1_20251115_092355.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1650063337"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Running Experiments at Multiple Sample Sizes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section breaks down how the iterative experiment loop works, why the SAP RPT-1 OSS model has a max-context limit, and how performance changes as we scale up the dataset. By running the same models across several sample sizes, we can see where traditional ML shines, where RPT-1 stays competitive, and how both behave as the data grows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;sample_sizes = np.linspace(50, len(X), 200, dtype=int)
results, max_r2_rpt1, max_sample_rpt1 = [], 0, 0

for n in sample_sizes:
    idx = np.random.choice(len(X), n, replace=False)
    X_sample, y_sample = X.iloc[idx], y.iloc[idx]


    # SAP RPT-1 OSS (limited sample size)
    if n &amp;lt;= rpt1_limit:
        rpt_res = train_sap_rpt1(X_sample, y_sample)
        fn = plot_predictions(rpt_res[2], rpt_res[0], rpt_res[1], "SAP_RPT1", n)
        video_frames["SAP_RPT1"].append(fn)
        r2_rpt1 = rpt_res[1]
        max_r2_rpt1 = max(max_r2_rpt1, r2_rpt1)
    else:
        r2_rpt1 = max_r2_rpt1
        if max_sample_rpt1 == 0:
            max_sample_rpt1 = n

    # Train and plot models
    rf_res = train_random_forest(X_sample, y_sample)
    fn = plot_predictions(rf_res[2], rf_res[0], rf_res[1], "RandomForest", n)
    video_frames["RandomForest"].append(fn)

    lgb_res = train_lightgbm(X_sample, y_sample)
    fn = plot_predictions(lgb_res[2], lgb_res[0], lgb_res[1], "LightGBM", n)
    video_frames["LightGBM"].append(fn)

    lin_res = train_linear_model(X_sample, y_sample)
    fn = plot_predictions(lin_res[2], lin_res[0], lin_res[1], "LinearModel", n)
    video_frames["LinearModel"].append(fn)

    results.append((n, rf_res[1], r2_rpt1, lgb_res[1], lin_res[1]))

    # Early stop if traditional model reaches SAP RPT-1
    if rf_res[1] &amp;gt;= max_r2_rpt1 or lgb_res[1] &amp;gt;= max_r2_rpt1 or lin_res[1] &amp;gt;= max_r2_rpt1:
        break
    gc.collect()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;This loop compares SAP RPT-1 OSS with traditional ML models as sample sizes increase. Each iteration randomly selects a subset of the data and trains all models on the same slice for a fair comparison. SAP RPT-1 can only run up to its max-context limit, so once the sample size exceeds that threshold, it stops retraining and simply carries forward its best R². The traditional models continue training at every step. The loop ends early when any traditional model matches or surpasses RPT-1’s best score, making the experiment efficient while showing how performance evolves as data grows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1846576842"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":end_arrow:"&gt;🔚&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Conclusion and Final Thoughts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP RPT-1 OSS stands out because it performs well with small datasets, requires minimal code, and can generate useful predictions with just an API call and a bit of context. This makes it ideal for jump-starting predictive use cases early on, delivering fast business value without a full ML pipeline. Traditional models, however, still shine when projects mature, data grows, and fine-tuned control becomes important. It’s not about choosing one over the other, but understanding where each approach brings the most value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aspect&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 OSS&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Traditional ML (RF, LGBM, Linear)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Data Requirements&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Low (performs well with small samples)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Medium/High (performance scales with data&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Setup Effort&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Minimal (API call + context)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Higher (preprocessing, encoding, tuning)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Training Process&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;None (pretrained context model)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Full training pipeline required&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Speed to Insights&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Very fast&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Moderate to slow&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Best Use Case&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Early-stage predictive cases, quick baselines&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Mature pipelines, high control and customization&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Flexibility&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Limited tuning / plug-and-play&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Highly customizable&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="19.011815252416756%" height="30px"&gt;Business Value&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="38.66809881847476%" height="30px"&gt;Immediate, fast, accessible&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="42.21267454350161%" height="30px"&gt;Strong when optimized and scaled&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;This experiment highlights a simple truth: &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP RPT-1 isn’t here to replace traditional ML, it jump-starts it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;With a pretrained, context-driven approach, RPT-1 delivers fast, reliable insights with very little data and almost no setup. Traditional models still excel in mature, data-rich scenarios, but RPT-1 shines as a rapid accelerator and early-value generator inside SAP landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1958473942"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt;Open for Exchange&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you're testing RPT-1, exploring predictive cases, or want the full code, feel free to reach out.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Happy to connect, compare experiences, and push this topic forward together.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-rpt-1-context-model-vs-training-classical-models-the-models-battle/ba-p/14268507"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T07:50:27.670000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-added-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-with-databricks-snowflake-and-ms/ba-p/14273953</id>
    <title>The Added Value of SAP Business Data Cloud with Databricks, Snowflake and MS Fabric</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:41:22.717000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>florian_hamon</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/60103</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;There as been a lot of partnership announcement lately broadening the extend of SAP Business Data Cloud capabilities and integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s multi-platform data landscapes, organizations are increasingly blending SAP and non-SAP data to drive insights, automate decision-making, and accelerate innovation. But combining the trusted semantics of SAP with the scalability and flexibility of modern cloud data platforms is not always straightforward.&lt;BR /&gt;This is where &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;—powered by SAP Datasphere—delivers extraordinary strategic value. And with &lt;STRONG&gt;BDC connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP takes cross-ecosystem integration even further, enabling a harmonized, governed, bidirectional data fabric that works seamlessly with platforms such as &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Fabric, Snowflake, and Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1765547276"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why SAP Business Data Cloud Changes the Game&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud is designed to bridge the historical gap between SAP’s rich business context and the broader data landscape. It moves beyond simple data replication or extraction: it &lt;STRONG&gt;preserves SAP’s business semantics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, delivers harmonized models, and enables federated consumption with minimal data movement, to take on-time decisions based on data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s what makes it transformative:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698116490"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Business-ready data out of the box&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP systems contain deeply embedded logic—currency conversions, hierarchies, master data relationships, authorizations, time-dependencies—none of which carry over when raw tables are moved into a data lake or modern warehouse.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Throughts Business Data Cloud, SAP provides out-of-the box Data Products that automatically collects and exposes SAP data &lt;STRONG&gt;with meaning intact&lt;/STRONG&gt;, avoiding:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;custom semantic reconstruction&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;brittle pipelines&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;manual hierarchical transformations&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This dramatically reduces time-to-insight for downstream analytics platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1501602985"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Governance, lineage, and security at enterprise scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;BDC maintains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;end-to-end lineage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP role-based security&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;metadata enrichment&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;business catalogs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This ensures that downstream platforms consume &lt;STRONG&gt;trusted, governed data&lt;/STRONG&gt;, not raw or misinterpreted tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176006761"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How BDC combines with Microsoft Fabric, Snowflake, and Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAP Business Data Cloud is a fully standalone powerful platform for data and analytics, customers may have chosen another technology to handle some aspects of their data storage and governance. Providing a partnership with these platforms enables to propose a deep integration within a broader ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1108575975"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;- SAP Business Data Cloud + Microsoft Fabric&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;BDC connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Fabric can tap directly into SAP semantic models with a zero-copy capabilities enabling to successfully combine SAP and non-SAP data and leverging the existing features of Microfot Fabric.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-912062470"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;- SAP Business Data Cloud + Snowflake&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Snowflake excels at multi-cloud elasticity, secure data sharing, and workload isolation. BDC complements Snowflake through:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP-optimized data contracts exposed as Snowflake-ready datasets&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Replication or federation with preserved semantics&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Accelerated development of Snowflake Data Cloud applications using SAP-trusted data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here too, the BDC Connect capabilities enables to do a zero-copy sharing of the data, avoiding data replication and keeping the context of the data..&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-715548965"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;- SAP Business Data Cloud + Databricks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Databricks is the leader in lakehouse architecture, ML/AI workloads, and open data formats. With BDC:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data scientists gain business-aware SAP data without reverse-engineering SAP logic&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;ML models can be trained on harmonized SAP+non-SAP datasets&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Semantic consistency is maintained from source to model consumption&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unity Catalog benefits from SAP lineage and metadata&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;BDC connect enables bi-directional zero-copy interoperability, including pushing curated datasets back into analytics or operational systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-389952741"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BDC connect: The Integration Accelerator&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A core enabler in the ecosystem is &lt;STRONG&gt;BDC connect&lt;/STRONG&gt;, providing a streamlined, governed, and high-performance integration zero-copy mechanism between SAP Business Data Cloud and modern data platforms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With BDC connect, your data platform of choice becomes &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP-aware by design&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarize :&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BDC ensures your modern data platforms stop treating SAP as just another source, and start treating it as a first-class, business-ready data foundation.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-added-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-with-databricks-snowflake-and-ms/ba-p/14273953"/>
    <published>2025-11-20T16:41:22.717000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-intelligent-applications-to-trusted-data-accelerating-insight-to/ba-p/14274297</id>
    <title>From Intelligent Applications to Trusted Data: Accelerating Insight to Action for Business Analysts</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T17:00:00.025000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>laurenwong</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1740192</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business analysts today are expected to turn complex datasets into insight faster than ever; analyzing trends, spotting opportunities, and ultimately providing line-of-business leaders with the information necessary to make informed decisions. To meet these demands, they need tools that simplify analysis, ensure data quality, and accelerate their path from question to actionable insight.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;At&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd 2025&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;, SAP announced a suite of advancements designed to do just that—continuing to drive momentum across its data and AI portfolio. New intelligent applications, expanded access to curated data products in&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and deeper AI-driven assistance powered by Joule empower analysts to work smarter, make faster decisions, and deliver insights with confidence, all while maintaining governance and accuracy at every step.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Intelligent Applications: Purpose-Built Insights for Every Line of Business&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/intelligent-applications.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Intelligent applications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in SAP Business Data Cloud continue to evolve, giving analysts prebuilt, AI-driven insights across domains like finance, HR, supply chain, and more. By embedding more intelligence directly into everyday workflows, these applications let analysts start with much of the foundational work already modeled, monitored, and enriched with AI—so they can focus on understanding trends, identifying gaps, and answering the “why” behind the data, rather than the mechanics of assembling it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Value of Intelligent Applications at a Glance:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Consistent, trusted data&lt;SPAN&gt; sources resulting in reliable, repeatable insights&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Less manual prep work&lt;SPAN&gt; and more time spent analyzing and interpreting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Shorter analysis cycles&lt;SPAN&gt; through immediate access to prebuilt dashboards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Higher trust and alignment through unified metrics and premodeled insights&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Clearer explanations &lt;SPAN&gt;behind anomalies, trends, and performance drivers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;AI-enhanced recommendations &lt;SPAN&gt;tailored to each line of business&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Intelligent Applications by Line of Business" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345212iC18AA34F61DAA573/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Intelligent Applications for Line-of-Business.png" alt="Intelligent Applications by Line of Business" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Intelligent Applications by Line of Business&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Updates and Expanded Use Cases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Following up on the intelligent application announcement made at SAP Sapphire in 2025, SAP has expanded both previews&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and general availability. Spend Intelligence, Supply Chain Intelligence, and Revenue Intelligence are now in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/intelligent-applications/preview.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;restricted public preview,&lt;/A&gt; while Finance Intelligence, People Intelligence, and Cloud ERP Intelligence private packages are generally available. Together, these additions broaden the library of ready-to-use insights business analysts can tap into with minimal setup.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;People Intelligence: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New HR-focused use cases now &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;deliver deeper insight into recruiting, learning effectiveness, and employee performance. Analysts gain more accurate attrition predictions and intuitive dashboards that make it easy to compare trends and risks across business units.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Revenue Intelligence: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Expanded capabilities provide revenue and sales leaders with a real-time, holistic view of pipeline performance. These updates combine continuously learning ML forecasts, automated variance detection, and unified insights across sales, finance, and operations to support more predictable planning and decision-making.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consumer Products Intelligence&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: A new intelligent application for consumer goods manufacturers helps optimize trade promotion planning and manage spending with greater precision. Features include real-time price elasticity analysis, promotion effectiveness insights, margin optimization tools, and streamlined workflows for executing financial operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trusted Data Products Fueling Reliable, Reusable Insights&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/resources/what-are-data-products" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data products&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; remain one of the most impactful pillars of SAP Business Data Cloud—especially for analysts who need quick access to context-rich and ready-to-use business data. Instead of repeatedly rebuilding the same datasets for each analysis or project, analysts can tap into governed, out-of-the-box data products that are automatically kept up to date.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This not only eliminates duplication but also ensures that everyone across functional teams are working from the same source of truth. By standardizing reusable models, metrics, and pipelines, analysts gain a foundation that speeds up reporting cycles and reduces back-and-forth with technical teams.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In summary, here's what data products bring to the table for business analysts:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reusable datasets reduce manual preparation and accelerate reporting cycles&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shared metrics and models ensure consistent definitions across teams&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Faster insight generation with less time spent requesting or rebuilding data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Increased trust in data quality, making findings easier to validate and share&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Momentum Continues: More Data Products Across SAP Applications&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is expanding its catalog of ready-to-use data products across critical application areas, including SAP Cloud ERP, SAP SuccessFactors, sustainability, and customer experience. These additions will be available in SAP Business Data Cloud in H1 2026, giving business analysts access to richer, more discoverable datasets to support planning, reporting, and advanced analysis.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Overview: Data Products in SAP Business Data Cloud" style="width: 828px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345211i3D3FFA68362B9688/image-dimensions/828x587/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="828" height="587" role="button" title="Data Products Overview.png" alt="Overview: Data Products in SAP Business Data Cloud" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Overview: Data Products in SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI Assistants and Augmented Workflows: Work Smarter, Act Faster&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP’s latest advancements in AI assistants and automation deliver clear benefits to business analysts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/cloud-analytics.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(SAC) already offers strong AI capabilities, including natural language querying and machine learning-powered insights, that provide analysts with a robust foundation for faster data exploration and discovery.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is extending SAC with even more powerful, automated, and generative workflows designed to accelerate both analysis and planning:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Story Generation Agent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – Automatically transforms raw data, business context, and user prompts into complete, insight-rich SAC stories or intelligent applications. It assembles visualizations, narrative structure, and recommendations using reusable components and user preferences.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-assisted workflows for planning and analytics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – Includes comment summarization, comment translation, and natural language generation of advanced formulas. Analysts can describe complex planning logic conversationally and have SAC generate or refine the script behind it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule embedded natively in SAC&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – Provides in-context conversational support to help analysts refine queries, adjust dashboards, troubleshoot logic, or accelerate iterative analysis directly within the product.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Joule Capabilities in SAP Analytics Cloud (2026)" style="width: 904px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/345210i1003BA0B1ABCC756/image-dimensions/904x513/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="904" height="513" role="button" title="Joule Capabilities in SAP Analytics Cloud.png" alt="Joule Capabilities in SAP Analytics Cloud (2026)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Joule Capabilities in SAP Analytics Cloud (2026)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why This All Matters for Business Analysts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Across intelligent applications, curated data products, and AI-assisted workflows, the message is clear: SAP is removing the friction that slows analysts down and elevating their work to more strategic, impactful roles. Built natively into SAP Business Data Cloud, these capabilities ensure analysts can work within a single, unified environment where data, analysis, and decision support are seamlessly connected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analysts can now rely on workflows that are more automated, consistent, and cross-functionally integrated. The outcome: faster answers to critical business questions, clearer recommendations for business leaders, and more time spent on the high-value analytical work that drives real business impact.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To learn more about SAP Business Data Cloud and SAP’s latest announcements:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Visit &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;on sap.com&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Read the&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/topics/innovation-guide/h2#sap-business-data-cloud-enhancements-advance-access-to-trusted-semantically-rich-data-products" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;H2 2025 SAP Innovation Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for key highlights&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Watch the replays from SAP TechEd 2025 virtual sessions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1751961468799001rUtP" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud solution road map (DA806v)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1755678688968001xkoa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Planning and analytics: Innovations powering SAP Business Data Cloud (DA207v)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/virtual/flow/sap/tev25/catalog-virtual/page/catalog/session/1751961524830001rvfr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transforming how people work with Joule technology (ST123v)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Get hands-on with the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=5049141&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=155E33D499506054AF6FD5A553C2BD38&amp;amp;groupId=6298861&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BDC Getting Started workshop series&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (on-demand)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/from-intelligent-applications-to-trusted-data-accelerating-insight-to/ba-p/14274297"/>
    <published>2025-11-26T17:00:00.025000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/launch-alert-become-a-data-architecture-powerhouse-your-foundational/ba-p/14281620</id>
    <title>🚀 Launch Alert! Become a Data Architecture Powerhouse: Your Foundational Learning Journey</title>
    <updated>2025-12-02T06:14:39.976000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JaSoN_Luo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1708</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;To equip data professionals with the skills to bridge technical expertise and strategic business impact, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Data Architecture experts&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;SIX learning team&lt;/STRONG&gt; are thrilled to announce the launch of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Architect Learning Journey (Foundational)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This essential first stage of the &lt;I&gt;Becoming a Data Architect&lt;/I&gt; curriculum is designed to empower aspiring architects, data professionals, and solution experts to master the core principles, modern paradigms, and critical frameworks that define successful enterprise data architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1895490955"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":building_construction:"&gt;🏗&lt;/span&gt;️ Structure: Building Expertise from the Ground Up&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This learning journey is structured methodically, ensuring you build expertise layer by layer, from foundational theory to strategic impact.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The journey begins with &lt;STRONG&gt;Unit 1: Foundational Concepts&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where you will anchor your understanding in the essential principles of modeling, metadata management, and architectural alignment. You will master basic terminologies and fundamentals, including &lt;STRONG&gt;Conceptual, Logical, and Physical&lt;/STRONG&gt; data models, and understand how data architecture integrates with enterprise frameworks like &lt;STRONG&gt;Zachman and TOGAF&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, &lt;STRONG&gt;Unit 2: Modern Paradigms &amp;amp; Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt; takes you into the contemporary world of data patterns. You'll explore and compare models like &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Mesh, Data Fabric, Data Lake, and Data Lakehouse&lt;/STRONG&gt;, learning how to select the right approach for any scenario. This unit also delves into integration essentials, comparing and contrasting approaches such as &lt;STRONG&gt;ETL and ELT&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unit 3&lt;/STRONG&gt; focuses on the critical need for &lt;STRONG&gt;Governance, Security &amp;amp; Strategic Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;. As data ecosystems expand, governance becomes the bedrock of trust. You will learn to establish comprehensive &lt;STRONG&gt;data governance frameworks&lt;/STRONG&gt; (including stewardship and data lineage) and integrate crucial &lt;STRONG&gt;security and privacy controls&lt;/STRONG&gt; to ensure compliance and secure modern use cases like AI/ML.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The journey culminates in &lt;STRONG&gt;Unit 4: Communicating Data Value&lt;/STRONG&gt;. A great architect is also a great leader. This final unit strengthens the communication and leadership skills needed to influence change, teaching you how to articulate the limitations of the current ("as-is") data landscape and present a compelling, business-focused narrative for the future ("to-be") architecture, focusing on &lt;STRONG&gt;quality, cost, and scale&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1698977450"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":direct_hit:"&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt;Who Should Enroll? Shift from Technical Expert to Strategic Leader&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This curriculum is ideal for data professionals at every stage ready to evolve from technical implementers into strategic architectural leaders. This includes &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Engineers and Modelers&lt;/STRONG&gt; seeking advancement, &lt;STRONG&gt;Solution and Enterprise Architects&lt;/STRONG&gt; aiming to solidify their data design expertise, &lt;STRONG&gt;BI and Analytics Professionals&lt;/STRONG&gt; who need architectural context, and &lt;STRONG&gt;IT and Transformation Leaders&lt;/STRONG&gt; focused on aligning data systems with business outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1502463945"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;Why Start This Journey Now?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modern organizations demand architects who master both technology and business value. By mastering these principles, you will gain skills that directly translate into competitive advantages: you'll improve data quality and governance, learn how to connect data architecture directly to enterprise goals, and gain the credibility needed to influence strategic decisions. Crucially, this course sets the definitive foundation for the planned &lt;I&gt;SAP Certified Data Architect specialization&lt;/I&gt;* launching in 2026!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Visit SAP Learning and enroll in the Becoming an SAP Data Architect – Foundational Learning Journey Today!&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/becoming-an-sap-data-architect" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Becoming an SAP Data Architect (Foundational)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blue.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347330i288B98D22D9B13CC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blue.jpg" alt="Blue.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/launch-alert-become-a-data-architecture-powerhouse-your-foundational/ba-p/14281620"/>
    <published>2025-12-02T06:14:39.976000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/ignite-your-data-architecture-journey-empower-enterprise-and-data/ba-p/14281629</id>
    <title>🚀 Ignite Your Data Architecture Journey: Empower Enterprise and Data Architects Today!</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T05:18:15.798000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JaSoN_Luo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1708</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the era of digital transformation,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;is the heartbeat of innovation, strategy, and impactful decision-making. Strong&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;is the foundation that powers every thriving enterprise. To bridge technical expertise with strategic business outcomes, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Data Architecture experts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;alongside the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SIX learning team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;proudly unveil the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Architect Learning Journey (Foundational).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This inaugural phase of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Becoming a Data Architect&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;program is crafted to equip aspiring architects, data professionals, and solution experts with essential frameworks, modern methodologies, and core principles that shape successful enterprise data architectures.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766408245"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":building_construction:"&gt;🏗&lt;/span&gt;️ Layered Learning: From Fundamentals to Enterprise Impact&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This journey guides you through a carefully designed progression to build your expertise methodically:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unit 1: Foundational Concepts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;anchors you in the fundamentals—mastering modeling techniques, metadata management, and the integration of data architectures with enterprise frameworks such as&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Zachman and TOGAF&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Grasp the essentials of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conceptual, Logical, and Physical&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;models that form the backbone of data design.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unit 2: Modern Paradigms &amp;amp; Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;immerses you in today’s evolving landscape, exploring advanced patterns like&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Mesh, Data Fabric, Data Lake,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Lakehouse&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Understand when and how to apply each, plus gain insights into key integration frameworks, including the nuances between&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ETL and ELT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;strategies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unit 3: Governance, Security &amp;amp; Strategic Value&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;addresses the growing need to establish trust and compliance within expansive data ecosystems. Delve into comprehensive data governance frameworks—data stewardship, lineage, and privacy safeguards that secure modern architectures and enable AI/ML innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unit 4: Communicating Data Value&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;sharpens your leadership voice, guiding you to communicate complex architectural changes clearly and compellingly. Learn to narrate the journey from the current state to future architecture, emphasizing&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;quality, cost-efficiency, and scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to align with business priorities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569894740"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":direct_hit:"&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt;Who Should Embark?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Designed for data professionals ready to evolve beyond technical roles into influential architectural strategists, this foundation suits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Data Engineers and Modelers aspiring to architect-level roles&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Solution and Enterprise Architects deepening their data design acumen&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;BI and Analytics experts seeking architectural context&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;IT and Transformation leaders aligning data strategies with business goals&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1373381235"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;Why Now? Gain a Strategic Edge&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Today’s enterprises demand architects who not only understand technology but who can also drive meaningful business outcomes. This journey empowers you to enhance data quality, governance, and alignment with enterprise strategies—skills that translate directly into leadership credibility and competitive advantage. Plus, it sets the stage for the upcoming&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Certified Data Architect specialization&lt;/STRONG&gt;, launching in 2026.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176867730"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":motorway:"&gt;🛣&lt;/span&gt;️ Begin Your Path to Architecting Tomorrow&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ready to elevate your data architectural mindset and lead transformative initiatives? No prerequisites required—start your journey today!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/becoming-an-sap-data-architect" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enroll now at SAP Learning: Becoming an SAP Data Architect – Foundational Learning Journey!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Green.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/347331i81213307D0EAE0D8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Green.jpg" alt="Green.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/ignite-your-data-architecture-journey-empower-enterprise-and-data/ba-p/14281629"/>
    <published>2025-12-03T05:18:15.798000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-learning-group-blog-posts/welcome-to-the-data-and-analytics-learning-group/ba-p/14283942</id>
    <title>Welcome to the Data and Analytics Learning Group</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T14:13:56.115000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MarkGreen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/718</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are very excited to launch this brand-new learning group for all learners of SAP solutions in the Data and Analytics space. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here you can connect with SAP experts and fellow learners across all data and analytics topics.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The focus of this community is &lt;STRONG&gt;learning&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It is not meant to replace the existing SAP Community groups that focus on product-based discussions. Those still exist and should always be used whenever you have a question or want to discuss a topic around a product feature, or need help with trouble-shooting a product-based issue. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This learning community is a place to ask questions and join in discussions around SAP learning content such as courses, learning journeys and certification.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are here to help you get started and to support you if you run into trouble with topics in the learning content. We are also here to help you prepare for certification. Look out for blog posts from the experts that will soon appear to help with on your learning journey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The solutions that we cover in this community include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Databricks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BW / BW4HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BusinessObjects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Embedded Analytics&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP HANA Modeling and Data Provisioning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Developing data models using ABAP CDS&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The community is moderated by SAP experts who are instructors and content developers. This means that you are connecting with those who are very familiar with the course materials and certifications. Remember, these are the guys who developed them! &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make sure you click &lt;STRONG&gt;Join&lt;/STRONG&gt; so that you can ask questions, jump into discussions, create blog posts, and add your responses to posts. If you don’t join you will only be able to browse the posts in this community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MarkGreen_0-1764853593761.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348525i03276F8B289390F9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MarkGreen_0-1764853593761.png" alt="MarkGreen_0-1764853593761.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, don’t forget to &lt;STRONG&gt;subscribe&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the learning community and individual posts or tags, so you don’t miss any updates. One final thing: remember to set your notification preferences so you receive emails when a post that you subscribed to has been updated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MarkGreen_1-1764853611404.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348526i21C281D3A412681F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MarkGreen_1-1764853611404.png" alt="MarkGreen_1-1764853611404.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Community provides a separate place for discussions and questions, but we thought we’d try and simply things for you by combining them. After all, a question often leads to a discussion and vice-versa. So please use the &lt;STRONG&gt;Discussions&lt;/STRONG&gt; button to start a discussion and to ask questions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MarkGreen_2-1764853628674.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/348527i58FEF21DAEAC2FBF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MarkGreen_2-1764853628674.png" alt="MarkGreen_2-1764853628674.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why not introduce yourself to members of this community and let us know a little about your SAP journey? What brought you here? What are you hoping to get from this community? Simply post a reply here and let us know.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Make sure you spread the word about this community. Post a link in your social media so that we can build a vibrant and effective community of data and analytics learners. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As with all SAP communities, we want this to be a safe space for our members. Please familiarize yourself with the &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/resources/rules-of-engagement" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Community Rules of Engagement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Welcome aboard. Let’s get connected!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mark Green&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Moderator: SAP Community - Data and Analytics Learning Group&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-learning-group-blog-posts/welcome-to-the-data-and-analytics-learning-group/ba-p/14283942"/>
    <published>2025-12-04T14:13:56.115000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/embedded-analytics-for-sap-sales-amp-service-cloud-v2-list-of-available/ba-p/14284830</id>
    <title>Embedded Analytics for SAP Sales &amp; Service Cloud v2 - List of Available Tables Reporting &amp; Dashboard</title>
    <updated>2025-12-05T15:53:26.048000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud Version 2 (V2) introduces a modernized approach to analytics by embedding &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; directly into the platform. This integration provides powerful reporting and dashboard capabilities without relying on external tools, enabling real-time insights and advanced visualization options.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="F1g384dWcAE1-fu.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349003iDE8EEE14458F7297/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="F1g384dWcAE1-fu.jpg" alt="F1g384dWcAE1-fu.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="100%"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF00FF"&gt;Note :&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF6600"&gt;Embedded Analytics provided in SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud v2 is based on the embedded edition of SAP Analytics Cloud (eSAC). It is not the full version of SAP Analytics Cloud and therefore offers a limited set of functionalities compared to the standalone SAC solution.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1766499562"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is Embedded Analytics in V2?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unlike previous versions, V2 does not have native analytics. Instead, it leverages &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud, embedded edition (eSAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; as the single analytics engine across SAP solutions. This ensures:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unified reporting experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; across Sales and Service processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-time data analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; using standard C4C data sources.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced visualization&lt;/STRONG&gt; options like charts, tables, KPIs, and interactive dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1569986057"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Design Stories Workcenter&lt;/STRONG&gt; for administrators to create dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analysis Workcenter&lt;/STRONG&gt; for end-users to view and interact with stories.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role-based access&lt;/STRONG&gt; for personalized reporting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculated Columns &amp;amp; Filters&lt;/STRONG&gt; for custom metrics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Single Sign-On (SSO)&lt;/STRONG&gt; for secure access to eSAC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1373472552"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Available Data Sources &amp;amp; Tables&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Embedded SAC uses the same &lt;STRONG&gt;standard data sources&lt;/STRONG&gt; as native Business Analytics in C4C. These include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Opportunity Data&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Forecast vs. Actuals)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Account &amp;amp; Contact Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activity &amp;amp; Interaction Logs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Tickets / Cases&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Status, Escalation, Source Channels)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Orders &amp;amp; Quotes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lead Management Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product &amp;amp; Pricing Tables&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each data source can be extended with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Filters&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., by region, status, time frame)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculated Columns&lt;/STRONG&gt; (e.g., revenue variance, SLA compliance)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aggregations&lt;/STRONG&gt; for KPIs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1176959047"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reporting &amp;amp; Dashboard Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With embedded SAC, you can:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Build &lt;STRONG&gt;Stories&lt;/STRONG&gt; combining charts, tables, and text.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create &lt;STRONG&gt;Numeric Charts&lt;/STRONG&gt; for KPIs like Open Tickets or Revenue.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use &lt;STRONG&gt;Color Coding &amp;amp; Conditional Formatting&lt;/STRONG&gt; for better insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable &lt;STRONG&gt;Drill-down Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; for detailed exploration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Share dashboards securely across teams&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-980445542"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits for Sales &amp;amp; Service Teams&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Managers&lt;/STRONG&gt; can track pipeline health, forecast accuracy, and order conversion.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Managers&lt;/STRONG&gt; can monitor ticket resolution times, escalation trends, and customer satisfaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Executives&lt;/STRONG&gt; get consolidated dashboards for strategic decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-913014756"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF00FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Available Tables for Reporting &amp;amp; Dashbaord&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-12-05_15-49-45.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/349006i155785506B2B3F5C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-12-05_15-49-45.png" alt="2025-12-05_15-49-45.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="1150"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Available Table Names&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Techncial Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Individual Customer&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;individualcustomerservice_individualCustomer_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Volume Pipeline(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;volumepipelineservice_pipeline_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Quote Header&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesquoteservice_salesQuote_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Topic Analyzer Analytical Model&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;mlnlptopicanalyzerservice_caseTopicAnalysisResult_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Unique User Logins&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productmetricsservice_uniqueUserLogins_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Territory&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesterritoryservice_salesTerritory_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Competitor Product&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;competitorproductservice_competitorProduct_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Account Team Members&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accountservice_accountTeamMember_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Quote Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesquoteservice_salesQuoteItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Interaction Insight Analysis&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;bizinteractioninsightservice_interactionInsightAnalysis_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Templates Usage Information&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;templateusageservice_usageInfo_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Product&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productservice_product_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunity_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Channel information&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;emailchannelservice_channelInfo_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Account Sales Data&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accountservice_accountSalesArrangement_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Account Hierarchy&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accounthierarchyservice_accountHierarchy_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Plant&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;plantservice_plant_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Subscription Contract Header&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;subscriptioncontractservice_subscriptionContract_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Competitor(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;competitorservice_competitor_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Case&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;caseservice_case_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Aggregated API Statistics&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productmetricsservice_aggregatedAPIStats_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Service Category&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;servicecategoryservice_serviceCategory_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Contact&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;contactpersonservice_contactPerson_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Warranty Analytical Model&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;warrantyservice_warranty_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Quote Item(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesquoteservice_salesQuoteItem_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Analytical Model of In-Person Interactions&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;personinteractionservice_personInteraction_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Distribution Chain&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productservice_productSalesDistributionChain_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Case Flow Log Analytical Model&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;caseflowservice_caseFlowLog_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Competitor Product&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityCompetitorProduct_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey Design Element&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveydesignservice_surveyDesignElement_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Email interaction information&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;emailservice_emailInteractionInfo_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Letter Interaction&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;letterinteractionservice_letterInteraction_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Territory&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityTerritory_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveyservice_surveyResponse_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Contract Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salescontractservice_salesContractItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Revenue Schedule&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityRevenueSchedule_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Functional Location&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;functionallocationservice_functionalLocation_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Case(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;caseservice_case_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;opportunityItem_ext(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityItem_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Entity Count Metric&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productmetricsservice_entityCountMetric_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Unit of Measure Conversions&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productservice_productUnitOfMeasureConversion_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Registered Product&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;registeredproductservice_registeredProduct_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Service Catalog&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;servicecatalogservice_serviceCatalog_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Lead&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;leadservice_lead_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey Design Matrix Column&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveydesignservice_surveyDesignMatrixColumn_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Product Group&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productgroupservice_productGroup_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Service Order Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;serviceorderservice_serviceOrderItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Revenue Plan&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityRevenuePlan_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey Design&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveydesignservice_surveyDesign_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;accountSalesArrangement_ext(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accountservice_accountSalesArrangement_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Employee(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;employeeservice_employee_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Service Level&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;servicelevelservice_serviceLevel_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Subscription Contract Items&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;subscriptioncontractservice_subscriptionContractItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Chat&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;chatservice_chatInteraction_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Account&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accountservice_account_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Visit&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;visitservice_visit_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Lead Territory&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;leadservice_leadSalesTerritory_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;lbl_interaction_insight_analysis_result&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;bizinteractioninsightservice_interactionInsightResult_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Service Order&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;serviceorderservice_serviceOrder_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Forecast Opportunities(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;forecastservice_opportunity_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Visit(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;visitservice_visit_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Account(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;accountservice_account_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Time Log&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;timelogservice_timeLog_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Header&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunity_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Opportunity Related Entity&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;opportunityservice_opportunityRelatedObject_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Task&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;taskservice_task_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Organizational Unit&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;organizationalunitservice_organizationalUnit_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;User&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;userservice_user_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Case Related Object&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;caseservice_relatedObject_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Order Header&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesorderservice_salesOrder_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey Design Matrix Row&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveydesignservice_surveyDesignMatrixRow_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Call Lists&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;calllistservice_calllist_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Installed Base&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;installedbaseservice_installedBase_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Employee&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;employeeservice_employee_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Topic Keyword Analyzer Analytical Model&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;mlnlptopicanalyzerservice_caseTopicKeywordAnalysisResult_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Competitor&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;competitorservice_competitor_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Order Item&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salesorderservice_salesOrderItem_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Lead Product&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;leadservice_leadProduct_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Appointments&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;appointmentservice_appointment_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Lead Related Object&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;leadservice_leadRelatedObject_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Employee Assignments for Organizational Unit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;organizationalunitservice_organizationalUnitEmployeeAssignment_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Phone Calls&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;phoneservice_phoneCall_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Survey Design Element Response Option&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;surveydesignservice_surveyDesignResponseOption_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Pipeline Flow(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;pipelineflowservice_pipelineFlow_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Product(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;productservice_product_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Sales Contract Header&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;salescontractservice_salesContract_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="468.5px"&gt;Pipeline(Extension)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="680.5px"&gt;pipelineservice_pipeline_ext_view&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/embedded-analytics-for-sap-sales-amp-service-cloud-v2-list-of-available/ba-p/14284830"/>
    <published>2025-12-05T15:53:26.048000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
