<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Governance-Risk-Compliance-(GRC)-and-Cybersecurity-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Governance, Risk, Compliance (GRC), and Cybersecurity</title>
  <updated>2025-08-09T23:10:42.818089+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Governance, Risk, Compliance (GRC), and Cybersecurity/pd-p/237150e2-6555-4a16-b49e-e93dbf1891da" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Governance, Risk, Compliance (GRC), and Cybersecurity blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-leverage-free-trade-agreements-for-increased-competitiveness/ba-p/14087649</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: Leverage Free Trade Agreements for Increased Competitiveness</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T23:49:02.418000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_0-1745788195171.jpeg" style="width: 500px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255307i329468429807D9BC/image-dimensions/500x300?v=v2" width="500" height="300" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_0-1745788195171.jpeg" alt="T_Frenehard_0-1745788195171.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the era globalized supply chain, trade arrangements such as Preferential Trade Agreements (PTA), Regional Trade Agreements (RTA) or Free Trade Agreements (FTA), are designed to help organizations be more competitive in the global marketplace through reduced tariffs – or even no tariffs at all in the case of FTAs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At a geopolitical level, the Free Trade Agreements instrument has also been designed with a much wider objective to reduce trade barriers and, by that, facilitate cross-border import and export, and even “&lt;EM&gt;provide mechanisms that can contribute to economic stability, recovery, and resilience&lt;/EM&gt;” as per the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Despite uncertainty and rapidly evolving rules, a recent Gartner Research paper – &lt;A href="https://www.gartner.com/document-reader/document/6186455?ref=solrAll&amp;amp;refval=455135003" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Benchmarking Chief Supply Chain Officer (CSCO) Perspectives on the Shifting Tariff and Trade Environment&lt;/A&gt;, still identified that “&lt;EM&gt;More than half (59%) of surveyed CSCOs see opportunities to benefit their organization amid the evolving global trade environment, such as relaxed or reduced regulations, lower corporate tax rates and openings to make gains against competitors&lt;/EM&gt;”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is a clear indicator that companies are looking at making use of all the options available to them to strengthen their market presence. Including using tariff optimization of course.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With each preferential agreement containing a protocol specifying the conditions under which a product is regarded as an originating product of the signatory states, getting a formal proof of origin or a compliant self-certification declaration is easier said than done. And it is the duty of the company itself to determine applicability of preferential trade legislation programs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thankfully, Trade Preference Management capabilities, including rules of origin rule sets for instance, are available in SAP Global Trade Services or help organizations document and automate the process. SAP Global Trade Services can then determine for each product whether the specifications of the preferential agreements are met with regard to the sufficient working or processing of non-originating materials, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_1-1745788195176.png" style="width: 601px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255306i27899FD164CDB71D/image-dimensions/601x389?v=v2" width="601" height="389" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_1-1745788195176.png" alt="T_Frenehard_1-1745788195176.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since this is much more than just an IT feature activation, I wanted to invite experts in the domain to offer their insights on best practices in terms of free trade agreement implementation: where to start and to go on about it. And I was very fortunate that Greta Bhatia Villagran – CEO and Founder of Pinary Inc agreed to share her deep expertise on the matter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1709328751"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Who is Pinary?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have been researching SAP Global Trade Services, you may have already come across our joint customer story highlighting Pinary’s expertise with SAP Global Trade Services: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/financial-management/global-trade-management.html#:~:text=Simplifying%20global%20trade%20complexities" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Simplifying global trade complexities&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this is not the case, allow me to briefly introduce this expert SAP partner in the domain of international trade management. Pinary is a woman-owned business, defined by its commendable core values of honesty, transparency, and a pro-client approach. Thanks to their industry expertise, technology insights, and vast experience in this domain, Greta and her team boast a zero-defect go-live rate. Not bad, don’t you think?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And you will be able to find much more details on their expertise and service offering at the following location: &lt;A href="https://www.pinaryinc.com/services/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Pinary Inc.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1512815246"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;From your experience, what trade agreement best practices would you recommend companies implement?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When implementing Free Trade Agreements (FTAs) in SAP Global Trade Services (GTS), it is important to recognize that success is not only driven by system design and configuration, but equally by business process readiness and supplier engagement. While rules of origin are often provided by trusted third-party content providers and uploaded into GTS, governance over how the rules are applied and the accuracy of underlying master data remains essential. Although GTS significantly automates preferential calculations and reduces the day-to-day workload for the business, strong governance and ongoing internal training must be made a key part of the program to ensure sustainable compliance. Automating preferential calculation relies heavily on clean product data, complete bill of materials (BOMs), and accurate material classification with the tariff codes, and timely supplier declarations. Therefore, it is critical to involve suppliers early in the process, especially when introducing automation of Long-Term Supplier Declarations (LTSDs). Educating suppliers on the benefits of timely and accurate completion, such as, smoother trade flows, cost savings, and improved competitiveness ensures stronger participation and reduces delays. Internally companies should also establish a clear ownership of trade compliance responsibilities, maintain robust monitoring of key compliance metrics, and set up escalation paths for exceptions. Regular training, internal alignment between trade, procurement, and logistics teams, and a focus on data governance build a strong foundation for a sustainable FTA program.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1316301741"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where and how would you suggest companies start their Free Trade Agreement automation project?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Companies should start by evaluating their current trade compliance processes and data landscape. A readiness assessment to review product master data, supplier management processes, and existing trade agreements that are in scope is a critical first step. It is advisable to prioritize agreements that deliver the highest commercial value and align with key markets. From there, building a phased approach that includes supplier onboarding, data cleanup, and system integration milestones will help the organization manage complexity and reduce risk. It is equally important to also secure executive sponsorship early, to ensure cross-functional buy-in and resources. Typically, successful projects start small, therefore it is recommended to implement a pilot covering selected products and suppliers, which can be expanded once the processes are tested and stabilized. Keeping business objectives in clear view, rather than treating FTA automation as purely a system implementation, results in stronger adoption and long-term return on investment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1119788236"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finally, what are some pitfalls you recommend companies pay particular attention to when working on Free Trade Agreement initiatives?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Several pitfalls can derail FTA initiatives if not proactively addressed. First, underestimating the importance of clean and structured data, both in the material master and in supplier declaration is a common risk. Accurate tariff classification is especially critical, as errors at this stage can lead to incorrect preferential qualification, compliance risks, and potential penalties. Second, lack of supplier communication can significantly delay onboarding and jeopardize preferential claims. Suppliers must understand not only the new requirements but also the benefits to them, and processes should be put in place to manage non-responsiveness. Third, companies should resist the urge to overcomplicate the initial scope; focusing on too many agreements, products, or automation features at once can lead to unnecessary delays. &amp;nbsp;A phased approach typically delivers better results. In addition, thorough testing of preferential calculation logic and end-to-end scenarios is essential before go-live to identify potential gaps. Investing in user training is equally critical to ensure business teams understand not only the system but also the underlying compliance responsibilities. Finally, continuous monitoring after go-live is often overlooked. Trade compliance is not static, and changes in regulations, sourcing, and product design must be managed to keep the program compliant and audit ready.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can read, this is undoubtably a complex process. But, in a highly competitive environment, companies can make use of trade agreements to achieve great benefits including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="94"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_2-1745788195177.png" style="width: 51px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255305iCEE500DDFB5E84E4/image-dimensions/51x51?v=v2" width="51" height="51" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_2-1745788195177.png" alt="T_Frenehard_2-1745788195177.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="507"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reduce customs duties&lt;/STRONG&gt; with preferential origin duty rates&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="94"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_3-1745788195177.png" style="width: 51px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255308i8FB2F9720C9831AB/image-dimensions/51x51?v=v2" width="51" height="51" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_3-1745788195177.png" alt="T_Frenehard_3-1745788195177.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="507"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Avoid “worst case” determinations&lt;/STRONG&gt; for multi-sourced products&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="94"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_4-1745788195177.png" style="width: 50px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/255309i0D82B784544698B7/image-dimensions/50x50?v=v2" width="50" height="50" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_4-1745788195177.png" alt="T_Frenehard_4-1745788195177.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="507"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improve competitiveness&lt;/STRONG&gt; by reducing duty costs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;What about you, does your company leverage trade agreements to improve its competitiveness? I look forward to reading your thoughts and comments either on this blog or on Twitter &lt;A href="https://twitter.com/tfrenehard" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;@TFrenehard&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-leverage-free-trade-agreements-for-increased-competitiveness/ba-p/14087649"/>
    <published>2025-04-28T23:49:02.418000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/quick-enablement-of-sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-with-iag/ba-p/14093134</id>
    <title>Quick enablement of SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance with IAG QuickStart Service</title>
    <updated>2025-05-07T16:28:05.451000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Elvira_Khuzina</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1515939</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quick enablement of SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance with IAG QuickStart Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can streamline access management for both cloud-based and on-premise applications by implementing SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance (IAG) containing Access Analysis Service, Access Request Service, Role Design Service, Access Certification Service and Privileged Access Management Service. The configuration of SAP Cloud IAG can be subdivided in two main parts: basic steps relevant to all customers and steps that include individual settings. SAP Services offers the IAG QuickStart Service to simplify and speed up performance of the first part providing the initial setup and the technical baseline configuration in a short timeframe using SAP Best Practices content. The scope of the service includes the configuration of two target applications (incl. their productive as well as non-productive tenants) and a knowledge transfer session.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;How IAG QuickStart Service is performed?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Questionnaire&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Initially, SAP Services sends to a customer a questionnaire about technical data, required technical users and system hostnames. The information provided will be later used for automatic configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Ensure prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As prerequisites, the customer must provide network configuration and additional configuration required, e.g., SAP Cloud Connector and SAP Cloud Identity Services (SCI). These activities are out of the scope of the IAG QuickStart Service itself. Using SCI with SAP Cloud IAG is mandatory, in case it is not in place yet and the customer doesn’t have resources or knowledge to configure it, SAP Services can support as well with its dedicated SCI service offerings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Automatic and manual SAP Cloud IAG configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This stage includes the initial setup and technical baseline configuration, as well as setting up the connection to two target systems. Using scripts allows to significantly reduce time of the basic configuration steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Services &lt;SPAN&gt;utilizes those scripts that run on the basis of technical information provided by the customer, aiming to accomplish the following tasks&lt;/SPAN&gt;: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Setup of SAP Cloud IAG subaccounts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Setup of SAP Identity Authentication Service (IAS) standard groups for workflow and authorization purposes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Establish trust between SAP Cloud IAG and SAP IAS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Setup of SAP Cloud IAG standard destinations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Setup of IPS proxy systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Setup of target system destinations for two applications (excluding prerequisite steps in target systems and connectivity). We recommend selecting IAS as one of the two target systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. SAP service incident&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Services will create required SAP incidents on customer’s behalf, e.g., to upload SAP standard ruleset to SAP Cloud IAG.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Knowledge transfer and hand-over&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Services provides a configuration document, conducts a knowledge transfer workshop and hands over the preconfigured solution to the customer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;What is the outcome of the service and further steps?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a result, the customer obtains a basic configuration that facilitates rapid activation of SAP Cloud IAG such that the customer can focus on configuring the functional aspects. After the service hand over, the customer can configure SAP Cloud IAG functionality according to company needs and test scenarios. Here as well SAP Services can support using their long-lasting SAP Cloud IAG project experience from many other customer projects.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/quick-enablement-of-sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-with-iag/ba-p/14093134"/>
    <published>2025-05-07T16:28:05.451000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ai-security-how-to-tamperproof-ai-llm-s-with-sap-btp-kyma-and/ba-p/14099291</id>
    <title>SAP AI Security - How To: Tamperproof AI LLM's with SAP BTP Kyma and Enterprise Blockchain 🚀</title>
    <updated>2025-05-12T18:18:57.579000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndySilvey</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1397601</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This Blog is hand written...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Continuing the blog series on SAP and Enterprise Blockchain, which started with the,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/why-i-love-sap-and-blockchain-databases-and-why-you-should-too/ba-p/13625869" target="_blank"&gt;Why I love SAP and Blockchain Databases and why you should too &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and went through the journey of&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-enterprise-architecture-positioning-blockchain-database-as-an/ba-p/13629842" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;SAP Enterprise Architecture:&lt;/FONT&gt; Positioning Blockchain Database as an Enterprise Technology Standard &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-enterprise-architecture-let-the-use-case-find-the-blockchain/ba-p/13632458" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;SAP Enterprise Architecture:&lt;/FONT&gt; Let the Use Case find the Blockchain&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the Enterprise Blockchain Business Capability Map &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/enterprise-architecture-enterprise-blockchain-platform-business-capability/ba-p/13902640" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;FONT size="1 2 3 4 5 6 7"&gt;Enterprise Architecture:&lt;/FONT&gt; Enterprise Blockchain Platform Business Capability Map &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and subsequently discussed all manner of SAP related Enterprise Blockchain use cases which can be implemented today with the SAP BTP Kyma Service and Enterprise Blockchain software (eg atkrypto Enterprise Blockchain Platform for SAP), and which included a how to guide on how to run your own Enterprise Blockchain on the SAP BTP Kyma&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/running-your-own-blockchain-on-the-sap-btp-kyma-trial-a-hands-on-how-to/ba-p/13724580" target="_blank"&gt;Running Your Own Blockchain on The SAP BTP Kyma Trial: A Hands On How To Guide &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;then, this blog is going to explain a very simple way to secure SAP AI and AI LLM's with Enterprise Blockchain running on the SAP BTP Kyma Service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my opinion, Enterprise Blockchain is the world's most tamper resistant store of data, providing tamper resistance to a level which cannot be achieved by traditional Enterprise Database products and technology. I've explained this in detail in this blog:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/why-i-love-sap-and-blockchain-databases-and-why-you-should-too/ba-p/13625869" target="_blank"&gt;Why I love SAP and Blockchain Databases and why you should too &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_2-1747065636219.png" style="width: 584px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260144i69DB35350B5D8530/image-dimensions/584x294?v=v2" width="584" height="294" role="button" title="AndySilvey_2-1747065636219.png" alt="AndySilvey_2-1747065636219.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A lot has been written, and is being written on SAP and AI and LLM security, and rightly so, because at the same time this technology is both a huge opportunity and a huge risk. The opportunities are vast, in my opinion SAP &amp;amp; AI basically speeds up decision making across any dimension where it is applied, and therefore the corresponding risk is, can we trust the advice and recommendation that the SAP AI is giving us, what if the AI has been tampered with by a bad actor ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are some very nice articles and documents on this subject, here are a few:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2023/09/729b7ea1-8a7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Assessing the Security of Large Language Models - Exploring vulnerabilities, threats, and potential malicious use cases for generative AI as presented by the rapid proliferation of LLMs&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/defending-against-ai-security-risks-by-turning-llms-on-llms/ba-p/14032661" target="_blank"&gt;Defending Against AI Security Risks by Turning LLM... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;thanks to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160843"&gt;@JayThvV&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/navigating-the-generative-ai-era-blockchain-is-key-for-resilient-cross/ba-p/13581081" target="_blank"&gt;Navigating the Generative AI Era: Blockchain is ke... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;thanks to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/385483"&gt;@MirkoValentic&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/secure-your-llm-consuming-sap-generative-ai-deployments-in-a-simple-python/ba-p/13598263" target="_blank"&gt;Secure your LLM: Consuming SAP Generative AI deplo... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;thanks to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125338"&gt;@AronMac&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;who drew the perfect picture of the problem:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_0-1747063834020.png" style="width: 591px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260138iC1C7A9344C697382/image-dimensions/591x206?v=v2" width="591" height="206" role="button" title="AndySilvey_0-1747063834020.png" alt="AndySilvey_0-1747063834020.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This is Aron's picture (may I please ask for retrospective permission to reproduce it here) and it perfectly identifies where the risk is, read Aron's blog for more details&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/nl-sap-innovation-day-for-supply-chain/pdfs/future-supply-chain-with-sap-business-ai.pdf" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt; Secure Large Language Model Access&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_1-1747063964105.png" style="width: 583px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260139i6540D049794C9D75/image-dimensions/583x307?v=v2" width="583" height="307" role="button" title="AndySilvey_1-1747063964105.png" alt="AndySilvey_1-1747063964105.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The problem is how can we make AI LLM's tamper proof and therefore verifiably trustable ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;tldr:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The technical solution is basically a variation of this one,&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/cyber-security-protection-for-s-4hana-backups-with-enterprise-blockchain/ba-p/13872997" target="_blank"&gt;Cyber Security Protection for S/4HANA Backups with Enterprise Blockchain and SAP BTP Kyma &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, we simply run a background job which takes a digital finger print of the LLM at regular intervals and compares the hash each time to the original digital fingerprint hash which we have stored in the Enterprise Blockchain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The What:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An AI LLM is Data, there is a process to get from zero to operational, and that is, &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1) Initial Data Intake, 2) Data Conditioning, 3) Model Development, 4) Specialisation Phase, 5) Production Integration, 6) LifeCycle Oversight&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;and each phase of the process can be secured and protected with Enterprise Blockchain running on the SAP BTP Kyma.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Initial Data Intake&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Inputs: Collected content such as user-generated inputs, external datasets, sensor readings, or media files.&lt;BR /&gt;Risks: Unauthorized data sourcing, risk of ingesting biased or harmful content, and accidental inclusion of proprietary materials.&lt;BR /&gt;Safeguard: Store a cryptographic hash of each backup in the Enterprise Blockchain (SAP BTP Kyma). Automate batch jobs to periodically re-hash the current data and verify it against the original to ensure integrity and traceability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Conditioning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Inputs: Raw collected information that requires transformation into usable formats through parsing, validation, and structuring.&lt;BR /&gt;Risks: Accidental disclosure of sensitive patterns, inconsistent formatting leading to faulty models, and compliance oversights.&lt;BR /&gt;Safeguard: Generate a unique digital signature of the conditioned dataset and record it in the Enterprise Blockchain via SAP BTP Kyma. Schedule automated processes to regularly verify new signatures against the stored baseline for authenticity checks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Model Development&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Inputs: Curated datasets that serve as the learning foundation for model algorithms.&lt;BR /&gt;Risks: Loss of dataset lineage, misuse of confidential training sources, and exposure to adversarial inputs.&lt;BR /&gt;Safeguard: Digitally fingerprint the dataset versions and register them on the SAP BTP Kyma-based Blockchain. Use recurring batch processes to ensure the data used for training remains tamper-free and aligned with the original set.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Specialization Phase&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Inputs: Base models enhanced using narrowly focused or domain-specific datasets for accuracy improvements.&lt;BR /&gt;Risks: Fine-tuning errors due to data drift, accidental overwrites of optimized parameters, or non-compliant tuning sources.&lt;BR /&gt;Safeguard: Secure a hash of the updated models and input data in the SAP BTP Kyma Blockchain. Implement scheduled revalidation by hashing updated files and comparing them to the secured originals to prevent silent regressions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Production Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Inputs: Trained models deployed to serve real-time inputs, APIs, or embedded environments.&lt;BR /&gt;Risks: Exposure of inference logic, tampering with deployed assets, or leakage of sensitive model behavior.&lt;BR /&gt;Safeguard: Record a hashed snapshot of all deployment artifacts within the SAP BTP Kyma Blockchain. Automate monitoring routines that continuously compare current deployment fingerprints to the authenticated versions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lifecycle Oversight&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Inputs: System logs, telemetry data, and user interaction feedback used to update models or flag issues.&lt;BR /&gt;Risks: Silent model degradation, undocumented model mutations, or targeted manipulation attempts such as prompt injections.&lt;BR /&gt;Safeguard: Store a verifiable hash of lifecycle data and changes into the Enterprise Blockchain on SAP BTP Kyma. Set up recurring batch tasks to re-hash current states and detect unauthorized alterations or drifts in model behavior.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The How:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It all sounds easy doesn't it, and that's because it really is, all you need is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Your AI LLM's&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. A regular Backup of the AI LLM's - this should be automated&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Take a digital fingerprint hash of each backup of the AI LLM's (I wrote about that here: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/cyber-security-protection-for-s-4hana-backups-with-enterprise-blockchain/ba-p/13872997" target="_blank"&gt;Cyber Security Protection for S/4HANA Backups with Enterprise Blockchain and SAP BTP Kyma &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- this should be automate&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Get the SAP BTP and the BTP Kyma Service&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Deploy Enterprise Blockchain on the SAP BTP Kyma Service (here's a how to guide:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/running-your-own-blockchain-on-the-sap-btp-kyma-trial-a-hands-on-how-to/ba-p/13724580" target="_blank"&gt;Running Your Own Blockchain on The SAP BTP Kyma Trial: A Hands On How To Guide &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Store the first digital fingerprint of each LLM backup in the Enterprise Blockchain running on the SAP BTP Kyma - this should be automated&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Run a regular job to take a digital fingerprint of the AI LLM and compare the hash to the hash stored in the Enterprise Blockchain running on the SAP BTP Kyma - this should be automated&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The technical architecture would look something like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_4-1747066353457.png" style="width: 575px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260146iEE5164B4F89E567E/image-dimensions/575x322?v=v2" width="575" height="322" role="button" title="AndySilvey_4-1747066353457.png" alt="AndySilvey_4-1747066353457.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wrapping up, conclusions:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Trustable Enterprise AI depends on Data being stored in the Enterprise Blockchain&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Blockchain is:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;The Digital Transformation of Information Security&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. The Next Generation Data Integrity, Originality, Confidentiality Protection&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Re-imagining Information Security&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Natively, out of the box, due to its special characteristics the strongest, hardest, most resilient Enterprise Database product&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Blockchain is both:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. a Secure Store&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. a Secure Communication Channel&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The configurable Enterprise Blockchain Wallet enables you to store Big Data 'Off-Chain' and the hashes of the Big Data are stored safely and securely on the Enterprise Blockchain Database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The good news is, as we discussed in the previous blog, this is no longer hype, we can do all of this today,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;and now, within the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/norway/partners/partner-program/build.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Partner Edge Open EcoSystem&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;there are enabling technology Blockchain Products designed and built by SAP Experts specifically for the needs of SAP Customers to make doing Blockchain and SAP easy, and so you can do SAP and Blockchain, today it's real and there's nothing stopping you.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So what are we waiting for ? Oh yeah, more use cases, ok, that will be the next blog.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What do you think, are the words AI, Blockchain, Web3, Distributed Ledger Technology, starting to appear in your Company's visions and technology visions ? What use cases are you looking at ? Let's chat about it in the comments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For now, over and out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Andy Silvey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Independent SAP Technical Architect [you might also find my SAP S/4HANA RISE &amp;amp; BTP Toolbox interesting:&amp;nbsp; &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/%EF%B8%8F-the-sap-s-4hana-rise-amp-sap-btp-toolbox-%EF%B8%8F/ba-p/13944069" target="_blank"&gt;🧰👷‍ The SAP S/4HANA RISE &amp;amp; SAP BTP - Toolbox 👷‍🧰&lt;/A&gt;] and CEO of atkrypto (.) io&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Author Bio:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Andy Silvey is a 26 years SAP Technology veteran&amp;nbsp;[&lt;EM&gt;15 years SAP Basis and 11 years SAP Tech Arch including Tech, Integration, Security, Data from 3.1H to S/4HANA PCE on RISE and the BTP and everything in between, and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-blog-posts/andy-silvey-scn-moderator-spotlight/ba-p/13054438" target="_self"&gt;former SCN Moderator and Mentor alumni&lt;/A&gt;].&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Andy is also co-Founder of atkrypto inc, an startup whose ambition is to make Blockchain easy for Enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;atkrypto (.) io's flagship product is the atkrypto Enterprise Blockchain Platform for SAP,&amp;nbsp; and atkrypto (.) io is a SAP Partner Edge Open EcoSystem Partner.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;atkrypto Enterprise Blockchain Platform for SAP has been designed by SAP Independent Experts for the needs of SAP Customers and to be deployed on the SAP BTP Kyma Runtime Service and leverage native integration to SAP Products.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;atkrypto&amp;nbsp;Enterprise Blockchain Platform for SAP has a number of unique qualities, including being the only Blockchain software in the world which has a DataCenter version and a light mobile version which can run on Edge/IoT/Mobile devices and enables data to be written to the Blockchain at the Edge where that same Blockchain is running on a Server in the DataCenter, protecting the integrity and originality of data from the Edge to Insights. Taking Blockchain to the Data at the Edge instead of taking the Data to the Blockchain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ai-security-how-to-tamperproof-ai-llm-s-with-sap-btp-kyma-and/ba-p/14099291"/>
    <published>2025-05-12T18:18:57.579000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-is-a-tariff-who-pays-and-why-it-matters-to-your-business/ba-p/14098533</id>
    <title>What is a tariff, who pays, and why it matters to your business</title>
    <updated>2025-05-13T07:00:00.028000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="300911_AdobeStock_500170933.jpeg" style="width: 600px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/259869iEF8842DBBE8522C4/image-dimensions/600x337?v=v2" width="600" height="337" role="button" title="300911_AdobeStock_500170933.jpeg" alt="300911_AdobeStock_500170933.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;International trade has enjoyed relative stability in these last few decades—ruled by the arrangements of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade firstly and then by the regulations of the World Trade Organization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H2 id="what-are-tariffs" id="toc-hId-1710281065"&gt;What are tariffs?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In a nutshell, tariffs are an import tax. As such, they are generally considered part of the cost of goods sold because they are a direct cost associated with buying or producing a product. Most times, tariffs are set ad valorem, hence a percentage of the value of an import. But they could also be a specific tariff consisting of a fixed fee per unit of good (unit, ton, etc.), or even a combination of the two.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simple examples here are the “Chicken Tax,” a 25% tariff on light trucks imported in the US that started in 1964 as a retaliatory measure against European tariffs on chicken imports ... and still in effect to this day. Under the Australian Cheese and Curd Quota Scheme, a tariff quota applies to certain types of cheese with a $0.096 duty per kilogram until 11,500 tonnes per year and a higher rate after that.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="who-can-decide-on-tariffs" id="toc-hId-1513767560"&gt;Who can decide on tariffs?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;National governments, typically the legislative branch, have the authority to set tariffs to impose on their trading partners. In most cases, they do so for three reasons:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Increase revenue&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Since tariffs are duties to be paid when importing a good, this creates a revenue stream for countries that can be used to balance their budget or for public services. As per the Council of the European Union, for instance,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" title="13.7% of the EU budget comes from tariffs" href="https://www.consilium.europa.eu/en/policies/eu-tariffs-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;13.7% of the EU budget comes from tariffs&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Protect domestic industry&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;By specifically increasing tariffs on a defined scope of products and making it redhibitory to import these goods, governments are essentially protecting the local industry and associated jobs by promoting local production, either via established national actors or via Foreign Direct Investment mechanisms, both resulting in strengthening domestic manufacturing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Negotiation leverage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;When emergency tariffs are imposed, these can be limited in time and used as leverage to encourage concessions from other countries. Once the trading partners have agreed on new terms and any trade imbalance is reduced, tariffs can be lifted. This has often been described as a tool of “hardball diplomacy,” and is usually only available to countries already in a commanding position.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;International organizations such as the World Trade Organization can also influence—but not enforce—tariff policies through agreements. With its primary purpose being the promotion of open trade for the benefit of all and trade facilitation, when there are trade disputes such as disagreements between parties on tariffs, member countries can appeal to the World Trade Organization Dispute Settlement Body. If mediation fails, the Dispute Settlement Body can authorize the winning party to implement retaliatory measures such as trade sanctions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="who-pays-tariffs" id="toc-hId-1317254055"&gt;Who pays tariffs?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is the importer’s responsibility to determine and pay the right duty to the customs authorities in the importing country. Any errors in the customs clearance process—for example, incorrect classification of goods, undervaluation, and declaring the wrong country of origin—can lead to delays and even fines and penalties for underpayment or non-payment of tariffs of course but could also escalate to goods being seized until resolution or even legal actions with lawsuits and criminal charges being brought forward. All actors in the supply chain should also ensure they maintain evidence of origin throughout the end-to-end supply chain as evidence may be required to determine the true origin of goods and to substantiate claims of sufficient transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Nevertheless, to maintain margins, or if absorbing increased costs would jeopardize the overall business sustainability, part or entirety of the duties can be passed on to customers—either directly to the consumer for wholesale products, or to other companies when the product enters a manufacturing process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Realizing that tariffs could impede competition and impact end customers with higher prices, governments have collaborated on trade agreements. Sometimes even annulling tariffs for defined products or industries. This has shaped some sectors that have moved to an integrated value-added supply chain making full use of these trade agreements to optimize the manufacturing of products by focusing on areas of expertise and lower costs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An example here would be the North American automotive sector where the United States and Canada have historically had a long-standing trade agreement that enables car manufacturers to buy raw materials in Canada, manufacture car components in the US, then move the components access border to Canada to enter the manufacturing of a large component and revert to the US to an assembly line, all without incurring duties at every crossing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="long-lasting-effects" id="toc-hId-1120740550"&gt;Long lasting effects&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A pernicious aspect of temporarily imposed tariffs is that they often remain in place long after their intended effect. Much like in the example of the Chicken Tax mentioned earlier. They can also shift to non-tariff barriers if negotiations result in incomplete agreements. Affected industries, therefore, must adapt to a new normal, implement a longer-term mitigation approach, or accept the landscape that this creates a new de facto situation—which can be once again rapidly shaken by changing political factors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In a growing networked economy where businesses, individuals, and governments are interconnected, protectionism and barriers can have unintended impacts that remain to be fully uncovered. Flexible planning and agility, enabling companies to react to changing environments, will be of the utmost importance for businesses worldwide.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;I would like to thank&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" title="The Chartered Institute of Export &amp;amp; International Trade" href="https://www.export.org.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;The Chartered Institute of Export &amp;amp; International Trade&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for their collaboration on this article.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/blogs/why-tariffs-matter-to-businesses" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Originally published&lt;/A&gt; on May 6, 2025 &amp;amp; reposted on this platform&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-is-a-tariff-who-pays-and-why-it-matters-to-your-business/ba-p/14098533"/>
    <published>2025-05-13T07:00:00.028000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-why-grc-matters-for-growing-businesses/ba-p/14090087</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: Why GRC Matters for Growing Businesses</title>
    <updated>2025-05-27T07:00:00.036000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_0-1745985543697.jpeg" style="width: 500px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256388i18CA08406B1D41E8/image-dimensions/500x334?v=v2" width="500" height="334" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_0-1745985543697.jpeg" alt="T_Frenehard_0-1745985543697.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“&lt;EM&gt;Governance, Risk, and Compliance is not for us, we’re a mid-size company and these topics are only for large and international groups&lt;/EM&gt;”. if I was given a penny every time someone said this, then I would be a millionaire! And much like Jason and his Golden Fleece it is a myth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Companies of all sizes face risks, and companies of all sizes must comply with regulatory frameworks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But a risk always has two facets: the potential negative outcome of course, and the potential upside.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, I therefore decided to look at both and highlight how GRC can help mid-size companies achieve their objectives and thrive in a complex business landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1710038091"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Main Priorities for Small and Midsize Businesses&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To be able to identify how GRC can be a value-add activity, the first order of business is to understand main priorities for executives in these companies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on 40+ studies and reports from various regions, a summary picture is as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_1-1745985543709.png" style="width: 501px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256389i7D96F52A584B5878/image-dimensions/501x378?v=v2" width="501" height="378" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_1-1745985543709.png" alt="T_Frenehard_1-1745985543709.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the saying goes: clear as mud, right? So, let’s apply some analytics to this picture and group the priorities alongside 2 buckets: top challenges that SMEs need to address and top opportunities that they can leverage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1513524586"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Focus on top 5 challenges for SMBs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_2-1745985543718.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256387i8A8AE56BDEF11706/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_2-1745985543718.png" alt="T_Frenehard_2-1745985543718.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Governance, Risk, and Compliance is not a magic wand, so won’t solve all the issues of course. But it can help mitigate some of these challenges:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Digitization and Technology&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_3-1745985543719.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256390i8599242BE18ECC47/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_3-1745985543719.png" alt="T_Frenehard_3-1745985543719.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Digital transformation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: by “safeguarding” the digitalised landscape with embedded IT application controls, and identity and access management to ensure compliant access&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Online presence: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by protecting sensitive data from misuse and malicious access&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Poor use of technology: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by detecting and deterring cyber-attacks, but also by enforcing data sovereignty and residency requirements&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Funding&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_4-1745985543719.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256392i0F8DADF2A96EDB72/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_4-1745985543719.png" alt="T_Frenehard_4-1745985543719.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Funding the business: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by implementing IPO requirements&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seeking funding from investors: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by providing investors assurance on financial reports&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Rising (operating) Costs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_5-1745985543720.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256393i688CFC5F6C21A616/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_5-1745985543720.png" alt="T_Frenehard_5-1745985543720.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Increase in ongoing costs: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by improving operational efficiency (e.g. optimal operating cycle), and identifying invoice &amp;amp; inventory discrepancies&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Managing taxes (incl. filing): &lt;/STRONG&gt;by automating tax reporting and filing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tracking expenses: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by identifying payment anomalies (e.g. &lt;SPAN&gt;duplicate claims &amp;amp; other fraud,&lt;/SPAN&gt; expense claims outside of policy)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Sales and Revenue&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_6-1745985543720.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256394i8DD9DAAB1D4C5F8A/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_6-1745985543720.png" alt="T_Frenehard_6-1745985543720.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Attracting new customers&lt;/STRONG&gt;: by screening potential customers effortlessly to ensure that no business is performed with sanctioned parties&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Client dependence: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by risk assessing customers to reduce dependencies and improve reliability&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Converting leads: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by protecting sensitive customer data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Talent Shortage and Staffing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_7-1745985543720.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256395i9B24AC9C692CD020/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_7-1745985543720.png" alt="T_Frenehard_7-1745985543720.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recruiting talented staff: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by ensuring that localization of contracts is correctly performed for onboarding&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Churn and instability: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by promoting (and enforcing) ethical behaviour&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Retaining employees: &lt;/STRONG&gt;with ease of onboarding users to core systems and safe remote working&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Employee productivity&lt;/STRONG&gt;: with rapid and compliant user access provisioning, and by providing self-service password and access request&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Remote workforce&lt;/STRONG&gt;: by simplifying and securing logon to source systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1317011081"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Focus on top 5 opportunities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But it’s not all about managing the lurking threats. As all successful businesses know, it’s about leveraging the opportunities when they present themselves, and enhancing chances of success.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s change our lens and focus on these upsides instead:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_21-1745986065107.png" style="width: 886px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256410i48C891726CB7A841/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_21-1745986065107.png" alt="T_Frenehard_21-1745986065107.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here again, to be able to provide actionable suggestions, let’s break it down:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Digitization and Technology&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_9-1745985543726.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256399iAC02971A0A383B99/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_9-1745985543726.png" alt="T_Frenehard_9-1745985543726.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improving online presence:&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;by implementing data sovereignty and residency requirements, detecting and deterring cyber-attacks, and ultimately protecting sensitive data from misuse and malicious access&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Key Talent Staffing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_10-1745985543726.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256397i221498BFF0C6F679/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_10-1745985543726.png" alt="T_Frenehard_10-1745985543726.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Attracting key talent &lt;/STRONG&gt;but&lt;STRONG&gt; also Diversity, equity and inclusion: &lt;/STRONG&gt;with evidence of ethical behaviour and diversity, and no greenwashing especially when it comes to child or forced labour&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Personalized HR outreach&lt;/STRONG&gt;: with relevant localization of contracts to ensure applicability in relevant geographies&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Reducing (operating) Costs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_11-1745985543727.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256398i8B8A3BE68B989BEC/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_11-1745985543727.png" alt="T_Frenehard_11-1745985543727.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cutting costs: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by proactively detecting payment anomalies (duplicate invoices or fraudulent activities)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Sales and Revenue&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_12-1745985543727.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256400i9A3E9037E3992FB7/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_12-1745985543727.png" alt="T_Frenehard_12-1745985543727.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create new revenue streams&lt;/STRONG&gt;: by screening potential customers effortlessly to avoid high-risk businesses, individuals, and entities and more quickly confirming business parties&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Converting leads to customers: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by protecting sensitive customer data so protecting the company’s reputation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Scaling and Expanding&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_13-1745985543727.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256401i3810415399FDF292/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_13-1745985543727.png" alt="T_Frenehard_13-1745985543727.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Relocate or enter new markets:&lt;/STRONG&gt; by screening business partners to avoid high-risk businesses, individuals, and entities and more quickly confirming business parties&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expand internationally: &lt;/STRONG&gt;by automating tasks for international trade management and reacting more rapidly to changing trade dynamics (including tariff changes)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1120497576"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why now?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These challenges and opportunities of course aren’t exclusively relevant to small and medium organizations. But their top ranking reflects what business owners have rated their most pressing matters. Nevertheless, most companies would have very similar topics on their management agenda and GRC can act as a business enabler – not just a compliance exercise:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="634px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="109.078px"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Digitization and Technology&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="111.266px"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Funding&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114.938px"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operating Costs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="88.75px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales and Revenue&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="99.875px"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Talent and Staffing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="109.094px"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scaling and Expanding&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="109.078px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Digitized &amp;amp; integrated &lt;STRONG&gt;controls&lt;/STRONG&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;STRONG&gt;security&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;checks&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;identity management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Protect&lt;STRONG&gt; sensitive data &lt;/STRONG&gt;from misuse and malicious access&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Detect and deter &lt;STRONG&gt;cyber-attack&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enforce &lt;STRONG&gt;data sovereignty &lt;/STRONG&gt;and residency requirements&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="111.266px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Implement IPO &lt;STRONG&gt;compliance requirements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Provide investors &lt;STRONG&gt;assurance&lt;/STRONG&gt; on financial reports&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="114.938px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Improve &lt;STRONG&gt;operational efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and identify invoice &amp;amp; inventory &lt;STRONG&gt;discrepancies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Automate &lt;STRONG&gt;tax reporting and filing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Identify &lt;STRONG&gt;payment anomalies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="88.75px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;Screen&lt;/STRONG&gt; potential customers effortlessly&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Protect &lt;STRONG&gt;sensitive customer data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="99.875px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Protect brand with evidence of &lt;STRONG&gt;ethical behavior&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Safe &lt;STRONG&gt;remote working &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Rapid and &lt;STRONG&gt;compliant user access&lt;/STRONG&gt; provisioning, self-service password and access request, and &lt;STRONG&gt;secure logon &lt;/STRONG&gt;to multiple systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="109.094px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;Screen&lt;/STRONG&gt; business partners to avoid high-risk businesses, individuals, and entities&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Automate tasks for international &lt;STRONG&gt;trade management&lt;/STRONG&gt; and compliance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;And, even if there is no better time than the present, allow me to share a few insights from experts on why now is really a good time to start:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_20-1745985543735.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/256408iEBFE769BD571B502/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_20-1745985543735.png" alt="T_Frenehard_20-1745985543735.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What about you, does this resonate with the top priorities for your company?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are interested in learning more about SAP solutions for Governance, Risk, and Compliance, feel free to fill-in the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/request-demo.html?product=237150e2-6555-4a16-b49e-e93dbf1891da&amp;amp;productName=Governance%2C+Risk%2C+Compliance+%28GRC%29%2C+and+Cybersecurity&amp;amp;pageTitle=Cybersecurity+and+Governance%2C+Risk%2C+and+Compliance+Software&amp;amp;countryOfOrigin=en_au&amp;amp;refererPagePath=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sap.com%2Faustralia%2Fproducts%2Ffinancial-management%2Fgrc.html&amp;amp;refererContentPath=%2Fcontent%2Fsapdx%2Flanguages%2Fen_gb%2Fproducts%2Ffinancial-management%2Fgrc&amp;amp;navTitle=Request+a+Demo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;demo request form&lt;/A&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-why-grc-matters-for-growing-businesses/ba-p/14090087"/>
    <published>2025-05-27T07:00:00.036000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/kickstart-your-cloud-sap-grc-learning-journey-introduction-to-cloud-sap-grc/ba-p/14115962</id>
    <title>Kickstart your Cloud SAP GRC Learning Journey: Introduction to Cloud SAP GRC, its Submodules details</title>
    <updated>2025-06-05T10:56:56.081000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>santhosha_dasari</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/750626</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="1743422989454.jpg" style="width: 890px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268149i095F279DDAFBCAC8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1743422989454.jpg" alt="1743422989454.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I would recommend referring&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt; my below earlier article on SAP GRC (On-premise) before you start your journey into Cloud SAP GRC. It helps you understand the basic concepts and how On-premise SAP GRC helps organization to achieve business goals.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/kickstart-your-sap-grc-learning-journey-introduction-to-sap-grc-submodules/ba-p/13997059" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/kickstart-your-sap-grc-learning-journey-introduction-to-sap-grc-submodules/ba-p/13997059&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Cloud GRC encompasses a range of robust solutions tailored to meet diverse organizational needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Below are some of the key offerings in the SAP GRC, public cloud solutions portfolio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Risk Assurance Management&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Enterprise Threat Detection, Cloud Edition&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Watchlist Screening&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance is a comprehensive solution designed to simplify user access management in the cloud environment. While it offers similar functionality like on-premises SAP Access Control, it is not a cloud version of SAP Access Control (On-prem) or SAP Access Control hosted on cloud. Instead, it is a new SAAS solution from SAP, built on the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP). It supports both on-premise and cloud systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Submodules/services:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance, Access Analysis Service (like ARA)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance, Access Request Service (like ARM)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance, Role Design Service (like BRM)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance, Privileged Access Management service (like EAM)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance, access certification service (like UAR etc.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="iag.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268150i38EADC525E94D316/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="iag.png" alt="iag.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Image Source: SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Common IAG and Access Control scenarios:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Cloud IAG only - supports only Cloud systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Cloud IAG with Cloud Connector - supports both On-prem and cloud systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Access Control with IAG integrated edition (as a bridge) - supports both On-prem and cloud systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Access Control – supports only On-Prem and SuccessFactors EC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Reference SAP hep portal:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Risk and Assurance Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Risk Assurance Management (RAM) is a comprehensive solution designed to document risks and controls, automate controls to safeguard financial and nonfinancial data, policies, and processes in the cloud environment. &amp;nbsp;This can be like on-prem SAP Process Control. However, it is not a cloud version of SAP Process Control (On-Prem) or either SAP Process Control (on-Prem) hosted on cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Earlier it was called as “SAP Financial Compliance Management” solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;It provides the predefined integration and content for SAP S/4HANA on premise and in the cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ram.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268151iEEE5DD30D275BAA6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ram.png" alt="ram.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Image Source: SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Reference SAP hep portal:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/risk-and-assurance-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/risk-and-assurance-management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Enterprise Threat Detection, Cloud Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Enterprise Threat Detection enables you to evaluate security threats in your IT landscapes in real time by leveraging SAP and non-SAP log data. It helps to identify, analyze, and neutralize cybersecurity threats with real-time SIEM intelligence in your SAP applications as they happen and before serious damage occurs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This solution allows organizations to monitor and respond to potential threats in real-time, ensuring the security of your cloud operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key features/modules:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Log correlation and analysis&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Automated threat detection and alerting&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;·&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Straightforward integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="etd.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268152iA2B078CF662E87C4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="etd.png" alt="etd.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Image Source: SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Reference SAP hep portal:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ENTERPRISE_THREAT_DETECTION" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ENTERPRISE_THREAT_DETECTION&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Watchlist Screening&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Watch List Screening enables enterprises across all industries to screen the names and addresses of their business partners against sanctioned party lists, thus ensuring their compliance with guidelines, regulations, and legislation. To facilitate this task, SAP Watch List Screening is integrated with SAP Business Partner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;It helps in assessing potential risks on an exception basis helps avoid high-risk businesses, individuals, and entities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;This can be integrated with SAP S/4HANA and SAP S/4HANA Cloud, as well as with APIs to extend to other systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;A vital tool for screening against various watchlists to ensure compliance with legal and regulatory requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Reference SAP hep portal:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_WATCH_LIST_SCREENING" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_WATCH_LIST_SCREENING&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;EM&gt;I hope this helps to start your journey into Cloud SAP GRC also if you're aiming to level up your skills in Cloud SAP GRC ! By diving deep into these modules, you'll gain the knowledge and skills needed to excel in the world of Governance, Risk, and Compliance.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Please connect and follow&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;me for the next upcoming informative articles in SAP Security, GRC, BTP, Internal Controls and Risk &amp;amp; Controls area.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Share your thoughts in the comments below !&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/kickstart-your-cloud-sap-grc-learning-journey-introduction-to-cloud-sap-grc/ba-p/14115962"/>
    <published>2025-06-05T10:56:56.081000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-regulatory-compliance-trends-and-outlook/ba-p/14111181</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: Regulatory Compliance Trends and Outlook</title>
    <updated>2025-06-10T07:00:00.021000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_0-1748220354886.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265812iD9E0E2D7BDB0DB9B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_0-1748220354886.png" alt="T_Frenehard_0-1748220354886.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If looming trade wars and changing trade compliance dynamics have monopolized the debate recently, it’s undeniable that there are many other regulatory requirements that companies face – and more to come in the near future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition to the top risks report released at the beginning of the year (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blogs-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-risks-to-look-out-for-in-2025/ba-p/13972228" target="_blank"&gt;What Risks to Look Out for in 2025&lt;/A&gt;), I thought it might also be relevant to publish a consolidated view of the most often cited regulatory challenges for organizations. Immediate challenges, but also upcoming ones already on the radar for future enforcement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog summarizes the findings of 23+ individual reports as well as interviews with executives. It is by no means perfect nor exhaustive, but I am still hoping that it will prove useful for anyone in a compliance, audit or risk management role looking at planning the way ahead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1731309820"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Long story short&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cybersecurity &amp;amp; information protection are the major regulatory concerns for companies, closely followed by specific emerging laws for trusted and responsible Artificial Intelligence. Some may argue that trusted AI should also be part of Cybersecurity, and there are indeed areas of overlap, but since AI legislation goes beyond data protection and ventures into ethics and governance, I decided to follow the lead of reports that keep them separated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Combined with Environmental, Social and Governance and rapidly evolving Trade Compliance, these 4 categories together already cover over 50% of compliance concerns for companies for 2025-2027.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1534796315"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Top compliance requirements for next 12-24 months&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Altogether, the first 6 categories in the list are cited in 75% of the cases as main challenges facing organizations:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cybersecurity &amp;amp; Information Protection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_1-1748220354892.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265813iD2DA8954A2DA43DA/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_1-1748220354892.png" alt="T_Frenehard_1-1748220354892.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This grouping encapsulates requirements designed to safeguard information systems and data from cyber threats. Data privacy and protection and breach notification requirements are of course also in the scope here. Examples of legislations include the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) or the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) for instance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trusted/Responsible AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_2-1748220354897.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265814iEB8095D98987DD24/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_2-1748220354897.png" alt="T_Frenehard_2-1748220354897.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;As mentioned earlier in this blog, this is a separate category to Cybersecurity since it doesn’t focus exclusively on the data protection, but also includes ethical and accountability to ensure that artificial intelligence systems operate fairly and without discriminatory bias. One example here would be the EU AI Act but also the South Korea AI Framework Act.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Environmental, Social and Governance (ESG)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_3-1748220354901.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265815i345F4602AB496C00/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_3-1748220354901.png" alt="T_Frenehard_3-1748220354901.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, requirements are meant to ensure that companies operate responsibly and sustainably. Associated standards are designed to measure a company's impact on the environment (climate change, natural resource and waste management), its social responsibilities (diversity and inclusion, protection of human rights), and its governance practices (board diversity, compensation model). The International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS), Sustainability Disclosure Standards, Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) standards or the EU Corporate Sustainability Reporting Directive (CSRD) are good illustrations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;International Trade&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_4-1748220354907.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265816i1D8ED3F9EF5098E2/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_4-1748220354907.png" alt="T_Frenehard_4-1748220354907.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This compliance category refers to the processes and procedures guaranteeing that goods and services imported and exported are done so in accordance with the legislative framework and this includes Export Control, Free Trade Agreements, Sanctions and Embargo obligations and more. There is no overarching regulation, but some examples here can be U.S. Export Administration Regulations (EAR), the Australia-United States Free Trade Agreement (AUSFTA), and the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) Sanctions List.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Financial and Operational Resiliency&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_5-1748220354910.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265817i03742FD0932EA7AC/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_5-1748220354910.png" alt="T_Frenehard_5-1748220354910.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section addresses the regulatory requirements that ensure organizations, can withstand and recover from disruptions, whether they be financial or operational failures. Historically, financial services and providers of essential services have been the core focus, but compliance requirements are now expanding to many other sectors. In addition to Basel III, other examples include the UK Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) and Prudential Regulation Authority (PRA) Rules, the Digital Operational Resilience Act (DORA) or the various Cybersecurity Supply Chain Risk Management (C-SCRM) legislations around the world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consumer Protection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_6-1748220354915.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265818i06860AFD817209AE/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_6-1748220354915.png" alt="T_Frenehard_6-1748220354915.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simply put, these are the laws and regulations designed to safeguard consumers from unfair, deceptive, or abusive practices in the marketplace. The scope is quite large, ranging from fair and equitable lending practices, to product safety standards, preventing product misrepresentation in advertising, etc. These are represented by the Consumer Rights Directive in the European Union, the requirements of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) or Federal Trade Commission (FTC) in the United States for instance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;And there are many more of course but, as for the annual blog on risk, my intent here is to provide a baseline and then revisit each year to identify new trends instead of listing all possible obligatory mandates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What about you, what are the top regulatory topics on your mind? I look forward to reading your thoughts and comments on this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And if you are interested in learning more about SAP solutions for Governance, Risk, and Compliance, feel free to fill-in the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/request-demo.html?product=237150e2-6555-4a16-b49e-e93dbf1891da&amp;amp;productName=Governance%2C+Risk%2C+Compliance+%28GRC%29%2C+and+Cybersecurity&amp;amp;pageTitle=Cybersecurity+and+Governance%2C+Risk%2C+and+Compliance+Software&amp;amp;countryOfOrigin=en_au&amp;amp;refererPagePath=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sap.com%2Faustralia%2Fproducts%2Ffinancial-management%2Fgrc.html&amp;amp;refererContentPath=%2Fcontent%2Fsapdx%2Flanguages%2Fen_gb%2Fproducts%2Ffinancial-management%2Fgrc&amp;amp;navTitle=Request+a+Demo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;demo request form&lt;/A&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-regulatory-compliance-trends-and-outlook/ba-p/14111181"/>
    <published>2025-06-10T07:00:00.021000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/streamlining-privileged-access-in-sap-practical-tips-for-reliable-session/ba-p/14124644</id>
    <title>Streamlining Privileged Access in SAP: Practical Tips for Reliable Session Management</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T04:38:01.776000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ElyasAhmed</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1886529</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For enterprises running SAP at scale, privileged access is both a necessity and a significant risk. Whether responding to production incidents, executing sensitive financial transactions, or configuring core systems, elevated access must be tightly governed. Without robust controls, organizations risk compliance violations, audit gaps, and unauthorized exposure of sensitive data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This post highlights how &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Identity Access Governance (IAG)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; can help your organization secure, monitor, and audit privileged access, with practices tailored to meet the scrutiny of internal auditors, external regulators, and executive risk committees.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Common Use Cases&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When to Assign Privileged Access&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;PAM IDs are &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;not&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for routine tasks. They should be reserved for high-risk or time-sensitive operations such as:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Urgent Fixes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – for example responding to production outages.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System Setup or Configuration Changes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – including user management or master data updates.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sensitive Transactions in Regulated Areas&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – such as finance or healthcare, where full traceability is required.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Where to Use PAM IDs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Not all systems require the same level of access control. Here’s how to prioritize:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Production Systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Always enforce PAM to protect live data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Development/Test Systems&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Use PAM for high-impact changes, while allowing standard accounts for daily work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best Practices&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Synchronizing PAM Logs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reliable synchronization between SAP ABAP systems and SAP IAG ensures that every privileged session is logged, reviewed, and auditable.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Recommendations:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sync Interval:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Schedule synchronization jobs every &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6 to 12 hours&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to achieve near real-time visibility without overburdening the system.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Avoid Over-Syncing:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Running sync jobs too frequently (e.g., every 30 minutes) can lead to job overlaps and potential failures.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Optimize Timing:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Execute jobs during &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;off-peak hours&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (e.g., midnight) to reduce system load and avoid conflicts with business operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Proactive Monitoring:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Regularly monitor sync jobs and review log files to detect errors or delays early and prevent data gaps.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tip:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; In high-volume environments, a single sync job may take over an hour. Plan sync windows accordingly to avoid cascading delays.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Privileged Access Log Sync job&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; scans all sessions tied to PAM assignments across connected systems, including both active and expired sessions (within the last six months). This ensures continuity—even if a system was temporarily unavailable or if one system’s sync succeeded while another failed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; As of the last release, the PAMLOGSYNC - LAST_SYNC_DATE_TIME setting has been removed from the Configuration app, simplifying setup and reducing sync inconsistencies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pitfalls in Session Handling: The “Unlock” Problem&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A common issue in customer environments is &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;improper session termination&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Many users do not select &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Unlock"&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; button in the SIAG_PAM_LAUNCH_PAD after completing their task. This leads to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sessions remain open for hours—or even for days.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Overlapping sessions under the same PAM ID.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Inaccurate audit trails and failed sync jobs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Quick Fix:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Implement &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Note &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3604073/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3604073&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to fix missing logged off timestamps. This ensures sessions are properly closed, even when users forget to terminate them manually.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additional Recommendations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For improved performance and session accuracy, we recommend applying the following SAP Notes:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3606297/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3606297&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – Configure sync intervals for better log preparation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3586699/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3586699&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3586925/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3586925&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; – Enable paging for PAM access logs to boost sync reliability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Takeaway&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When used effectively, Privileged Access Management in SAP IAG is more than a compliance checkbox—it’s a strategic layer of defense. With proper assignment policies, smart sync scheduling, and user discipline, you can ensure privileged sessions are secure, auditable, and well-managed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Want to learn more about implementing PAM in your SAP landscape? Contact us or explore the latest updates in &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Author(s)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Yuliia Shpak&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Swetta Singh&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/streamlining-privileged-access-in-sap-practical-tips-for-reliable-session/ba-p/14124644"/>
    <published>2025-06-11T04:38:01.776000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-business-technology-platform-btp-security-best-practices-expert-tips-to/ba-p/14125423</id>
    <title>SAP Business Technology Platform(BTP) Security Best Practices: Expert Tips to Protect Your Platform</title>
    <updated>2025-06-13T16:10:20.147000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AditiArora16</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1581574</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="flyd-zAhAUSdRLJ8-unsplash.jpg" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273155i92CE2F1EF6A6D165/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flyd-zAhAUSdRLJ8-unsplash.jpg" alt="flyd-zAhAUSdRLJ8-unsplash.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Heard about those big cyber-attacks recently? No names needed, but chances are, your weekly shop has been hit. The interesting thing is that they followed a familiar pattern. Security analysts found that over 52,000 new vulnerabilities were disclosed in 2024, indicating that outdated or misconfigured systems are a growing invitation to attackers (sentinelone.com). Hackers often slip in via a ‘side door’: an unpatched server, an ill-configured cloud service, or a tricked user giving up a password. Another analysis of supply-chain incidents found that about half were driven by stolen or weak credentials (securityinfowatch.com). In plain terms, cybercrooks lean on low-hanging fruit - phishing, reused passwords, forgotten updates , more than any sci-fi-style hack.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Naturally, this has SAP customers asking: “Are our own SAP BTP environments secure? Is our user management tight? Are we following cloud security best practices?” These are great questions, and we’ve been hearing them a lot. So in this blog post we tried to answer these burning questions. We will address everything from locking down user accounts to broader security best practices, and we promise it won’t be a parade of jargon or doom-and-gloom.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1732355204"&gt;What can we learn from the recent cyber-attacks in the UK?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The recent cyber-attacks targeting major UK retailers mark a significant moment in cyber security as these are among the first Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attacks to penetrate networks that were protected by enterprise-grade firewalls. In many cases, these firewalls are managed by hyper scalars such as AWS, Microsoft Azure, or Google Cloud, who provide the foundational infrastructure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, it’s important to recognise that responsibility for security is shared. There’s a fine line between what the hyper scaler secures and what platform providers, like SAP BTP or Microsoft Power Platform, are responsible for. Most organisations today operate across multiple platforms, each with its own security model, tools, and SLAs, which can lead to gaps in the overall defence posture if not carefully managed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s also a reminder of the real-world consequences of cybersecurity failures. When breaches occur, especially those involving customer data, organisations face not just supply chain or reputational damage, but significant financial penalties under regulations like GDPR. We’ve seen this play out repeatedly, including with major social media companies in recent years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These all point to the importance of a well-coordinated, multi-layered security approach. It’s got to be holistic and span infrastructure, platforms, and application layers, with clear roles and responsibilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1535841699"&gt;How secure is SAP BTP out of the box, and what are the most common gaps you see in customer configurations?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, that’s the approach, but how is this carried out? The&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://bluestonex.com/knowledge-bank/the-ultimate-guide-to-sap-btp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;is designed with security and governance in mind across multiple layers. Out of the box, SAP BTP offers:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Built&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;‑&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;in Identity &amp;amp; Access Management (IAM) &amp;amp; Network Security:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Native support for Single Sign On(SSO) /Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA), Role Based Access Control(RBAC), and the SAP Authorisation Management service. Only authorised users and roles can access each sub-account or application.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Encryption &amp;amp; Transport Security:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;All user traffic is TLS-encrypted&amp;nbsp;, and SAP exclusively establishes encrypted communication channels by default.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitoring &amp;amp; Audit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP BTP automatically logs admin and user activities. The Cloud Foundry&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Audit Log Viewer&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;service lets you review all operations (applications created, users added, etc.), and connect these logs as desired.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Secure Development Tools:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP’s Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP) and other frameworks include built-in security guards (XSRF tokens, JWT checks, etc.), plus tools like the SAP Code Vulnerability Analyser (CVA) that statically scan ABAP code on SAP BTP before deployment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, despite this strong foundation, we often see gaps in how customers configure their environments. The most common issues include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bypassing SAP BTP Connectivity Guidelines&lt;/STRONG&gt; Customers sometimes integrate third-party APIs or services directly, without using the secure connectivity mechanisms provided by SAP BTP. This can create vulnerabilities and reduce visibility over traffic flows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improper Credential Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; Instead of using SAP BTP’s built-in credential stores, credentials are sometimes hardcoded or stored in less secure ways, leaving applications open to compromise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Neglecting Secure App Design Principles&lt;/STRONG&gt; Applications are not always developed using the security best practices. This can lead to poor access controls, exposure to common vulnerabilities, or lack of proper authorisation checks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAP BTP provides a secure foundation, maintaining a strong security posture requires careful configuration and adherence to recommended best practices, particularly when it comes to connectivity, credential management, and application architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1339328194"&gt;How to prevent similar attacks when running business-critical workloads on SAP BTP?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To safeguard business-critical workloads on SAP BTP, a few key practices should be followed:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use SAP Services for All Integrations:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ensure every integration and API call goes through SAP’s connectivity and security layers. Use the SAP Destination Service, API Management, and the Cloud Connector/Connectivity Service, rather than hard‑coding endpoints. This way, TLS is enforced and flows are logged and constrained. (Think of&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://bluestonex.com/service/sap-btp-partner-managed-cloud/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP services&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;like a secure gateway that you should not bypass.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enforce Multi-Factor Authentication Everywhere:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Require MFA for all user logins – not just admins. SAP Cloud Identity Service (or your corporate IdP) can enforce MFA policies on every SAP BTP access. SAP’s TechEd guide even walks through configuring MFA for SAP BTP apps. This means stolen passwords alone won’t give attackers an easy in.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Harden IAM and Accounts:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Follow the principle of least privilege. Regularly audit user roles and prune any unused or generic accounts. Disable any unused features like self-registration or social sign-on. Use roles and groups in your Identity Provider (IdP) to ensure people only get the permissions needed for their job.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitor and Respond to Logs:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Subscribing to the SAP Audit Log Viewer (for Cloud Foundry (CF)) is critical. Review logs periodically for anomalies (e.g. logins from new locations, sudden privilege grants). Configure alerts or integrate these logs into your Security Information &amp;amp; Event Management(SIEM). Quick detection can stop an incident in its tracks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even doing just these steps drastically cuts risk. In effect,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;you’re closing the ‘side doors’&lt;/STRONG&gt;: every inbound or outbound connection is tracked by SAP, every user action is logged, and strong authentication blocks the common tricks that took down those retailers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1142814689"&gt;What role does identity and access management play in defending against modern cyber threats in SAP environments?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Identity and Access Management (IAM) is the keystone of SAP BTP security. SAP BTP supports a full identity lifecycle and fine-grained authorisation model:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role-Based Access Control (RBAC):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;You define roles or role collections in your SAP BTP sub-accounts (and business roles in the ABAP environment) that grant only needed permissions. Then you assign these roles to users/groups. This enforces&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;least privilege&lt;/EM&gt;, so even if a user’s credentials are compromised, the attacker’s access is limited.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trusted Identity Providers:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;BTP can federate with SAP Cloud Identity (Identity Authentication Service) or any SAML/OAuth IdP. Once trust is set up, employees authenticate with corporate credentials (with MFA, if you’ve enforced it). This ensures a single point of control over user accounts and policies. IAM integrates with identity providers and defines roles and permissions to secure applications and data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Principal Propagation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;When a user calls between SAP systems (for example, a CF app calling an ABAP endpoint), their identity and roles “travel” with the request. This maintains security boundaries across services.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;IAM practices help organisations enforce strict access boundaries, maintain compliance, and defend against unauthorised access—whether from external attackers or internal misconfigurations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-946301184"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How can organisations balance innovation on SAP BTP with the need for robust security and compliance?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Innovation and security are not opposing forces—they must evolve together. As applications built on SAP BTP grow in complexity, the security measures surrounding them must also mature. The more advanced and interconnected your solutions become, the greater the need for enhanced controls, monitoring, and governance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organisations that fail to innovate risk becoming obsolete. But equally, those that innovate without embedding strong security and compliance practices expose themselves to serious vulnerabilities. Every new capability, integration, or user touchpoint introduces potential risks that must be addressed as part of the innovation lifecycle.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Training is also key. Ensure developers and admins know SAP BTP best practices. Ignorance may be bliss, but it also breeds vulnerabilities, since human error is often the weakest link. If all personal interacting with the platform are aware of the threats, they can help mitigate them but also spot them. Make security part of your culture and process – every innovation needs to come with corresponding security guardrails.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sustainable innovation on SAP BTP requires a security-first mindset—where governance, compliance, and threat prevention are integrated into every phase of development and deployment.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-749787679"&gt;Securing your innovation on SAP BTP&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The recent cyber-attacks serve as a stark reminder that even the most well-defended systems are not immune to evolving and opportunistic threats. For organisations leveraging SAP BTP to drive innovation, the message is clear: security must be treated as a continuous discipline, not a one-time checklist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While SAP BTP provides a strong out-of-the-box security framework, real resilience comes from how that framework is implemented, monitored, and adapted. From enforcing secure connectivity and managing access intelligently, to following coding best practices and monitoring audit logs—every detail matters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To conclude, the balance between innovation and security is not a compromise; it’s a partnership. With the right governance, identity management, and adherence to best practices, organisations can confidently build and scale on SAP BTP—without sacrificing trust, compliance, or control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please feel free to share your experiences and thoughts on the similar approaches you might have taken securing your applications on SAP BTP in the comments section.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-business-technology-platform-btp-security-best-practices-expert-tips-to/ba-p/14125423"/>
    <published>2025-06-13T16:10:20.147000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/ibm-cloud-security-and-compliance-center-workload-protection-for-ibm-cloud/ba-p/14128532</id>
    <title>IBM Cloud® Security and Compliance Center Workload Protection for IBM Cloud® VPC and IBM® PowerVS</title>
    <updated>2025-06-17T10:48:47.784000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ludwig-mueller</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2159526</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PowerVS Hybrid Cloud.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/274612i1E21A0E5C9464977/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="PowerVS Hybrid Cloud.png" alt="PowerVS Hybrid Cloud.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IBM Cloud® Security and Compliance Center Workload Protection can be used to find and prioritize software vulnerabilities, detect and respond to threats, and manage configurations, permissions, and compliance from source to run.&amp;nbsp;When deploying your architecture in the Cloud, effective protection is crucial for ensuring the health, compliance and early threat detection of your system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature can be turned on when deploying using the Catalog tiles: IBM® Power Virtual Server with IBM Cloud® VPC landing zone and IBM® Power Virtual Server for SAP HANA®.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Key Features&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;Real-time visibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;IBM® Power Virtual Server Cloud Security Posture Management.&amp;nbsp;Workload Protection now supports IBM® Power Virtual Server resources as part of its Cloud Security Posture Management (CSPM) feature. Supported resources includes IBM® Power Virtual Server Workspaces, Instances, Instance Volumes, Networks, Network Security Groups and Public Networks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;STRONG&gt;Reports:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Resource Report generates a CSV that includes Compliance results with the resource detail.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Who is it of interest to?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IBM Cloud® VPC, IBM® Power Virtual Server and SAP® on IBM® Power Virtual Server Customers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Benefits&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fully automated installation and configuration, add on feature for IBM® Power Virtual Server with IBM Cloud® VPC landing zone and IBM® Power Virtual Server for SAP HANA®,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continuous monitoring of workloads for threats, vulnerabilities, and suspicious behavior.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Uses behavioral analysis and threat intelligence to detect attacks in real-time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simplifies compliance auditing with continuous posture monitoring.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provides reports and evidence for regulatory and internal audits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Centralized dashboard for visibility across multi-cloud and hybrid workloads.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easy management of security policies and incident responses.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;Links&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://cloud.ibm.com/docs/workload-protection?topic=workload-protection-getting-started" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://ibm.biz/BdnZKB" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://ibm.biz/BdnZKB&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://cloud.ibm.com/docs/sap-powervs?topic=sap-powervs-automation-solution-relnotes#sap-powervs-mar21" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://ibm.biz/BdnZKx" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://ibm.biz/BdnZKx&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://cloud.ibm.com/docs/powervs-vpc?topic=powervs-vpc-powervs-vpc-relnotes#powervs-vpc-mar18" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://ibm.biz/BdnZKR" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://ibm.biz/BdnZKR&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Featured Image Source: IBM&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/ibm-cloud-security-and-compliance-center-workload-protection-for-ibm-cloud/ba-p/14128532"/>
    <published>2025-06-17T10:48:47.784000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/identifying-sap-certificates-in-personal-security-environment-a/ba-p/14131296</id>
    <title>Identifying SAP Certificates in Personal Security Environment: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-06-18T19:35:52.547000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mcharrison</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149617</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1604075140"&gt;Understanding Personal Security Environment (PSE) Fundamentals&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;At its core, a Personal Security Environent (PSE) in SAP is a digital container designed to securely store cryptographic information, primarily digital certificates and their corresponding private keys. Think of it as a digital wallet for your SAP system's security credentials. PSEs are essential for enabling secure communication channels, such as those used in SSL/TLS, SNC (Secure Network Communications), and digital signatures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are several types of PSEs, each serving a specific purpose within the SAP ecosystem:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;System PSE (SSFS): Often used for internal system-to-system communication and secure storage of sensitive data like database credentials.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Application PSE: Employed by specific SAP applications for their secure communication needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Client PSE: Used by SAP clients (e.g., SAP GUI, external applications) to authenticate themselves to SAP servers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;PSEs can also exist in different formats, primarily:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Legacy format (v2): An older format that might still be found in some older SAP installations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Current format (v4): The modern and more secure format, offering enhanced cryptographic capabilities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1407561635"&gt;The Structure and Components of a PSE&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;To effectively identify certificates within a PSE, it's crucial to understand its internal structure and the components it typically contains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Owner Certificate (with Private Key): This is the primary certificate associated with the PSE, along with its unique private key. This pair is used by the SAP system or application to identify itself and encrypt/decrypt data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Certificate Chain: A sequence of certificates that links the owner certificate back to a trusted root Certificate Authority (CA). This chain establishes the trustworthiness of the owner certificate.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Trust Anchors (Trusted Certificates): These are certificates of trusted Certificate Authorities (CAs) or self-signed certificates from other systems that the SAP system explicitly trusts. They are used to validate the authenticity of incoming certificates.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Address Book (Optional): In some cases, a PSE might also contain an address book of trusted communication partners.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;PSE files are typically stored in the file system, often with a .pse extension. Common storage locations include the sec directory under the SAP instance directory (e.g., /usr/sap/&amp;lt;SID&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;Instance&amp;gt;/sec/). For certificates managed within the SAP HANA database, they might reside in database tables such as SYS.CERTIFICATES and SYS.PSE_CERTIFICATES.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To protect the sensitive private keys and certificates, PSEs employ several protection mechanisms:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PIN Protection: A password or PIN is often used to encrypt the private key within the PSE, preventing unauthorized access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;File Permissions: Operating system file permissions are critical to restrict access to the PSE files themselves, ensuring only authorized users or processes can read or modify them.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Database Privileges: For in-database certificates, appropriate database privileges are essential to control who can view, modify, or delete certificate entries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1211048130"&gt;Dissecting Certificate Structure for Identification:&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before diving into identification methods, let's briefly review the key elements of a digital certificate that aid in its identification:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Distinguished Name (DN) Components: The DN is a unique identifier for the certificate's subject. Key components include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Common Name (CN): Typically the hostname or application name.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Organization (O): The name of the organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Organizational Unit (OU): A specific department or unit within the organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Country (C): The two-letter country code.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Certificate Attributes: Beyond the DN, other attributes provide crucial identification details:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Serial Number: A unique identifier assigned by the Certificate Authority.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validity Period: The start and end dates during which the certificate is considered valid.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Issuer Information: Details about the Certificate Authority that issued the certificate.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Key Usage: Defines the cryptographic purposes for which the public key contained in the certificate can be used (e.g., digital signature, key encipherment).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Signature Algorithm: The algorithm used to sign the certificate.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1014534625"&gt;Methods for Certificate Identification&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Identifying certificates in SAP PSEs can be approached through various methods, each with its own strengths and use cases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-947103839"&gt;1. Identification by Location&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The simplest form of identification is by knowing where PSE files are typically stored. Standard file paths and instance-specific locations are common starting points. For SAP HANA, certificates might also be found within database collections.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-750590334"&gt;2. Identification by Attributes&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once a certificate is accessed, its attributes can be used for precise identification:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Distinguished Name (DN) Matching: Comparing the DN components against expected values.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Serial Number Lookup: Searching for a specific certificate by its unique serial number.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fingerprint Comparison: Using cryptographic hash functions (e.g., SHA-256) to generate a unique fingerprint of the certificate for comparison.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-554076829"&gt;3. Identification by Purpose&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Certificates are often used for specific functions, which can also aid in their identification:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SSL Server Certificates: Used by SAP servers to secure incoming connections.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SSL Client Certificates: Used by SAP clients to authenticate to servers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAML Certificates: Used for Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) based single sign-on.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Signing Certificates: Used for digital signatures.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-228480605"&gt;Tools for Certificate Identification&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP provides several tools, both command-line and GUI-based, to help with certificate identification and management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-161049819"&gt;Using the sapgenpse Tool&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;sapgenpse is a powerful command-line utility provided by SAP for managing PSEs and certificates. It's particularly useful for scripting and automated tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key commands for identification include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sapgenpse get_my_cert -p &amp;lt;PSE_path&amp;gt; -v: Extracts and displays the owner certificate from a specified PSE file.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sapgenpse maintain_pk -p &amp;lt;PSE_path&amp;gt; -l: Lists all certificates contained within a PSE file.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sapgenpse maintain_pk: &lt;SPAN&gt;maintain the server's certificate list within a PSE&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The output of these commands provides detailed certificate information, including validity status and trust chain information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--164546405"&gt;Using the STRUST Transaction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;For those who prefer a graphical interface, the STRUST transaction in SAP GUI is the primary tool for managing PSEs and certificates. It offers a user-friendly way to visualize and interact with certificate data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to STRUST via the transaction code. Here, you can select and manage various PSE types. STRUST provides a visual certificate browser, allowing you to view detailed information about each certificate, including its chain, validity, and key attributes. It also supports import and export functionalities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-408680173"&gt;Python-Based Identification&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;For advanced automation and integration with other systems, Python scripting offers a flexible and powerful approach to certificate identification. Libraries like cryptography or OpenSSL can be used to parse certificate files, while custom scripts can be developed to interact with SAP systems or database views.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Python-based solutions offer significant automation benefits, including bulk certificate discovery, automated metadata extraction, and proactive expiration monitoring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-212166668"&gt;Best Practices for SAP Certificate Management&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Effective certificate identification is just one piece of the puzzle. Implementing best practices ensures a secure and manageable SAP certificate landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Naming Conventions: Adopt consistent Distinguished Name (DN) formats and use purpose-indicating Common Names (CNs). Include version tracking in comments or metadata.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Organization: Centralize PSE management where possible. Maintain comprehensive documentation of certificate purposes and regularly update your certificate inventory.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Monitoring: Implement automated expiration checks to prevent outages. Regularly validate trust chains and audit certificate usage to detect anomalies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-15653163"&gt;Common Challenges and Solutions&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Managing SAP certificates comes with its share of challenges. Here are some common ones and their practical solutions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge: Identifying certificates across distributed systems.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Implement a centralized certificate inventory system with location mapping to track all PSEs and certificates across your SAP landscape.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge: Determining certificate purpose.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Enforce standardized naming conventions and metadata tagging during certificate creation to clearly indicate their intended use.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge: Legacy format detection.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Utilize version-aware tools (like sapgenpse with appropriate flags) and plan for systematic conversion of legacy PSEs to current formats.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge: PIN-protected PSEs.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Implement secure PIN management strategies, potentially leveraging secure credential stores or automation tools that can securely provide PINs when needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--180860342"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Identifying SAP certificates within the Personal Security Environment is a critical aspect of maintaining a secure and reliable SAP landscape. It requires a systematic approach, leveraging a combination of SAP-provided tools like sapgenpse and STRUST, alongside powerful scripting capabilities offered by Python.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By understanding the fundamentals of PSE, its structure, and the various identification methods, you can gain better control over your SAP security infrastructure. Adhering to best practices in naming, organization, and monitoring, coupled with proactive solutions to common challenges, will significantly enhance your ability to manage certificates effectively and prevent security vulnerabilities or system outages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ultimately, a comprehensive and up-to-date inventory of your SAP certificates forms the foundation for robust security and efficient operations. Embrace these strategies to ensure your SAP systems remain secure and trustworthy.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/identifying-sap-certificates-in-personal-security-environment-a/ba-p/14131296"/>
    <published>2025-06-18T19:35:52.547000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/configuring-workflow-for-automated-controls-in-sap-process-control-my/ba-p/14130361</id>
    <title>Configuring Workflow for Automated Controls in SAP Process Control – My Experience</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T15:08:17.925000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Supriya_Roy1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1393403</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I want to share my experience of working on workflow configuration for automated controls in SAP GRC Process Control, especially for versions like SAP GRC 12.0, recalling my steps which I did 4-5 years back. This post will be helpful for the candidates who are starting their journey with SAP GRC PC.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While implementing this, I followed an end-to-end approach&amp;nbsp;from technical workflow setup to email notifications for control testers. Here's a walkthrough of the steps I followed. If you’ve worked on something similar, please feel free to add or suggest improvements!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step-by-Step: Workflow Configuration for Automated Controls&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. SWU3 – Automatic Workflow Customization&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Used TCode `SWU3` to:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Generate the workflow runtime environment&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Schedule background jobs&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Ensure the `WF-BATCH` user was active and authorized&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. SPRO – Task Classification and Event Linkage&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Path: SPRO &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;→&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Governance, Risk and Compliance &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;→&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; General Settings &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;→&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Workflow&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Marked workflow tasks as “General” or “Background”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Activated relevant “event linkages”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Scheduled and released the “event queue job”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. SWDD – Workflow Logic Customization (Optional)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In some cases, I modified standard workflows (e.g., `WS********`) via `SWDD`:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Added new paths (e.g., “Void” or exception handling)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Included additional Process Control steps&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Saved and activated new versions&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Agent Determination&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ensured proper agent assignment for:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Control Tester&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Reviewer&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Fallback recipient&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This was done under:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SPRO &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;→&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Workflow &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;→&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; GRC Maintain Agent Determination Rules&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Email Notifications for Control Testers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SWNCONFIG – Extended Notification Setup&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Subscribed to event types (e.g., `GRPC_CONTROL_TEST_EXECUTION`)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Enabled HTML email format and delivery method&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Maintained a message template with placeholders like:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;- `%CONTROL_NAME%`, `%CONTROL_ID%`, `%LINK_APPROVE_REJECT%`&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SPRO – Mapping Scenarios to Events&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mapped notification scenario (e.g., `GRPC_AUTO_NOTIFiCATION`) to:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Control Test Assignment&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Automated Monitoring Exception&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reminder Notifications&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scheduled the program `GRFNMW_BATCH_EMAIL_REMINDER` for overdue test alerts:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Configured variant with workflow type and template ID&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Scheduled job to run daily&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Troubleshooting Tools&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Used the following transactions during testing:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- `SOST` – to verify outbound email status&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- `SWEL` – to check workflow event triggers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- `SLG1` – to monitor job and planner log&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Summary&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="466.0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Task&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tool/TCode&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Workflow Setup&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SWU3, SPRO&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Workflow Custom Logic&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SWDD&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Agent Rules&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SPRO &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;→&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Workflow&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Notifications (Standard)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SWNCONFIG&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reminder Emails&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GRFNMW_BATCH_EMAIL_REMINDER&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Monitoring/Debugging&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SOST, SWEL, SLG1&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Thoughts:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This setup helped streamline the “control execution process” by automating tester assignments and keeping stakeholders informed via email. The tight integration between CCM, Workflow, and Notification Framework provides great flexibility when configured correctly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If anyone has worked on advanced workflow routing, escalation, or Fiori inbox integration for automated controls—please share your experience as well! Happy to have an interactive conversation!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/configuring-workflow-for-automated-controls-in-sap-process-control-my/ba-p/14130361"/>
    <published>2025-06-19T15:08:17.925000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-s-coming-in-sap-solutions-for-three-lines-of-defense/ba-p/14132369</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: What's Coming in SAP Solutions for Three Lines (of Defense)</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T07:00:00.040000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_0-1750377816865.jpeg" style="width: 500px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276501i6F6909A6444ECE79/image-dimensions/500x337?v=v2" width="500" height="337" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_0-1750377816865.jpeg" alt="T_Frenehard_0-1750377816865.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To help drive a unified vision across all SAP solutions for Three Lines (of Defense), &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rohit-hotwani-00003450/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Rohit Hotwani&lt;/A&gt; has recently been announced as the Strategic Product Manager for these products. And Rohit will already be very familiar to many of you since he was until then Global Solution Advisor for SAP GRC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a result, Rohit and I thought it would be a good opportunity to provide an update on what’s planned in terms of roadmap items for SAP Process Control, SAP Risk Management and SAP Audit Management. And there’s quite a lot!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1733188521"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Harmonized management of compliance issues and findings from different source systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have been following these GRC Tuesdays blogs for some time now, you may recall a partner blog from Turnkey Consulting: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/grc-tuesdays-hidden-gems-integration-between-sap-process-control-pc-and-sap/ba-p/13581354" target="_blank"&gt;Hidden Gems. Integration between SAP Process Control (PC) and SAP Business Integrity Screening (BIS)&lt;/A&gt;. This post highlighted how both tools can already complement each other's strengths, allowing for a healthier control management process. But there have recently been customer requirements to take this integration a step further and make it easier to leverage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a result, Product Management and Engineering are working on a sub-scenario in SAP Process Control to expose SAP Business Integrity Screening to its continuous control monitoring functionality. This would enable to link controls in SAP Process Control with detection strategies in SAP Business Integrity Screening so that continuous monitoring can make use of this powerful fraud detection capability and, at the same time, enable a unified issue remediation process in SAP Process Control. With this integration, organizations will be able to centralize and organize compliance issues and findings into one system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1536675016"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extending integration of continuous control monitoring to SAP and non-SAP systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By integrating SAP Process Control with SAP Integration Suite, users will be able to connect to SAP and third-party systems and use these additional data as sources for continuous control monitoring and automated controls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will help build a holistic control environment system with SAP Process Control being the central hub to analyse and monitor data from connected systems, but also to follow-up on compliance issues and remediate them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To do so, the plan is to provide pre-delivered integration flows and continuous monitoring across hybrid systems:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_1-1750377816868.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276499i3EAC58325FEF7004/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_1-1750377816868.png" alt="T_Frenehard_1-1750377816868.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1340161511"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent self-diagnostics cockpit app&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this planned innovation, internal control experts will be able to get self-diagnosing errors and solutions provided within a dedicated app. This app will deliver detailed error descriptions and will help guide users through the resolution process, hence supporting problem-solving with step-by step approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_2-1750377816871.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276500iEED0999DCC1DC4C6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_2-1750377816871.png" alt="T_Frenehard_2-1750377816871.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1143648006"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cybersecurity Risk Management framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-s-new-in-sap-solutions-for-three-lines-q3-2023-to-q1-2024/ba-p/13615040" target="_blank"&gt;announced last year&lt;/A&gt;, National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) SP800-53 revision 5 and Cybersecurity Framework CSF Version 2.0 content can now be uploaded as central controls in SAP Process Control to help organizations enhance their IT Security &amp;amp; Cybersecurity controls with a best in class set of guidelines that define the baseline controls for information systems and organizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To even better support customers looking at adopting the NIST best practices – especially in the area of &lt;A href="https://csrc.nist.gov/publications/detail/nistir/8286/final" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Integrating Cybersecurity and Enterprise Risk Management&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(NIST IR 8286), we will provide a support of NIST’s risk management framework by importing content as a risk template or a response template. This will enable customers to benefit from best-practice guidance from the leading Cybersecurity agency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_3-1750377816881.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276504iD7AE8A6B988055D4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_3-1750377816881.png" alt="T_Frenehard_3-1750377816881.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-947134501"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business continuity management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In continuation of the first building blocks delivered last year – &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-s-new-in-sap-solutions-for-three-lines-q1-2024-to-q2-2024/ba-p/13716529" target="_blank"&gt;Business Impact Analysis in SAP Risk Management&lt;/A&gt;, we plan to continue on this business continuity management journey with additional enhancements, including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business continuity planning by supporting strategy definition and documentation, including business continuity and disaster recovery plans to help ensure critical business processes or activities in the organization can survive serious disruptions and to enable organizations to provide a clear blueprint for what everyone should do when business processes can't continue as normal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business continuity test and exercise to create a picture of the scenarios, making it easier for business continuity team members and stakeholders to get practical preparation and identify any loopholes in the business continuity plan, and improve it continuously&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-750620996"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vendor and third-party risk assessment and due diligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once again building on &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-s-new-in-sap-solutions-for-three-lines-vendor-risk/ba-p/13887665" target="_blank"&gt;initial deliveries from last year&lt;/A&gt;, the Vendor Risk Assessment capability will be enhanced with the introduction of a new a survey type and format to support the onboarding and due diligence of third parties and vendors. This survey will support issuing to external recipients to cater for onboarding and due diligence for 3rd parties.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-554107491"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creation and reuse of a recommendation across multiple findings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To increase the efficiency of the 3rd line in SAP Audit Management, we plan on helping avoid developing duplicate recommendations for the same or similar findings by enabling the reuse of recommendations across multiple findings. This will also come with enhancements to help auditors monitor and manage recommendations centrally, through a holistic view of the remediation process and, ultimately, should promote collaborative problem-solving with auditees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_4-1750377816885.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276502iEA40639A5236C886/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_4-1750377816885.png" alt="T_Frenehard_4-1750377816885.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-357593986"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consolidation of email notification for multiple actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make it easier for auditors and auditees to track updates, our colleagues are working on a setting that would enable the system administrator to quickly configure and consolidate multiple e-mail notifications into a single mailing. Once activated, related email notifications would be grouped into one message. Of course, non-consolidated notifications would still be immediately dispatched.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will help reduce email clutter that can occur when a high number of actions are performed in a short time frame – all sending their individual notification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_5-1750377816905.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276503i22C3D72A297936B9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_5-1750377816905.png" alt="T_Frenehard_5-1750377816905.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rohit and I hope that this short overview will have provided some valuable insights on the roadmap plans for these solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And if you are interested in learning more about SAP solutions for Governance, Risk, and Compliance, feel free to fill-in the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/request-demo.html?product=237150e2-6555-4a16-b49e-e93dbf1891da&amp;amp;productName=Governance%2C+Risk%2C+Compliance+%28GRC%29%2C+and+Cybersecurity&amp;amp;pageTitle=Cybersecurity+and+Governance%2C+Risk%2C+and+Compliance+Software&amp;amp;countryOfOrigin=en_au&amp;amp;refererPagePath=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sap.com%2Faustralia%2Fproducts%2Ffinancial-management%2Fgrc.html&amp;amp;refererContentPath=%2Fcontent%2Fsapdx%2Flanguages%2Fen_gb%2Fproducts%2Ffinancial-management%2Fgrc&amp;amp;navTitle=Request+a+Demo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;demo request form&lt;/A&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-s-coming-in-sap-solutions-for-three-lines-of-defense/ba-p/14132369"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T07:00:00.040000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/podcast-sap-enterprise-threat-detection-cloud-edition-meets-microsoft/ba-p/14145718</id>
    <title>Podcast: SAP Enterprise Threat Detection, cloud edition Meets Microsoft Sentinel Solution for SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-07-07T11:39:20.552000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lingscheid</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/38175</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The latest episode 245 of the Microsoft SAP on Azure podcast brings together experts from SAP Michael Schmitt and Microsoft Martin Pankraz to discuss a game-changing integration: SAP Enterprise Threat Detection, cloud edition with Microsoft Sentinel. In an increasingly interconnected digital landscape, securing enterprise systems has never been more crucial. This collaboration promises to revolutionize how organizations monitor and respond to security threats across their SAP and Microsoft environments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-07-07 at 08.19.49.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/283355i9C0D76AFB20B40E2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-07-07 at 08.19.49.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-07-07 at 08.19.49.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Azure Market Place" href="https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/en-us/marketplace/apps/sap_jasondau.azure-sentinel-solution-sapetd?tab=overview" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Azure Market Place&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unified Security Monitoring: The integration allows security teams to view SAP-specific threats alongside other security events in Microsoft Sentinel. This holistic approach enables faster threat detection and response across the entire IT landscape.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simplified Connectivity: Setting up the integration is straightforward, especially for Enterprise Threat Detection, cloud edition. It leverages standard Business Technology Platform (BTP) authentication mechanisms, making it accessible for organizations already invested in SAP's cloud ecosystem.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced Threat Intelligence: By combining SAP's deep application-level insights with Microsoft's broader security context, organizations can build more comprehensive attack graphs and correlate events more effectively.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer-Driven Development: Both SAP and Microsoft are actively seeking customer feedback to shape the future of this integration, ensuring it addresses real-world security challenges.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the most compelling moments in the podcast is when Martin demonstrates an attack scenario. He shows a potentially malicious action in an SAP system (accessing sensitive function modules) that is instantly detected by Enterprise Threat Detection and seamlessly reported to Sentinel. This real-time visibility across platforms is a game-changer for security operations teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical resources shared during the podcast include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A detailed technical guide for setting up a test environment to explore the ETD-Sentinel integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Information on accessing free trials for both ETD and Sentinel to experiment with the integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A link to provide feedback on desired features and use cases for future development&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ETD API Sentinel.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/283366i5AD051F87AB3ED55/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ETD API Sentinel.png" alt="ETD API Sentinel.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;While the integration shows great promise, Martin and Michael acknowledge that there's still is work to be done in areas like attribute correlation between SAP and Microsoft systems e.g. via email addresses as a common identifier across platforms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Call to action:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For those intrigued by this overview, the full podcast offers much more. Listening in you will gain deeper insights into the technical aspects of the integration, you will hear about real customer reactions from recent hands-on workshops during the DSAG Technologie Tage in Wiesbaden and get a glimpse into the future roadmap for this collaborative security solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To experience the full depth of this discussion and stay ahead of the curve in enterprise security, be sure to listen to the complete podcast episode.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SaAguCqRjyU" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SaAguCqRjyU&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don't forget to subscribe to stay updated on the latest developments in SAP and Microsoft technologies!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/podcast-sap-enterprise-threat-detection-cloud-edition-meets-microsoft/ba-p/14145718"/>
    <published>2025-07-07T11:39:20.552000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-keeping-up-to-date-with-tariff-changes/ba-p/14120668</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: Keeping up to date with tariff changes</title>
    <updated>2025-07-08T07:00:00.030000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="277952_277952_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" style="width: 501px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/270437i35820233451C81B9/image-dimensions/501x393?v=v2" width="501" height="393" role="button" title="277952_277952_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" alt="277952_277952_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;In our new global trade reality, keeping track of tariff changes can seem an insurmountable task. Trade policies are changing more rapidly than ever before and being enforced at a moment’s notice; requiring flexibility and adaptability from companies to implement new tariffs to ensure that they are not penalised for underpaying duties.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If continuously monitoring customs authorities’ official communication channels is the most straight forward option, it comes with great resource constraint. And a certain dose of expertise to determine which change applies to the organization, in what context, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another option is engaging with a licensed customs broker. These experts would be able to provide the level of monitoring and guidance mentioned above, on behalf of the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But there is a third option for companies wishing to do it themselves and leverage these uncertain times to gain a competitive advantage by reacting faster and more precisely: aligning best-in-class content with best-in-class technology from SAP Global Trade Services to get information in real time and directly connected to the core processes and supply chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1732208300"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How can companies get the latest duty rates?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As per leading analyst firm Gartner, there are two types of global trade management software providers: those that do and those that do not provide content with their tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On this matter, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP&lt;/A&gt; has strategically decided to work with its ecosystem of professional global trade data partners offering subscription-based access to a wide selection of trade content. Content from dedicated teams that specialize in identifying, interpreting, and collecting changes and updates to trade regulations that can be imported into SAP through standardized interfaces, but, more importantly, content that can be tailored to each customer’s specific needs in terms of geographic coverage (regions and countries to monitor), content types, and process areas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This provides organizations with the freedom to select a global trade data partner covering their specific requirements or even combine content from various providers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a result, the global trade data partner acts as a central source for up-to-date information helping companies navigate evolving trade regulations. Information provided includes, but not limited to, customs tariff measures and duty rates, export control lists, rules for preferential origin determination for free trade agreements, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Companies such as &lt;A href="https://www.mendel-verlag.de/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Mendel Verlag&lt;/A&gt; started decades ago with production and publication of customs tariffs and other publications and have expanded to electronic formats that can be directly consumed by global trade management platforms such as &lt;A href="https://sap.com/gts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Global Trade Services&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To produce this foreign trade content, Mendel Verlag follows a 5-step approach – all done internally by a team of specialists:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Research for the identification and review of relevant sources&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Compile information from step 1&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Evaluate for relevance and validity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consolidate different information and sources for integrated data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quality control including classic editing but also manual checks of electronically processed data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This last step is crucial, as only with expert review can the content provider ensure credibility and reliability of the trade compliance master data information. As highlighted by Mendel Verlag: “&lt;EM&gt;Quality is a key requirement of our work. Only valid data can be used effectively in foreign trade and customs processes.&lt;/EM&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once subscribed to a data content service, customers will receive continuous updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;To ensure that the trade compliance information in SAP Global Trade Services&amp;nbsp;is in sync and therefore also continuously up to date, the procedure is quite simple. The updated file from the content provider – usually in an XML format, is placed on a secure file transfer protocol (SFTP) folder where it is picked up by SAP Global Trade Services&amp;nbsp;and values are uploaded into the platform.&amp;nbsp; This process includes control parameter checks, and errors can be manually reviewed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;If a company decides to change data providers, and therefore need to replace the previous data provider's content with the new data provider's content, SAP Global Trade Services&amp;nbsp;can of course enable the configuration of time-dependency of this content. This flexibility enables customers to enter two competing sets of content in the system, and when they activate the new data provider's content, the old data provider's content – and all dependent items, is deactivated automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1535694795"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Typical misconceptions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We, at SAP, strongly believe that working hand-in-hand with a global trade data partner provider is in the best interest of our customers to be able to freely choose, change or combine content from various content providers, addressing specific countries or regions, content types and process areas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This can raise a few questions and misconceptions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="720px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="298.641px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Misconception&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="420.359px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reality&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="298.641px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is more expensive to have the content and the software from different providers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="420.359px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The cost of the content itself is much less than the cost of running a global trade management system, and you pay for it, even when bundled in “one software package”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="298.641px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is more hassle to manage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="420.359px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the one-time setup is completed, updates will flow via certified and tested interfaces with little to no manual intervention (only in case of errors or exceptions)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="298.641px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach constraints customers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="420.359px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Quite the opposite, it offers the freedom to pick and choose the best provider for the requirement (compliance area, countries where the company has trade operations, industry, etc.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="298.641px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP recommends this because it is not a content provider&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="420.359px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is absolutely true! In the area of trade compliance, SAP is not a content provider. SAP strategically chose to work with external, specialized, third-party vendors. SAP focuses on delivering the necessary system logic, the workflow, and the integration with core systems and business processes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;As eloquently stated by Christian Stadler – Chief Product Owner for SAP International Trade Management portfolio: “working with content partners such as Mendel Verlag makes our SAP solutions even more relevant, and constantly adapted to rapidly changing situations”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are interested in discovering more about SAP Global Trade Services, see &lt;A href="https://sap.com/gts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;our dedicated website&lt;/A&gt; and associated resources: videos, customer stories, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to thank Mendel Verlag for their collaboration on this article.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/blogs/keeping-up-to-date-with-tariff-changes" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Originally published&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;on June 30, 2025 &amp;amp; reposted on this platform&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-keeping-up-to-date-with-tariff-changes/ba-p/14120668"/>
    <published>2025-07-08T07:00:00.030000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-q2-2025/ba-p/14147771</id>
    <title>What’s New in SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance: Q2 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-08T23:52:00.006000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ElyasAhmed</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1886529</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome to the Q2&amp;nbsp;2025 release highlights for &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/financial-management/cloud-iam.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance&lt;/A&gt; (IAG), where we unveil the new features designed to enhance security, streamline access governance, and empower your teams. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE/e739622ded9b4d92964c6a0f50b5f90e/513aadc0379642feb989a4a9480da00f.html?version=CLOUDFOUNDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;This quarter’s release&lt;/A&gt; brings refined role-based risk controls, seamless system integrations, and powerful in-app analysis tools designed to keep your security posture both robust and agile. Whether you’re aiming to automate provisioning tasks or tighten privileged-access reviews, these updates deliver practical improvements you can implement today. Dive into the details below to see how each enhancement makes your day-to-day access governance faster, smarter, and more reliable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mitigation Control Assignment to Business Roles&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mitigation controls can now be assigned directly to Business Roles through the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE/96f4b1ec2df9455492adaec07e6029f4/2cb258274e40490988a23df89883a647.html?version=CLOUDFOUNDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Role UI&lt;/A&gt; or the Mitigation Assignment application, which includes a new Business Roles–specific category. All assignments are recorded in the audit log, and risk assessments for Business Roles inherit any access-level mitigations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ElyasAhmed_0-1752011080802.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284329i7B49669A65E8C7A7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ElyasAhmed_0-1752011080802.png" alt="ElyasAhmed_0-1752011080802.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Secure Storage of Reports on a Customer-Owned Document Server&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Analyze User Access downloads can now be directed straight to your organization’s &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE/e12d8683adfa4471ac4edd40809b9038/5cd1a3b708c74efbbb047622540202b1.html?version=CLOUDFOUNDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Document Management Service (DMS)&lt;/A&gt;. Each report is stored in accordance with your retention and classification policies, removing the need for manual file handling and keeping sensitive data securely within your content repository. Keep an eye on the &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73555000100800000334&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q3%202025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;roadmap&lt;/A&gt; as this feature will be extended to include other report types in future releases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ElyasAhmed_1-1752011080815.png" style="width: 931px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284330i52BEE6D5A91F8E54/image-dimensions/931x600?v=v2" width="931" height="600" role="button" title="ElyasAhmed_1-1752011080815.png" alt="ElyasAhmed_1-1752011080815.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Access Analysis App&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE/9621f10c676c497a8355b7e36053e837/33373ebe82a84bfb9c34d037f9f0667d.html?version=CLOUDFOUNDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Access Analysis detail view&lt;/A&gt; now includes a built-in smart filter bar for both Access and Risk lists, letting you search, sort, and filter your dataset without ever leaving the interface. This one-pane experience replaces spreadsheet workarounds and speeds up investigations by keeping all controls at your fingertips.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ElyasAhmed_0-1752186737063.png" style="width: 1006px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285291i9B252C95D031CF0A/image-dimensions/1006x561?v=v2" width="1006" height="561" role="button" title="ElyasAhmed_0-1752186737063.png" alt="ElyasAhmed_0-1752186737063.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ariba Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additional Ariba user attributes stored in IdDS are automatically provisioned to newly created &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/common-data-import-and-administration-for-sap-ariba-procurement-solutions/sap-ariba-solutions-integration-with-sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-ad9fbd99ee1a49038ee9e767d9511ba1?version=2505" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Ariba accounts&lt;/A&gt;. This capability is available in both standalone Cloud Identity Access Governance and SAP Access Control via Bridge integration for IdDS customers. By sourcing attributes directly from the central IdDS, it eliminates manual updates in Ariba and ensures provisioning remains compliant with corporate standards across systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ElyasAhmed_3-1752011080835.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284331i79B43BD9C6263414/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ElyasAhmed_3-1752011080835.png" alt="ElyasAhmed_3-1752011080835.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Updated Rulesets for Concur &amp;amp; BTP Financial Applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This release adds new segregation-of-duties rulesets for Concur (Expense, Invoice, Request), SAP S/4HANA and SuccessFactors core transactions, and BTP’s advanced financial-closing processes, so you can detect and manage cross-system risks with greater precision and enforce compliance consistently across your finance and HR applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Forward Privileged Access Review Requests&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE/37bacb728d75468c92b1f1e20d5afbe2/cee1cb62728f469bb027ec60a543f499.html?version=CLOUDFOUNDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;forward functionality&lt;/A&gt; in the Privileged Access Monitoring Report enables PAM administrators to efficiently reassign log-review requests to additional reviewers without altering the current workflow stage. This feature enhances resource flexibility by allowing easy redistribution of reviewer responsibilities while maintaining the integrity of existing review processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ElyasAhmed_4-1752011080846.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284332i5703AECB7969D671/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ElyasAhmed_4-1752011080846.png" alt="ElyasAhmed_4-1752011080846.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Looking Ahead!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Q2 2025’s release, SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance continues its march toward more intuitive, integrated, and audit-ready access management. These updates deliver targeted improvements that reduce administrative overhead and bolster compliance. Stay tuned for even more innovations next quarter as we refine workflows and expand capabilities based on your feedback.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, to view detailed feature lists, or to get started with SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance, please visit SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/financial-management/cloud-iam.html?video=2805c5b3-e57d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Product Page&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Documentation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-q2-2025/ba-p/14147771"/>
    <published>2025-07-08T23:52:00.006000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/securing-agentic-ai-through-threat-modeling-at-sap/ba-p/14155323</id>
    <title>Securing Agentic AI Through Threat Modeling at SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T18:17:00.624000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>helenoakley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/221997</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="agentic-ai.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288025i83B23ADACD168DDC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agentic-ai.jpg" alt="agentic-ai.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;By&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/helen-oakley/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Helen Oakley&lt;/A&gt;, Senior Director of Software and AI Security, SAP Global Security &amp;amp; Cloud Compliance&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This year, at SAP Sapphire, SAP unveiled its expanded vision for Business AI, introducing a growing network of Joule Agents that work across systems and lines of business. This marks a clear step into the era of Agentic AI – systems that can understand context, take initiative, and drive outcomes autonomously. “SAP combines the world’s most powerful suite of business applications with uniquely rich data and the latest AI innovations to create a flywheel of customer value,” &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/05/sap-business-ai-reimagine-how-enterprises-run/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;said CEO Christian Klein&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. While this evolution opens exciting possibilities for automation and productivity, it also introduces a new layer of complexity in how we approach security. Agentic systems challenge traditional safeguards, making it essential to identify and mitigate risks early through tailored threat modeling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At its core, threat modeling is about asking the right questions early in the development process, while the system is still being designed and built. Rather than simply looking for bugs or code flaws, it forces us to think through how a system might behave in the real world. What could go wrong if an agent’s goals are manipulated? Could someone poison its memory over time? What if an agent uses a tool in an unintended or unsafe way? How could agent-generated content be used to mislead or overload human decision-makers? What happens when agents collaborate or collide in ways that expose the system to cascading failures or manipulation?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These are not hypothetical questions. They reflect the real and emerging risks of agentic systems. The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://genai.owasp.org/resource/agentic-ai-threats-and-mitigations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OWASP Agentic AI Threats &amp;amp; Mitigations Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is a valuable resource that brings structure to this thinking. It highlights specific threats such as memory poisoning, cascading hallucinations, privilege compromise, and agent communication poisoning. For teams building these systems, it helps provide a common vocabulary and practical examples to guide threat modeling work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To give an example of how threat modeling helps in practice, let’s take the case of goal manipulation – one of the emerging risks identified in the OWASP guide. In agentic systems, attackers don’t necessarily need to exploit traditional software flaws. Instead, they can attempt to influence an agent’s behavior over time by subtly manipulating its objectives. This might happen through indirect prompt injection, compromised data sources, or crafted tool responses. Imagine an agent responsible for prioritizing financial transactions; if adversarial inputs gradually shift its decision logic, it could start approving risky payments outside of the intended policy. In threat modeling exercises, we explore how such scenarios could play out by analyzing how the agent forms and updates its goals, how memory and feedback loops could reinforce undesired behaviors, and how downstream actions might be impacted. This helps define targeted mitigations, such as isolating goal-setting logic from external inputs, monitoring shifts in agent behavior, and adding human validation for sensitive decisions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The OWASP Agentic AI Threats &amp;amp; Mitigations Guide provides a helpful reference architecture that illustrates where these types of risks can emerge. The diagram below maps threats to key components in a typical agentic system, making it easier to visualize how threat modeling applies in practice.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="helenoakley_0-1752751657687.png" style="width: 844px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287897iD3D301C81278E582/image-dimensions/844x449?v=v2" width="844" height="449" role="button" title="helenoakley_0-1752751657687.png" alt="helenoakley_0-1752751657687.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Image Source: OWASP Agentic AI Threats and Mitigations guide, “Threat Model Summary”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At SAP, threat modeling has long been part of our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2016/03/a248a699-627c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Secure Software Development and Operations Lifecycle (Secure SDOL)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, which is certified under ISO 27001. This framework ensures security is built into every phase of the product lifecycle, from design to operations. With Agentic AI, we are expanding our threat modeling approach to address risks that don’t typically appear in traditional application security. This includes analyzing agent memory behavior, reasoning patterns, system autonomy, human interaction points, and the dynamics of multi-agent ecosystems. The focus shifts from identifying static vulnerabilities to understanding how autonomy and learning can lead to unintended behaviors. From there, we define appropriate controls and mitigations to reduce those risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The field of Agentic AI security continues to take shape. Standards like ISO 42001 and regulations such as the EU AI Act are in development, and industry best practices are actively maturing. That’s why collaboration is essential. SAP is contributing to the conversations held with industry groups focused on these challenges, including &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://genai.owasp.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OWASP GenAI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; initiatives. We’re not just adopting ideas, we’re helping shape them, working with peers and regulators to advance the state of AI security. Our teams bring deep expertise in both enterprise security and AI systems, offering a perspective that’s helping guide how the broader ecosystem approaches agentic risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transparency remains central to how SAP approaches product security. As we continue evolving our work with AI, we’re committed to sharing what we learn through resources like the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Trust Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Security is not a one-time effort. It is a continuous process, especially with systems as dynamic as Agentic AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Threat modeling helps us stay ahead of these evolving risks and supports the design of systems that are both capable and safe. As Agentic AI becomes more embedded in enterprise workflows, this kind of proactive thinking becomes essential.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is proud to contribute to shaping the future of secure AI. By collaborating across the industry and applying deep expertise from our teams, we’re helping advance practical, forward-looking approaches to securing the next generation of intelligent systems.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/securing-agentic-ai-through-threat-modeling-at-sap/ba-p/14155323"/>
    <published>2025-07-17T18:17:00.624000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-ai-powered-fraud-prevention/ba-p/14130451</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: AI-Powered Fraud Prevention</title>
    <updated>2025-07-22T07:00:00.024000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_0-1750211341627.jpeg" style="width: 501px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275591i62B7B51A93E3D817/image-dimensions/501x335?v=v2" width="501" height="335" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_0-1750211341627.jpeg" alt="T_Frenehard_0-1750211341627.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we are all (too much) aware, Artificial Intelligence has changed our working habits. Sometimes for the good, such as creating a nice illustration for this blog, but also sometimes to the benefit of the dark force when used with malicious intents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the area of fraud, AI-generated deception strategies have become more and more sophisticated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While confirming during a Teams meeting with the Treasurer that a request for an urgent transfer was legitimate and was previously a sure protection against business email compromise scams, advanced audio and video deepfakes have rendered this earlier failsafe obsolete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, should we just give up and all move to just one office location so that you can get in person confirmations on sensitive transactions?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No, of course not.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, I’d like to discuss how SAP solutions for Governance, Risk, and Compliance can be enhanced with “last mile checks” from &lt;A href="https://trustpair.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Trustpair&lt;/A&gt; to catch any fraudulent activity before it’s too late.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1733129861"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building a resilient treasury governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With ninety percent of US companies reporting being targeted by cyber fraud in 2024, and thirty-eight percent targeted by payment fraud more than 10 times over the same period as per Trustpair’s &lt;A href="https://trustpair.com/blog/fraud-report-2025-press-release/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Fraud in the Cyber Era: 2025 Fraud Trends &amp;amp; Insights&lt;/A&gt;, this is clearly not an isolated issue and it’s not going away any time soon. And just to put it into perspective, the FBI’s latest &lt;A href="https://www.ic3.gov/AnnualReport/Reports/2024_IC3Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Internet Crime Report&lt;/A&gt; mentions that business email compromise alone totalled $2,770,151,146 reported losses in 2024...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To combat this scourge, companies are investing in 3 main areas:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="200"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Training &amp;amp; Awareness&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_1-1750211341629.png" style="width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275589i5AE991BA2594D33F/image-dimensions/100x100?v=v2" width="100" height="100" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_1-1750211341629.png" alt="T_Frenehard_1-1750211341629.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="200"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authorizations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_2-1750211341630.png" style="width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275590i2217A62FFE285930/image-dimensions/100x100?v=v2" width="100" height="100" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_2-1750211341630.png" alt="T_Frenehard_2-1750211341630.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="200"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technology&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_3-1750211341631.png" style="width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275593i636386698FED152A/image-dimensions/100x100?v=v2" width="100" height="100" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_3-1750211341631.png" alt="T_Frenehard_3-1750211341631.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Training &amp;amp; Awareness and Authorizations are perfect examples of preventative control measures: by reducing the fraud attack surface, companies reduce the likelihood of a fraud succeeding.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But much like phishing attacks, if the sample is large enough and the incentives sufficiently compelling, chances are that business email compromise scams will still succeed. And when you think that findings from the &lt;A href="https://www.afponline.org/training-resources/resources/survey-research-economic-data/details/payments-fraud" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;2025 AFP® Payments Fraud and Control Survey&lt;/A&gt; indicate that only 22% of organizations were able to recover 75% or more of the funds lost due to payments fraud in 2024, more proactive measures are needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where technology plays an important role, in my opinion, to address the remaining gap and moves the needle to earlier detection – before the loss is incurred.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1536616356"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fraud prevention triangle&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Indeed, what if the treasury employee targeted already has the role and authorization to perform the transaction, had the relevant training and is aware that these types of attacks exist but has been convinced by an advanced deepfake that the request is legitimate and still processes the payment?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This where technology takes the relay and enhances human checks to provide a last dependable defense layer based on 3 angles creating the Fraud Prevention Triangle. This depiction below is not from me so all credit here goes to my colleague &lt;A href="https://it.linkedin.com/in/emanuelefumeo" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Emanuele Fumeo&lt;/A&gt; - Finance Solution Advisor at SAP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="T_Frenehard_4-1750211341642.png" style="width: 601px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275592i748DB0DDA9A72029/image-dimensions/601x251?v=v2" width="601" height="251" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_4-1750211341642.png" alt="T_Frenehard_4-1750211341642.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="601"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Anomaly detection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By screening large volumes of transactional data, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/financial-management/fraud-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Integrity Screening&lt;/A&gt; helps identify anomalous activity quickly using flexible rule sets and predictive analyses to uncover potential fraud patterns or deviations from policy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Should the attack follow a known pattern, it would be detected at this stage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="601"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Partner Screening&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Within SAP Business Integrity Screening, a dedicated module enables enterprises across all industries to screen their business partners against lists of denied persons and organizations published by governments and global institutions, thus ensuring their compliance with guidelines, regulations, and legislation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the business party involved in the transaction has already been flagged by authorities as being on a sanctioned list for instance, then this second automated step would prevent any further processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="601"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Account Validation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, even if the attack hasn’t been detected and the party seems legitimate, Account Validation – also known as Confirmation of Payee, is the last mile check. It is the ultimate control and here, &lt;A href="https://trustpair.com/connect/sap-s4hana/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;TrustPair&lt;/A&gt; can automatically perform one-time checks for new vendors in SAP Ariba but also continuous monitoring of vendor master data and payment files in the ERP system to detect risks, abnormal amounts and duplicates. Ultimately making the entire process more secure and efficient with a last protection net validating the company identity, but also the bank account ownership against banking sources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, human factor prevention with adequate training, attack surface reduction with relevant authorizations and advanced technology detection can help ensure that even advanced fraudulent attacks are deterred – hence safeguarding the company’s financials.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And this must be done consistently across the end-to-end procure to pay process but also directly embedded within the transactional systems to ensure adequate and timely action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What about you, how does your company address the AI-powered fraud threat? I look forward to reading your thoughts and comments on this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And if you are interested in learning more about TrustPair’s solutions for SAP and how it applies a 5-layer validation with external sources, smart algorithms and complementary checks to secure the source to pay chain, then have a look &lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/product/display-2001011315_live_v1/trustpair-payment-fraud-prevention" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Trustpair Payment Fraud Prevention&lt;/A&gt; on the SAP Store.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-ai-powered-fraud-prevention/ba-p/14130451"/>
    <published>2025-07-22T07:00:00.024000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/navigating-governance-risk-and-compliance-grc-in-today-s-business/ba-p/14165506</id>
    <title>Navigating Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC) in Today’s Business Environment</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T10:05:01.341000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Xenia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/899</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In complex regulatory and business environments, organizations are under growing pressure to manage risks, ensure compliance, and uphold strong governance practices. Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC) is the strategic framework designed to meet these demands—helping businesses align IT with corporate objectives, manage risk proactively, and ensure compliance across an increasingly complex regulatory landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1736050190"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is GRC?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC) is a coordinated strategy for managing an organization's overall governance, enterprise risk management, and compliance with regulations. GRC provides a structured approach to decision-making by integrating risk, compliance, and performance data across departments. When effectively implemented, GRC helps reduce uncertainty, control costs, mitigate IT and security risks, and improve overall business performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1539536685"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s Driving the Need for GRC Today?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organizations face big waves in diverse, fast-moving risks—from cybersecurity threats to geopolitical disruptions—creating a need for real-time risk awareness and accountability. At the same time, global regulatory frameworks are becoming more demanding and complex, with increasing expectations around transparency and internal controls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Digital transformation of businesses introduces both opportunity and risk. Real-time processes, machine learning, robotic process automation (RPA), and increased collaboration across organizational boundaries demand new approaches to monitoring, assurance, and control. Traditional, manual GRC practices are no longer sufficient in this dynamic environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GRC and SAP’s Secure Operations Map&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP’s Secure Operations Map (SOM), GRC is embedded in four critical domains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Security Governance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Risk Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regulatory Process Compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Audit &amp;amp; Fraud Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This integration provides a foundational structure to ensure GRC principles are applied consistently across IT, finance, and operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRC in the Context of the Secure Operations Map (SOM)" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293246iD971443EBFD59761/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Xenia_0-1753775564593.png" alt="GRC in the Context of the Secure Operations Map (SOM)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;GRC in the Context of the Secure Operations Map (SOM)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1343023180"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why Do Organizations Need GRC Tools?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many organizations still manage internal controls and compliance processes manually—using spreadsheets, shared drives, emails, and physical binders. This fragmented approach leads to delays, errors, outdated information, and in some cases, missed control testing. This is especially concerning given the need for CEOs and CFOs to sign off on financial statements under personal liability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;GRC tools centralize and automate these processes, providing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A unified view of internal controls across the enterprise&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Timely and accurate compliance data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reduced risk of financial misstatements or regulatory breaches&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Greater efficiency in audits, due diligence, M&amp;amp;A, and IPO processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The objective is clear: ensure operational consistency, identify irregularities or non-compliance, and build a resilient and trustworthy organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example control - Record-to-Report Process" style="width: 961px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293248i2DCD3A2AF107F7CF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Xenia_1-1753775730382.png" alt="Example control - Record-to-Report Process" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example control - Record-to-Report Process&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1146509675"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Implementing a GRC Strategy: Key Steps&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1079078889"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Define the Purpose and Scope&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;An effective GRC strategy begins with defining its purpose and scope. Organizations need to determine whether the approach will be applied enterprise-wide or focused on high-risk areas such as finance, IT, or third-party relationships. Objectives such as improving audit readiness, meeting regulatory requirements, and reducing operational risk should be clearly defined from the outset.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-882565384"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Establish a Governance Structure&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next step is to establish a governance structure. This involves forming a cross-functional GRC steering committee with representatives from compliance, legal, IT, HR, and business leadership. Responsibility for managing risks, maintaining policies, overseeing controls, and handling reporting must be clearly assigned. A dedicated GRC lead should be appointed to coordinate implementation and ensure consistency across departments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-686051879"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Conduct a Risk and Compliance Assessment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A risk and compliance assessment follows. This assessment identifies internal and external risks, maps relevant regulations such as GDPR, HIPAA, and SOX, and evaluates existing compliance gaps. A risk register is developed to classify risks based on their likelihood and potential impact on the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-489538374"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Develop and Document Policies and Controls&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the risks identified, the organization can develop and document appropriate policies and controls. These cover areas such as data protection, access management, and anti-fraud measures. Each risk is linked to corresponding control measures, and responsibilities are assigned using a controls matrix to ensure clear traceability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-293024869"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. Select and Deploy a GRC Tool&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selecting and deploying a GRC tool is essential for effective execution. The tool should centralize risk and compliance data, support integration with existing systems such as HR, ERP, and incident reporting platforms, and automate key tasks such as alerts, workflows, and compliance tracking. A pilot rollout helps test the setup in a controlled environment before broader deployment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-96511364"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6. Train and Communicate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Training and communication play a key role in supporting your GRC framework. Employees receive role-specific training on relevant policies and how to report concerns. Internal awareness efforts help foster a culture of compliance and accountability. Managers are provided with tools such as dashboards to monitor compliance within their teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--175233510"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7. Monitor, Audit, and Continuously Improve&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To keep the GRC strategy effective, organizations must implement ongoing monitoring, regular audits, and continuous improvement. This involves scheduled control testing, internal audits, and the use of key risk indicators to track changes and emerging issues. Reviewing incidents, near misses, and evolving regulations ensures the GRC framework remains current and effective.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Steps for Implementing a GRC Strategy" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293252i883D7DC2464F7950/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Xenia_2-1753775924369.png" alt="Steps for Implementing a GRC Strategy" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Steps for Implementing a GRC Strategy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--78344008"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tools for GRC in Hybrid SAP Landscapes: Introducing SAP Risk and Assurance Management (RAM)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s traditional GRC suite—including Process Control (PC) and Risk Management (RM)—is tightly integrated with on-premise ERP systems. However, in today’s cloud and hybrid environments, their capabilities can be limited.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Risk and Assurance Management (RAM)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: a modern GRC platform designed for hybrid landscapes, including S/4HANA Cloud (both Public and Private Editions). SAP RAM enables organizations to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Leverage a single platform for multiple use cases across the enterprise&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Turn GRC from a compliance burden into a strategic differentiator&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Focus resources on high-impact risks, processes, and regulations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Continuously monitor control performance using real-time business data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Improve compliance and control effectiveness while reducing operational costs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By automating labor-intensive tasks like control testing, RAM not only enhances assurance quality but also frees up internal audit and compliance teams to focus on what matters most.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example Process Flow in RAM" style="width: 981px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293253iADF2658BACAF2FFB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Xenia_3-1753775977456.png" alt="Example Process Flow in RAM" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example Process Flow in RAM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--274857513"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;GRC is no longer just a back-office function—it has become a critical enabler of strategic agility, operational resilience, and trust in the digital age. With a well-defined strategy, clear governance structure, and tools like SAP Risk and Assurance Management, organizations can shift from reactive compliance to proactive risk management and business optimization. As part of this evolution, integrating GRC with security monitoring is essential. Giving responsible teams access to timely and accurate security information strengthens their ability to detect potential threats and respond effectively. Auditing and monitoring tools further enhance this by measuring the success of GRC efforts and highlighting areas for improvement. In the next blog post, we’ll explore how SAP supports real-time security monitoring and auditing—turning insight into action to improve enterprise security and compliance.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/navigating-governance-risk-and-compliance-grc-in-today-s-business/ba-p/14165506"/>
    <published>2025-07-29T10:05:01.341000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/linda-bettenhausen/ba-p/14168705</id>
    <title>Linda Bettenhausen</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T22:18:36.108000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanieMarley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1437516" target="_self"&gt;Linda&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Germany&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;SAP Mentor since 2025&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Follow Linda on &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/linda-bettenhausen-785868207/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Linda Bettenhausen headshot.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/294843i04AEE02CB2A492F6/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Linda Bettenhausen headshot.jpg" alt="Linda Bettenhausen headshot.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Linda is an expert in accounting topics. During her career she collected very different experiences. Starting in a big corporation in 2013 she dealt with everyday accounting business which still supports her understanding of the customer perspective and their needs nowadays. 2019 she changed to one of the bigger German consulting companies and took over different roles in several S/4HANA implementation projects. Besides this she became involved to support SAP careers and Women in Tech quite early. Since spring 2024 she changed to a smaller consulting company facing to built up the accounting team and the expertise in this area with an approach of a more customer-centric and sustainable consulting to meet the clients on eye-level and bringing real benefit to them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Topics of interest:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Accounting, Finance, Controlling, Governance, Planning, Financial Supply Chain Management&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Linda, what inspired you to become an SAP Mentor?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="handshake .png" style="width: 68px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52491i8E9D2FFB3C7BC293/image-dimensions/68x68?v=v2" width="68" height="68" role="button" title="handshake .png" alt="handshake .png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;Colleagues from my network suggested the SAP mentor nomination to me. I frequently use to bring up potential topics to my customers as I am hugely interested in bringing a real benefit to them. For me, the role as a mentor can gather the next stage as I can bring the feedback and user experiences from the customers back to SAP. I believe that this combination improves both the products and the consulting services that all of us provide to our clients.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What advice would like to share with other SAP community members?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" style="width: 65px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52495i64D82195EFF8CCB9/image-dimensions/65x65?v=v2" width="65" height="65" role="button" title="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;I strongly recommend staying in touch with your customers. Listen to them and support them in their activities by bringing up creative ideas and solution approaches. Even if you do not get a deal done today, this strengthens your relationship by building mutual trust. Furthermore, I can give the advice to closely work together with junior consultants within your organization. They are highly motivated and thankful to trustworthy mentors. It is not just about the professional and technical expertise. It is also about the soft factors such as communication, organization, taking care, how to push things forward etc. When all of this comes together, you will build up that kind of consultants that we need for the future.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/linda-bettenhausen/ba-p/14168705"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T22:18:36.108000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
