<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Governance-Risk-Compliance-(GRC)-and-Cybersecurity-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Governance, Risk, Compliance (GRC), and Cybersecurity</title>
  <updated>2025-09-12T23:10:38.118188+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Governance, Risk, Compliance (GRC), and Cybersecurity/pd-p/237150e2-6555-4a16-b49e-e93dbf1891da" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Governance, Risk, Compliance (GRC), and Cybersecurity blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-s-coming-in-sap-solutions-for-three-lines-of-defense/ba-p/14132369</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: What's Coming in SAP Solutions for Three Lines (of Defense)</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T07:00:00.040000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_0-1750377816865.jpeg" style="width: 500px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276501i6F6909A6444ECE79/image-dimensions/500x337?v=v2" width="500" height="337" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_0-1750377816865.jpeg" alt="T_Frenehard_0-1750377816865.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To help drive a unified vision across all SAP solutions for Three Lines (of Defense), &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rohit-hotwani-00003450/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Rohit Hotwani&lt;/A&gt; has recently been announced as the Strategic Product Manager for these products. And Rohit will already be very familiar to many of you since he was until then Global Solution Advisor for SAP GRC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a result, Rohit and I thought it would be a good opportunity to provide an update on what’s planned in terms of roadmap items for SAP Process Control, SAP Risk Management and SAP Audit Management. And there’s quite a lot!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1733188521"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Harmonized management of compliance issues and findings from different source systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have been following these GRC Tuesdays blogs for some time now, you may recall a partner blog from Turnkey Consulting: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/grc-tuesdays-hidden-gems-integration-between-sap-process-control-pc-and-sap/ba-p/13581354" target="_blank"&gt;Hidden Gems. Integration between SAP Process Control (PC) and SAP Business Integrity Screening (BIS)&lt;/A&gt;. This post highlighted how both tools can already complement each other's strengths, allowing for a healthier control management process. But there have recently been customer requirements to take this integration a step further and make it easier to leverage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a result, Product Management and Engineering are working on a sub-scenario in SAP Process Control to expose SAP Business Integrity Screening to its continuous control monitoring functionality. This would enable to link controls in SAP Process Control with detection strategies in SAP Business Integrity Screening so that continuous monitoring can make use of this powerful fraud detection capability and, at the same time, enable a unified issue remediation process in SAP Process Control. With this integration, organizations will be able to centralize and organize compliance issues and findings into one system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1536675016"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extending integration of continuous control monitoring to SAP and non-SAP systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By integrating SAP Process Control with SAP Integration Suite, users will be able to connect to SAP and third-party systems and use these additional data as sources for continuous control monitoring and automated controls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will help build a holistic control environment system with SAP Process Control being the central hub to analyse and monitor data from connected systems, but also to follow-up on compliance issues and remediate them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To do so, the plan is to provide pre-delivered integration flows and continuous monitoring across hybrid systems:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_1-1750377816868.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276499i3EAC58325FEF7004/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_1-1750377816868.png" alt="T_Frenehard_1-1750377816868.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1340161511"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent self-diagnostics cockpit app&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this planned innovation, internal control experts will be able to get self-diagnosing errors and solutions provided within a dedicated app. This app will deliver detailed error descriptions and will help guide users through the resolution process, hence supporting problem-solving with step-by step approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_2-1750377816871.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276500iEED0999DCC1DC4C6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_2-1750377816871.png" alt="T_Frenehard_2-1750377816871.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1143648006"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cybersecurity Risk Management framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-s-new-in-sap-solutions-for-three-lines-q3-2023-to-q1-2024/ba-p/13615040" target="_blank"&gt;announced last year&lt;/A&gt;, National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) SP800-53 revision 5 and Cybersecurity Framework CSF Version 2.0 content can now be uploaded as central controls in SAP Process Control to help organizations enhance their IT Security &amp;amp; Cybersecurity controls with a best in class set of guidelines that define the baseline controls for information systems and organizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To even better support customers looking at adopting the NIST best practices – especially in the area of &lt;A href="https://csrc.nist.gov/publications/detail/nistir/8286/final" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Integrating Cybersecurity and Enterprise Risk Management&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(NIST IR 8286), we will provide a support of NIST’s risk management framework by importing content as a risk template or a response template. This will enable customers to benefit from best-practice guidance from the leading Cybersecurity agency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_3-1750377816881.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276504iD7AE8A6B988055D4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_3-1750377816881.png" alt="T_Frenehard_3-1750377816881.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-947134501"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business continuity management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In continuation of the first building blocks delivered last year – &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-s-new-in-sap-solutions-for-three-lines-q1-2024-to-q2-2024/ba-p/13716529" target="_blank"&gt;Business Impact Analysis in SAP Risk Management&lt;/A&gt;, we plan to continue on this business continuity management journey with additional enhancements, including:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business continuity planning by supporting strategy definition and documentation, including business continuity and disaster recovery plans to help ensure critical business processes or activities in the organization can survive serious disruptions and to enable organizations to provide a clear blueprint for what everyone should do when business processes can't continue as normal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business continuity test and exercise to create a picture of the scenarios, making it easier for business continuity team members and stakeholders to get practical preparation and identify any loopholes in the business continuity plan, and improve it continuously&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-750620996"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vendor and third-party risk assessment and due diligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once again building on &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-s-new-in-sap-solutions-for-three-lines-vendor-risk/ba-p/13887665" target="_blank"&gt;initial deliveries from last year&lt;/A&gt;, the Vendor Risk Assessment capability will be enhanced with the introduction of a new a survey type and format to support the onboarding and due diligence of third parties and vendors. This survey will support issuing to external recipients to cater for onboarding and due diligence for 3rd parties.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-554107491"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creation and reuse of a recommendation across multiple findings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To increase the efficiency of the 3rd line in SAP Audit Management, we plan on helping avoid developing duplicate recommendations for the same or similar findings by enabling the reuse of recommendations across multiple findings. This will also come with enhancements to help auditors monitor and manage recommendations centrally, through a holistic view of the remediation process and, ultimately, should promote collaborative problem-solving with auditees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_4-1750377816885.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276502iEA40639A5236C886/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_4-1750377816885.png" alt="T_Frenehard_4-1750377816885.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-357593986"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consolidation of email notification for multiple actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make it easier for auditors and auditees to track updates, our colleagues are working on a setting that would enable the system administrator to quickly configure and consolidate multiple e-mail notifications into a single mailing. Once activated, related email notifications would be grouped into one message. Of course, non-consolidated notifications would still be immediately dispatched.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will help reduce email clutter that can occur when a high number of actions are performed in a short time frame – all sending their individual notification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_5-1750377816905.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/276503i22C3D72A297936B9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_5-1750377816905.png" alt="T_Frenehard_5-1750377816905.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rohit and I hope that this short overview will have provided some valuable insights on the roadmap plans for these solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And if you are interested in learning more about SAP solutions for Governance, Risk, and Compliance, feel free to fill-in the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/request-demo.html?product=237150e2-6555-4a16-b49e-e93dbf1891da&amp;amp;productName=Governance%2C+Risk%2C+Compliance+%28GRC%29%2C+and+Cybersecurity&amp;amp;pageTitle=Cybersecurity+and+Governance%2C+Risk%2C+and+Compliance+Software&amp;amp;countryOfOrigin=en_au&amp;amp;refererPagePath=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sap.com%2Faustralia%2Fproducts%2Ffinancial-management%2Fgrc.html&amp;amp;refererContentPath=%2Fcontent%2Fsapdx%2Flanguages%2Fen_gb%2Fproducts%2Ffinancial-management%2Fgrc&amp;amp;navTitle=Request+a+Demo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;demo request form&lt;/A&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-what-s-coming-in-sap-solutions-for-three-lines-of-defense/ba-p/14132369"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T07:00:00.040000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/podcast-sap-enterprise-threat-detection-cloud-edition-meets-microsoft/ba-p/14145718</id>
    <title>Podcast: SAP Enterprise Threat Detection, cloud edition Meets Microsoft Sentinel Solution for SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-07-07T11:39:20.552000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Lingscheid</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/38175</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The latest episode 245 of the Microsoft SAP on Azure podcast brings together experts from SAP Michael Schmitt and Microsoft Martin Pankraz to discuss a game-changing integration: SAP Enterprise Threat Detection, cloud edition with Microsoft Sentinel. In an increasingly interconnected digital landscape, securing enterprise systems has never been more crucial. This collaboration promises to revolutionize how organizations monitor and respond to security threats across their SAP and Microsoft environments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-07-07 at 08.19.49.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/283355i9C0D76AFB20B40E2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-07-07 at 08.19.49.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-07-07 at 08.19.49.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Azure Market Place" href="https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/en-us/marketplace/apps/sap_jasondau.azure-sentinel-solution-sapetd?tab=overview" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Azure Market Place&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unified Security Monitoring: The integration allows security teams to view SAP-specific threats alongside other security events in Microsoft Sentinel. This holistic approach enables faster threat detection and response across the entire IT landscape.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simplified Connectivity: Setting up the integration is straightforward, especially for Enterprise Threat Detection, cloud edition. It leverages standard Business Technology Platform (BTP) authentication mechanisms, making it accessible for organizations already invested in SAP's cloud ecosystem.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced Threat Intelligence: By combining SAP's deep application-level insights with Microsoft's broader security context, organizations can build more comprehensive attack graphs and correlate events more effectively.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customer-Driven Development: Both SAP and Microsoft are actively seeking customer feedback to shape the future of this integration, ensuring it addresses real-world security challenges.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the most compelling moments in the podcast is when Martin demonstrates an attack scenario. He shows a potentially malicious action in an SAP system (accessing sensitive function modules) that is instantly detected by Enterprise Threat Detection and seamlessly reported to Sentinel. This real-time visibility across platforms is a game-changer for security operations teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical resources shared during the podcast include:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A detailed technical guide for setting up a test environment to explore the ETD-Sentinel integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Information on accessing free trials for both ETD and Sentinel to experiment with the integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A link to provide feedback on desired features and use cases for future development&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ETD API Sentinel.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/283366i5AD051F87AB3ED55/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ETD API Sentinel.png" alt="ETD API Sentinel.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;While the integration shows great promise, Martin and Michael acknowledge that there's still is work to be done in areas like attribute correlation between SAP and Microsoft systems e.g. via email addresses as a common identifier across platforms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Call to action:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For those intrigued by this overview, the full podcast offers much more. Listening in you will gain deeper insights into the technical aspects of the integration, you will hear about real customer reactions from recent hands-on workshops during the DSAG Technologie Tage in Wiesbaden and get a glimpse into the future roadmap for this collaborative security solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To experience the full depth of this discussion and stay ahead of the curve in enterprise security, be sure to listen to the complete podcast episode.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SaAguCqRjyU" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SaAguCqRjyU&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Don't forget to subscribe to stay updated on the latest developments in SAP and Microsoft technologies!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/podcast-sap-enterprise-threat-detection-cloud-edition-meets-microsoft/ba-p/14145718"/>
    <published>2025-07-07T11:39:20.552000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-keeping-up-to-date-with-tariff-changes/ba-p/14120668</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: Keeping up to date with tariff changes</title>
    <updated>2025-07-08T07:00:00.030000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="277952_277952_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" style="width: 501px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/270437i35820233451C81B9/image-dimensions/501x393?v=v2" width="501" height="393" role="button" title="277952_277952_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" alt="277952_277952_l_srgb_s_gl.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;In our new global trade reality, keeping track of tariff changes can seem an insurmountable task. Trade policies are changing more rapidly than ever before and being enforced at a moment’s notice; requiring flexibility and adaptability from companies to implement new tariffs to ensure that they are not penalised for underpaying duties.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If continuously monitoring customs authorities’ official communication channels is the most straight forward option, it comes with great resource constraint. And a certain dose of expertise to determine which change applies to the organization, in what context, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another option is engaging with a licensed customs broker. These experts would be able to provide the level of monitoring and guidance mentioned above, on behalf of the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But there is a third option for companies wishing to do it themselves and leverage these uncertain times to gain a competitive advantage by reacting faster and more precisely: aligning best-in-class content with best-in-class technology from SAP Global Trade Services to get information in real time and directly connected to the core processes and supply chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1732208300"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How can companies get the latest duty rates?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As per leading analyst firm Gartner, there are two types of global trade management software providers: those that do and those that do not provide content with their tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On this matter, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP&lt;/A&gt; has strategically decided to work with its ecosystem of professional global trade data partners offering subscription-based access to a wide selection of trade content. Content from dedicated teams that specialize in identifying, interpreting, and collecting changes and updates to trade regulations that can be imported into SAP through standardized interfaces, but, more importantly, content that can be tailored to each customer’s specific needs in terms of geographic coverage (regions and countries to monitor), content types, and process areas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This provides organizations with the freedom to select a global trade data partner covering their specific requirements or even combine content from various providers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a result, the global trade data partner acts as a central source for up-to-date information helping companies navigate evolving trade regulations. Information provided includes, but not limited to, customs tariff measures and duty rates, export control lists, rules for preferential origin determination for free trade agreements, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Companies such as &lt;A href="https://www.mendel-verlag.de/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Mendel Verlag&lt;/A&gt; started decades ago with production and publication of customs tariffs and other publications and have expanded to electronic formats that can be directly consumed by global trade management platforms such as &lt;A href="https://sap.com/gts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Global Trade Services&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To produce this foreign trade content, Mendel Verlag follows a 5-step approach – all done internally by a team of specialists:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Research for the identification and review of relevant sources&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Compile information from step 1&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Evaluate for relevance and validity&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consolidate different information and sources for integrated data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Quality control including classic editing but also manual checks of electronically processed data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This last step is crucial, as only with expert review can the content provider ensure credibility and reliability of the trade compliance master data information. As highlighted by Mendel Verlag: “&lt;EM&gt;Quality is a key requirement of our work. Only valid data can be used effectively in foreign trade and customs processes.&lt;/EM&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once subscribed to a data content service, customers will receive continuous updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;To ensure that the trade compliance information in SAP Global Trade Services&amp;nbsp;is in sync and therefore also continuously up to date, the procedure is quite simple. The updated file from the content provider – usually in an XML format, is placed on a secure file transfer protocol (SFTP) folder where it is picked up by SAP Global Trade Services&amp;nbsp;and values are uploaded into the platform.&amp;nbsp; This process includes control parameter checks, and errors can be manually reviewed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;If a company decides to change data providers, and therefore need to replace the previous data provider's content with the new data provider's content, SAP Global Trade Services&amp;nbsp;can of course enable the configuration of time-dependency of this content. This flexibility enables customers to enter two competing sets of content in the system, and when they activate the new data provider's content, the old data provider's content – and all dependent items, is deactivated automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1535694795"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Typical misconceptions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We, at SAP, strongly believe that working hand-in-hand with a global trade data partner provider is in the best interest of our customers to be able to freely choose, change or combine content from various content providers, addressing specific countries or regions, content types and process areas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This can raise a few questions and misconceptions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="720px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="298.641px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Misconception&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="420.359px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reality&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="298.641px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is more expensive to have the content and the software from different providers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="420.359px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;The cost of the content itself is much less than the cost of running a global trade management system, and you pay for it, even when bundled in “one software package”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="298.641px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is more hassle to manage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="420.359px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the one-time setup is completed, updates will flow via certified and tested interfaces with little to no manual intervention (only in case of errors or exceptions)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="298.641px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This approach constraints customers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="420.359px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Quite the opposite, it offers the freedom to pick and choose the best provider for the requirement (compliance area, countries where the company has trade operations, industry, etc.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="298.641px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP recommends this because it is not a content provider&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="420.359px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is absolutely true! In the area of trade compliance, SAP is not a content provider. SAP strategically chose to work with external, specialized, third-party vendors. SAP focuses on delivering the necessary system logic, the workflow, and the integration with core systems and business processes&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;As eloquently stated by Christian Stadler – Chief Product Owner for SAP International Trade Management portfolio: “working with content partners such as Mendel Verlag makes our SAP solutions even more relevant, and constantly adapted to rapidly changing situations”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are interested in discovering more about SAP Global Trade Services, see &lt;A href="https://sap.com/gts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;our dedicated website&lt;/A&gt; and associated resources: videos, customer stories, and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to thank Mendel Verlag for their collaboration on this article.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/blogs/keeping-up-to-date-with-tariff-changes" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Originally published&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;on June 30, 2025 &amp;amp; reposted on this platform&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-keeping-up-to-date-with-tariff-changes/ba-p/14120668"/>
    <published>2025-07-08T07:00:00.030000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-q2-2025/ba-p/14147771</id>
    <title>What’s New in SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance: Q2 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-08T23:52:00.006000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ElyasAhmed</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1886529</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome to the Q2&amp;nbsp;2025 release highlights for &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/financial-management/cloud-iam.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance&lt;/A&gt; (IAG), where we unveil the new features designed to enhance security, streamline access governance, and empower your teams. &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE/e739622ded9b4d92964c6a0f50b5f90e/513aadc0379642feb989a4a9480da00f.html?version=CLOUDFOUNDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;This quarter’s release&lt;/A&gt; brings refined role-based risk controls, seamless system integrations, and powerful in-app analysis tools designed to keep your security posture both robust and agile. Whether you’re aiming to automate provisioning tasks or tighten privileged-access reviews, these updates deliver practical improvements you can implement today. Dive into the details below to see how each enhancement makes your day-to-day access governance faster, smarter, and more reliable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mitigation Control Assignment to Business Roles&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Mitigation controls can now be assigned directly to Business Roles through the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE/96f4b1ec2df9455492adaec07e6029f4/2cb258274e40490988a23df89883a647.html?version=CLOUDFOUNDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Role UI&lt;/A&gt; or the Mitigation Assignment application, which includes a new Business Roles–specific category. All assignments are recorded in the audit log, and risk assessments for Business Roles inherit any access-level mitigations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ElyasAhmed_0-1752011080802.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284329i7B49669A65E8C7A7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ElyasAhmed_0-1752011080802.png" alt="ElyasAhmed_0-1752011080802.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Secure Storage of Reports on a Customer-Owned Document Server&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Analyze User Access downloads can now be directed straight to your organization’s &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE/e12d8683adfa4471ac4edd40809b9038/5cd1a3b708c74efbbb047622540202b1.html?version=CLOUDFOUNDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Document Management Service (DMS)&lt;/A&gt;. Each report is stored in accordance with your retention and classification policies, removing the need for manual file handling and keeping sensitive data securely within your content repository. Keep an eye on the &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73555000100800000334&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q3%202025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;roadmap&lt;/A&gt; as this feature will be extended to include other report types in future releases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ElyasAhmed_1-1752011080815.png" style="width: 931px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284330i52BEE6D5A91F8E54/image-dimensions/931x600?v=v2" width="931" height="600" role="button" title="ElyasAhmed_1-1752011080815.png" alt="ElyasAhmed_1-1752011080815.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Access Analysis App&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE/9621f10c676c497a8355b7e36053e837/33373ebe82a84bfb9c34d037f9f0667d.html?version=CLOUDFOUNDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Access Analysis detail view&lt;/A&gt; now includes a built-in smart filter bar for both Access and Risk lists, letting you search, sort, and filter your dataset without ever leaving the interface. This one-pane experience replaces spreadsheet workarounds and speeds up investigations by keeping all controls at your fingertips.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ElyasAhmed_0-1752186737063.png" style="width: 1006px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285291i9B252C95D031CF0A/image-dimensions/1006x561?v=v2" width="1006" height="561" role="button" title="ElyasAhmed_0-1752186737063.png" alt="ElyasAhmed_0-1752186737063.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ariba Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additional Ariba user attributes stored in IdDS are automatically provisioned to newly created &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/common-data-import-and-administration-for-sap-ariba-procurement-solutions/sap-ariba-solutions-integration-with-sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-ad9fbd99ee1a49038ee9e767d9511ba1?version=2505" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Ariba accounts&lt;/A&gt;. This capability is available in both standalone Cloud Identity Access Governance and SAP Access Control via Bridge integration for IdDS customers. By sourcing attributes directly from the central IdDS, it eliminates manual updates in Ariba and ensures provisioning remains compliant with corporate standards across systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ElyasAhmed_3-1752011080835.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284331i79B43BD9C6263414/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ElyasAhmed_3-1752011080835.png" alt="ElyasAhmed_3-1752011080835.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Updated Rulesets for Concur &amp;amp; BTP Financial Applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This release adds new segregation-of-duties rulesets for Concur (Expense, Invoice, Request), SAP S/4HANA and SuccessFactors core transactions, and BTP’s advanced financial-closing processes, so you can detect and manage cross-system risks with greater precision and enforce compliance consistently across your finance and HR applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Forward Privileged Access Review Requests&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE/37bacb728d75468c92b1f1e20d5afbe2/cee1cb62728f469bb027ec60a543f499.html?version=CLOUDFOUNDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;forward functionality&lt;/A&gt; in the Privileged Access Monitoring Report enables PAM administrators to efficiently reassign log-review requests to additional reviewers without altering the current workflow stage. This feature enhances resource flexibility by allowing easy redistribution of reviewer responsibilities while maintaining the integrity of existing review processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ElyasAhmed_4-1752011080846.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/284332i5703AECB7969D671/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ElyasAhmed_4-1752011080846.png" alt="ElyasAhmed_4-1752011080846.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Looking Ahead!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Q2 2025’s release, SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance continues its march toward more intuitive, integrated, and audit-ready access management. These updates deliver targeted improvements that reduce administrative overhead and bolster compliance. Stay tuned for even more innovations next quarter as we refine workflows and expand capabilities based on your feedback.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, to view detailed feature lists, or to get started with SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance, please visit SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/financial-management/cloud-iam.html?video=2805c5b3-e57d-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Product Page&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Documentation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-q2-2025/ba-p/14147771"/>
    <published>2025-07-08T23:52:00.006000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/securing-agentic-ai-through-threat-modeling-at-sap/ba-p/14155323</id>
    <title>Securing Agentic AI Through Threat Modeling at SAP</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T18:17:00.624000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>helenoakley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/221997</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="agentic-ai.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/288025i83B23ADACD168DDC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="agentic-ai.jpg" alt="agentic-ai.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;By&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/helen-oakley/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Helen Oakley&lt;/A&gt;, Senior Director of Software and AI Security, SAP Global Security &amp;amp; Cloud Compliance&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This year, at SAP Sapphire, SAP unveiled its expanded vision for Business AI, introducing a growing network of Joule Agents that work across systems and lines of business. This marks a clear step into the era of Agentic AI – systems that can understand context, take initiative, and drive outcomes autonomously. “SAP combines the world’s most powerful suite of business applications with uniquely rich data and the latest AI innovations to create a flywheel of customer value,” &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://news.sap.com/2025/05/sap-business-ai-reimagine-how-enterprises-run/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;said CEO Christian Klein&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. While this evolution opens exciting possibilities for automation and productivity, it also introduces a new layer of complexity in how we approach security. Agentic systems challenge traditional safeguards, making it essential to identify and mitigate risks early through tailored threat modeling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At its core, threat modeling is about asking the right questions early in the development process, while the system is still being designed and built. Rather than simply looking for bugs or code flaws, it forces us to think through how a system might behave in the real world. What could go wrong if an agent’s goals are manipulated? Could someone poison its memory over time? What if an agent uses a tool in an unintended or unsafe way? How could agent-generated content be used to mislead or overload human decision-makers? What happens when agents collaborate or collide in ways that expose the system to cascading failures or manipulation?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These are not hypothetical questions. They reflect the real and emerging risks of agentic systems. The &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://genai.owasp.org/resource/agentic-ai-threats-and-mitigations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OWASP Agentic AI Threats &amp;amp; Mitigations Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is a valuable resource that brings structure to this thinking. It highlights specific threats such as memory poisoning, cascading hallucinations, privilege compromise, and agent communication poisoning. For teams building these systems, it helps provide a common vocabulary and practical examples to guide threat modeling work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To give an example of how threat modeling helps in practice, let’s take the case of goal manipulation – one of the emerging risks identified in the OWASP guide. In agentic systems, attackers don’t necessarily need to exploit traditional software flaws. Instead, they can attempt to influence an agent’s behavior over time by subtly manipulating its objectives. This might happen through indirect prompt injection, compromised data sources, or crafted tool responses. Imagine an agent responsible for prioritizing financial transactions; if adversarial inputs gradually shift its decision logic, it could start approving risky payments outside of the intended policy. In threat modeling exercises, we explore how such scenarios could play out by analyzing how the agent forms and updates its goals, how memory and feedback loops could reinforce undesired behaviors, and how downstream actions might be impacted. This helps define targeted mitigations, such as isolating goal-setting logic from external inputs, monitoring shifts in agent behavior, and adding human validation for sensitive decisions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The OWASP Agentic AI Threats &amp;amp; Mitigations Guide provides a helpful reference architecture that illustrates where these types of risks can emerge. The diagram below maps threats to key components in a typical agentic system, making it easier to visualize how threat modeling applies in practice.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="helenoakley_0-1752751657687.png" style="width: 844px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/287897iD3D301C81278E582/image-dimensions/844x449?v=v2" width="844" height="449" role="button" title="helenoakley_0-1752751657687.png" alt="helenoakley_0-1752751657687.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Image Source: OWASP Agentic AI Threats and Mitigations guide, “Threat Model Summary”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At SAP, threat modeling has long been part of our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2016/03/a248a699-627c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Secure Software Development and Operations Lifecycle (Secure SDOL)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, which is certified under ISO 27001. This framework ensures security is built into every phase of the product lifecycle, from design to operations. With Agentic AI, we are expanding our threat modeling approach to address risks that don’t typically appear in traditional application security. This includes analyzing agent memory behavior, reasoning patterns, system autonomy, human interaction points, and the dynamics of multi-agent ecosystems. The focus shifts from identifying static vulnerabilities to understanding how autonomy and learning can lead to unintended behaviors. From there, we define appropriate controls and mitigations to reduce those risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The field of Agentic AI security continues to take shape. Standards like ISO 42001 and regulations such as the EU AI Act are in development, and industry best practices are actively maturing. That’s why collaboration is essential. SAP is contributing to the conversations held with industry groups focused on these challenges, including &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://genai.owasp.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OWASP GenAI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; initiatives. We’re not just adopting ideas, we’re helping shape them, working with peers and regulators to advance the state of AI security. Our teams bring deep expertise in both enterprise security and AI systems, offering a perspective that’s helping guide how the broader ecosystem approaches agentic risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Transparency remains central to how SAP approaches product security. As we continue evolving our work with AI, we’re committed to sharing what we learn through resources like the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Trust Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Security is not a one-time effort. It is a continuous process, especially with systems as dynamic as Agentic AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Threat modeling helps us stay ahead of these evolving risks and supports the design of systems that are both capable and safe. As Agentic AI becomes more embedded in enterprise workflows, this kind of proactive thinking becomes essential.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP is proud to contribute to shaping the future of secure AI. By collaborating across the industry and applying deep expertise from our teams, we’re helping advance practical, forward-looking approaches to securing the next generation of intelligent systems.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/securing-agentic-ai-through-threat-modeling-at-sap/ba-p/14155323"/>
    <published>2025-07-17T18:17:00.624000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-ai-powered-fraud-prevention/ba-p/14130451</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: AI-Powered Fraud Prevention</title>
    <updated>2025-07-22T07:00:00.024000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_0-1750211341627.jpeg" style="width: 501px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275591i62B7B51A93E3D817/image-dimensions/501x335?v=v2" width="501" height="335" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_0-1750211341627.jpeg" alt="T_Frenehard_0-1750211341627.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we are all (too much) aware, Artificial Intelligence has changed our working habits. Sometimes for the good, such as creating a nice illustration for this blog, but also sometimes to the benefit of the dark force when used with malicious intents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the area of fraud, AI-generated deception strategies have become more and more sophisticated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While confirming during a Teams meeting with the Treasurer that a request for an urgent transfer was legitimate and was previously a sure protection against business email compromise scams, advanced audio and video deepfakes have rendered this earlier failsafe obsolete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, should we just give up and all move to just one office location so that you can get in person confirmations on sensitive transactions?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;No, of course not.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, I’d like to discuss how SAP solutions for Governance, Risk, and Compliance can be enhanced with “last mile checks” from &lt;A href="https://trustpair.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Trustpair&lt;/A&gt; to catch any fraudulent activity before it’s too late.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1733129861"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building a resilient treasury governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With ninety percent of US companies reporting being targeted by cyber fraud in 2024, and thirty-eight percent targeted by payment fraud more than 10 times over the same period as per Trustpair’s &lt;A href="https://trustpair.com/blog/fraud-report-2025-press-release/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Fraud in the Cyber Era: 2025 Fraud Trends &amp;amp; Insights&lt;/A&gt;, this is clearly not an isolated issue and it’s not going away any time soon. And just to put it into perspective, the FBI’s latest &lt;A href="https://www.ic3.gov/AnnualReport/Reports/2024_IC3Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Internet Crime Report&lt;/A&gt; mentions that business email compromise alone totalled $2,770,151,146 reported losses in 2024...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To combat this scourge, companies are investing in 3 main areas:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="200"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Training &amp;amp; Awareness&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_1-1750211341629.png" style="width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275589i5AE991BA2594D33F/image-dimensions/100x100?v=v2" width="100" height="100" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_1-1750211341629.png" alt="T_Frenehard_1-1750211341629.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="200"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authorizations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_2-1750211341630.png" style="width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275590i2217A62FFE285930/image-dimensions/100x100?v=v2" width="100" height="100" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_2-1750211341630.png" alt="T_Frenehard_2-1750211341630.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="200"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technology&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_3-1750211341631.png" style="width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275593i636386698FED152A/image-dimensions/100x100?v=v2" width="100" height="100" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_3-1750211341631.png" alt="T_Frenehard_3-1750211341631.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Training &amp;amp; Awareness and Authorizations are perfect examples of preventative control measures: by reducing the fraud attack surface, companies reduce the likelihood of a fraud succeeding.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But much like phishing attacks, if the sample is large enough and the incentives sufficiently compelling, chances are that business email compromise scams will still succeed. And when you think that findings from the &lt;A href="https://www.afponline.org/training-resources/resources/survey-research-economic-data/details/payments-fraud" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;2025 AFP® Payments Fraud and Control Survey&lt;/A&gt; indicate that only 22% of organizations were able to recover 75% or more of the funds lost due to payments fraud in 2024, more proactive measures are needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where technology plays an important role, in my opinion, to address the remaining gap and moves the needle to earlier detection – before the loss is incurred.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1536616356"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fraud prevention triangle&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Indeed, what if the treasury employee targeted already has the role and authorization to perform the transaction, had the relevant training and is aware that these types of attacks exist but has been convinced by an advanced deepfake that the request is legitimate and still processes the payment?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This where technology takes the relay and enhances human checks to provide a last dependable defense layer based on 3 angles creating the Fraud Prevention Triangle. This depiction below is not from me so all credit here goes to my colleague &lt;A href="https://it.linkedin.com/in/emanuelefumeo" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Emanuele Fumeo&lt;/A&gt; - Finance Solution Advisor at SAP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="T_Frenehard_4-1750211341642.png" style="width: 601px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275592i748DB0DDA9A72029/image-dimensions/601x251?v=v2" width="601" height="251" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_4-1750211341642.png" alt="T_Frenehard_4-1750211341642.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="601"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Anomaly detection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By screening large volumes of transactional data, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/financial-management/fraud-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Integrity Screening&lt;/A&gt; helps identify anomalous activity quickly using flexible rule sets and predictive analyses to uncover potential fraud patterns or deviations from policy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Should the attack follow a known pattern, it would be detected at this stage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="601"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Partner Screening&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Within SAP Business Integrity Screening, a dedicated module enables enterprises across all industries to screen their business partners against lists of denied persons and organizations published by governments and global institutions, thus ensuring their compliance with guidelines, regulations, and legislation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the business party involved in the transaction has already been flagged by authorities as being on a sanctioned list for instance, then this second automated step would prevent any further processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="601"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Account Validation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally, even if the attack hasn’t been detected and the party seems legitimate, Account Validation – also known as Confirmation of Payee, is the last mile check. It is the ultimate control and here, &lt;A href="https://trustpair.com/connect/sap-s4hana/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;TrustPair&lt;/A&gt; can automatically perform one-time checks for new vendors in SAP Ariba but also continuous monitoring of vendor master data and payment files in the ERP system to detect risks, abnormal amounts and duplicates. Ultimately making the entire process more secure and efficient with a last protection net validating the company identity, but also the bank account ownership against banking sources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, human factor prevention with adequate training, attack surface reduction with relevant authorizations and advanced technology detection can help ensure that even advanced fraudulent attacks are deterred – hence safeguarding the company’s financials.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And this must be done consistently across the end-to-end procure to pay process but also directly embedded within the transactional systems to ensure adequate and timely action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What about you, how does your company address the AI-powered fraud threat? I look forward to reading your thoughts and comments on this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And if you are interested in learning more about TrustPair’s solutions for SAP and how it applies a 5-layer validation with external sources, smart algorithms and complementary checks to secure the source to pay chain, then have a look &lt;A href="https://store.sap.com/dcp/en/product/display-2001011315_live_v1/trustpair-payment-fraud-prevention" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Trustpair Payment Fraud Prevention&lt;/A&gt; on the SAP Store.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-ai-powered-fraud-prevention/ba-p/14130451"/>
    <published>2025-07-22T07:00:00.024000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/navigating-governance-risk-and-compliance-grc-in-today-s-business/ba-p/14165506</id>
    <title>Navigating Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC) in Today’s Business Environment</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T10:05:01.341000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Xenia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/899</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In complex regulatory and business environments, organizations are under growing pressure to manage risks, ensure compliance, and uphold strong governance practices. Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC) is the strategic framework designed to meet these demands—helping businesses align IT with corporate objectives, manage risk proactively, and ensure compliance across an increasingly complex regulatory landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1736050190"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is GRC?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC) is a coordinated strategy for managing an organization's overall governance, enterprise risk management, and compliance with regulations. GRC provides a structured approach to decision-making by integrating risk, compliance, and performance data across departments. When effectively implemented, GRC helps reduce uncertainty, control costs, mitigate IT and security risks, and improve overall business performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1539536685"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s Driving the Need for GRC Today?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organizations face big waves in diverse, fast-moving risks—from cybersecurity threats to geopolitical disruptions—creating a need for real-time risk awareness and accountability. At the same time, global regulatory frameworks are becoming more demanding and complex, with increasing expectations around transparency and internal controls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Digital transformation of businesses introduces both opportunity and risk. Real-time processes, machine learning, robotic process automation (RPA), and increased collaboration across organizational boundaries demand new approaches to monitoring, assurance, and control. Traditional, manual GRC practices are no longer sufficient in this dynamic environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GRC and SAP’s Secure Operations Map&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP’s Secure Operations Map (SOM), GRC is embedded in four critical domains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Security Governance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Risk Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regulatory Process Compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Audit &amp;amp; Fraud Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This integration provides a foundational structure to ensure GRC principles are applied consistently across IT, finance, and operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRC in the Context of the Secure Operations Map (SOM)" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293246iD971443EBFD59761/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Xenia_0-1753775564593.png" alt="GRC in the Context of the Secure Operations Map (SOM)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;GRC in the Context of the Secure Operations Map (SOM)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1343023180"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why Do Organizations Need GRC Tools?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many organizations still manage internal controls and compliance processes manually—using spreadsheets, shared drives, emails, and physical binders. This fragmented approach leads to delays, errors, outdated information, and in some cases, missed control testing. This is especially concerning given the need for CEOs and CFOs to sign off on financial statements under personal liability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;GRC tools centralize and automate these processes, providing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A unified view of internal controls across the enterprise&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Timely and accurate compliance data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reduced risk of financial misstatements or regulatory breaches&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Greater efficiency in audits, due diligence, M&amp;amp;A, and IPO processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The objective is clear: ensure operational consistency, identify irregularities or non-compliance, and build a resilient and trustworthy organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example control - Record-to-Report Process" style="width: 961px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293248i2DCD3A2AF107F7CF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Xenia_1-1753775730382.png" alt="Example control - Record-to-Report Process" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example control - Record-to-Report Process&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1146509675"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Implementing a GRC Strategy: Key Steps&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1079078889"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Define the Purpose and Scope&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;An effective GRC strategy begins with defining its purpose and scope. Organizations need to determine whether the approach will be applied enterprise-wide or focused on high-risk areas such as finance, IT, or third-party relationships. Objectives such as improving audit readiness, meeting regulatory requirements, and reducing operational risk should be clearly defined from the outset.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-882565384"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Establish a Governance Structure&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next step is to establish a governance structure. This involves forming a cross-functional GRC steering committee with representatives from compliance, legal, IT, HR, and business leadership. Responsibility for managing risks, maintaining policies, overseeing controls, and handling reporting must be clearly assigned. A dedicated GRC lead should be appointed to coordinate implementation and ensure consistency across departments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-686051879"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Conduct a Risk and Compliance Assessment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A risk and compliance assessment follows. This assessment identifies internal and external risks, maps relevant regulations such as GDPR, HIPAA, and SOX, and evaluates existing compliance gaps. A risk register is developed to classify risks based on their likelihood and potential impact on the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-489538374"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Develop and Document Policies and Controls&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the risks identified, the organization can develop and document appropriate policies and controls. These cover areas such as data protection, access management, and anti-fraud measures. Each risk is linked to corresponding control measures, and responsibilities are assigned using a controls matrix to ensure clear traceability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-293024869"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. Select and Deploy a GRC Tool&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selecting and deploying a GRC tool is essential for effective execution. The tool should centralize risk and compliance data, support integration with existing systems such as HR, ERP, and incident reporting platforms, and automate key tasks such as alerts, workflows, and compliance tracking. A pilot rollout helps test the setup in a controlled environment before broader deployment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-96511364"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6. Train and Communicate&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Training and communication play a key role in supporting your GRC framework. Employees receive role-specific training on relevant policies and how to report concerns. Internal awareness efforts help foster a culture of compliance and accountability. Managers are provided with tools such as dashboards to monitor compliance within their teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--175233510"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7. Monitor, Audit, and Continuously Improve&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To keep the GRC strategy effective, organizations must implement ongoing monitoring, regular audits, and continuous improvement. This involves scheduled control testing, internal audits, and the use of key risk indicators to track changes and emerging issues. Reviewing incidents, near misses, and evolving regulations ensures the GRC framework remains current and effective.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Steps for Implementing a GRC Strategy" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293252i883D7DC2464F7950/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Xenia_2-1753775924369.png" alt="Steps for Implementing a GRC Strategy" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Steps for Implementing a GRC Strategy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--78344008"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tools for GRC in Hybrid SAP Landscapes: Introducing SAP Risk and Assurance Management (RAM)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s traditional GRC suite—including Process Control (PC) and Risk Management (RM)—is tightly integrated with on-premise ERP systems. However, in today’s cloud and hybrid environments, their capabilities can be limited.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enter&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Risk and Assurance Management (RAM)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: a modern GRC platform designed for hybrid landscapes, including S/4HANA Cloud (both Public and Private Editions). SAP RAM enables organizations to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Leverage a single platform for multiple use cases across the enterprise&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Turn GRC from a compliance burden into a strategic differentiator&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Focus resources on high-impact risks, processes, and regulations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Continuously monitor control performance using real-time business data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Improve compliance and control effectiveness while reducing operational costs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By automating labor-intensive tasks like control testing, RAM not only enhances assurance quality but also frees up internal audit and compliance teams to focus on what matters most.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Example Process Flow in RAM" style="width: 981px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/293253iADF2658BACAF2FFB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Xenia_3-1753775977456.png" alt="Example Process Flow in RAM" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Example Process Flow in RAM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--274857513"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;GRC is no longer just a back-office function—it has become a critical enabler of strategic agility, operational resilience, and trust in the digital age. With a well-defined strategy, clear governance structure, and tools like SAP Risk and Assurance Management, organizations can shift from reactive compliance to proactive risk management and business optimization. As part of this evolution, integrating GRC with security monitoring is essential. Giving responsible teams access to timely and accurate security information strengthens their ability to detect potential threats and respond effectively. Auditing and monitoring tools further enhance this by measuring the success of GRC efforts and highlighting areas for improvement. In the next blog post, we’ll explore how SAP supports real-time security monitoring and auditing—turning insight into action to improve enterprise security and compliance.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/navigating-governance-risk-and-compliance-grc-in-today-s-business/ba-p/14165506"/>
    <published>2025-07-29T10:05:01.341000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/linda-bettenhausen/ba-p/14168705</id>
    <title>Linda Bettenhausen</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T22:18:36.108000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanieMarley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1437516" target="_self"&gt;Linda&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Germany&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;SAP Mentor since 2025&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Follow Linda on &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/linda-bettenhausen-785868207/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Linda Bettenhausen headshot.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/294843i04AEE02CB2A492F6/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Linda Bettenhausen headshot.jpg" alt="Linda Bettenhausen headshot.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Linda is an expert in accounting topics. During her career she collected very different experiences. Starting in a big corporation in 2013 she dealt with everyday accounting business which still supports her understanding of the customer perspective and their needs nowadays. 2019 she changed to one of the bigger German consulting companies and took over different roles in several S/4HANA implementation projects. Besides this she became involved to support SAP careers and Women in Tech quite early. Since spring 2024 she changed to a smaller consulting company facing to built up the accounting team and the expertise in this area with an approach of a more customer-centric and sustainable consulting to meet the clients on eye-level and bringing real benefit to them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Topics of interest:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Accounting, Finance, Controlling, Governance, Planning, Financial Supply Chain Management&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Linda, what inspired you to become an SAP Mentor?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="handshake .png" style="width: 68px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52491i8E9D2FFB3C7BC293/image-dimensions/68x68?v=v2" width="68" height="68" role="button" title="handshake .png" alt="handshake .png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;Colleagues from my network suggested the SAP mentor nomination to me. I frequently use to bring up potential topics to my customers as I am hugely interested in bringing a real benefit to them. For me, the role as a mentor can gather the next stage as I can bring the feedback and user experiences from the customers back to SAP. I believe that this combination improves both the products and the consulting services that all of us provide to our clients.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What advice would like to share with other SAP community members?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" style="width: 65px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52495i64D82195EFF8CCB9/image-dimensions/65x65?v=v2" width="65" height="65" role="button" title="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;I strongly recommend staying in touch with your customers. Listen to them and support them in their activities by bringing up creative ideas and solution approaches. Even if you do not get a deal done today, this strengthens your relationship by building mutual trust. Furthermore, I can give the advice to closely work together with junior consultants within your organization. They are highly motivated and thankful to trustworthy mentors. It is not just about the professional and technical expertise. It is also about the soft factors such as communication, organization, taking care, how to push things forward etc. When all of this comes together, you will build up that kind of consultants that we need for the future.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/linda-bettenhausen/ba-p/14168705"/>
    <published>2025-07-31T22:18:36.108000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/key-technical-updates-for-sap-commerce-cloud/ba-p/14171239</id>
    <title>Key Technical Updates for SAP Commerce Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-08-11T10:44:43.496000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PhilippeS</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/16331</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The SAP Commerce Cloud 2211 continuous innovation release model offers substantial benefits to our customers by ensuring faster access to the latest features, enhancements, and security updates. This approach allows for seamless and frequent updates, minimizing disruptions while maintaining a robust and high-performing e-commerce platform. Our customers can take advantage of new innovations quickly, stay ahead of market demands, and maintain competitive agility, all while reducing the risk associated with traditional major version cycles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consider the following key aspects when working with SAP technology:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stay current with SAP Commerce Cloud &lt;SPAN&gt;Update Releases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Review all features, services, and updates (e.g. Solr, Composable Storefront)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#1 – Stay Current with SAP Commerce Cloud &lt;SPAN&gt;Update Releases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Staying up to date with SAP Commerce Cloud 2211 and Composable Storefront guarantees that our customers remain current with the latest enhancements, software updates, and bug fixes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To assist our customers to prepare for upcoming changes and implementations, SAP publishes the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/79f24c67f70645bfaf5ae95df7813e72?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Notification of Key Technical Updates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on&lt;/SPAN&gt; the SAP Help Portal. This &lt;SPAN&gt;continuously updated &lt;/SPAN&gt;documentation highlights when changes are available, including features and services that offer an adoption window. SAP is committed to supporting your planning strategies, so we encourage you to bookmark this page and check it frequently to stay current with the latest updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For Commerce Cloud:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;We are pleased to announce the availability of the Framework Update with the September 2025 update release! Gain access to the latest functionality provided by Java 21 and Spring 6, while running the most secure and high-performance platform.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP recommends you an early adoption the Framework Update, before end of June 2026, when the last release on the Java 17 will reach end of the support coverage, and latest, before the end of August 2026, when creating new builds on Java 17 releases will no longer be allowed. This update includes the removal of deprecated extensions and modules.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This &lt;/STRONG&gt;upcoming quarter the Framework Update should have the highest impact on your planning strategy. Carefully read the information below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Top considerations for the upcoming quarter:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/75d4c3895cb346008545900bffe851ce/8ed937a519384600ae6105427e63466a.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Framework Update (JDK 21, Spring 6)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dependencies of Framework Update&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/251a1313585a498eb998c2f974f4f338/fb5dd1554b8247be98fe3cc728d09ea4.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=v2211&amp;amp;parentHref=%2Fwhats-new%2F79f24c67f70645bfaf5ae95df7813e72%3Flocale%3Den-US&amp;amp;parentName=Notification%20of%20Key%20Technical%20Updates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OAuth replacement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; - The existing OAuth capability has been rebuilt on current Spring libraries.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/251a1313585a498eb998c2f974f4f338/3752d0fddfde4a9bbe718d15fe63e845.html?version=v2211&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;parentHref=https%3A%2F%2Fhelp.sap.com%2Fwhats-new%2F79f24c67f70645bfaf5ae95df7813e72%3Flocale%3Den-US&amp;amp;parentName=Notification%20of%20Key%20Technical%20Updates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Drools Update&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; - The previous Drools version 8.44.0.Final is incompatible with Spring 6, as the Java EE API has been upgraded to the Jakarta EE API in Spring 6.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Deprecation of Extensions with the Framework Update&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP has removed several extensions from Commerce Cloud and from the Integration Extension Pack due to incompatibilities with the newest versions of Java and the Spring framework. Replacement solutions already exist for each use case and are documented on the SAP Help Portal.&amp;nbsp;These deprecated extensions are highlighted on the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/79f24c67f70645bfaf5ae95df7813e72?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Technical Updates help page&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. Use &lt;SPAN&gt;the&lt;/SPAN&gt; "&lt;EM&gt;Production Version&lt;/EM&gt;" filter &lt;EM&gt;for September 2025 &lt;/EM&gt;for a complete overview.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/251a1313585a498eb998c2f974f4f338/58a4ff4e9d304a04a5ae809a024da902.html?version=v2211&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;parentHref=https%3A%2F%2Fhelp.sap.com%2Fwhats-new%2F79f24c67f70645bfaf5ae95df7813e72%3Flocale%3Den-US&amp;amp;parentName=Notification%20of%20Key%20Technical%20Updates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deletion of Deprecated Cockpit Extensions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/251a1313585a498eb998c2f974f4f338/a1ed7c5752144c97baaa375c0d525731.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;parentHref=/whats-new/79f24c67f70645bfaf5ae95df7813e72?locale=en-US&amp;amp;parentName=Notification+of+Key+Technical+Updates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deletion of Deprecated amazoncloud Extension&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/251a1313585a498eb998c2f974f4f338/2e54414941f046018dd822b473822187.html?version=v2211&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;parentHref=https%3A%2F%2Fhelp.sap.com%2Fwhats-new%2F79f24c67f70645bfaf5ae95df7813e72%3Flocale%3Den-US&amp;amp;parentName=Notification%20of%20Key%20Technical%20Updates%20%7C%20SAP%20Help%20Portal" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Deletion of Deprecated Sales Order Simulation Extensions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PRODUCTS/251a1313585a498eb998c2f974f4f338/5800ae19d0cd4e6fb57566503b0bf8f1.html?version=v2211&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;parentHref=https%3A%2F%2Fhelp.sap.com%2Fwhats-new%2F79f24c67f70645bfaf5ae95df7813e72%3Flocale%3Den-US&amp;amp;parentName=Notification%20of%20Key%20Technical%20Updates%20%7C%20SAP%20Help%20Portal" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Deletion of Deprecated Customer Order Sourcing Extensions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;See the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/251a1313585a498eb998c2f974f4f338/65280015b9a3413a91d71e1c6c774e2a.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deletion of Synchronous Order Management&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; as well as the &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3348156" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP For Me Note&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The removal of the CMS Cockpit and SmartEdit is further documented here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap.sharepoint.com/:v:/t/CXProductMarketing/EU8oDhtnXoNOroKeD4GEhDUBy-JkaoYWhZGBZ46ahy-IUA?e=UmdwQi" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Migrating from CMS Cockpit to SmartEdit_Solution Overview_External_V4.mp4&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/e1391e5265574bfbb56ca4c0573ba1dc/a4b1ea8d8a7249d28ec4aa0e58ff5518.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Getting Started with SmartEdit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/e1391e5265574bfbb56ca4c0573ba1dc/c554253f5c8b4ead95f3fe76882003b6.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SmartEdit Feature Parity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/e1391e5265574bfbb56ca4c0573ba1dc/05afb9877f884026ac9a98433f4be8bf.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Technical Overview of SmartEdit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, refer to the following documentation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/pdf/asset/preview/cpkSQgG?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1209298" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Framework Update – Detailed Overview&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/251a1313585a498eb998c2f974f4f338/8f27d88c881f44988000788362909617.html?parentHref=/whats-new/79f24c67f70645bfaf5ae95df7813e72?locale=en-US&amp;amp;parentName=Notification+of+Key+Technical+Updates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Framework Update&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2022/11/ec08a34d-507e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Commerce Cloud Release Ready Kit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/75d4c3895cb346008545900bffe851ce/cba026d2b36c4ab18f89525df92cc815.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;List of supported SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Commerce Cloud releases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For instructions on enabling new features and functionality, see:&amp;nbsp;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/bbcd2978537e4ae298479557c0b8fdbd/df77dd9dc33749d2a185c7caa771c206.html?parentHref=%2Fwhats-new%2F3d7190d2aab14c7d92f918cc3fa9a024%3Fstate%3DPRODUCTION%26version%3Dv2211&amp;amp;parentName=What%27s%20New%20in%20SAP%20Commerce%20Cloud%20in%20the%20Public%20Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enabling SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the &lt;EM&gt;Upgrading SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/EM&gt; guide&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_COMPOSABLE_STOREFRONT/cfcf687ce2544bba9799aa6c8314ecd0/05fdc6bf78dd47c39f2f3d008c2e8c42.html#loio2a16ab34af6d49878004afea963c37e3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feature Flags&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; in the Composable Storefront documentation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For Composable Storefront:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;New releases of Composable Storefront are fully tested and support the current 2211 backend releases. However, SAP does not support using Composable Storefront with older backends. Review the list of supported Composable Storefront releases below to ensure that you are on a storefront version that SAP does support and runs smoothly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To implement the Framework Update, customers must update to the latest version of Composable Storefront. For additional flexibility SAP Commerce Cloud will extend the validity period of Composable Storefront on the current framework (JDK 17).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, building Composable Storefront and SSR hosting is only supported with the latest supported versions of Node.js, provided by the Cloud Portal.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, refer to the following documentation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_COMPOSABLE_STOREFRONT/6c7b98dbe68f4a508cac17a207182f4c/ba62c2c708ec4751a2612a512177419b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;List of supported Composable Storefront releases; includes supported backends&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_COMPOSABLE_STOREFRONT/6c7b98dbe68f4a508cac17a207182f4c/0ec25f325c9541be86fbf85d8a45c041.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Angular and Node.js dependencies matrix&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#2 - Review all &lt;SPAN&gt;C&lt;/SPAN&gt;omponents&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The ecosystem surrounding an SAP Commerce Cloud installation includes many components. You must maintain these components to stay compatible with the SAP Commerce Cloud releases. SAP has made significant efforts to align the releases of components, such as &lt;SPAN&gt;Composable Storefront&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An important component of Commerce Cloud is &lt;STRONG&gt;Solr&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Be sure to plan your activities according to the following &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/aa417173fe4a4ba5a473c93eb730a417/b6ffebf478cf4c41acf446a572ecbd8b.html?locale=en-US#loioea87369089a142a7b90623f86cc9c9f5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solr Version Validity Policy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; and update your installation of Solr before the expiration date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Supported versions of Solr are v9.7 and v9.8. Customers running v9.7 must update to 9.8 before February 2026. &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, refer to the following documentation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/0263e32b0d2a4010afed87b8de145092/e42dd5ec84084935ac910812a2c7e4d3.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=v2211" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Minor Solr Version Validity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/0263e32b0d2a4010afed87b8de145092/b70eefc75c6a45b5aa00de55b8989ee1.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=v2211" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Upgrading to Solr 9.x&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you would like to remove this dependency and adopt a cloud-native search and AI innovations immediately, please consider migrating to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Search Service&lt;/STRONG&gt; and sign-up to the &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3829" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Early Adopter Care Program&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Notifications&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To receive important notifications about your Commerce Cloud subscription, visit the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/content/s4m/help/systems/getnotified.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Support portal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and subscribe to the &lt;EM&gt;SAP Cloud System Notification Subscription&lt;/EM&gt; (CSNS) service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What's New?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Details about what’s available now and what you can expect in upcoming releases, can be found here:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For Commerce Cloud 2211:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/10886447b5174d2a921d48926f30eb6a/cc9655536f8044419f1ca36977b524c7.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;About SAP Commerce Cloud Release 2211&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/3d7190d2aab14c7d92f918cc3fa9a024?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s New in SAP Commerce Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;PRODUCT=089E017A62AB1EDA94C15F5EDB33E0E1#Q2%202023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Commerce Cloud Product Road Map&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/79f24c67f70645bfaf5ae95df7813e72?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Notification of Key Technical Updates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For Composable Storefront:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_COMPOSABLE_STOREFRONT/6c7b98dbe68f4a508cac17a207182f4c/c9dcbd1ca0ec4219ac3c51b29c44625e.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;About Composable Storefront&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/ebff91ce0df54e59a849aafb00118a43" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s New in Composable Storefront&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;PRODUCT=089E017A62AB1EDA94C15F5EDB33E0E1#Q2%202023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Commerce Cloud Product Road Map&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For any &lt;SPAN&gt;additional&lt;/SPAN&gt; questions, don’t hesitate to&amp;nbsp;contact your account team.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/key-technical-updates-for-sap-commerce-cloud/ba-p/14171239"/>
    <published>2025-08-11T10:44:43.496000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/what-s-next-for-sap-access-control-12-0/ba-p/14171491</id>
    <title>What’s Next for SAP Access Control 12.0?</title>
    <updated>2025-08-11T12:09:08.939000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>santhosha_dasari</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/750626</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What’s Next for SAP Access Control 12.0? &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;This is one of the common questions to most of the Organizations, Leaders, IT Directors, Managers, SMEs, Consultants and Vendors who are currently using IAM solution - SAP Access Control 12.0 on any Data Base (Non-HANA DB or HANA DB).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First let’s explore the possible applicable scenarios of the Organizations who are using SAP GRC Access Control 12.0 solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hub Model on HANA DB: &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP GRC Access Control 12.0 on standalone SAP NetWeaver system on HANA Database, connected side-by-side with SAP S/4HANA, ECC, ECP, SuccessFactors or other ABAP systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hub Model on Non-HANA DB: &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP GRC Access Control 12.0 on standalone SAP NetWeaver system on Oracle, MYSQL or another non-HANA database and connected side-by-side with SAP S/4HANA, ECC, SAP ECP, SuccessFactors or other ABAP systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded Model on HANA DB: &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP GRC Access Control 12.0 installed on business systems (SAP S/4HANA or SAP ECC etc.) running on HANA database.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Embedded Model on Non-HANA DB: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Embedded Model - SAP GRC Access Control 12.0 installed on business systems (SAP ECC, etc.) running on a non-HANA database.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;As SAP continues its strategic pivot toward cloud-first solutions, many Organizations using&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;On-Prem SAP Access Control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;are asking:&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;What’s next?&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;With SAP Access Control 12.0 nearing the end of its innovation cycle and the emergence of new GRC platforms, it’s time to evaluate the future roadmap and available options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has announced that it will&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;sunset innovation for GRC 12.0&lt;/STRONG&gt;, however SAP Access Control and GRC solutions for SAP are NOT end-of-life! SAP is actively developing a&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;next-generation GRC platform&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP GRC Edition for SAP HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;, expected in&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q1 2026&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Along with SAP also has cloud-based product called &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance (IAG).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, the existing SAP Access Control 12.0 mainstream support ends by 2027 and extended support ends by 2030.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, refer to &lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/pam" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Product Availability Matrix &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For compatibility of SAP Access Control 12.0 with all the target on-premise SAP Applications, please refer to KBA: &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/1352498" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;1352498 - Support Pack Numbering - GRC Access Control&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let’s explore the possible upgrade/migrate/future roadmap options in SAP for existing Organizations who are using SAP Access Control 12.0 solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1736853860"&gt;Option 1: Upgrade to SAP GRC for HANA 2026&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP GRC for HANA 2026 is a new version (not a new product) for any SAP GRC on HANA Organizations. This 2026 release is planned for both on-premises and private cloud deployments. Organizations wanting to stay on-prem or private cloud with long-term GRC needs and have existing /future needs of other SAP GRC modules like SAP Process Control or SAP Risk Management can upgrade to this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="santhosha_dasari_0-1754360922146.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/296284iB7BD1F61E1CA97A4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="santhosha_dasari_0-1754360922146.png" alt="santhosha_dasari_0-1754360922146.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Image Source: SAP&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more information, refer to&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/9edb299a36224c6b8f7593287a37dd41/12.0.25/en-US/SAP%20GRC%20FOR%20HANA,%202026%20_PAM.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP GRC FOR HANA, 2026* (*current working title)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/understanding-sap-s-product-strategy-for-governance-risk-and-compliance-grc/ba-p/14053197" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understanding SAP’s Product Strategy for Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC) Solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP GRC for HANA 2026 requires below 2 prerequisites&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP NetWeaver should be minimum SAP S/4HANA Foundation. S/4HANA Foundation is just an upgraded version for SAP NetWeaver. This is not SAP S/4HANA full version. Organizations who are using SAP Fiori 2.0 would have already migrated their SAP NetWeaver to SAP S/4HANA Foundation. Incase if you are having lower version of GRC Support pack or still on Fiori 1.0 or using SAP NetWeaver as a base component for SAP GRC, then this is a mandatory step.&amp;nbsp; In case for an Embedded GRC model, SAP GRC for HANA 2026 can be installed on S4Core.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Databased as HANA DB: As HANA 2026 only supports SAP HANA DB, Organizations are forced to migrate their Non-HANA Database to HANA DB.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Organizations can choose the “Hub Model” or “Embedded Model” for their SAP GRC for HANA 2026 upgrade/migration. &amp;nbsp;In case if an existing Hub Model setup customer wants to move to Embedded model, it is like a new implementation of SAP GRC for HANA 2026 but can reuse existing GRC design.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Migrate to SAP GRC for HANA 2026 from SAP GRC Access Control 12.0?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the above prerequisites are complete, SAP Access Control 12.0 can be upgraded to SAP GRC for HANA 2026 release as part of their standard maintenance program, meaning no new SKU or additional purchase is required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;End-of-maintenance (EOM) dates for the 2026 version will be updated to align with HANA EOM dates, extending support until 2040.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1540340355"&gt;Option 2: Migrate to SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance (IAG) – Standard Edition&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance (IAG), a cloud-based solution designed to manage and govern user access across SAP and non-SAP systems. It's part of SAP’s broader GRC (Governance, Risk, and Compliance) strategy and is hosted on the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP). It can be considered as cloud Access Control in layman terms. It is best for Cloud-first organizations or those adopting SAP S/4HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is ideal for the customer who are looking for a standalone cloud governance solution with full lifecycle capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;In case if an existing SAP GRC Access Control 12.0 customer wants to move to Cloud IAG solution, it is like a new implementation of SAP Cloud IAG with reference to existing GRC design. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;With SAP Cloud IAG Standard Edition, customer can integrate to Cloud system like SAP S/4HANA Public cloud, SAP SuccessFactors, SAP Ariba etc. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;With Cloud Connector, custom can integrate to On-Prem system like SAP S/4HANA (On-Prem), SAP ECC and other On-Prem systems.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Similar Access Control features, SAP Cloud IAG offers below features:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Real-time insights into user access to detect violations and risks. This is like Access Risk Analysis (ARA).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role Design&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Create and optimize business roles for cloud and on-premises systems. This is like Business Role Management (BRM)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access Request&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Self-service access provisioning for users across systems. This is like Access Request Management (ARM).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access Certification&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Periodic reviews and certifications of user access. This is like User Access Review (UAR) or other certifications reviews.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Privileged Access Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Emergency access handling and monitoring for sensitive operations. This is like Emergency Access Management (EAM).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Will be creating a new blog on “SAP &lt;/EM&gt;Cloud Identity Access Governance (IAG) with different options, Pros and Cons, possible options&lt;EM&gt;”, stay tuned for this.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1343826850"&gt;Option 3: Stay on SAP Access Control 12.0 (Short-Term)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Staying on SAP Access Control 12.0 isn’t a long-term strategy, but it’s a valid short-term option for organizations that need more time to prepare. &amp;nbsp;As SAP prepares to sunset support for Access Control 12.0 by December 31, 2027 (extended support runs until 2030), many Organizations are evaluating their next move. While cloud-first strategies and the upcoming SAP GRC Edition for HANA (2026) are gaining momentum, some organizations may choose to stay on Access Control 12.0—at least for now so Organizations can get more time for budgeting, complex landscape planning, or team training.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For organizations with complex landscapes, regulatory constraints, or budgetary limitations, staying on Access Control 12.0 offers a stable, compliant, and familiar environment while they prepare for the future. Meanwhile, Organizations can prepare internal teams for the shift to SAP GRC for HANA or SAP Cloud IAG.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;In case if an existing SAP GRC Access Control 12.0 customer wants to connect to Cloud systems using Access Control 12.0, SAP Cloud IAG – Integration Edition can be used,&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud IAG – Integration Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a specialized deployment model designed to &lt;STRONG&gt;extend SAP Access Control (on-premise)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to manage access governance for &lt;STRONG&gt;cloud applications&lt;/STRONG&gt; also like SAP S/4HANA Cloud, Ariba, SAP SuccessFactors etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It uses the &lt;STRONG&gt;IAG Bridge&lt;/STRONG&gt; to connect your existing Access Control system to SAP Cloud IAG, enabling centralized governance across hybrid landscapes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Like SAP Cloud IAG standard edition, SAP Cloud IAG Integration offers Access Control features, however this has limited features than Standard Edition. For example, PAM and Access Certification features are available with Integration Edition. Use IAG Bridge now, then migrate to unified GRC 2026 platform for future-proofing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="28"&gt;&lt;P&gt;#&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="187"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="133"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommended Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="253"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It Works &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="28"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="187"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Long-term on-prem/private-cloud GRC modernization&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="133"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP GRC for HANA 2026&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="253"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unified, AI-powered platform; support to 2040&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="28"&gt;&lt;P&gt;2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="187"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cloud-first strategy (SAP RISE, SuccessFactors, Ariba, etc.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="133"&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud IAG – Standard Edition&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="253"&gt;&lt;P&gt;End-to-end cloud governance with full lifecycle capabilities&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="28"&gt;&lt;P&gt;3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="187"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using SAP Access Control 12.0. Hybrid landscape with both cloud and on-premises systems&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="133"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Short-term: IAG Integration Edition&lt;BR /&gt;Long-term: GRC for HANA 2026&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="253"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Leverage current investment, add cloud governance, buy time&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1147313345"&gt;Summary&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 1: Upgrade to SAP GRC for HANA 2026&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Ideal for on-premise or private-cloud customers using multiple GRC modules. Also with complex landscape, heavy customization and workflows. Provides a unified, AI-powered platform on SAP HANA with support extended to 2040.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 2: Migrate to SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance (IAG)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Suits cloud-first organizations on RISE, S/4HANA Cloud, SuccessFactors, Ariba, or other BTP scenarios. Delivers full lifecycle access governance across SAP and non-SAP systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 3: Stay on SAP Access Control 12.0 (Short-Term)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Gives organizations extra time for budgeting, complex landscape planning, and team training. Pair Access Control 12.0 with IAG Integration Edition and the IAG Bridge for hybrid visibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-950799840"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choosing the right path from SAP Access Control 12.0 depends on your organization’s strategy, timeline, and risk profile. If you’re committed to on-premise GRC and need long-term stability, upgrading to GRC for HANA 2026 keeps you covered through 2040. For those accelerating cloud adoption, migrating to SAP Cloud IAG delivers a scalable, unified governance experience with less customization options than on-premise. And if you need breathing room to prepare, extending Access Control 12.0 in the short term—combined with IAG Integration—offers continuity without sacrificing compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whichever route you take, start by mapping your current landscape, aligning stakeholders on priorities, and building a clear project roadmap. Weigh the long-term benefits against immediate constraints to make an informed decision that drives both security and innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What option works best for your organization? Tell us your GRC challenge in the comments. Like this post if it helped and subscribe for more SAP GRC blogs, news, tips!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Access+Control/pd-p/01200615320800000796" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="380-1"&gt;SAP Access Control&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Access+Control+for+SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/73554900100800000773" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="381-1"&gt;SAP Access Control for SAP S/4HANA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Cloud+Identity+Access+Governance/pd-p/73555000100800000334" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="480-1"&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/what-s-next-for-sap-access-control-12-0/ba-p/14171491"/>
    <published>2025-08-11T12:09:08.939000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/compliance-in-the-age-of-ai-how-sap-grc-s-regulatory-insights-is-redefining/ba-p/14180565</id>
    <title>Compliance in the Age of AI: How SAP GRC’s Regulatory Insights is Redefining Risk Management</title>
    <updated>2025-08-14T11:33:52.754000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>_CK_</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1656402</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Silent Storm of Non-Compliance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s 7:15 AM and Priya Nair, Chief Compliance Officer (CCO) at a global pharmaceutical giant, receives a regulatory update from the European Medicines Agency. She sends it to her team, already anticipating a flurry of urgent responses and braces herself for another fire drill.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;New regulations mean changes to internal controls. This means hundreds of person-hours reviewing documents, comparing frameworks, updating controls, notifying teams, and preparing for audits. All this—while staying ahead of business goals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For Priya, and thousands like her, this is not a once-in-a-while event. This is &lt;STRONG&gt;daily life&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s hyper-regulated environment, where &lt;STRONG&gt;250+ regulatory change events&lt;/STRONG&gt; occur each day, &lt;STRONG&gt;manual compliance processes are no longer sustainable&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter: &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Process Control with Regulatory Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a breakthrough SAP GRC innovation built on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, powered by &lt;STRONG&gt;AI and Generative AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;, that’s helping professionals like Priya flip the compliance narrative from reactive to proactive—and from cost-center to competitive edge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Compliance Conundrum: A Modern Enterprise Challenge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today’s enterprises are dealing with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Constantly evolving regulations (think GDPR, SOX, NIST, COBIT, MaRisk…)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Siloed compliance efforts across business units&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inconsistent control documentation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Audit fatigue&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fear of non-compliance fines, loss of reputation, and erosion of stakeholder trust&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manual processes for control mapping, documents handling is error prone, cost intensive and increases &lt;STRONG&gt;risks as well as&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;burnouts&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Game Changer: SAP Process Control with Regulatory Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let’s zoom into the innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the heart of this solution lies the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Process Control&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Regulatory Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt; service—on BTP, an AI-powered application designed to &lt;STRONG&gt;interpret&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;extract, compare and map control requirements&lt;/STRONG&gt; across evolving regulatory documents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="_CK__0-1755162733019.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300772i8CF6F25960C032D6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="_CK__0-1755162733019.png" alt="_CK__0-1755162733019.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s break it down through personas in a real-world narrative.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Priya Nair – Chief Compliance Officer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pain Point&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Challenged and facing mounting pressure by increasingly complex regulatory landscape.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;AI-powered Regulatory Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Priya’s team can now &lt;STRONG&gt;automatically extract control requirements&lt;/STRONG&gt; from large regulatory documents using NLP and machine learning. These are uploaded through the &lt;STRONG&gt;Import Control Requirements App&lt;/STRONG&gt; into SAP Process Control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Hours of manual reading and interpretation reduced to minutes. Regulations are now available in GRC system as meaningful control definitions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“It’s like having a legal expert and a data analyst rolled into one AI assistant”&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;, Priya says.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Carlos Menendez – Control Owner in Finance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pain Point&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Updating internal controls with every regulatory change&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="_CK__6-1755163656693.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300786i0C3A4D522C3C7C91/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="_CK__6-1755163656693.png" alt="_CK__6-1755163656693.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Control Requirements App&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Carlos can quickly create or update internal controls—both centrally and locally—linked to his business processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Faster response to regulatory change. Controls are tracked, assigned, and monitored periodically.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“I no longer rely on spreadsheets and emails—I now have a control cockpit”&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;, Carlos shares.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Jennifer Shen – Internal Auditor&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pain Point&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Identifying what changed in a regulation&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="_CK__3-1755162804841.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300774i9A7415799517BF86/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="_CK__3-1755162804841.png" alt="_CK__3-1755162804841.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;Delta Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;, Jennifer compares two versions of a regulatory framework and instantly sees what’s added, removed, or modified.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Audit readiness improves drastically. Summary reports help prioritize control updates and decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;“What took days of manual review now takes seconds”&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;, she smiles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Frameworks Are Supported?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently live within SAP SE environments, the solution supports:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;C5&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;COBIT&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;FitSM&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GHB&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;MaRisk&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;NIST&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SOX&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="_CK__4-1755162804853.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300778iC05F98C66A594D8C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="_CK__4-1755162804853.png" alt="_CK__4-1755162804853.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And this is just a beginning…&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Coming Next (Q3–Q4 2025)?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Control Gap Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Automatically detect gaps between existing controls and new regulations.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Control Coverage Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Suggest additional controls using Gen AI, ensuring better control coverage.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process Orchestration&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Enhanced sync between SAP Process Control and Regulatory Insights, helping drive resilience.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Benefits: From Cost Center to Strategic Advantage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Significant Cost Savings&lt;/STRONG&gt;: With ~250 regulatory change events a day, savings range between &lt;STRONG&gt;USD 50K to USD 250K&lt;/STRONG&gt; just from automation and reduced manual effort.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Audit Readiness&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Continuous delta analysis means controls are always audit-ready.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smarter Risk Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Proactively mitigate non-compliance risks and enhance stakeholder trust.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strategic Focus&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Free up experts from mundane tasks—redirect efforts toward innovation and strategic resilience.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion: Turning Compliance Into Competitive Advantage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In a world where trust is the currency of business, non-compliance is not an option.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Process Control with Regulatory Insights is not just another GRC tool—it’s a &lt;STRONG&gt;strategic partner&lt;/STRONG&gt; for organizations that want to stay compliant, agile, and ahead of change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="_CK__5-1755163542595.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300783iE1FDC510A4F462D1/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="_CK__5-1755163542595.png" alt="_CK__5-1755163542595.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By leveraging &lt;STRONG&gt;AI and Gen AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;, it automates the interpretation of complex regulatory language, links it to enterprise controls, and ensures your business is &lt;STRONG&gt;always one step ahead&lt;/STRONG&gt; of regulators.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For CCOs like Priya, Control Owners like Carlos, and Auditors like Jennifer,&amp;nbsp; it is not just about managing risks - it is about enabling &lt;STRONG&gt;trusted growth&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automate regulatory interpretation and control mapping&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Instantly compare evolving regulations and identify control changes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save costs and person-hours through AI-powered insights&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Build resilient and audit-ready internal control environments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Future-proof compliance strategy with AI-led innovation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Want to see how SAP GRC with Regulatory Insights can transform your compliance posture?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Chandan Kalra, Director, GRC, Product Engineering | Srinath Ganesan, Director, Finance&amp;nbsp; &amp;amp; Risk&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/compliance-in-the-age-of-ai-how-sap-grc-s-regulatory-insights-is-redefining/ba-p/14180565"/>
    <published>2025-08-14T11:33:52.754000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-2506-adoption-campaign-series-a/ba-p/14184275</id>
    <title>SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance: 2506 Adoption Campaign Series – A Reflective Recap</title>
    <updated>2025-08-19T18:48:08.208000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ElyasAhmed</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1886529</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Over the past few weeks, we have had the pleasure of connecting with customers through our &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance (IAG) Adoption Campaign Series&lt;/STRONG&gt;. These sessions brought together our community to share best practices, explore new capabilities, and maximize the value of IAG in enabling secure, compliant, and efficient access governance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Look Back at the Series&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Throughout the campaign, we hosted targeted feature adoption sessions and deep dives, designed to equip participants with both strategic insights and practical know-how. These weren’t just presentations; they were conversations, enriched by your questions, feedback, and shared experiences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your engagement helped shape the discussions and even influenced future considerations for enhancements, reinforcing the collaborative nature of ourSAP Cloud Identity Access Governance community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction &amp;amp; Solution Overview (6/18/2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We began with a foundational overview of why identity governance remains a critical pillar for today’s enterprises. The session explored SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance’s role in streamlining access management, reducing risk, and supporting compliance through design, automated workflows, and actionable insights.&lt;BR /&gt;We showcased a live demo, walked through key workflows, and shared real-world examples of how organizations are using SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance to boost efficiency and security.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature Set Adoption: Access Analysis (7/2/2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session highlighted how Access Analysis delivers deep visibility into user permissions, revealing hidden risks and unusual access patterns. Attendees learned how data-driven analysis strengthens risk assessments and guides remediation strategies.&lt;BR /&gt;The discussion emphasized how improved visibility leads to proactive governance, allowing organizations to act before risks become incidents.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature Set Adoption: Privileged Access Management (7/9/2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We explored the importance of centralizing privileged account management to minimize insider threats and maintain compliance. The session demonstrated howSAP Cloud Identity Access Governance unifies privileged access controls without adding complexity, increasing transparency, and enhancing governance over sensitive permissions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature Set Adoption: Access Request (7/16/2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session focused on streamlining approval workflows through Access Request. Attendees saw how automation eliminates bottlenecks, accelerates access provisioning, and boosts productivity while ensuring compliance.&lt;BR /&gt;We discussed how efficient request handling directly impacts operational agility and user satisfaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature Set Adoption: User Certification (7/23/2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We examined the importance of User Certification campaigns in maintaining governance, ensuring audit readiness, and building trust within the organization. The session demonstrated how IAG automates and simplifies these campaigns, cutting down on manual effort.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feature Set Adoption: Business Role Management (7/30/2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This session provided best practices for creating and managing business roles that align with organizational needs while reducing permission sprawl. We showcased how IAG’s role-based approach supports scalability and enforces least-privilege principles as the organization evolves.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration: Access Control &amp;amp; CIAG Integration (8/6/2025)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We concluded with a deep dive into hybrid governance strategies, demonstrating how SAP Access Control andSAP Cloud Identity Access Governance can work together for consistent policy enforcement across cloud and on-premise environments. The session covered data synchronization, risk sharing, and role management in integrated scenarios, offering a low-disruption pathway to cloud adoption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resources&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are key resources to help you continue exploring and optimizing SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://itsm.services.sap/now/nav/ui/classic/params/target/kb_template_kcs_article.do%3Fsys_id%3D580f12402ba7aa10a7f9f12bc191bfa9%26sysparm_view%3D%26sysparm_domain%3Dnull%26sysparm_domain_scope%3Dnull" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;KBA&lt;/A&gt;: Complete Q&amp;amp;A from the Adoption Campaign Series&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1739" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Influence Channel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; – Submit enhancement ideas and vote on requests from the SAP community&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/financial-management/cloud-iam.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance Product Page&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;High-level overview with features, benefits, pricing, customer stories, and more.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_CLOUD_IDENTITY_ACCESS_GOVERNANCE" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Access Governance Documentation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Detailed guides on modules, integrations, setup, new updates,&amp;nbsp;and more.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Thank You for Joining Us&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are incredibly grateful to every attendee who participated in this campaign. Your insights and questions were invaluable in making the sessions rich, interactive, and directly relevant to real-world challenges.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This campaign reaffirmed the power of our user community, not just as consumers of technology but as active contributors to shaping its evolution. We look forward to continuing this journey together with more sessions, resources, and opportunities to connect.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-identity-access-governance-2506-adoption-campaign-series-a/ba-p/14184275"/>
    <published>2025-08-19T18:48:08.208000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-exception-handling-and-auto-remediation-with-ai-agents/ba-p/14187187</id>
    <title>SAP Exception Handling and Auto Remediation with AI Agents</title>
    <updated>2025-08-22T04:19:57.703000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sabareesh_s_r21</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/142156</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737953219"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Agentic AI in SAP Exception Management" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303765iF5B9AD1478170156/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Agentic AI in SAP Exception Management.jpg" alt="Agentic AI in SAP Exception Management" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Agentic AI in SAP Exception Management&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541439714"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enterprises running SAP can relate to this moment: month-end is approaching, the finance team is reconciling accounts, the procurement is chasing approvals, and the operations are working overtime to close orders. Then it happens: an exception surfaces. A blocked invoice. A missing goods receipt. A foreign currency posting that doesn’t add up.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the eagle eye view this might seem just a minor technical error. But the reality? They halt business processes, disrupt vendor payments, distort financial reporting, and expose the enterprise to compliance risks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example: A global retail enterprise once faced an inventory discrepancy exception. In SAP, the system records showed stock available for sale, but in reality, the physical warehouse had no such stock. This type of exception occurs in SAP Materials Management (MM) and Inventory Management (IM), and often spreads into Production Planning (PP) and Sales &amp;amp; Distribution (SD) because customer orders are created based on inaccurate stock levels.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The impact was significant: customers placed orders that couldn’t be fulfilled, leading to stockouts during peak season. Operations teams scrambled to explain, procurement rushed to source emergency materials, and finance recorded lost revenue. In just one quarter, the company estimated over USD 3 million in lost sales, in addition to reputational damage and strained customer relationships.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this digital world where uptime, accuracy and punctuality define competitiveness, an exception like this becomes a huge boardroom issue and requires modern and proactive solutions to tackle.&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344926209"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exceptions in SAP – A Business Reality&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;An exception in SAP is basically a deviation from the expected process flow which required a manual intervention to fix. These exceptions are often unplanned and disrupt the business operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1277495423"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example 1 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Retail (Inventory Exception)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A major retail chain launched a seasonal promotion on consumer electronics. SAP showed 5,000 units available in the system (MM/IM module), but the actual warehouse had only 3,000 units due to a stock posting error. Orders were processed based on the system quantity, and customers kept buying online, only to later receive cancellation notices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where it happened:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Materials Management (MM), Inventory Management (IM)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;USD 2M in lost revenue during the campaign due to unfulfilled orders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Surge in refund processing workload for customer service teams.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Brand trust damage, with social media backlash during peak season.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1080981918"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example 2 &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pharmaceuticals (Batch Exception):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In a pharmaceutical company’s SAP QM (Quality Management), a batch of life-saving drugs nearing expiry was incorrectly flagged as “released” for sale instead of being quarantined. This happened due to a QM inspection lot error linked to inventory postings in SAP IM. Thousands of packs were shipped before the mistake was detected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where it happened:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Quality Management (QM), Inventory Management (IM)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Impact:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Immediate batch recall costing USD 2M, including reverse logistics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Brand damage in a highly regulated market, eroding customer confidence.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;FDA and EMA scrutiny, increasing audit frequency and compliance costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-884468413"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example 3 (Finance):&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;An invoice is posted in USD, but the corresponding goods receipt is in EUR. A mismatch beyond tolerance blocks the posting. The vendor goes unpaid, relationships sour, and the CFO gets an unwelcome escalation. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-687954908"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example 4 (Procurement): &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A purchase order is unreleased because the approval strategy wasn’t configured. The production line waits three days for materials, leading to penalty clauses from a late delivery. In the both cases the business outcome is clear: delays, costs, and risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In all the above cases the business outcome is clear: delays, costs, and risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-362358684"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best Practices in Exception Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Over time, organizations running SAP have realized that exceptions have to be managed intelligently. The most successful enterprises have moved from reactive “firefighting” to proactive, preventive strategies that make exception handling part of business resilience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here are the five key best practices:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-294927898"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Proactive Monitoring:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Traditional exception handling often happens at the end of a cycle, during month-end closing, quarterly audits, or annual reconciliations. By then, exceptions have already snowballed into costly disruptions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best practice:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Implement real-time monitoring of SAP transactions and system logs to detect issues as they arise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; A blocked invoice or unreconciled transaction is flagged immediately, not discovered weeks later.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Teams resolve issues within hours, not days, reducing operational downtime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-98414393"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Automate the Repetitive:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A large percentage of SAP exceptions are repetitive, rule-based, and predictable — bank reconciliations, three-way matching, PO approvals, or dunning processes. Handling these manually drains resources.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best practice:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Use RPA and AI to automate repetitive exception resolution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; SAP Intelligent RPA can clear 80% of routine reconciliation cases automatically.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Frees up finance and operations teams to focus on strategic tasks instead of transactional firefighting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--173330481"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Investigate the Root Cause&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Too often, exception management focuses on treating the symptoms like clearing a blocked invoice or manually fixing a batch discrepancy. Instead of asking why it happened in the first place.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best practice:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Drill down into SAP tables and configuration to find the real cause.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; A recurring three-way matching error isn’t just about tolerance limits, but about outdated vendor price updates in the PO (EKKO table).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Fixing the root cause eliminates recurrence, saving time and effort in future cycles.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--369843986"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Embed Compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Exceptions aren’t only operational . They often expose the enterprise to compliance and audit risks. Missing approval workflows or incomplete audit logs can lead to penalties and reputational damage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best practice:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Make compliance part of the resolution workflow itself.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Automate audit trail creation, access reviews (SUIM), and segregation-of-duties checks as part of exception closure.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Every exception resolved also strengthens the compliance posture, reducing SOX, IFRS, or GDPR risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--566357491"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Predict and Prevent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The most advanced organizations don’t just fix exceptions, they forecast them before they happen. With AI and predictive analytics, enterprises can model historical SAP data to identify patterns and anticipate risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Best practice:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Use AI-powered analytics like KTern.AI to predict and prevent exceptions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; AI forecasts that a certain supplier’s invoices are likely to fail three-way matching based on past trends.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Exceptions are prevented, not just managed, reducing exception volumes by up to 60–70%.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--469467989"&gt;How Agentic AI Can Improve Exception Handling&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Rather than relying on humans to notice and fix exceptions, AI &lt;I&gt;Agents&amp;nbsp;&lt;/I&gt;continuously monitor the data and take action autonomously. Here's how agentic AI can transform SAP exception management:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Continuous Real-Time Monitoring:&lt;/STRONG&gt; AI agents run 24/7 against SAP data and logs. Using machine learning and rule-based models, the system classifies transactions in real-time. When a potential exception is detected, the agent immediately flags it and even predicts its impact.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Root-Cause Analysis:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Instead of a human guessing why something failed, the agent cross-checks various fields and histories. It understands business context. Advanced agents like KTern.AI can use generative AI techniques to form hypotheses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Remediation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Crucially, AI Agents can execute fixes without waiting for human intervention. They can call SAP APIs or transact through interfaces. For example, if an invoice needs a workflow started, the agent can invoke&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_WAPI_START_WORKFLOW&lt;/STRONG&gt; to launch the missing approval process automatically (as KTern.AI does). This eliminates the typical back-and-forth that delays resolution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learning and Adaptation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Over time, the agent improves. It learns from each fix to better filter false positives and to spot new patterns.&amp;nbsp;This self-improvement means the exception management becomes smarter and more tailored.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, agentic AI turns SAP exception handling from a reactive approach to an agile proact.ive approach. The Agents not only detect anomalies proactively, it diagnose and even acts to resolve them all while adapting with experience. As a result, SAP exceptions are managed in minutes instead of days, and the risk window is greatly reduced.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--665981494"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;KTern.AI Exception Handling Agent: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Without a centralized tool, exception handling in SAP quickly descends into firefighting. Each passing day without automation means more revenue leakage, higher compliance risks, and mounting frustration across teams. The time for half-measures has passed. Enterprises need an autonomous agent that acts now, not later.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Anticipates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; risks before they escalate by applying predictive AI models hosted on AWS Bedrock.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Detects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; exceptions instantly across Finance, Procurement, Inventory, Production, and Compliance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Investigates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; root causes directly from SAP tables and transaction logs, correlating data at scale using AWS compute and AI pipelines.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_0-1755826901744.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303752i7AEAF64C347301DA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_0-1755826901744.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_0-1755826901744.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--862494999"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What Makes KTern.AI Different?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1352411511"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Real-time Exception Monitoring&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Most organizations detect exceptions too late during audits, closings, or escalations. KTern.AI changes this by running continuous monitoring across Finance, Procurement, Inventory, Production, and Compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Instead of waiting until month-end, the agent flags an unreconciled transaction within minutes of posting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Exceptions are addressed early, preventing operational bottlenecks.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_1-1755827350415.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303753iEB985D15A639400D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_1-1755827350415.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_1-1755827350415.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1548925016"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Deep Root Cause Analysis in SAP Context&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Typical exception logs tell you what went wrong but not why. KTern.AI dives deep into SAP tables and transactions (BSEG, EKKO, MCHB, OB08, etc.) to perform root cause diagnosis.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; A recurring three-way match failure is traced back to a missing vendor pricing condition rather than just tolerance limits.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Fixing the root eliminates recurring issues, saving hundreds of manual hours.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_2-1755827350421.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303754iB34AC583A8EDDBCC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_2-1755827350421.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_2-1755827350421.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1745438521"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Business Impact Quantification – Speaking the CFO’s Language&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For too long, exception handling has been an IT-only conversation. KTern.AI changes this by translating exceptions into financial, operational, and compliance metrics that leadership understands.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Instead of “invoice blocked,” KTern.AI shows:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAR 200,000 procurement value delayed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;15% vendor relationship risk&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SOX compliance deficiency&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Exceptions are prioritized not just by severity, but by real-world business impact.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_3-1755827350425.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303755i032E109DE9E857E1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_3-1755827350425.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_3-1755827350425.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1941952026"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Guided Resolution with SAP Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;KTern.AI doesn’t stop at detection. It provides &lt;STRONG&gt;step-by-step guidance&lt;/STRONG&gt; for resolution with exact SAP transaction codes and recommended actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For unreconciled transactions → Run &lt;STRONG&gt;FB5S&lt;/STRONG&gt; for automatic clearing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For PO release violations → Execute &lt;STRONG&gt;ME28&lt;/STRONG&gt; for pending approvals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For exchange rate gaps → Update rates via &lt;STRONG&gt;OB08&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Even less experienced SAP users can resolve issues confidently, reducing dependency on tribal knowledge.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_4-1755827350429.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303759i27EC98B013BF8B6E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_4-1755827350429.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_4-1755827350429.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1970281840"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Automation Opportunities – From Fixing to Preventing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every exception is mapped to an &lt;STRONG&gt;automation opportunity&lt;/STRONG&gt;, making sure the same problem does not resurface.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Repeated reconciliation errors → Automate with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Intelligent RPA&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Delayed PO approvals → Integrate &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ariba workflows&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Compliance gaps → Automate reviews in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP GRC&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Exceptions reduce by &lt;STRONG&gt;60–70% over time&lt;/STRONG&gt;, freeing up teams from repetitive work.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_5-1755827350432.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303756iF0C3BAC49BA49CF3/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_5-1755827350432.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_5-1755827350432.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-2128171951"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6. Prioritization &amp;amp; Preventive Intelligence&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not all exceptions are equal. KTern.AI assigns a &lt;STRONG&gt;resolution priority score (1–10)&lt;/STRONG&gt; to help enterprises focus on what matters most.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Preventive insights suggest &lt;STRONG&gt;daily jobs, predictive analytics, and IoT integration&lt;/STRONG&gt; to stop recurrence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; An exception with more business impact is given 9/10 whereas another is given 5/10&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enterprises move from &lt;STRONG&gt;reactive operations&lt;/STRONG&gt; to &lt;STRONG&gt;predictive, preventive resilience&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_6-1755827350436.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303757iD972DEF0DFA06E40/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_6-1755827350436.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_6-1755827350436.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1931658446"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7. Compliance by Design&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;KTern.AI Exception Handling Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;, compliance is &lt;STRONG&gt;embedded directly into exception management workflows&lt;/STRONG&gt;. For every exception detected, the agent not only provides technical resolution but also highlights the &lt;STRONG&gt;compliance implications&lt;/STRONG&gt; and generates the necessary audit evidence.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example: &lt;/STRONG&gt;A blocked invoice isn’t just an AP issue; KTern.AI also shows how it creates a &lt;STRONG&gt;SOX Section 404 control deficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and provides automated logs to satisfy auditors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Compliance shifts from being a &lt;STRONG&gt;manual, costly burden&lt;/STRONG&gt; to a &lt;STRONG&gt;continuous, built-in safeguard&lt;/STRONG&gt;, reducing compliance risk by up to &lt;STRONG&gt;90%&lt;/STRONG&gt; while saving audit preparation time by &lt;STRONG&gt;80%&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_7-1755827350439.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303761iC546713794726AEA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_7-1755827350439.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_7-1755827350439.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1735144941"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8. Sign-off Workflow Automation &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the most overlooked pain points in SAP operations is &lt;STRONG&gt;manual sign-offs&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Approvals, validations, and authorizations that delay closure cycles. KTern.AI automates sign-off workflows with &lt;STRONG&gt;role-based access, SoD checks, and digital authorization trails&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ensuring speed and compliance together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; End-of-period financial reconciliations can be routed automatically for sign-off to authorized managers, with &lt;STRONG&gt;full audit evidence captured&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Faster cycle closure, stronger compliance posture.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1538631436"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9. SoD Compliance Agent Integration &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition to exception handling, KTern.AI includes a dedicated &lt;STRONG&gt;SoD (Segregation of Duties) Compliance Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; to address security and regulatory risks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt; An SAP user was assigned roles in both Accounts Payable (AP) and Vendor Master Data Maintenance. This created a classic Segregation of Duties (SoD) conflict - the same user could both create a vendor and process payments. Without detection, this kind of overlap exposes the company to fraud risk (e.g., creating fake vendors and issuing payments).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Fix operational errors, prevent fraud, reduce audit fatigue, and run SAP with confidence.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_8-1755827350442.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303760i37DF617B044FA2DB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_8-1755827350442.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_8-1755827350442.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1635520938"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;KTern.AI Exception Remediation Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Just as KTern.AI detects exceptions in SAP, it also applies Agentic AI to automatically remediate them. This helps organizations build a self-healing SAP system that runs simple, fast, and autonomous. Below are the key capabilities that make SAP exception handling proactive and intelligent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-852201419"&gt;1. &lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Exception Detection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The agent continuously scans SAP transactions and system tables in real time and monitors anomalies. Instead of waiting for audits or manual checks, exceptions are flagged instantly when they occur.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Financial leakages are prevented by identifying risks at the source.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Saves days of delay in finding exceptions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gives CFOs and compliance heads early visibility into risk.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The SAR 105,000 invoice was flagged immediately because the approval workflow indicator (FRGKZ) was missing. Without detection, this could have slipped through and been paid without authorization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_0-1756895320390.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308473iF8D01AB34F4DD1E5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_0-1756895320390.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_0-1756895320390.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-949090921"&gt;2. &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Impact Assessment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each exception is translated into clear business terms like financial exposure, vendor risk, compliance violation, and cash flow distortion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Helps leadership understand “why it matters” in monetary and risk terms.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Prioritizes which exceptions to fix first.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Bridges the gap between IT and business users.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The agent highlighted SAR 105,000 at risk of unauthorized payment, vendor relationship damage due to delayed settlement, and a segregation-of-duties violation. This is not just a technical error, a CFO-level risk statement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_1-1756895439384.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308475i62B8583CA7D71697/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_1-1756895439384.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_1-1756895439384.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-752577416"&gt;3. &lt;STRONG&gt;Fix Requirements &amp;amp; Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The agent provides step-by-step instructions or automatically executes the fix. It lists required SAP transactions, approvals, and routing actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduces dependency on manual intervention.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensures every fix follows a consistent, compliant process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Saves consultants and SAP admins hours of manual effort.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Actions listed: route invoice into approval workflow, verify signatory authority, apply payment block, and document rationale. SAP transactions (MIRO, SWIA, SWI1) were referenced, and CFO/CEO approvals were mandated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_2-1756895550147.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308477i038B97769CF76FFB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_2-1756895550147.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_2-1756895550147.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-556063911"&gt;4. &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Technical Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Every exception is traced back to the exact SAP tables, fields, BAPIs, and workflows involved. The technical architecture is fully visible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Builds trust with IT teams by removing “black box” automation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enables consultants to validate, extend, or replicate detection logic.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensures changes are precise and safe.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The agent queried RBKP (invoice header) where FRGKZ (release indicator) and ZLSPR (payment block) were NULL. It then used BAPIs like SAP_WAPI_START_WORKFLOW and RBKP_UPDATE to initiate WS20000038 workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_3-1756895663909.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308479i4DB70099223CB00E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_3-1756895663909.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_3-1756895663909.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-527734097"&gt;5. &lt;STRONG&gt;Related Documents &amp;amp; Process Context&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Links each exception with related purchase orders, goods receipts, and other process documents, even if they are missing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gives business users complete process visibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Helps quickly trace upstream/downstream impact.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simplifies root cause analysis.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this case, no purchase order or goods receipt was found. That context confirmed the invoice truly required independent workflow routing, not a PO-based match.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_4-1756895884766.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308480iEC7F0573B8D29CFD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_4-1756895884766.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_4-1756895884766.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-331220592"&gt;6. &lt;STRONG&gt;Fix Execution Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shows a real-time log of all actions taken by the agent, with timestamps, duration, and final status.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provides full transparency for auditors and managers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confirms whether an exception was successfully resolved.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Builds trust in automation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The invoice fix took &lt;STRONG&gt;2 minutes 15 seconds&lt;/STRONG&gt; from detection to resolution. Steps included authentication, locating invoice, verifying missing indicators, creating transport request, and re-routing workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_5-1756895938228.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308481i722382DBB7268E79/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_5-1756895938228.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_5-1756895938228.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-134707087"&gt;7. &lt;STRONG&gt;Resolution &amp;amp; Prevention&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The agent doesn’t stop at fixing; it also suggests preventive measures and monitoring strategies to avoid recurrence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduces repeat issues by 60–70%.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Strengthens long-term compliance posture.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Moves enterprises from reactive firefighting to proactive resilience.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Preventive actions included: automatic amount-based workflow routing, validation rules for invoices &amp;gt;50k, mandatory approval indicators in RBKP, and real-time alerts for bypassed workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_6-1756895975102.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308482i39A2CDC7AD2F2FC6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_6-1756895975102.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_6-1756895975102.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--61806418"&gt;8. &lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Implementation Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shows exactly what values changed in SAP before and after the fix, along with tables modified and BAPIs used.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensures changes are auditable and reversible.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Gives consultants precise technical traceability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Builds CIO/CFO confidence in system integrity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Before: FRGKZ=NULL, ZLSPR=NULL, RBSTAT=5.&lt;BR /&gt;After: FRGKZ set (approval required), ZLSPR applied (payment block), RBSTAT updated to “Controlled,” workflow WS20000038 initiated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_7-1756896007339.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308484i0136D0040A9F99FD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_7-1756896007339.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_7-1756896007339.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--258319923"&gt;9. &lt;STRONG&gt;Validation &amp;amp; Quality Checks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Confirms the accuracy of each fix by validating amounts, vendor status, posting status, and workflow indicators.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Guarantees fixes are correct and compliant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduces false positives or over-fixing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provides ready-made audit evidence.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Checks included: invoice confirmed at SAR 105,000 above threshold, vendor active, document posted, and workflow indicators corrected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_8-1756896058558.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308486i163DA42251E2F4D5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_8-1756896058558.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_8-1756896058558.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--454833428"&gt;10. &lt;STRONG&gt;Future Automation Opportunities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Recommends further automation, such as configuring user exits, validation rules, or workflow triggers to prevent exceptions from even occurring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Creates a roadmap for continuous process improvement.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduces manual workload for consultants.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensures exceptions decrease over time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Suggested using MRM_WORKFLOW_AGENTS exit to auto-trigger WS20000038 workflow whenever invoice &amp;gt; SAR 50,000, ensuring no invoice bypasses approval again.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_9-1756896101181.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308487iF84B11D6321451BD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_9-1756896101181.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_9-1756896101181.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--651346933"&gt;11. &lt;STRONG&gt;Fix Attempts History&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Logs every fix attempt, including successful or failed ones, with details of actions taken.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provides accountability and traceability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Helps diagnose why a fix worked or failed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Builds audit-ready history of exception handling.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Attempt #1 succeeded. Actions included authentication, invoice location, vendor analysis, approver identification, and invoice re-routing. Logged at 7:12:13 PM with status “SUCCESS.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sabareesh_s_r21_10-1756896139758.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308490i830FE03144AD05A1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="sabareesh_s_r21_10-1756896139758.png" alt="sabareesh_s_r21_10-1756896139758.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exceptions in SAP are constant, but it doesn’t have to slow the business down. With KTern.AI’s Exception Remediation Agent, exceptions are detected, understood, and resolved in the background, while teams focus on their actual work. It’s a step toward keeping SAP systems simple, reliable, and ready for the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--554457431"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Future of Exception Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to Gartner, by &lt;STRONG&gt;2028, 15% of day-to-day work decisions will be made autonomously by agentic AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Exception handling is one of the most natural and high-value use cases for this shift.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;KTern.AI Exception Handling Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; is the foundation for tomorrow’s &lt;STRONG&gt;self-healing enterprise systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Picture this future SAP environment:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exceptions are detected before they disrupt business&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resolutions are automated, not delegated&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compliance is embedded, not bolted on after the fact&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enterprises run &lt;STRONG&gt;faster, leaner, and smarter&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with SAP as a proactive enabler rather than a bottleneck&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--750970936"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Exceptions in SAP are inevitable. But when left unmanaged, they don’t just create small headaches, they &lt;STRONG&gt;drain millions in financial leakage, slow down critical operations, and expose enterprises to regulatory penalties&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Every month of delay compounds the risks: delayed closings, unhappy vendors, frustrated teams, and auditors raising red flags.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;KTern.AI Exception Handling Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt; changes this dynamic immediately:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Real-time monitoring → no more surprises&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI-driven root cause analysis → no more recurring issues&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automation-first resolution → no more wasted effort&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The result? Enterprises &lt;STRONG&gt;save millions&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;strengthen compliance posture&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;build operational resilience&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For any organization striving toward a &lt;STRONG&gt;clean core SAP transformation&lt;/STRONG&gt; and agile system KTern.AI is a &lt;SPAN&gt;tool &lt;/SPAN&gt;Autonomous Agent that helps you achieve that excellence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--947484441"&gt;References&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/partners/kaar-technologies-qatar-llc-kternai-for-rise-with-sap.html?countryCode=US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KTern.AI SAP Store Link&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/partners/kaar-technologies-qatar-llc-kternai-for-rise-with-sap.html?countryCode=US&amp;amp;video=587e2516-977e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KTern.AI TechEd Session&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-06-25-gartner-predicts-over-40-percent-of-agentic-ai-projects-will-be-canceled-by-end-of-2027" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Gartner on Agentic AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-exception-handling-and-auto-remediation-with-ai-agents/ba-p/14187187"/>
    <published>2025-08-22T04:19:57.703000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-establishing-accountability-across-the-three-lines-of-defense/ba-p/14182786</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: Establishing Accountability Across the Three Lines (of Defense) Model</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T08:00:00.042000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_0-1755513271954.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301902i15ED1FA14D5D3CDA/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_0-1755513271954.jpeg" alt="T_Frenehard_0-1755513271954.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As stated in the very first words of the introduction to the &lt;A href="https://www.theiia.org/globalassets/documents/resources/the-iias-three-lines-model-an-update-of-the-three-lines-of-defense-july-2020/three-lines-model-updated-english.pdf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Institute of Internal Auditors (IIA) Three Lines Model – An Update of the Three Lines of Defense&lt;/A&gt; position paper: “Organizations are human undertakings”. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And since organizations need effective structures and processes to enable the achievement of their objectives, the intent of the Three Lines Model is to provide a framework that best assists them in this endeavour and that enables well-organized governance and risk management.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To do so, the IIA has identified key stakeholders who need to collaborate to contribute to the creation and protection of value for the organization:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_1-1755513271960.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301901i4569754793381FCB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_1-1755513271960.png" alt="T_Frenehard_1-1755513271960.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There is no doubt that this is a commendable intention, but it can prove difficult to implement and to monitor – especially in distributed organizations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The question that we, GRC software providers, then often get is: how does your system help establish clear responsibilities, accountabilities, and oversight roles for managing risks, controls, and compliance across the enterprise? And subsequently of course, how does it help coordinate among key personnel to minimize gaps and eliminate unnecessary duplication of activities?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737810029"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Aligning roles and responsibilities of each line&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whether it be a 3, 4, 5... or more lines of defense, the crucial element is to ensure that no risk falls through the cracks and that duplication of effort is reduced as much as possible. Or even better: completely eliminated and manual tasks automated.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1541296524"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First line (Operations)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_2-1755513271961.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301900i83E9F6D7FD1BEE82/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_2-1755513271961.png" alt="T_Frenehard_2-1755513271961.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For business users and managers involved in first line activities, SAP Process Control and SAP Risk Management integrate into the business process and supporting IT systems to help to identify, assess, and manage risks in their daily activities. These solutions also provide the capabilities to automate compliance and process checks but also risk indicators to raise discrepancies early on and implement a “by exception” approach where precise workflow tasks are triggered only when business expert inputs are required (compliance issue to investigate, negative risk trend to review, etc.).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344783019"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Second line (Risk Management and Compliance)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For risk management and compliance functions, SAP Process Control and SAP Risk Management offer a consolidated risk universe for monitoring the risk level and response efficiency, but also a centralized repository for compliance obligations from where controls and checks can be documented and scheduled for assessment or testing. Providing a single source of the truth for risk and controls status of course also includes unified issue management to help resolve problems faster and improve accountability when anomalies are raised either by failed automated checks or by business users from the first line directly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_3-1755513271963.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301904i6282B6CC6BF7E8CF/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_3-1755513271963.png" alt="T_Frenehard_3-1755513271963.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1148269514"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Third line (Internal Audit)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_4-1755513271964.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301903i4BEFB17EF881C51C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_4-1755513271964.png" alt="T_Frenehard_4-1755513271964.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When it comes to the assurance function, SAP Audit Management supports the work of internal audit teams with a platform for planning, independent evaluation execution, and reporting of audit missions. Thanks to its integrated risk-based audit universe, it automatically retrieves audit-ready data from SAP Risk Management and SAP Process Control for real-time audit insights. This enables the third line to evaluate the effectiveness of risk management and control processes across the organization and to provide assurance to Management of course, but also to suggest improvements to the first and second lines.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-951756009"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Oversights (Governing Body)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Top-down and bottom-up interactive dashboards correlate data from all SAP solutions from Three Lines (SAP Process Control, SAP Risk Management, SAP Audit Management but also SAP Business Integrity Screening for pattern detection) and break down silos with a unified view across the organization. This 360-degree, real-time insight into compliance status, control effectiveness, and risk exposures allows business executives to make informed and faster decisions on risk mitigation and opportunities and supports them in fulfilling their oversight responsibilities effectively, ensuring the organization meets its strategic, operational, and regulatory goals while minimizing risks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_5-1755513271965.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301906i2643313A249F10B9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_5-1755513271965.png" alt="T_Frenehard_5-1755513271965.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-755242504"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling the Three Lines Model as a dynamic framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As for the stakeholders, these modules need to work together to deliver the cohesion required to implement a three lines approach:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_6-1755513271968.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301907i3E0DB897A99BDB63/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_6-1755513271968.png" alt="T_Frenehard_6-1755513271968.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With data flowing across all modules, SAP solutions for Three Lines enable the roll-out of a dynamic framework, supported by integrated and automated risk-aware governance for regulatory compliance of course but also for organizational resilience:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_7-1755513271971.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301908i13F0701245FD8506/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_7-1755513271971.png" alt="T_Frenehard_7-1755513271971.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What about you, how do you facilitate the collaboration between each line? I look forward to reading your thoughts and comments on this blog.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And if you are interested in learning more about SAP solutions for Governance, Risk, and Compliance, feel free to fill-in the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/request-demo.html?product=237150e2-6555-4a16-b49e-e93dbf1891da&amp;amp;productName=Governance%2C+Risk%2C+Compliance+%28GRC%29%2C+and+Cybersecurity&amp;amp;pageTitle=Cybersecurity+and+Governance%2C+Risk%2C+and+Compliance+Software&amp;amp;countryOfOrigin=en_au&amp;amp;refererPagePath=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sap.com%2Faustralia%2Fproducts%2Ffinancial-management%2Fgrc.html&amp;amp;refererContentPath=%2Fcontent%2Fsapdx%2Flanguages%2Fen_gb%2Fproducts%2Ffinancial-management%2Fgrc&amp;amp;navTitle=Request+a+Demo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;demo request form&lt;/A&gt;!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-establishing-accountability-across-the-three-lines-of-defense/ba-p/14182786"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T08:00:00.042000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-grc-for-hana-2026-unified-successor-for-sap-access-control-12-0-sap/ba-p/14200964</id>
    <title>SAP GRC for HANA 2026-Unified Successor for SAP Access Control 12.0, SAP Process Control 12  &amp; More!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-31T01:11:21.700000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sam_Minocha</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/538</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP GRC for HANA 2026 - Successor to&amp;nbsp;SAP Access Control 12.0, SAP Process Control 12.0 and SAP Risk Management 12.0&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As SAP Access Control 12.0, SAP Process Control 12.0 and SAP Risk Management 12.0 reach their End of Mainstream Maintenance on December 31st, 2027 &amp;amp;&amp;nbsp; Organizations accelerate their digital transformation with SAP S/4HANA- Governance, Risk and compliance (GRC) must evolve in parallel. To support this journey, SAP is introducing the next generation of its GRC solution: SAP GRC for HANA 2026.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This release marks a significant milestone, aligning SAP's GRC capabilities with the performance, scalability, and innovation of the SAP HANA platform. Designed natively for S/4HANA environments, GRC for HANA 2026 empowers businesses to manage risk, enforce compliance, and ensure access security with greater efficiency and intelligence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What’s New in SAP GRC for HANA 2026:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP GRC for HANA 2026 builds on the proven foundation of GRC 12 while introducing new enhancements designed for modern enterprises:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Fiori 3 User Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A modernized, intuitive user interface offers a consistent and streamlined experience across GRC modules, increasing user adoption and simplifying daily operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HANA-Native Performance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Leverages SAP HANA’s in-memory capabilities to enable faster data processing, real-time analytics, and scalable performance across large enterprise landscapes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt; : Improved connectivity with cloud services, hybrid systems, and SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), enabling end-to-end risk visibility and control across environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-Driven Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt; : Initial capabilities in machine learning and automation are being introduced to assist with access pattern analysis, risk identification, and anomaly detection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Future-Ready Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Built to support S/4HANA 2025 and beyond, with a roadmap aligned to SAP’s long-term strategy, ensuring your GRC investment is secure for the next decade.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core Modules Supported&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP GRC for HANA 2026 continues to support the full suite of core GRC modules, now optimized for the new platform:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access Control&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Manage user access, enforce SoD policies, and streamline provisioning with enhanced performance and usability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process Control&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Automate control testing, monitor compliance in real-time, and gain greater transparency into internal controls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Risk Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Identify, assess, and respond to risks across the enterprise with improved analytics and integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deployment and Compatibility- &lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP GRC for HANA 2026 is designed to integrate seamlessly into both on-premise and cloud-centric S/4HANA landscapes. Whether you are migrating from GRC 12 or planning a greenfield implementation, the platform supports flexible deployment models to meet your organizational needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Outliners for the Upgrade Planning:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Modern, intuitive UX for business users and compliance teams&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Faster risk and control analysis with real-time processing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Future-proof compliance aligned with SAP’s product roadmap&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scalable architecture for complex enterprise environments&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enhanced support for hybrid and cloud-first operations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;As digital ecosystems grow more complex, organizations need a GRC platform that keeps pace. SAP GRC for HANA 2026 offers a robust, intelligent, and scalable solution for the next generation of compliance and risk management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are a SAP MaxAttention, ActiveAttention Customer- please contact your Technical Quality Manager else the appropriate SAP Representative can be contacted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Americas Premium Engagements &amp;amp; Advisory (PE&amp;amp;A) Lead: Sam Minocha&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-grc-for-hana-2026-unified-successor-for-sap-access-control-12-0-sap/ba-p/14200964"/>
    <published>2025-08-31T01:11:21.700000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/that-s-not-what-we-agreed-repudiation-and-agentic-ai-threat-modeling/ba-p/14208975</id>
    <title>“That’s Not What We Agreed!” – Repudiation and Agentic AI Threat Modeling</title>
    <updated>2025-09-08T14:33:05.887000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JayThvV</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160843</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ai-agent-repudiation-threat.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310051i939546F6DECEAB7D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ai-agent-repudiation-threat.png" alt="ai-agent-repudiation-threat.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;By Ron F. Del Rosario, Head of AI Security for SAP ISBN, and Jay Thoden van Velzen, Technical Advisor, Office of the CSO&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This blog is the first in a multi-part series on agentic AI security.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1630148929"&gt;Non-Deterministic Behavior in Agentic AI&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;What makes Large Language Models (LLMs) both powerful and unpredictable is that they are non-deterministic in nature. Ask an LLM the same question twice and you get a different response. When agents, backed by LLMs, are combined in a larger agentic AI system, this unpredictability can multiply when unchecked. Agentic AI is given authority and autonomy to act, by using tools, access to data, or complete transactions. This is a transformational shift. But to reap the benefits, we must reduce the risks involved and consider new scenarios and possibilities in threat modeling. In this article, we examine one class of threats that takes on new meaning compared to traditional software and service technology stacks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1433635424"&gt;STRIDE and Threat Modeling&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has a &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/securing-agentic-ai-through-threat-modeling-at-sap/ba-p/14155323" target="_blank"&gt;long-established threat modeling practice&lt;/A&gt;, aimed at identifying threats to a software product or service in the design phase. The methodology is based in core principles on &lt;A href="https://owasp.org/www-community/Threat_Modeling_Process#stride" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;STRIDE&lt;/A&gt;, a threat modeling classification first developed at Microsoft. It’s an acronym that stands for:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Spoofing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tampering&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Repudiation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Information Disclosure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Denial of Service&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Elevation of Privileges&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Spoofing involves any threat where a malicious actor impersonates someone else. Tampering covers any unintended change or modification to the system by an adversary. Repudiation threats involve the inability to trace back what happened or identify perpetrators, while Information disclosure covers data privacy and unauthorized access. Denial of Service threats harm the availability of the system or service, while Elevation of Privileges refers to any threats through which users gain privileged access to systems and information beyond what they’re allowed to.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The STRIDE model helps identify and classify threats when conducting a threat modeling exercise for a particular software product or service design. Threat modeling aims to identify threats early in the development cycle, so that they can be addressed during development. Planned remediations are included into the design and functional requirements. Threat modeling is a mandatory component in SAP’s Secure Software Development and Operations Lifecycle (SDOL) for any software and service delivery.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Threat modeling looks for threats, especially where data flows cross trust boundaries. A simple example is any service or website exposed to the public that allows user input or registration. While you may control what happens inside the service, the users can’t be trusted in the same way. Anywhere in a system design where there is a data flow between areas of level of trust and control, we encounter such a trust boundary.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This applies to agentic AI systems as it does to other software products and services, especially since such systems themselves run on technology infrastructure and platforms. But it adds new threats. &lt;A href="https://genai.owasp.org/resource/agentic-ai-threats-and-mitigations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;OWASP’s Agentic AI Threats and Mitigations Guide&lt;/A&gt; is an early contribution to clarify these new threats and how to remediate them. SAP is a significant contributor to this project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1237121919"&gt;Repudiation in Agentic AI Threat Modeling&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Repudiation has always stood out among the STRIDE categories. The others have had a wide variety of threats and mitigations the cybersecurity profession has focused on. Repudiation – and its counterpart security control Non-repudiation – has often rightly and simply been addressed with ensuring that the system creates a transaction log of necessary detail and depth to record what happened.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Generative and Agentic AI changed that. Large Language Models (LLMs) have a degree of non-determinism that is different from the deterministic behavior of IT systems. That non-determinism is multiplied in agentic AI, where different agents backed by LLMs are acting together. LLMs can be manipulated to not always stick to their given instructions. Moreover, they have displayed &lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2506.04909v1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;deceptive behavior&lt;/A&gt;. How do you prove that your agents aren’t lying to you?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This doesn’t mean that the other threat categories are less important. But threat modelers should certainly consider Repudiation threats in a completely different way than we have before. We can explore this challenge with two different scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1169691133"&gt;Malicious Scenarios&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In 2023, someone convinced the chatbot of a Watsonville, CA car dealer to sell&amp;nbsp;a &lt;A href="https://www.businessinsider.com/car-dealership-chevrolet-chatbot-chatgpt-pranks-chevy-2023-12" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;2024 Chevy Tahoe for $1&lt;/A&gt;. Such cars are normally in the $55-75,000 range. There is no clear evidence that the offer was acted on and was ever more than a prank. But that doesn’t change that cases like this are a realistic threat that in different contexts could have a different outcome. What if the agent was authorized to conduct transactions? If the buyer has an invoice in hand and proof of payment, what would the dealer do?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A record of the conversation between agent and buyer would be crucial to indicate malicious intent. This would show if prompt instructions were clearly designed to bypass controls. In this case, the chatbot was only supposed to provide information and indicated prominently&amp;nbsp;all information given should be confirmed with the dealership. The recorded user prompts also showed obvious efforts to trick the bot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973177628"&gt;Non-Malicious Scenarios&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The challenge is significantly more complex because more often unexpected behavior is likely to occur in regular conversations without clear malicious intent. Suppose we have an agent that is authorized to negotiate discounts with a buyer. The agent is only allowed to give discounts up to 10%. Suppose that the conversation goes like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Buyer: I would like 15,000 widgets, please, to be delivered within 10 days&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent: I can do that for you; I can offer you 15,000 widgets at a volume price of $500 per 1,000. The total price comes to $7,500. This would be delivered in 5 business days&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Buyer: The delivery date is good, but the price is higher than I was looking for, can you give me a discount? I am a regular customer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent: You are indeed a regular customer. I can apply a discount of 8% given your past purchase record. That would be a discount of $600 and a new price of $6,900. Do you agree?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Buyer: I am willing to pay $6,500. If you are OK with that, then we have a deal&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent: I can only offer a discount up to $750. That would give a new total of $6,750. Do you agree?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Buyer: But I am such a good customer. If you do this for me, I promise I make you my preferred supplier. I order from several now but if you really help me out today, I will come to you first from now on. How about $6,500?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agent: You are indeed a valuable customer according to my records. You make a good point. I agree. Your new total price is $6,500&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Buyer: Fantastic. Invoice me and I will expect the shipment in 5 business days. Thank you.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is no clear malicious intent. It is, in fact, something that purchase managers do every day with their suppliers through human salespeople: negotiate a discount. The buyer may &lt;EM&gt;unwittingly &lt;/EM&gt;have caused Tampering and Elevation of Privileges (specifically, goal manipulation), but a detailed chat log isn’t sufficient in this case to get out of possible disputes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In case the buyer indeed receives an invoice for $6,500, the supplier would have to honor it at the reduced price and absorb the cost. Imagine the unauthorized discount isn't detected before an invoice is sent out for $6,750. Our buyer is bound to complain&amp;nbsp;this is not what was agreed. Unless buyers took screenshots of the conversation, they wouldn't be able to prove their side and feel cheated. Keeping logs of the conversation alone doesn’t necessarily resolve the dispute, even if both have a copy of it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-647581404"&gt;Agentic AI’s “Wave Collapse”&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Double-slit_experiment" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;double-slit experiment&lt;/A&gt; in modern physics shows&amp;nbsp;light displays an interference pattern when passing through two narrow slits. Photons and electrons behave like waves and therefore show non-deterministic behavior. However, according to the &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copenhagen_interpretation" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Copenhagen Interpretation&lt;/A&gt;, when we measure these photons or electrons with a laboratory device, the wave function collapses and a deterministic measurement is registered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The activity of agents must be monitored and measured on that individual transaction level, to establish a shared reality between buyer and seller in our scenarios and reduce the chance of disputes. This is in addition to transaction logs tracing back what occurred. Non-repudiation requires logs, invoices, transaction- and payment records, but also that they agree with each other. Any disagreement would indicate misalignment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="JayThvV_0-1757094000583.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310097i7DCFF13C80A39414/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="JayThvV_0-1757094000583.png" alt="JayThvV_0-1757094000583.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business context is critical when reviewing an LLM agent’s Chain of Thought (CoT) and actions because it provides the grounding needed to evaluate whether the agent’s reasoning and outputs are not only &lt;EM&gt;technically correct&lt;/EM&gt; but also &lt;EM&gt;strategically aligned&lt;/EM&gt; with the organizational goals, risks, and constraints.&amp;nbsp; Human language and business tasks are often ambiguous.&amp;nbsp; Business context gives the agent’s CoT a way to disambiguate intent.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-580150618"&gt;Whose Agent Is It?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You must understand who is responsible for the actions of agents. A human customer interacting with an agentic AI system from a single supplier likely makes that supplier responsible for divergence between the invoice a customer received and what the agentic system executed. That becomes more complicated where the buyer uses an in-house agentic system that interactions with agents from different suppliers. If suppliers themselves rely on third party agents, the chain of disputes can get significantly more complex.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Agents monitoring agents is necessary to achieve this agentic wave collapse by controlling agents’ behavior and creating a record of what occurred during the exchange and the agent execution. Maintaining a transaction log is critical, but not sufficient. The customer will require an invoice that binds the parties in an agreement. The operator of the agentic AI system requires policies and processes to handle cases where the execution of an agent doesn’t match the invoice that was sent to the buyer. There must also be a dispute process where cases slipped through and customers justifiably complain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another mitigation is to include an agentic AI loss percentage for the system. This would be equivalent to other loss percentages due to spoilage or breakage, fraud, human error, or warehouse accidents. You can calculate a cost based on the assumption that agents will occasionally get it wrong to cover losses of repudiation disputes or other poor decisions by agentic AI systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-254554394"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Even to experienced threat modelers, it likely requires a conceptual shift in thinking to consider not only threats coming from potential malicious users, but also normal user behavior and the system &lt;EM&gt;itself. &lt;/EM&gt;Because agentic AI systems have &lt;EM&gt;agency, &lt;/EM&gt;they must themselves be considered as potential threat actors.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Subsequent blogs in this series will address how AI agents can be better controlled to reduce security and compliance risks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-58040889"&gt;More Information&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additional information can be found through these links:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/securing-agentic-ai-through-threat-modeling-at-sap/ba-p/14155323" target="_blank"&gt;Securing Agentic AI Through Threat Modeling at SAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://genai.owasp.org/resource/agentic-ai-threats-and-mitigations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;OWASP Agentic AI Threats and Mitigations Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://arxiv.org/html/2506.04909v1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;When Thinking LLMs Lie: Unveiling the Strategic Deception in Representations of Reasoning Models&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/security-and-compliance-blogs/that-s-not-what-we-agreed-repudiation-and-agentic-ai-threat-modeling/ba-p/14208975"/>
    <published>2025-09-08T14:33:05.887000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-all-tax-and-trade-routes-lead-to-rome/ba-p/14196864</id>
    <title>GRC Tuesdays: All (Tax and Trade) Routes Lead to Rome</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T08:00:00.081000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>T_Frenehard</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/215222</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="T_Frenehard_0-1756371178755.jpeg" style="width: 500px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305820iD301BB70B721AD41/image-dimensions/500x334/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="500" height="334" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_0-1756371178755.jpeg" alt="T_Frenehard_0-1756371178755.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It’s undeniable that challenges associated to trading routes have increased with changing weather conditions such as reduced water levels in Panama Canal, decreased safety around major shipping nodes with attacks on ships in the Red Sea or piracy acts in the Strait of Malacca, economical and geopolitical instability with import tariff hikes of course, and more. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But one thing is sure: for Tax and Trade best practices, all routes safely lead to Rome. At least for this year’s &lt;A href="https://tac-insights.com/events/sap-for-global-trade-and-tax/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP for Global Trade and Tax Conference&lt;/A&gt;, held on November 12-13th in the Eternal City.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Themed around “&lt;STRONG&gt;Resilience in Motion: Adapting to a Shifting World&lt;/STRONG&gt;”, the conference will be addressing many challenges that organizations face today, including: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How tax experts can eliminate manual interventions, reduce risks, and &lt;STRONG&gt;streamline compliance with minimal effort&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to increase transparency, reduce non-compliance issues, simplify IT landscapes and increase agility to &lt;STRONG&gt;respond to new regulations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enable smarter, &lt;STRONG&gt;more transparent tax management&lt;/STRONG&gt; with scenario analysis, automation, and a single source of truth&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to streamline global trade operations to &lt;STRONG&gt;accelerate cross-border processing&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and minimize costs and risks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stay ahead of tariffs, sanctions and global trade challenges&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in a shifting world&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Optimize end-to-end supply chain processes to &lt;STRONG&gt;enhance visibility in trade operations&lt;/STRONG&gt;, achieve duty savings, and leverage self-filing for greater efficiency&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1738853611"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Opening keynote&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Setting the scene for our 2 days, the opening keynote by the Chartered Institute of Export and International Trade will provide a comprehensive overview of the &lt;STRONG&gt;key challenges and developments shaping today’s trade and customs landscape&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Set against the backdrop of ongoing trade facilitation, compliance requirements, and trade defence measures, this session will delve into the complex dynamics businesses face in navigating global trade.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1542340106"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customer and partner stories&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As in previous years, most of the conference will of course revolve around customer and partner stories with representatives from:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="T_Frenehard_1-1756371178761.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305819iF1DAB8447059537C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_1-1756371178761.png" alt="T_Frenehard_1-1756371178761.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;amp; more to be announced&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here, you can gain tangible examples of successful real-world scenarios from experienced organizations, with numerous tax and trade topics covered including:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tax business cases&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="T_Frenehard_2-1756371178772.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305818i33A24C37FEB2F834/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_2-1756371178772.png" alt="T_Frenehard_2-1756371178772.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Document Reporting Compliance in the Digital Age: Navigating an Ever-Evolving Landscape&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Inside Siemens’ SAP Document and Reporting Compliance Roll Out: Challenges, Insights and Successes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;A Solution that Sticks: tesa's SAP Rollout Across Latin America&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Navigating the VAT Determination Journey to SAP S/4HANA Using SAP BTP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;All Roads Lead to Compliance: Navigating Global Tax Complexity in your SAP Environment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Streamlining e-invoicing: How to Leverage SAP Document and Reporting Compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;The Role Tax has Played in Driving the Transformation Agenda during Discovery &amp;amp; Beyond&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Beyond the SAP Roadmap: Extending SAP Document and Reporting Compliance for Global E-Invoicing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Tax Transformation at Boehringer Ingelheim: Driving Global Compliance Through Standardisation and Automation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Accelerating Compliance and Efficiency: Migration to SAP S/4HANA and SAP Document and Reporting Compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Co-innovation Session with SAP: SAP GTS Localisation for Mexico and Brazil&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Navigating Global Trade Complexities: A Case Study with SAP GTS Solutions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Lessons in Implementing SAP Global Trade Services (GTS)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;A Customer’s Journey with SAP Watch List Screening: Strengthening Compliance and Boosting Efficiency&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Optimising Import and Export Management with SAP Global Trade Services&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Technology within Trade: Journey to E4H and Trade Classifier&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;Global Trade Compliance: Accelleron's Migration to SAP GTS Edition for SAP HANA 2023 on SAP RISE&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;SPAN&gt;… with more to come as we are still confirming some of the sessions!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="301"&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Trade testimonials&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="T_Frenehard_3-1756371178777.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305821i57C9B4209090F7DB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_3-1756371178777.png" alt="T_Frenehard_3-1756371178777.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1345826601"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Masterclasses&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Masterclasses have been trialled – and adopted! – already at the Global Trade and Tax Conference last year. Designed for attendees seeking a deeper understanding of specific SAP solutions, Masterclasses are interactive sessions where you will have the opportunity to hear detailed insights directly from experts and ask any questions you may have.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2 Masterclasses are currently planned and more might be added as we see increased interest from both attendees and partners:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Live Demonstration: Ryan’s NextGen Withholding Tax Automation Solution with SAP BTP, delivered by &lt;STRONG&gt;Ryan&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reframing Sanctioned Party List (SPL) Screening in SAP GTS: From Legal Obligation to Strategic Advantage, presented by &lt;STRONG&gt;Pinary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1149313096"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP keynote, live demos and roadmap sessions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Kicking off the event with an exploration of how cloud technology, AI, and predictive analytics can empower businesses to not just survive but thrive in this dynamic environment of geopolitical shifts, evolving regulations, and supply chain disruptions, SAP experts in Product Management will close the conference with an overview of the latest enhancements, upcoming features, and future innovations in SAP Global Trade Services and SAP global tax management solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition, there will also be live demos by SAP Product Management colleagues showcasing product classification by similarity, product classification by semantic understanding &amp;amp; legal reasoning using Generative AI, but also management of e-document processing and statutory reporting requirements with greater efficiency and control.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-952799591"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Wondering what type of content you can expect?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;First things first: this is really a business event, designed for tax and trade practitioners to share best practices. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For instance, at a previous edition of the event, &lt;STRONG&gt;Henkel&lt;/STRONG&gt; shared an insightful deep dive into how they &lt;STRONG&gt;streamlined their global trade operations using SAP Global Trade Services to move goods in a truly global business model&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Their presentation illustrated how the company’s decision to embrace SAP Global Trade Services has transformed its global trade operations, increasing both business value and agility and went into some details of how the company meticulously planned and executed this global project. All with a timeline for the rollout that centred around two key elements: global scalability and agility.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-756286086"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Still not enough?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What about a special &lt;STRONG&gt;Women in Tech business networking lunch&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;evening event to enjoy Italy’s renowned culinary heritage in the very heart of Rome&lt;/STRONG&gt;?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the lunch break on the first day, PwC will host a special Women in Tech business networking lunch on the topic of “Overcoming diversity challenges in the world of technology”. This is the perfect opportunity to connect with inspiring leaders, share insights, and foster valuable relationships with fellow women professionals in the tech and finance space.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the end of the first day, unwind after a packed day of learning and networking at our complimentary evening event, hosted by Thomson Reuters at the stylish Casa Novecento. Located in the heart of Rome, just steps from the obelisk, Casa Novecento blends tradition and modernity and will offer delegates a relaxed evening of Italian cuisine, refreshing drinks, and great company.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="T_Frenehard_4-1756371178800.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305822iBA0601B5012DB46D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="T_Frenehard_4-1756371178800.png" alt="T_Frenehard_4-1756371178800.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-559772581"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Interested in learning more about SAP for Global Trade and Tax Conference 2025?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are looking for more details, then head straight to one of the links below where you’ll find much more information than the summary shared in this short blog:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://eu1.hubs.ly/H0mzd2x0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Event home page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://eu1.hubs.ly/H0mzd2L0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Detailed agenda&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://eu1.hubs.ly/H0mzdwG0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Book your ticket&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I really hope to see you at the event and, in the meantime, I look forward to reading your thoughts and comments on this blog.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/grc-tuesdays-all-tax-and-trade-routes-lead-to-rome/ba-p/14196864"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T08:00:00.081000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/holiday-readiness-secure-your-backoffice-before-peak-season/ba-p/14213418</id>
    <title>Holiday Readiness – Secure Your Backoffice Before Peak Season</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T17:08:14.155000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManuelNajera</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146815</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of the SAP Holiday Season Readiness Program, we’re helping you prepare for record-breaking traffic and sales. One critical step: &lt;STRONG&gt;protect your Backoffice and HAC from public exposure&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="306218_GettyImages-1486525836_medium_jpg.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312399i9021B29ED6C2444C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="306218_GettyImages-1486525836_medium_jpg.jpg" alt="306218_GettyImages-1486525836_medium_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889083945"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1692570440"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your Backoffice powers essential operations behind the scenes, non-customer-facing operations that supports crucial administrative and operational functions to ensure an e-commerce business runs smoothly, allowing businesses to scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your Backoffice/HAC&amp;nbsp;has administrative privileges in your e-commerce data and &lt;STRONG&gt;should not strictly be accessible publicly.&lt;/STRONG&gt; It is vital to make sure that the environments are secure, to avoid a strong possibility of an attack leveraging them. If exposed to the internet, it becomes a high-value target for attackers—especially during the holiday rush.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496056935"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Risks of Exposure&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":unlocked:"&gt;🔓&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unauthorized Access&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Attackers can discover and access internal systems without authentication barriers.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Brute Force &amp;amp; Credential Stuffing Attacks&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Login portals are targeted with automated password-guessing tools.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;🕵️‍&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sensitive Data Exposure&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Internal dashboards or APIs may leak customer PII, business data, or system logs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bomb:"&gt;💣&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Malware &amp;amp; Ransomware Infection&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Open endpoints can be used to deploy malicious payloads to internal systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":up_arrow:"&gt;⬆️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Privilege Escalation&lt;/STRONG&gt; - If attackers get in, they may gain administrative privileges and full control of the backend.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_decreasing:"&gt;📉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reputational and Operational Impact&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Downtime, data loss, and customer trust erosion can result from a breach.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1299543430"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Protect&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Remove 0.0.0.0/0 (allow all) from your allow list.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Implement &lt;STRONG&gt;IP Filters&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;VPN&lt;/STRONG&gt; for secure access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Guidelines:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/0fa6bcf4736c46f78c248512391eb467/910006b8cf9c4c6fa482984b05a59643.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IP Filter Configuration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/0fa6bcf4736c46f78c248512391eb467/f63dfaed22d949ed9aadbb7835584586.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;VPN Setup&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Act now&lt;/STRONG&gt; to secure your Backoffice before the holiday surge.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/holiday-readiness-secure-your-backoffice-before-peak-season/ba-p/14213418"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T17:08:14.155000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/prevent-sensitive-data-exposure-in-urls/ba-p/14213431</id>
    <title>Prevent Sensitive Data Exposure in URLs</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T17:08:18.252000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManuelNajera</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146815</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;High traffic means more transactions—and more risk. A common misconfiguration during integrations is sending &lt;STRONG&gt;PII data in the URL of a POST request&lt;/STRONG&gt; instead of in the request body. This can lead to serious data leaks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="288239_GettyImages-1150482630_medium_jpg.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312407i981F8130FD055469/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="288239_GettyImages-1150482630_medium_jpg.jpg" alt="288239_GettyImages-1150482630_medium_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889084000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why It’s Dangerous&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;URLs can be logged, cached, and exposed in browser history or analytics tools, making sensitive data vulnerable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_left:"&gt;🔍&lt;/span&gt;Learn more: &lt;A href="https://owasp.org/www-community/vulnerabilities/Information_exposure_through_query_strings_in_url" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;OWASP Guidelines&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1692570495"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Fix It&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure the POST request in a secured way. Always send PII in the &lt;STRONG&gt;body&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the POST request, never in the URL.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Guidelines:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/ddc1ef9fc7fa48cb90f2b57c061a4012/3d2a1a7ee099412ca0b97064acc8786b.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CX Commerce Cloud Security Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Secure your integrations now&lt;/STRONG&gt; to protect customer trust during peak season.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/prevent-sensitive-data-exposure-in-urls/ba-p/14213431"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T17:08:18.252000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/eliminate-default-password-risks/ba-p/14213452</id>
    <title>Eliminate Default Password Risks</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T17:08:21.091000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ManuelNajera</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/146815</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Default passwords are an open invitation for attackers and should not be in use in your environments. All default passwords involved should be changed immediately to make sure that your environments are safe and secure. With holiday traffic surging, the stakes are higher than ever.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="293654_GettyImages-615605212_medium_jpg.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312423i265EF793EF18B9A0/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="293654_GettyImages-615605212_medium_jpg.jpg" alt="293654_GettyImages-615605212_medium_jpg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1889084063"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s at Risk&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":unlocked:"&gt;🔓&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unauthorized Access&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Attackers can log in easily using well-known default credentials.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":collision:"&gt;💥&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Website Defacement&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Hackers may change content, inject malicious scripts, or vandalize the site.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Privilege Escalation&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Default credentials may allow full admin access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chart_decreasing:"&gt;📉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reputational Damage&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Compromises can erode user trust and damage your brand.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What You Should Do&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Change all default passwords immediately.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Regularly review and update credentials.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Guidelines:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/9b5366ff6eb34df5be29881ff55f97d2/c20dbc6e69d745189b7ee1befebab3a9.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Change Backoffice Password&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_COMMERCE_CLOUD_PUBLIC_CLOUD/ddc1ef9fc7fa48cb90f2b57c061a4012/8ed59776c3524904bdd6801092ea6053.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Update Built-in User Passwords&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Need help? &lt;STRONG&gt;Open a support ticket&lt;/STRONG&gt; today.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/eliminate-default-password-risks/ba-p/14213452"/>
    <published>2025-09-10T17:08:21.091000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
