<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/Internet-of-Things-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - Internet of Things</title>
  <updated>2025-10-04T23:10:51.875775+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Internet of Things/pd-p/103751587389184923742461" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Internet of Things blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/workplace-trends-in-the-metaverse-no-one-else-can-be-you/ba-p/13549759</id>
    <title>Workplace Trends In The Metaverse: No One Else Can Be You</title>
    <updated>2022-12-12T13:29:16+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>susangaler</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/105285</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px" id="toc-hId-961337315"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2022/12/Metaverse_SAP_innovation-1.jpg" height="237" width="237" /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If the &lt;A href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/sap/2022/09/27/why-the-metaverse-is-a-gutenberg-moment-for-business/?sh=63efddc13259" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;metaverse&lt;/A&gt; unfolds as expected, competitive office politics could become a relic of the past, as employees who are fully confident in their unique value work together to achieve shared goals with employers. Before dismissing this future as a fantasy, think back to the early 1990s. No one could fully envision how the internet would shake up every industry to its core. &lt;A href="https://www.gartner.com/en/webinars?commId=559062&amp;amp;channelId=14961&amp;amp;srcId=1-4582955171&amp;amp;ref=btem&amp;amp;&amp;amp;utm_campaign=outlook-calendar&amp;amp;utm_medium=calendar&amp;amp;utm_source=brighttalk-embed" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Gartner&lt;/A&gt; analysts recently predicted that by 2025, 10% of workers will regularly use virtual spaces -- up from 1% in 2022.​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-893906529"&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px" id="toc-hId-697393024"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Imagine a workplace where competition doesn’t matter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;The metaverse could create an open, global talent marketplace so trusted that verified organizations could find and hire the experts they need because everything about those individuals – including their accomplishments, aspirations, and development goals – was documented and readily available with their permission. Worker shortages could disappear because companies could submit tenders for projects to a community of meta creators. Experts would autonomously connect with a company’s opportunities and KPIs, working together to accomplish common goals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
“In the metaverse, employees won’t worry about someone trying to take their job because it will be impossible,” said Martin Wezowski, chief futurist at SAP New Ventures and Technology. “No one else can be you because your worth is verifiably documented, spanning not just your experience and accomplishments, but just as important, your people skills, optimism, and curiosity. Confident employees are more inclined to complete each other and not compete against opposing agendas.”&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-500879519"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Metaverse builds a more human-centered workplace&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The metaverse will consist of physical, augmented, and virtual worlds. Applied to the workplace of the future, people could easily gain contextual information and make better decisions across a realm of daily responsibilities. Data could include the employee’s personal passions and professional ambitions, along with relevant information from colleagues across business ecosystems, factoring in overall organizational and objectives.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
“Employees are not a single function or persona. They are cognitive humans who wear numerous hats in the course of a day,” said Wezowski. “Instead of getting stressed out trying to switch gears and keep up with multi-faceted requests, individuals working in the metaverse could be augmented with the contextual information they need as they perform various tasks, moving smoothly between their roles, whether it’s C-level executive, innovator, manager, project member, trainee, mentor, and more.”&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-304366014"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Autonomous workplaces go beyond automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In the first digital age, automation freed up people from tedious rote tasks. The metaverse would make this kind of rudimentary automation look like child’s play. Instead of static processes that are pre-programmed for completion in a one-dimensional physical space, the metaverse could provide all of the immediate information employees needs at the exact moment they need it in virtual, augmented, and/or physical reality.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
“These packages of personalized knowledge would speak to workers where they are with a dynamic, autonomous flow of information that moves between that person’s worlds, without overwhelming them,” said Wezowski. “Employees would grasp new knowledge and apply it faster because learning in the metaverse could be fully immersive, using all five senses. People would build stronger, trusted relationships because multi-sensory interactions in the metaverse would be more authentic and personalized.”&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-107852509"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tapping the value of people &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In the decentralized metaverse, people will not only remain an organization’s most valuable asset, but their individual skills could yield even greater value for themselves and the company. For example, alerts about pending machine part failures prevent downtime on the factory floor. What if machine intelligence could autonomously source engineering designs from the larger market ecosystem to prevent that problem in the first place?&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
“Creative decision-making could be the new value for organizations as the highest output that humans do better than any machines,” said Wezowski. “We would want to be not the best, but our optimal self in each situation, able to apply our unique human ingenuity, augmented by technology, to reach our objectives. This alters the employee/employer relationship to more of a win-win. Humans and machine intelligence will operate in empathic symbiosis, nurturing the core value of every company, which is the people.”&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--88660996"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Innovators with bold thinking leap ahead&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Much as digitalization upended last century business norms, the autonomous nature of the metaverse could fundamentally reshape our definition of meaningful work.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;“Let’s say that engineers in Asia design a part that’s 3D-printed in Mexico, distributed to factories in the US for robotized assembly, and sold in target markets based on precise market demand forecasts,” said Wezowski. “With the autonomous flow of highly contextualized information, people could be prompted to step in and make their most valuable contribution. They could transact business based on values they choose, such as money or mentoring. When employees focus on companies and projects that help them grow in new ways, it's beyond business transformation. This is human transformation.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Follow me @smgaler&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;This blog also appeared on &lt;A href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/sap/2022/11/28/workplace-trends-in-the-metaverse-no-one-else-can-be-you/?sh=131c559c5326" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP BrandVoice on Forbes.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/workplace-trends-in-the-metaverse-no-one-else-can-be-you/ba-p/13549759"/>
    <published>2022-12-12T13:29:16+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/iot-3-0/ba-p/13562130</id>
    <title>IoT 3.0</title>
    <updated>2023-01-03T15:40:33+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>architectSAP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/207</uri>
    </author>
    <content>For many years I have been sending IoT data into central databases starting with &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2016/06/18/connect-a-lego-mindstorms-nxt-to-the-hcp-internet-of-things-services-via-a-raspberry-pi-over-bluetooth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Connect a Lego Mindstorms NXT to the HCP Internet of Things Services via a Raspberry Pi over Bluetooth&lt;/A&gt;, followed by &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2017/12/21/send-your-raspberry-pi-sensor-data-to-sap-vora-via-apache-kafka-managed-by-the-sap-data-hub/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Send your Raspberry Pi sensor data to SAP Vora via Apache Kafka managed by the SAP Data Hub&lt;/A&gt;, and &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2018/11/13/send-your-raspberry-pi-sensor-data-to-sap-vora-via-eclipse-paho-mqtt-managed-by-the-sap-data-hub/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Send your Raspberry Pi sensor data to SAP Vora via Eclipse Paho MQTT managed by the SAP Data Hub&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
That had advantages in that I could leverage central application logic to &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2016/06/26/display-your-lego-mindstorms-sensor-data-on-a-fiori-overview-page-and-deploy-it-to-the-hcp-portal-fiori-launchpad/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Display your Lego Mindstorms sensor data on a Fiori Overview Page and deploy it to the HCP Portal Fiori Launchpad&lt;/A&gt; or &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2017/02/25/analyse-your-raspberry-pi-i2c-sensor-data-with-the-hana-cloud-platform-predictive-services-via-the-hana-cloud-platform-iot-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Analyse your Raspberry Pi I2C sensor data with the HANA Cloud Platform, predictive services&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The architecture had been looking like this:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;A href="http://www.iconsmind.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/DB.png" /&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
IoT data sent to a central instance and retrieved back from there.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
With the emergence of &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web3" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Web 3.0&lt;/A&gt; another option presented itself:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;A href="http://www.iconsmind.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/Twitter.png" /&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
A decentralized distributed ledger holds the IoT data with the former central instance becoming an equal member.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
For this blog I leverage &lt;A href="https://github.com/revoxhere/duino-coin/wiki/Duino's-take-on-the-Internet-of-Things" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Duino IoT&lt;/A&gt; that is a feature of &lt;A href="https://github.com/revoxhere/duino-coin" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Duino-Coin&lt;/A&gt;, a hybrid crypto currency.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This time, my device is an &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ESP32" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;ESP32&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/ESP32.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
It mines Duino-Coin combining it with my IoT data:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;PRE class="language-abap"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;Core 1 received a correct job with size of 87 bytes&lt;BR /&gt;
Core 0 found a correct hash (2.62s)&lt;BR /&gt;
Core 0 retrieved job feedback: GOOD, hashrate: 21.39kH/s, share #6062&lt;BR /&gt;
Core 0 asking for a new job for user: architectSAP&lt;BR /&gt;
AHT readings: 20.22*C, 47.76% rH&lt;BR /&gt;
Core 0 received a correct job with size of 87 bytes&lt;BR /&gt;
Core 1 found a correct hash (4.63s)&lt;BR /&gt;
Core 1 retrieved job feedback: GOOD, hashrate: 21.13kH/s, share #6069&lt;BR /&gt;
Core 1 asking for a new job for user: architectSAP&lt;BR /&gt;
AHT readings: 20.22*C, 47.78% rH&lt;BR /&gt;
Core 1 received a correct job with size of 87 bytes&lt;BR /&gt;
Core 0 found a correct hash (5.54s)&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
As a result, my IoT data is stored with the blockchain and for example accessible through the Doino-Coin Web Wallet:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/architectSAP.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In my opinion, the potential for distributed ledgers for IoT is enormous especially also by reducing integration challenges and risks.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/iot-3-0/ba-p/13562130"/>
    <published>2023-01-03T15:40:33+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-end-to-end-machine-learning-solution-for-product-inspection/ba-p/13554996</id>
    <title>Building an End-To-End Machine Learning Solution for Product Inspection Centered On SAP Kyma</title>
    <updated>2023-01-31T16:44:03+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>former_member13127</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/13127</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-962113924"&gt;Overview and Motivation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Over the last few months, &lt;A href="https://sg.linkedin.com/in/sanrajmitra97" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sanraj Mitra&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vriddhi-shetty/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Shetty Vriddhi&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://sg.linkedin.com/in/declanleeler" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;myself&lt;/A&gt; have been working on a product inspection solution combining SAP solutions with external technologies. Product inspection is a key part of quality assurance where goods are assessed for compliance with the company’s standards. Due to the wide range of checklists for each product, this often is a complex procedure. By automating the simpler tasks in this process and handing these responsibilities off to a computer, we would be able to lighten the workload of inspectors and speed up the duration of the inspection.In this use case, we will be simulating product inspection of beer cartons. Using a camera and a computer vision model, we will be able to count the number of beer bottles in a passing carton to ascertain whether the carton passes or fails inspection.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-765600419"&gt;Scenario&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Imagine a conveyor belt transporting beer cartons in a factory. By mounting a camera at a vantage point along the conveyor belt, we can record the cartons as they pass by. This live feed from the camera can be used as input to a machine learning model to count the number of beer bottles in each carton.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/webapp-frontpage.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Application frontpage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-569086914"&gt;Solution Architecture and Process&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/architecture.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Solution Architecture&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Although this is an end-to-end solution, the star of the show is of course the object detection. Let's have a closer look at its process flow.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic;font-family: SAPRegular, 'Helvetica Neue', Arial, sans-serif;overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/process-flow-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Process Flow for Beer Bottle Detection&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In addition to the above process flow, an SAC dashboard and SAP Build Apps mobile application are provided for end users to review the data collected for decision making.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-372573409"&gt;In Detail&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In this section we will go into more details about each component of the architecture.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-305142623"&gt;ESP32-CAM&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The first step was to find a suitable camera to record the beer cartons as they passed by. The requirements here was the camera needed to have Wi-Fi connectivity and be programmable. We were looking to create a WebSocket connection between the camera and the serving endpoint due to the quicker speed and low overhead per message, thus we needed to be able to program the camera to do so. The ESP32-CAM is a relatively affordable microcontroller with a camera mounted that fit the bill.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
When powered, the ESP32-CAM will run a continuous loop to take a picture and send it through a WebSocket connection it establishes with the Flask app in SAP Kyma. We chose not to deploy the model on the ESP32-CAM but that is also a viable option for those who require machine learning on the edge, albeit with possible reduction in the model’s effectiveness.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-108629118"&gt;YOLOv4 Bottle Detector Model&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Next, we trained an object detection model to analyze the beer carton images from the microcontroller. To create our bottle detector model, we opted to train a YOLOv4 model on our bottle dataset. This is a process called transfer learning where we leverage the existing knowledge of a pre-built model to solve a new problem. We created a suitable dataset by using the ESP32-CAM to take images of the beer carton from the top. The areas within the image containing beer bottles are then labelled. This process is repeated with different number of bottles in the carton, with the carton at different positions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/img_7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Training Data Image Example&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/labelling-example.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Training Data Labels Example&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Once trained, the model’s weights are saved and are placed in the same Docker container as the Flask application. Using the trained model, we are able to detect how many bottles are in each picture frame, and where they are. In this way, we can label the original image with green bounding boxes wherever a bottle is detected, for easy reviewing of the model's performance.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/4-beer-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Beer Carton Enters Camera View&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/0-beer.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Beer Carton Exits Camera View&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--87884387"&gt;Flask Web App&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The web app allows us to provide an endpoint to receive the image from the ESP32-CAM. It also serves the YOLOv4 model and saves the inference results to our HANA Cloud database. In addition, the frontend provides users with the option to view a live feed of the incoming frames from the ESP32-CAM to ensure that the camera and model are operating as expected, in real-time.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The web app is containerized using Docker and pushed to Docker Hub. SAP Kyma / Kubernetes will then download the image from Docker Hub and use it to build a container to run the application. The Docker repository is linked to Kyma through the deployment yaml file.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/webapp-frontpage-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Application Frontpage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--284397892"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP) and SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
As mentioned, we also need a place to save our results. For this we used an SAP HANA Cloud HDI container. To make reading and writing to the database easier, we opted to deploy a CAP application in SAP Kyma to create a service layer. This way, we will be able to use HTTP requests and OData services to send and receive data from the database. The Flask application is able to write to the database through POST requests, while the SAP Build Apps application and SAC dashboard are able to retrieve the latest data through OData service.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/Product-Data-Schema.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Table Schema in HANA Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--480911397"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) and SAP Build Apps&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Finally, we need to provide the end users with ways to view the data collected from the application. We demonstrated the utility in two products, SAC and SAP Build Apps in serving different purposes.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The SAC dashboard aims to provide users with a higher-level view across all production metrics. Here users can analyze historic trends and numbers.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/Dashboard.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;SAC Dashboard&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Meanwhile, the SAP Build Apps app is targeted towards staff working on the ground to gain quick access to inspection data. Here, users are able to view the batch information for specific dates, with an option to drill down further and double-check on the inspections' bottle counts.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
On the Home page, the user can view basic statistics as well as select the batch date to be inspected.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/appgyver-home-page.png" height="445" width="263" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Mobile App Home Page&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
After selecting the date, a list of all cartons that were manufactured on that date will be returned. The user can thus view which cartons passed or failed the inspection.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/appgyver-inspection-list.png" height="471" width="263" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Mobile App Batch Inspection Page&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Clicking onto any row will direct the user to that specific carton's information page. A labelled image of the carton will be displayed for the user to confirm that the machine learning model's bottle count is accurate. This can also be used to spot for consistent errors in the missing bottles. For example if the middle bottle on the top row is always missing, that could indicate an issue with the machine, rather than just random error.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/01/product-page-.png" height="419" width="246" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Mobile App Product Page&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--806507621"&gt;Closing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
To summarize, we have created an end-to-end product inspection solution revolving around SAP Kyma. While this proof of concept focused on an object counting use case, it can be easily extended to more complex inspection tasks.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Many thanks to &lt;A href="https://sg.linkedin.com/in/sanrajmitra97" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sanraj Mitra&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;SPAN class="mention-scrubbed"&gt;vriddhishetty&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN class="mention-scrubbed"&gt;lsm1401&lt;/SPAN&gt;, &lt;SPAN class="mention-scrubbed"&gt;gunteralbrecht&lt;/SPAN&gt;, and &lt;SPAN class="mention-scrubbed"&gt;jayadnure&lt;/SPAN&gt; for their help and guidance throughout the development of this solution.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-an-end-to-end-machine-learning-solution-for-product-inspection/ba-p/13554996"/>
    <published>2023-01-31T16:44:03+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/industry-4-0-and-the-standard-isa-95-the-pathway-to-revolutionizing-the/ba-p/13563444</id>
    <title>Industry 4.0 and the Standard ISA-95: The Pathway to Revolutionizing the Energy Industry</title>
    <updated>2023-04-05T23:11:38+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hgouda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6987</uri>
    </author>
    <content>The digital revolution of Industry 4.0, powered by big data and digital twins, has opened up new opportunities for the energy industry. By providing closer insight into production processes, digital technologies can enable more efficient, optimized, and automated operations to improve margins, reduce costs and reduce energy consumption. The Global Energy Industry is rapidly incorporating technologies such as the internet of Things (IoT), artificial intelligence (AI), 3D printing, cloud computing, and other cutting-edge innovations to support more efficient, competitive operations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
To ensure smooth and efficient operations, it is necessary that there is industry-wide interoperability and standardization. An excellent example is the Standard ISA-95 (also known as IEC 62264), developed by the International Society of Automation (ISA).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The Standard ISA-95 helps to streamline the collection, storage, and exchange of data to enable more meaningful insights and visibility. It provides the basis for digital data integration, describing the processes and equipment that support and manage digital communications within an enterprise. It differentiates between host sites (target systems such as electric meters and PLCs) and client sites (if available). It allows host sites to effectively collect and process data from other connected sites. It does this by using four levels – each of which have a distinct role in device control, level 0 being the field devices, level 1 being the field controllers (PLCs, PACs, PACs, etc.), level 2 being the supervisory systems, and level 3 being the enterprise system.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The Standard ISA-95 supports a range of communication networks, such as proprietary and open standards like OPC UA. It is already widely implemented, enabling deep data integration, messaging, and services. It makes it easy to connect equipment and subscribe to events to get updates and manage objects and addresses in the asset model. In addition, it allows users to develop enterprise control systems rather than individual control systems.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/03/Picture-3.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: center"&gt;&lt;B&gt;The traditional ISA-95 production stack is evolving into a digital manufacturing &lt;/B&gt;&lt;B&gt;platform.&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In short, the Standard ISA-95 is an intelligent, user-friendly platform that integrates different communication protocols, enabling more efficient, cost-effective, and better-informed operations. This gives the Global Energy Industry a cost-effective way to standardize its processes over a vast network and digitalize and secure its operations. This standardized system is essential for the energy industry to realize the promise of Industry 4.0 – enabling the energy industry to revolutionize its business.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP Industry 4.0 solutions and technology can bring data-driven processes and operational flexibility to the entire energy business.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/industry-4-0.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/scm/industry-4-0.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/industry-4-0-and-the-standard-isa-95-the-pathway-to-revolutionizing-the/ba-p/13563444"/>
    <published>2023-04-05T23:11:38+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/streamlining-sensor-data-integration-enhancing-telematics-with-aws-and-sap/ba-p/13566335</id>
    <title>Streamlining Sensor Data Integration: Enhancing Telematics with AWS and SAP Digital Vehicle Hub</title>
    <updated>2023-05-30T16:21:15+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>abhishek05</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143940</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-963091074"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In the rapidly evolving world of connected vehicles, leveraging telematic data is crucial for improving operations, enhancing driver safety, and optimizing vehicle performance. Integrating various systems and databases can be complex and time-consuming, but with the right tools and strategies, it becomes an achievable goal. In this blog post, we will explore how the combination of &lt;STRONG&gt;AWS&lt;/STRONG&gt; services and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Digital Vehicle Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; can simplify the process of enabling telematic data persistence, integrating &lt;STRONG&gt;Otonomo&lt;/STRONG&gt; with&lt;STRONG&gt; Amazon Kinesis&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and displaying sensor data on SAP's user interface of SAP Digital Vehicle Hub.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-895660288"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling Telematic Data Persistence into an AWS Timeseries Database:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
One of the key steps in harnessing the power of telematic data is its persistent storage for analysis and future use. By leveraging Amazon Timeseries Database, you can store and manage vast amounts of sensor data efficiently. This eliminates the need for manual intervention, allowing a seamless and automated transfer of telematic data from vehicles to the database.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-828229502"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Reduced implementation efforts: By leveraging Amazon Timeseries Database, the process of bringing sensor data from vehicles is simplified, reducing implementation efforts significantly.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Streamlined data transfer: The automated integration enables a streamlined and efficient transfer of data from vehicles to the timeseries database.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Cost-effective storage: Amazon Timeseries database offers cost-effective storage solutions, allowing you to handle large volumes of sensor data without breaking the bank.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-502633278"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Continuing Integration of Otonomo with Amazon Kinesis:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Integrating Otonomo, a leading automotive data services platform, with Amazon Kinesis provides a powerful solution for processing and streaming real-time vehicle data. Amazon Kinesis allows you to receive and process massive volumes of sensor data at high speed, ensuring timely and accurate insights.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-435202492"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Enhanced data processing: By integrating Otonomo with Amazon Kinesis, you can efficiently process and analyze vast amounts of sensor data, unlocking valuable insights for your operations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Real-time analytics: Amazon Kinesis enables real-time data streaming, empowering you to make informed decisions and respond promptly to critical events.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Cost-effective scalability: With Amazon Kinesis, you can scale your data processing capabilities based on demand, ensuring a cost-effective solution that grows with your needs.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-109606268"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enabling Persistence of Telematic Data Using SAP Digital Vehicle Hub Naming Conventions:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP Digital Vehicle Hub is a comprehensive platform for managing vehicle-related data. By leveraging its naming conventions, you can ensure consistent and standardized storage of telematic data in the Timeseries database. This enables easy access and retrieval of sensor data when needed, enhancing the overall functionality of your system.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-42175482"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Standardized data organization: Utilizing SAP Digital Vehicle Hub's naming conventions ensures consistent and organized storage of sensor data, simplifying data retrieval and management.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Seamless integration: The integration of SAP Digital Vehicle Hub with the Timeseries database enables a seamless flow of telematic data, reducing complexity and maintenance efforts.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Improved data accessibility: With standardized naming conventions, sensor data can be easily accessed and displayed across various applications and user interfaces.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--283420742"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Displaying Sensor Data on SAP Digital Vehicle Hub's User Interface:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
To fully leverage the power of telematic data, it is crucial to present it in a user-friendly and intuitive manner. By displaying the sensor data from the Amazon Timeseries database directly into the vehicle master of SAP Digital Vehicle Hub, you can provide a comprehensive view of vehicle performance and enable informed decision-making.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--350851528"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Enhanced data visualization: Displaying sensor data on SAP Digital Vehicle Hub's user interface enables intuitive visualization, making it easier for users to interpret and analyze the information.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Improved operational insights: By presenting sensor data within the context of SAP Digital Vehicle Hub, you gain valuable insights into vehicle performance.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--805530471"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Integration details:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Prerequisite: Subscriptions to AWS and Otonomo accounts are available.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The following services are required in AWS for the integration: Kinesis Data Stream, Kinesis Data Analytics, Amazon Timestream&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Follow the below steps to set up the integration&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Configure the Streaming for fleet to send the data to AWS Kinesis from the Otonomo Dashboard&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/otonomo-dashboard-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Configure Streaming for a Fleet in Otonomo Dashboard&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create a data stream in AWS Kinesis&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/aws-kinesis-datatstream-6.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;AWS Kinesis data stream overview section&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create a Database and table in Amazon Timestream&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/amazon-timestream-3.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Amazon TImeseries tables section&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Upload the JAR file provided by SAP Digital Vehicle Hub in S3. For JAR file please reach our us by creating a ticket using component LOD-DMO-DVH (this process could change in the future)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/S3-upload-3.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Upload the provided JAR file in S3 bucket&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create a AWS Kinesis Analytics Application with the provided JAR file&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/Configure-kinesis-analytics-application-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Provide the path of the upload JAR file in S3 in configuration of streaming application&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create Runtime properties for the application&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/runtime-properties-for-kinesis-analytics-application-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Runtime Properties section for streaming application&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Once, the application is created you should be able to open the Apache Flink Dashboard and see a running job called “Preprocess and save to Timestream”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/apache-flink-dashboard-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Job in Apache Flink Dashboard&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Create a technical user in AWS with permission "AmazonTimestreamReadOnlyAccess" using IAM&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create an access key for the technical user&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create a destination in your BTP subaccount: DVH_AWS_IOT.&lt;BR /&gt;
See: &lt;SPAN class="ph emphasis emphasis"&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DIGITAL_VEHICLE_HUB/6d83a7f380b741f087e8f1401e2ec576/edb1d2b23c114615bb31d0d55efd3bc8.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Setting up destination for fetching telematics data from AWS&lt;/A&gt; for more information&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/Screenshot-2023-08-28-at-11.16.55-AM-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create a vehicle using &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/VehicleObjectAPI/path/Vehicle%20Create" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;create vehicle API&lt;/A&gt; with same vin present in Otonomo fleet and “telematicsDataSource” as “02” (AWS Kinesis Timestream).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/create-vehicle-API-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;Creating a Vehicle using Postman&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Open View/Modify Vehicles App in IAM FLP. Search for the newly created vehicle and open it. Navigate to the “Indicator Chart” section, select the sensor for which you would like to view the data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/Indicator-Chart-in-DVH-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="font-style: italic;text-align: center"&gt;Indicator Chart section in View/Modify Vehicles App&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
You should now be able to visualize the telematics data for vehicles present in your system. There also new features panned which should help you in visualize the complex data of the vehicle sensors in an easier way.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Please, share your feedback in the comments. If you have any questions, you can reach out to me or &lt;SPAN class="mention-scrubbed"&gt;harshachaithanya.kethepalle&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Also, make sure to follow the blog, we have exciting new features on the way, they will be shared in upcoming blogs.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Thanks!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/streamlining-sensor-data-integration-enhancing-telematics-with-aws-and-sap/ba-p/13566335"/>
    <published>2023-05-30T16:21:15+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/how-is-nordlaks-leveraging-iot-technology-and-cloud-processing-to-farm/ba-p/13554578</id>
    <title>How is Nordlaks Leveraging IoT Technology and Cloud Processing to Farm Salmon in a more Sustainable Way?</title>
    <updated>2023-06-20T16:25:51+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karin_fent</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/198077</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/06/Pic-Nordlaks-scaled.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
When The Department of Fisheries challenged the industry in 2015 to find new solutions for farming fish in the open seas, Norway based Nordlaks Oppdrett stepped up and won the competition based upon an innovative and sustainable approach.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Reinventing Salmon Production in a Sustainable Way&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Family owned &lt;A href="https://www.nordlaks.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Nordlaks Oppdrett AS&lt;/A&gt; has been a leader in aquaculture in Norway since the company’s founding in 1989, with comprehensive operations from breeding premium Atlantic salmon to sales and marketing. However, continuing its robust growth depends on adopting new and sustainable production methods, as space within fjords for traditional net-pen farming is limited.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Nordlaks&lt;/U&gt; realized that the answer lay in economies of scale and designed a unique sea vessel called Havfarm which is currently the largest floating structure in the world. To put it in perspective, it is almost the length of 4 football fields and is designed to have a lifetime of at least 25 years without the need to bring it into a dry dock for maintenance and repairs.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Mr. Bjarne Johnsen, Project Manager Havfarm at Nordlaks explained: “To keep up with growing global demand and support sustainable farming, we recognized the opportunity to turn to the open seas to expand production. We realized that the answer lay in economies of scale. If we built larger containers, we would no longer be restricted to the calm waters of the fjord and could afford to deploy more robust materials and sophisticated safety measures.”&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Leveraging IoT Sensors and Cloud Processing to Empower Operations and Maintenance Processes&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/STRONG&gt;It is not only the sheer size of the Havfarm that is impressive, but also the technology that empowers it.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
To take salmon aquaculture to a new level, Nordlaks looked to the latest technology to support operations and maintenance processes. They strategically placed IoT sensors on the vessel to monitor, analyze and broadcast motion data in real-time. This data is used to run the digital twin model of the vessel in&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/enterprise-product-development.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt; SAP&lt;SUP&gt;®&lt;/SUP&gt;&amp;nbsp;Enterprise Product Development (SAP EPD)&lt;/A&gt;, a cloud-based application that enables improved and streamlined processes for monitoring of operations and maintenance.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This monitoring system enables Nordlaks to focus inspections and maintenance activities on critical areas of the vessel structure, identified through Digital Twin technology and virtual sensors. It measures the integrity of the structure under adverse conditions to ensure everything from the longevity of the materials to the grip of the mooring. Furthermore, heat maps are used to monitor feed output ensuring that there is no lasting impact on the environment.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The company now has access to historic and near real-time data and actionable insights leading to improved decision-making. They can monitor the balance of the vessel to improve ballast operations. And it has now processes in place to support efficient feed spill monitoring and simplified soil sampling underneath the vessel required to meet strict compliance regulations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
As Mr. Bjarne Johnsen states “Everything we do needs to be sustainable and that means when we leave an area, there should be no trace that we were ever there. He concluded, “&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/enterprise-product-development.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Enterprise Product Development&lt;/A&gt; helps us monitor the Havfarm vessel infrastructure and environmental impacts on the seabed, which is key to our strategy for sustainable growth”.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Request a &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/cmp/td/sap-enterprise-product-development-trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;free trial&lt;/A&gt; and watch an &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/enterprise-product-development.html?video=be180455-b17d-0010-87a3-c30de2ffd8ff" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;overview video&lt;/A&gt; to learn how to enable fast, collaborative product development and lifecycle management with SAP EPD. In addition, you can watch a Nordlaks &lt;A href="https://youtu.be/eQl1EdpsfxM" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;video&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/how-is-nordlaks-leveraging-iot-technology-and-cloud-processing-to-farm/ba-p/13554578"/>
    <published>2023-06-20T16:25:51+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/events-2-business-action-framework-create-plant-maintenance-notification-in/ba-p/13573476</id>
    <title>Events-2-Business Action Framework – Create Plant Maintenance Notification in SAP S/4 HANA</title>
    <updated>2023-08-03T02:18:50+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>wolfgang_moeller_itellige</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/324750</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Companies are driving the digitization of the factory, plants, warehouses, and business networks and creating an ecosystem by linking Information Technology (IT) with Operational Technology (OT). Bridging the gaps between different landscapes and processes with integrated frameworks is key for building a seamless, efficient, bi-directional collaborative ecosystem.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This scenario is built to trigger plant maintenance notifications automatically for repair or maintenance based on critical events determined by IoT device.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The intention of the initial project was to set-up an event-driven framework based on SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) to respond to and integrate with events generated from industrial production processes in plants, warehouses, and logistics into enterprise business systems, triggering associated business processes to enhance enterprise operations and enable rapid decision-making. Target of this generic framework is to configure new scenarios rather than developing them individually. With the framework we reduce the implementation time significantly.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This scenario is fully built on the framework without individual development or modification and was validated by SAP Labs India.)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
See blog initial project shared by &lt;A href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/www.linkedin.com/in/pavankumarpvn/__;!!B0kNdk3R__Efj5F6ERhD!6Sa5xr0q5Mo3440n3enVzxzNKYM-BhjaCGecEKb_ofNcItBO3Lw-dqyhM0wQbqiC54KgKi_Xv0xRiPOTQVLDAKPQBkHaF2L8$" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;PVN PavanKumar&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;(SAP Labs India):&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/01/27/part-1-events-to-business-actions-architecture-an-event-driven-framework-on-sap-btp-to-implement-industry-4.0-scenarios-with-microsoft-azure-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://blogs.sap.com/2023/01/27/part-1-events-to-business-actions-architecture-an-event-driven-framework-on-sap-btp-to-implement-industry-4.0-scenarios-with-microsoft-azure-services/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-834843589"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Our aim is to adopt event-driven architecture, by building an&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;open-source framework on the SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;which can integrate events generated from non-SAP platforms and solutions into SAP business processes thereby extending the value of existing SAP applications and processes. The events may originate from various sources such as IoT platforms, mobile and web applications, enterprise systems, and industrial production, logistics platforms, and so on. Thus, this framework helps in making business intelligent and interconnected to improve overall process efficiency. The Event-to-Business Framework can run on your own BTP or as SaaS solution provided by NTTDATA Business Solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-1: &amp;nbsp;“Events-to-Business Actions”&amp;nbsp;Framework&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-638330084"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-570899298"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenges&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Industrial processes in factories, plants, warehouses, and logistics generate critical events from disparate and discrete industrial systems and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;there is a need to trigger business processes as a response to these events&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-374385793"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Create a Plant Maintenance Notification for the inhouse service technicians to maintain or repair an equipment, triggered by sensors reacting on changing conditions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;IoT device reports regularly status of equipment, e.g. temperature monitoring of a manufacturing machine and report to MS Azure IoT platform&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Rules for dedicated telemetry properties, e.g. abnormal temperature to trigger export of event data (temperature too high)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;“Create Plant Maintenance Notification” in SAP S/4 HANA by streaming the event to Event-to-Business Framework, where the streaming event is interpreted and enriched by business rules to create final content for functional transaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;This action payload triggers the API in the connected SAP business system, here S/4 HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-2: &amp;nbsp;Process Steps&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-48789569"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--18641217"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sensor/IoT devices determine conditions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
IoT devices with sensors monitor the operation-critical figures of an equipment and transmit them to an IoT platform for further activities. We simulate the case with an IoS App, developed by NTTDATA Business Solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-3: &amp;nbsp;Simulate abnormal temperature increase&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--215154722"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ingest the data in an IoT platform&lt;BR /&gt;
(here Microsoft Azure IoT Central)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild5.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-4: &amp;nbsp;Data Export to SAP Event Mesh&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The event data is ingested in a platform, such as an IoT platform. In our scenario we use Microsoft Azure IoT Central. But any other platform, which can export data managed by rules, can be used. We select the records which are relevant for the process with Data Export functionality. In this step we also enrich the data string with content we need in the next steps of the Event-to-Business Framework. The data string is published on to SAP Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--411668227"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activities in Event-2-Business Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild6.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-5: &amp;nbsp;UI modeler&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
As shown in&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure-5&lt;/STRONG&gt;, this framework provides an out-of-the-box UI modeler that is intuitive to configure different types of actions like workflow or process execution that can be taken in SAP backend systems as an outcome of the incoming events from external sources via SAP Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--608181732"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Actions &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In this scenario with our preconfigured actions, we create a plant maintenance notification in a SAP S/4 HANA system. For flexible configuration we use main actions (for each transaction), which can be chained with pre-action and post-action activities.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-6: &amp;nbsp;Action Categories&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild8.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-7: &amp;nbsp;Actions to create Plant Maintenance Notification&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This framework leverages business rules capability within the SAP Build Process Automation, which lets you automatically choose a business action that should be executed for an incoming event based on the configured decision tables.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
For the creation of a Plant Maintenance Notification you need the Main-Action to feed the API with all required fields to execute the transaction. The data to feed the API has its source in the IoT platform (see Enrichment) or is derived from business rules. A Pre-Action fetches the derived data from the business rules, e.g. maintenance plant, notification type. The Post-Action is used for actions after the successful execution of the Main-Action. In this case we use it to set the status and notification number in the device in MS Azure IoT. With that we avoid that the event is executed again after already creating a notification in SAP Plant Maintenance.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--804695237"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Rules &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--653954385"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild9.png" /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-8: &amp;nbsp;Business Rules&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The Business Rule triggered by the action, for Plant Maintenance Notification the Pre-Action triggers the Business Rule to determine relevant parameters to feed the payload of the Main-Action.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Using If – Then Rules to determine Notification Type, Maintenance Plant, Asset Location etc. based on Device Location (information from MS Azure IoT Enrichments).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--850467890"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Logging&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild10.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-9: &amp;nbsp;Error Log&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Every transaction processed is recorded in the (error) log. From the log lauchpad you can control the details of the event with its payload. A restart function is on the SAP development roadmap.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--753578388"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reference Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The architecture is based on leveraging the services of&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform which includes event-based integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP Event Mesh, the upcoming event bridging functionality of SAP Integration Suite (Beta), Advanced Event Mesh (to be updated), Business rules capability in SAP Build Process Automation coming from SAP Workflow Management, SAP Destination Service, SAP Private Link service, SAP Connectivity Service and Cloud Connector and a Node.js extension application on the SAP Cloud Foundry runtime.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild11.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-10: &amp;nbsp;High-level architecture with SAP S/4HANA on-premise and private cloud&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;following steps depict the information flow across systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(1)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Event is triggered from Microsoft Azure and is published on to SAP Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In Event-to-Business-Action framework (extension app),&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(2)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;processor module endpoint is subscribed to SAP Event Mesh to receive the event.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(3)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;processor module leverages the Business Rules capability of SAP Build Process Automation to derive business action (For example, Purchase Order Requisition creation in SAP S/4HANA system) based on certain characteristics of incoming event.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(4), (5), (6),&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;(7)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;(8)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;processor module triggers the defined action in the SAP S/4HANA system using the SAP Destination Service and SAP Private Link Service.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In case SAP S/4HANA is on-premise and private cloud (refer to Figure-6) – communication with SAP S/4HANA happens via SAP Connectivity Service and Cloud Connector.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(9)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;(10)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;are on the SAP development roadmap. SAP S/4HANA publishes an event (e.g., Plant Maintenance Notification creation) to Microsoft Azure Event Grid via SAP Event Mesh Connectivity Bridge for further processing by Microsoft Azure applications.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1243494900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Advantages of This Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Developers implementing this framework architecture would benefit from the following design considerations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;A flexible and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;generic framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that can be&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;easily extensible for any Line of Business (LoB)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;scenario /workflow/process and any source system events.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Event-driven integration architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP Event Mesh as a central hub, including a bi-directional flow of events (Microsoft Azure to SAP S/4HANA and vice versa). We are also evaluating on leveraging Advanced Event Mesh (to be updated soon).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Enriched with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;resilient and high availability&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;architectural patterns.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network security-focused design&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP Private Link specifically for RISE with SAP customers between SAP BTP on Azure (any region) and SAP S/4HANA on Microsoft Azure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1146605398"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario Setup and Deployment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
To get the entire scenario working, there are prerequisites and initial configurations required in SAP Business Technology Platform, Microsoft Azure, and SAP S/4HANA.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Please refer to the published GitHub repository and Discovery Center mission of the initial set-up (see blog).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1343118903"&gt;About Author&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild12.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/events-2-business-action-framework-create-plant-maintenance-notification-in/ba-p/13573476"/>
    <published>2023-08-03T02:18:50+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/simplifying-the-iot-puzzle-with-sap-asset-performance-management-and/ba-p/13579517</id>
    <title>Simplifying the IoT Puzzle with SAP Asset Performance Management and Cumulocity IoT</title>
    <updated>2023-08-16T16:23:24+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>former_member478976</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/478976</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Following up from my previous &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2022/10/05/sap-iot-retirement-and-sap-asset-performance-management/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; on SAP Asset Performance Management (APM) and SAP IoT, I'd like to share some additional thoughts about IoT and APM, because we see such a diverse range of different customer situations. While some customers have started rationalising on a preferred ‘strategic’ IoT platform, others have a range of IoT tools, and many have inherited extensive&amp;nbsp; applications and historians which will remain valuable data sources. &amp;nbsp;In almost all customers we see&amp;nbsp; a mix of these scenarios, and no ‘one platform’ nirvana.&amp;nbsp; Therefore, I’d like to reiterate how important it is for APM to provide robust IoT capabilities as well as a flexible integration framework to simplify this IoT puzzle.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
As we see our customers continue to rationalize their IT/OT platforms and shift to a more outcome based approach, our APM IoT strategy will continue to be agnostic and be able to ingest equipment/sensor data from any data source or end point: smart or IoT devices/edge gateways, data historians and data lakes, and other IoT/OT platforms or middleware. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Furthermore, APM offers standard integrations with SAP S/4HANA and ECC Plant Maintenance and it can blend maintenance records and inspection data and measuring documents along with sensor timeseries data to provide a complete view of the asset health for condition-based maintenance (CBM) and predictive maintenance (PdM).&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Some of CBM/PdM connectivity use cases that we have seen in our customer’s project include:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Oil &amp;amp; gas customers with data historians and data lake via REST APIs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Utilities customers with SCADA systems via OPC UA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Transportation customer with connected assets via MQTT and edge&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Industrial manufacturing customers with shopfloor systems via Plant Connectivity (PCo)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
You might have seen this &lt;A href="https://newscenter.softwareag.com/en/news-stories/press-releases/2023/0816-software-ag-and-sap-join-forces-to-innovate-on-asset-performance-management-solution-with-cumulocity-iot-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;press release&lt;/A&gt; from Software AG announcing that they are with working us on integration with SAP Asset Performance Management.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This relationship is a great example of our strategy at work – integration with their &lt;A href="https://www.softwareag.com/en_corporate/platform/iot/iiot-platform-gartner.html?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;amp;utm_campaign=iot_smart-products&amp;amp;utm_region=hq&amp;amp;utm_subcampaign=stg-2&amp;amp;utm_content=stg-2_anaylst-report_gartner-mq-global-iiot-platforms-2022&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwwvilBhCFARIsADvYi7JexsDG47lSV_Niqd9vPf531cQzhK2fTXreD4K9F8f9Wbpyk3XoTKkaAhfiEALw_wcB" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;market-leading Cumulocity IoT&lt;/A&gt; will help our joint, existing and new, customers to simplify their IoT connectivity scenarios and focus on leveraging their IoT data to optimize their maintenance plans and activities.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/softwareag.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
We also see this relationship opening the door for more innovative use cases such as &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2022/09/02/its-time-to-get-serious-about-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;servitization&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp; As our equipment manufacturing customers start to roll out as-a-service business models, Cumulocity IoT and SAP Asset Performance Management can help ensure the smart equipment/product is always working and optimize the maintenance schedules based on actual usage and health conditions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Please watch this space and we will have more IoT-related news later this year.&amp;nbsp; To learn more about SAP Asset Performance Management, please visit sap.com/apm and check out my latest APM Overview webinar &lt;A href="https://gateway.on24.com/wcc/eh/3582337/lp/4208753/sap-asset-performance-management-solution-overview?source=email-smc" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/simplifying-the-iot-puzzle-with-sap-asset-performance-management-and/ba-p/13579517"/>
    <published>2023-08-16T16:23:24+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/events-2-business-action-framework-create-service-ticket-in-sap-cx/ba-p/13572338</id>
    <title>Events-2-Business Action Framework – Create Service Ticket in SAP CX</title>
    <updated>2023-08-25T16:28:28+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>wolfgang_moeller_itellige</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/324750</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Companies are driving the digitization of the factory, plants, warehouses, and business networks and creating an ecosystem by linking Information Technology (IT) with Operational Technology (OT). Bridging the gaps between different landscapes and processes with integrated frameworks is key for building a seamless, efficient, bi-directional collaborative ecosystem.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This scenario is built to trigger service tickets in SAP CX automatically for repair or maintenance based on critical events determined by IoT device.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The intention of the initial project was to set-up an event-driven framework based on SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) to respond to and integrate with events generated from industrial production processes in plants, warehouses, and logistics into enterprise business systems, triggering associated business processes to enhance enterprise operations and enable rapid decision-making. Target of this generic framework is to configure new scenarios rather than developing them individually. With the framework we reduce the implementation time significantly.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This scenario is fully built on the framework without individual development or modification.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
See blog initial project shared by &lt;A href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/www.linkedin.com/in/pavankumarpvn/__;!!B0kNdk3R__Efj5F6ERhD!6Sa5xr0q5Mo3440n3enVzxzNKYM-BhjaCGecEKb_ofNcItBO3Lw-dqyhM0wQbqiC54KgKi_Xv0xRiPOTQVLDAKPQBkHaF2L8$" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;PVN PavanKumar&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;(SAP Labs India):&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/01/27/part-1-events-to-business-actions-architecture-an-event-driven-framework-on-sap-btp-to-implement-industry-4.0-scenarios-with-microsoft-azure-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://blogs.sap.com/2023/01/27/part-1-events-to-business-actions-architecture-an-event-driven-framework-on-sap-btp-to-implement-industry-4.0-scenarios-with-microsoft-azure-services/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
See my blog about Events-2-Business Action Framework –&lt;BR /&gt;
Create Plant Maintenance Notification in SAP S/4 HANA&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/08/03/events-2-business-action-framework-create-plant-maintenance-notification-in-sap-s-4-hana/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://blogs.sap.com/2023/08/03/events-2-business-action-framework-create-plant-maintenance-notification-in-sap-s-4-hana/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Our approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Our aim is to adopt event-driven architecture, by building an&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;open-source framework on the SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;which can integrate events generated from non-SAP platforms and solutions into SAP business processes thereby extending the value of existing SAP applications and processes. The events may originate from various sources such as IoT platforms, mobile and web applications, enterprise systems, and industrial production, logistics platforms, and so on. Thus, this framework helps in making business intelligent and interconnected to improve overall process efficiency. The Event-to-Business Framework can run on your own BTP or as SaaS solution provided by NTTDATA Business Solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild1-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-1: &amp;nbsp;“Events-to-Business Actions”&amp;nbsp;Framework&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-834812715"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-767381929"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenges&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Industrial processes in factories, plants, warehouses, and logistics generate critical events from disparate and discrete industrial systems and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;there is a need to trigger business processes as a response to these events&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-699951143"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Create Service Ticket for external service technician to repair or maintain equipment&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;IoT device reports regularly status of equipment, i.e. manufacturing machine to MS Azure IoT platform&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Rules for dedicated telemetry property, i.e. oil consmption to trigger export of exception data (oil consumption too high)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Stream event and interpret content enriched by business rules to create functional transaction for&lt;BR /&gt;
“Create SAP CX Service Ticket“&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Trigger posting mechanism in SAP CX&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/cx.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-2: &amp;nbsp;Process Steps&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-245272200"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-177841414"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sensor/IoT devices determine conditions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
IoT devices with sensors monitor the operation-critical figures of an equipment and transmit them to an IoT platform for further activities. We simulate the case with an IoS App, developed by NTTDATA Business Solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/cx2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-3: &amp;nbsp;Simulate abnormal temperature increase&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--18672091"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ingest the data in an IoT platform&lt;BR /&gt;
(here Microsoft Azure IoT Central)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/cx3.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-4: &amp;nbsp;Data Export to SAP Event Mesh&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The event data is ingested in a platform, such as an IoT platform. In our scenario we use Microsoft Azure IoT Central. But any other platform, which can export data managed by rules, can be used. We select the records which are relevant for the process with Data Export functionality. In this step we also enrich the data string with content we need in the next steps of the Event-to-Business Framework. The data string is published on to SAP Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--215185596"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activities in Event-2-Business Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild6-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-5: &amp;nbsp;UI modeler&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
As shown in&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure-5&lt;/STRONG&gt;, this framework provides an out-of-the-box UI modeler that is intuitive to configure different types of actions like workflow or process execution that can be taken in SAP backend systems as an outcome of the incoming events from external sources via SAP Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--411699101"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Actions &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In this scenario with our preconfigured actions, we create a service ticket SAP CX system. For flexible configuration we use main actions (for each transaction), which can be chained with pre-action and post-action activities.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild7-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-6: &amp;nbsp;Action Categories&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/cx4.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-7: &amp;nbsp;Actions to create Service Ticket&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
This framework leverages business rules capability within the SAP Build Process Automation, which lets you automatically choose a business action that should be executed for an incoming event based on the configured decision tables.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
For the creation of a Service Ticket you need the Main-Action to feed the API with all required fields to execute the transaction. The data to feed the API has its source in the IoT platform (see Enrichment) or is derived from business rules. A Pre-Action fetches the derived data from the business rules, e.g. service priority, service category. The Post-Action is used for actions after the successful execution of the Main-Action. In this case we use it to set the status and ticket number in the device in MS Azure IoT. With that we avoid that the event is executed again after already creating a service ticket in SAP CX.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--608212606"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Rules&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/cx5.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-8: &amp;nbsp;Business Rules&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;The Business Rule triggered by the action, for Service Ticket the Pre-Action triggers the Business Rule to determine relevant parameters to feed the payload of the Main-Action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Using If – Then Rules to determine Service Priority, Incident Category, Service Category, etc. from Pump Type of Device.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--804726111"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Logging&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild10-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-9: &amp;nbsp;Error Log&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Every transaction processed is recorded in the (error) log. From the log lauchpad you can control the details of the event with its payload. A restart function is on the SAP development roadmap.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--360582252"&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--557095757"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reference Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The architecture is based on leveraging the services of&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform which includes event-based integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP Event Mesh, the upcoming event bridging functionality of SAP Integration Suite (Beta), Advanced Event Mesh (to be updated), Business rules capability in SAP Build Process Automation coming from SAP Workflow Management, SAP Destination Service, SAP Private Link service, SAP Connectivity Service and Cloud Connector and a Node.js extension application on the SAP Cloud Foundry runtime.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild11-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-10: &amp;nbsp;High-level architecture with SAP CX&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;following steps depict the information flow across systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(1)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Event is triggered from Microsoft Azure and is published on to SAP Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In Event-to-Business-Action framework (extension app),&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(2)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;processor module endpoint is subscribed to SAP Event Mesh to receive the event.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(3)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;processor module leverages the Business Rules capability of SAP Build Process Automation to derive business action (For example, Purchase Order Requisition creation in SAP S/4HANA system) based on certain characteristics of incoming event.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(4), (5), (6),&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;(7)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;(8)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;processor module triggers the defined action in the SAP S/4HANA system using the SAP Destination Service and SAP Private Link Service.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In case SAP S/4HANA is on-premise and private cloud (refer to Figure-6) – communication with SAP S/4HANA happens via SAP Connectivity Service and Cloud Connector.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(9)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;(10)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;are on the SAP development roadmap. SAP S/4HANA publishes an event (e.g., Plant Maintenance Notification creation) to Microsoft Azure Event Grid via SAP Event Mesh Connectivity Bridge for further processing by Microsoft Azure applications.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1047012269"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Advantages of This Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Developers implementing this framework architecture would benefit from the following design considerations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;A flexible and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;generic framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that can be&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;easily extensible for any Line of Business (LoB)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;scenario /workflow/process and any source system events.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Event-driven integration architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP Event Mesh as a central hub, including a bi-directional flow of events (Microsoft Azure to SAP S/4HANA and vice versa). We are also evaluating on leveraging Advanced Event Mesh (to be updated soon).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Enriched with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;resilient and high availability&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;architectural patterns.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network security-focused design&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP Private Link specifically for RISE with SAP customers between SAP BTP on Azure (any region) and SAP S/4HANA on Microsoft Azure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--950122767"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario Setup and Deployment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
To get the entire scenario working, there are prerequisites and initial configurations required in SAP Business Technology Platform, Microsoft Azure, and SAP S/4HANA.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Please refer to the published GitHub repository and Discovery Center mission of the initial set-up (see blog).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1146636272"&gt;About Author&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild12-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/events-2-business-action-framework-create-service-ticket-in-sap-cx/ba-p/13572338"/>
    <published>2023-08-25T16:28:28+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/events-2-business-framework-create-shopfloor-confirmation-in-sap-s-4-hana/ba-p/13573509</id>
    <title>Events-2-Business Framework – Create Shopfloor Confirmation in SAP S/4 HANA</title>
    <updated>2023-08-29T16:32:25+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>wolfgang_moeller_itellige</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/324750</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Companies are driving the digitization of the factory, plants, warehouses, and business networks and creating an ecosystem by linking Information Technology (IT) with Operational Technology (OT). Bridging the gaps between different landscapes and processes with integrated frameworks is key for building a seamless, efficient, bi-directional collaborative ecosystem.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This scenario is built to trigger service tickets in SAP CX automatically for repair or maintenance based on critical events determined by IoT device.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The intention of the initial project was to set-up an event-driven framework based on SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) to respond to and integrate with events generated from industrial production processes in plants, warehouses, and logistics into enterprise business systems, triggering associated business processes to enhance enterprise operations and enable rapid decision-making. Target of this generic framework is to configure new scenarios rather than developing them individually. With the framework we reduce the implementation time significantly.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This scenario is fully built on the framework without individual development or modification.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
See blog initial project shared by &lt;A href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/www.linkedin.com/in/pavankumarpvn/__;!!B0kNdk3R__Efj5F6ERhD!6Sa5xr0q5Mo3440n3enVzxzNKYM-BhjaCGecEKb_ofNcItBO3Lw-dqyhM0wQbqiC54KgKi_Xv0xRiPOTQVLDAKPQBkHaF2L8$" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;PVN PavanKumar &lt;/A&gt;(SAP Labs India)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/01/27/part-1-events-to-business-actions-architecture-an-event-driven-framework-on-sap-btp-to-implement-industry-4.0-scenarios-with-microsoft-azure-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://blogs.sap.com/2023/01/27/part-1-events-to-business-actions-architecture-an-event-driven-framework-on-sap-btp-to-implement-industry-4.0-scenarios-with-microsoft-azure-services/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
See my blog about Events-2-Business Action Framework –&lt;BR /&gt;
Create Plant Maintenance Notification in SAP S/4 HANA&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/08/03/events-2-business-action-framework-create-plant-maintenance-notification-in-sap-s-4-hana/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://blogs.sap.com/2023/08/03/events-2-business-action-framework-create-plant-maintenance-notification-in-sap-s-4-hana/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-834844336"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Our approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Our aim is to adopt event-driven architecture, by building an&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;open-source framework on the SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;which can integrate events generated from non-SAP platforms and solutions into SAP business processes thereby extending the value of existing SAP applications and processes. The events may originate from various sources such as IoT platforms, mobile and web applications, enterprise systems, and industrial production, logistics platforms, and so on. Thus, this framework helps in making business intelligent and interconnected to improve overall process efficiency. The Event-to-Business Framework can run on your own BTP or as SaaS solution provided by NTTDATA Business Solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-1: &amp;nbsp;“Events-to-Business Actions”&amp;nbsp;Framework&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-638330831"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-570900045"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenges&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Industrial processes in factories, plants, warehouses, and logistics generate critical events from disparate and discrete industrial systems and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;there is a need to trigger business processes as a response to these events&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-374386540"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Create Shop Floor Confirmation (here with NTT DATA IoTConnect App)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Simulation of a packing process in shopfloor which needs a worker confirmation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;We simulate the recording of&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Packed good parts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Scrap&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Rework&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;This leads to a partial confirmation on a shopfloor order&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;App triggers data record for each case and report to MS Azure IoT platform&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Stream each event and interpret content enriched by business rules to create functional transaction for “Shopfloor order confirmation“&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Trigger posting mechanism in SAP S/4 HANA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/pp-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-2: &amp;nbsp;Process Steps&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-48790316"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Process steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--18640470"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sensor/IoT devices determine conditions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
IoT devices with sensors monitor the operation-critical figures of an equipment and transmit them to an IoT platform for further activities. We simulate the case with an IoS App, developed by NTTDATA Business Solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/pp-4.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-3: &amp;nbsp;Simulate Shopfloor Confirmation&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--215153975"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ingest the data in an IoT platform&lt;BR /&gt;
(here Microsoft Azure IoT Central)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/pp-6.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-4: &amp;nbsp;Data Export to SAP Event Mesh&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The event data is ingested in a platform, such as an IoT platform. In our scenario we use Microsoft Azure IoT Central. But any other platform, which can export data managed by rules, can be used. We select the records which are relevant for the process with Data Export functionality. In this step we also enrich the data string with content we need in the next steps of the Event-to-Business Framework. The data string is published on to SAP Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--411667480"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activities in Event-2-Business Framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild6.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-5: &amp;nbsp;UI modeler&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
As shown in&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Figure-5&lt;/STRONG&gt;, this framework provides an out-of-the-box UI modeler that is intuitive to configure different types of actions like workflow or process execution that can be taken in SAP backend systems as an outcome of the incoming events from external sources via SAP Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--608180985"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Actions &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In this scenario with our preconfigured actions, we create a shopfloor confirmations in a SAP S/4 HANA system. For flexible configuration we use main actions (for each transaction), which can be chained with pre-action and post-action activities.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-6: &amp;nbsp;Action Categories&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/pp-7.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-7: &amp;nbsp;Actions to create Shopfloor Confirmation&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
This framework leverages business rules capability within the SAP Build Process Automation, which lets you automatically choose a business action that should be executed for an incoming event based on the configured decision tables.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
For the creation of a Shopfloor Confirmation you need the Main-Action to feed the API with all required fields to execute the transaction. The data to feed the API has its source in the IoT platform (see Enrichment) or is derived from business rules. A Pre-Action fetches the derived data from the business rules. The Post-Action is used for actions after the successful execution of the Main-Action. In this case we use it to update the production order and confirmation number in the device in MS Azure IoT.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--804694490"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Rules&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/pp-8.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-8: &amp;nbsp;Business Rules&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--653953638"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Logging&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild10.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-9: &amp;nbsp;Error Log&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Every transaction processed is recorded in the (error) log. From the log lauchpad you can control the details of the event with its payload. A restart function is on the SAP development roadmap.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--557064136"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reference Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The architecture is based on leveraging the services of&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform which includes event-based integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP Event Mesh, the upcoming event bridging functionality of SAP Integration Suite (Beta), Advanced Event Mesh (to be updated), Business rules capability in SAP Build Process Automation coming from SAP Workflow Management, SAP Destination Service, SAP Private Link service, SAP Connectivity Service and Cloud Connector and a Node.js extension application on the SAP Cloud Foundry runtime.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild11.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure-10: &amp;nbsp;High-level architecture with SAP S/4HANA on-premise and private cloud&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;following steps depict the information flow across systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(1)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Event is triggered from Microsoft Azure and is published on to SAP Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In Event-to-Business-Action framework (extension app),&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(2)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;processor module endpoint is subscribed to SAP Event Mesh to receive the event.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(3)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;processor module leverages the Business Rules capability of SAP Build Process Automation to derive business action (For example, Purchase Order Requisition creation in SAP S/4HANA system) based on certain characteristics of incoming event.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(4), (5), (6),&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;(7)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;(8)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;processor module triggers the defined action in the SAP S/4HANA system using the SAP Destination Service and SAP Private Link Service.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In case SAP S/4HANA is on-premise and private cloud (refer to Figure-6) – communication with SAP S/4HANA happens via SAP Connectivity Service and Cloud Connector.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;(9)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;(10)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;are on the SAP development roadmap. SAP S/4HANA publishes an event (e.g., Plant Maintenance Notification creation) to Microsoft Azure Event Grid via SAP Event Mesh Connectivity Bridge for further processing by Microsoft Azure applications.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1046980648"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Advantages of This Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Developers implementing this framework architecture would benefit from the following design considerations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;A flexible and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;generic framework&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;that can be&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;easily extensible for any Line of Business (LoB)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;scenario /workflow/process and any source system events.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Event-driven integration architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP Event Mesh as a central hub, including a bi-directional flow of events (Microsoft Azure to SAP S/4HANA and vice versa). We are also evaluating on leveraging Advanced Event Mesh (to be updated soon).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Enriched with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;resilient and high availability&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;architectural patterns.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Network security-focused design&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP Private Link specifically for RISE with SAP customers between SAP BTP on Azure (any region) and SAP S/4HANA on Microsoft Azure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--950091146"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario Setup and Deployment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
To get the entire scenario working, there are prerequisites and initial configurations required in SAP Business Technology Platform, Microsoft Azure, and SAP S/4HANA.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Please refer to the published GitHub repository and Discovery Center mission of the initial set-up (see blog).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1146604651"&gt;About Author&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/E2B-Bild12.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/events-2-business-framework-create-shopfloor-confirmation-in-sap-s-4-hana/ba-p/13573509"/>
    <published>2023-08-29T16:32:25+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/be-ready-future-proofing-asset-management-in-your-organization/ba-p/13571764</id>
    <title>Be Ready: Future-Proofing Asset Management in Your Organization</title>
    <updated>2023-10-20T17:22:09+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Richard_Howells</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170530</uri>
    </author>
    <content>My basement flooded a few weeks ago, and my wife was on a mission to get to the bottom of the issue. And like any good husband, I got out of her way, and let here get to the root of the problem.&amp;nbsp; As it happens, due to unprecedented rain fall over a very short space of time (who says there is no such thing as climate change) the sump pump, the device that protects us against flooding, had failed. Unfortunately, it was not smart enough to alert us to this situation and simply gave up.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
And this is a metaphor for the challenges we are seeing from larger disruptions all over the world, from the impacts of environmental, geopolitical, and other types of risks.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/10/maint.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;Yet, if you work at all in &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/asset-management-eam.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;asset management&lt;/A&gt;, you’ve probably felt the impact of disruption much more deeply than most. Asset management and &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/field-service-management.html?campaigncode=crm-ya22-int-1517076&amp;amp;source=ppc-de-google_ads-search-71700000112013028-58700008463511428-dsc_dsc-x-x-x&amp;amp;dfa=1&amp;amp;gad=1&amp;amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwgZCoBhBnEiwAz35Rwsil6EszIahgd1O2pASW5KKRngrIvCw0P9Uhfw8rsQyyLjf07tHD2BoCFxYQAvD_BwE&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;field service management&lt;/A&gt; are among the operations most hurt by unexpected events as well as environmental, geopolitical, and other types of risk. In fact, when companies aren’t careful, many disruptions to business actually start with an asset failure (like my sump pump).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
That’s why asset management is evolving. The future of modern asset management is always on, increasingly intelligent, and now – accessible wherever you are.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-963869576"&gt;Supporting asset management’s role in strong supply chains&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
As we move to the future, asset management continues to grow in importance. That’s because asset management professionals are responsible for a rapidly growing network of, often very expensive, equipment, and much of this equipment is more complex – and intelligent – than ever before. Advanced technologies such as IOT and &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence.html#active_tab_item_1680650651731" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;artificial intelligence&lt;/A&gt; (AI) are increasingly available and play a role in effectively executing business processes. In field service management, there are a greater number of field service operators, too, spread across a larger range of services and supporting more customers.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Whether you’re managing your own assets or providing asset management services to customers, these operations have never been more demanding of your time and attention. However, despite this growing complexity, many businesses continue to depend on the asset management and field service management software designed for the equipment and processes of 20 years ago. This software isn’t prepared to support the demands of modern equipment – or the disruptions of tomorrow.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The latest generation of asset management software connects business processes by closing the loop between asset strategy and maintenance execution, helps companies make better decisions by contextualizing their asset health and performance data through real-time insights, and supports improved collaboration with the ecosystem through network solutions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-767356071"&gt;Enabling asset management in the moment and on the go&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
As you look to the future, it’s time to ask yourself one all-important question: how can my assets be always-on, even if my asset management software and professionals aren’t?&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Any asset management software will focus on keeping your assets up and running, but the right asset management software will do so by empowering your workers anytime, anywhere.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-570842566"&gt;A brief look back in time&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Early 2020 posed an extreme challenge for those businesses that didn’t have the tools or data integration to continue supporting everyday operations off site. You may now offer your workers some asset management tools on mobile, but do they provide all the features workers need to do their jobs and keep your assets running? Are they integrated and serving the data insights workers need to make fast, accurate decisions?&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Modern asset management software is designed for a holistic approach to asset management that empowers you to connect, contextualize, and collaborate. Ultimately, it’s one part of a whole business that doesn’t work as intended when it’s siloed away from other operations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
For example, if you’re a manufacturer, your asset management team should be able to collaborate freely with operators and service providers. The impact of disruption is compounded by silos across the business. In field service management, you should be able to integrate front- and back-office processes for effective collaboration across teams – while keeping customers informed.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-374329061"&gt;Expecting the unexpected with predictive analytics&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The seasonally high rain fall in my area wasn’t a complete surprise. However, the failure of my asset (the sump-pump) was. I had no way of knowing that it was going to break down. Why?&amp;nbsp; Because it didn’t tell me! I didn’t have the data. Why didn’t I have an app on my phone to alert me when the water level got to a certain point? Or when the part started to fail (which was probably several weeks ago)?&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In that same way, the right data and predictive analytics can help your business prepare for what’s next in asset management.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
For example, AI-based predictive maintenance is designed to help you determine a piece of equipment’s failure curve based on calculated probabilities. With these insights, you can clearly see the equipment’s remaining useful life and quickly make the best decision for your business. Predictive analytics can also reveal the likelihood of service needs for specific operations or customers by analyzing historical data from previous service requests.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
AI enhances your understanding of asset operations and helps you make more-informed decisions, especially when these insights are available on mobile for your workers on the go. Embedding AI into asset management can help you get on the path to achieving your most important asset management goals, such as eliminating unplanned asset downtime and increasing resource utilization. &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/asset-management-eam.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enterprise asset management&lt;/A&gt; (EAM) solutions from SAP include AI-powered capabilities such as these.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
EAM solutions from SAP, including the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/field-service-management.html?campaigncode=crm-ya22-int-1517076&amp;amp;source=ppc-de-google_ads-search-71700000112013028-58700008463511428-dsc_dsc-x-x-x&amp;amp;dfa=1&amp;amp;gad=1&amp;amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwgZCoBhBnEiwAz35Rwsil6EszIahgd1O2pASW5KKRngrIvCw0P9Uhfw8rsQyyLjf07tHD2BoCFxYQAvD_BwE&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Field Service Management&lt;/A&gt; solution, can help you create a more-resilient supply chain, deliver service precision, and revolutionize equipment performance. To learn more about SAP solutions and how they help enable modern, mobile asset management, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/field-service-management/features.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;visit us online&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Also, &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/cmp/dg/arc-report-Intelligent-asset-management/index.html?source=blog-glo-dsc-sapcommunity-beready" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;download&lt;/A&gt; the ARC Advisory Group report to learn how asset-intensive companies are rethinking their asset management priorities.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Oh! My wife now has a smart pump, and an app on her mobile phone to tell her exactly how it is performing. What else would you get your wife of 30 years on her wedding anniversary.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/be-ready-future-proofing-asset-management-in-your-organization/ba-p/13571764"/>
    <published>2023-10-20T17:22:09+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/aws-and-sap-joint-reference-architecture-for-iot-scenarios-using-amazon/ba-p/13580723</id>
    <title>AWS and SAP – Joint reference Architecture for IoT scenarios using Amazon Monitron</title>
    <updated>2023-11-14T14:30:24+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>praveenpadegal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/804325</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;When industrial machinery breaks down, it often results in significant operational downtime. Predictive maintenance can alleviate many issues related to equipment upkeep, but its implementation is not without challenges. The process usually requires the integration of sensors, data infrastructure, data analysis, and machine learning, a blend of software and hardware skills that often leads to lengthy setup periods and delayed return on investment. Therefore, it is vital to find a solution for managing equipment failure that seamlessly integrates with existing business procedures for asset management and plant maintenance.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Amazon &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Monitron&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; enables the customers to implement a predictive maintenance program and reduce unplanned downtime.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt; customers &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;use &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Enterprise &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Asset Management &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to create maintenance notifications for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;industrial equipment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/11/flow1-2.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog post,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; we will walk you through a framework on SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) with which we can provide an integration framework between Amazon Monitron and SAP S/4HANA Asset Management and thereby automating the process of creating maintenance notifications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the upcoming sections of the blog post, we will describe the solution architecture, systems involved, PoC scenario and a quick demo followed by the instructions to deploy the solution from a GitHub repository.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1093845900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Engagement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/11/joint2-1.png" border="0" width="427" height="86" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The outcome described in this article was facilitated by an engagement between&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/STRONG&gt; which resulted in the creation and validation of a joint reference architecture use cases and PoC. Teams from &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/pavankumarpvn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;PVN Pavan Kumar&lt;/A&gt; (&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/saplabsindia/mycompany/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Labs India&lt;/A&gt;) and &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/soulat-khan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Soulat Khan&lt;/A&gt; (&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/amazon-web-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/A&gt;) have participated in this engagement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-897332395"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Predictive maintenance plays a crucial role in helping industries avoid downtime by using advanced analytics and machine learning algorithms to predict equipment failures before they occur. By analyzing historical data and real-time sensor readings, it can identify patterns and anomalies that indicate potential issues. This enables proactive maintenance thereby minimizing the impact on production.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this scenario, abnormal conditions are detected and the events are generated and sent to the Events-to-Business Action Framework which maps it to an associated business action, which in this case, is to create a maintenance notification in SAP S/4HANA Asset Management. The business value of this integration helps industries to improve operational efficiency and ensure uninterrupted production.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Amazon Monitron is an end-to-end system&lt;/STRONG&gt; that uses machine learning to detect abnormal conditions in industrial rotating equipment, enabling you to implement a predictive maintenance program and reduce unplanned downtime. It includes sensors to capture vibration and temperature data, a gateway to securely transfer data to AWS, a service that analyzes the data using machine learning (ML), and a companion mobile and desktop app to set up the devices and track the condition of your machinery. The Monitron service can export data to a kinesis stream and S3, making data available for downstream SAP integration. For more information, please check out&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://aws.amazon.com/monitron/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Amazon Monitron&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/11/Monitron-1-1.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/11/monitron-2.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Image courtesy : &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://aws.amazon.com/pm/monitron" target="test_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://aws.amazon.com/pm/monitron&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Asset Management (EAM)&lt;/STRONG&gt; helps organizations to plan, optimize, execute, and track the necessary activities, priorities, skills, materials, tools, and information associated with an asset. Failure to manage and maintain enterprise assets can lead to unplanned downtime, suboptimal asset performance, and supply shortages. Customers also rely on EAM systems to demonstrate compliance with regulatory bodies to preclude liability if a failure occurs. To learn more about SAP EAM solution, refer &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/sea/products/scm/asset-management-eam.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Enterprise Asset Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/11/eam.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-700818890"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/11/sol-arch.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The following steps depicts the information flow across systems:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(1) Event is triggered from Amazon Monitron Hardware and sent to Amazon Monitron Software.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(2) and (3) Amazon Kinesis streams the sensor data from Amazon Monitron and lands it into the Amazon S3 bucket.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(4) AWS Lambda is a serverless function, which will orchestrate the process of detecting a stream contains any alerts related to failure or warnings, and then the inference result is passed to SAP Advanced Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(5a) AWS secrets manager is used to store credentials; these are used by the lambda function to provide payload to SAP Advanced Event Mesh.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(5) Event-to-Business-Action framework (extension app) processor module's endpoint is subscribed to SAP Advanced Event Mesh, hence receives this event.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(6) Event-to-Business-Action framework processor module leverages the Decisions capability of SAP Build Process Automation to derive a business action (for example, in this scenario, Plant Maintenance Notification creation in SAP S/4HANA system) based on certain characteristics of incoming event.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;(7), (8), (9) (10) and (11) Event-to-Business-Action framework processor module triggers the defined action in the SAP S/4HANA system by using the SAP Destination Service and SAP Private Link Service.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The integration architecture uses SAP &lt;STRONG&gt;“Events-to-Business Actions” architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;which is an event-driven framework on SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) to respond to and integrate with events generated from industrial production processes in plants, warehouses, and logistics into enterprise business systems, triggering associated business processes to enhance enterprise operations and enable rapid decision-making.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-504305385"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario Setup and Deployment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To get the entire scenario working, there are prerequisites and initial configurations required in SAP Business Technology Platform, Amazon Web Services, and SAP S/4HANA.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Please refer to the published GitHub repository which contains code samples and instructions for implementing this scenario&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-aws-monitron" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub Repo&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4345/4628/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Discovery Center Mission&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We have created this reference architecture with accompanying sample code which can be configured and extended as per your requirements. However, it is up to the end user to utilize the code, make modifications and keep it maintained for productive use.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If you are using AWS IoT services for your own sensors, please follow the instructions here:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP-samples/btp-events-to-business-actions-framework/blob/main/documentation/Integration-with-AWS-IoT/README.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;GitHub Repo&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-307791880"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits &lt;/STRONG&gt;The business value and technical benefits of this integration are &amp;nbsp;the following:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Detect machine issues before they occur with machine learning (ML) and take action to reduce operational costs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start monitoring equipment in minutes with easy installation and automatic, secure analysis through the Amazon Monitron end-to-end system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve system accuracy continuously as Amazon Monitron learns from technician feedback entered in the mobile and web apps.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Network security-focused design with SAP Private Link specifically for RISE with SAP customers between SAP BTP on AWS (any region) and SAP S/4HANA on AWS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Event-driven integration architecture with SAP Advanced Event Mesh as a central hub.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-111278375"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Demo&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The industrial equipment in Manufacturing plant is connected to Amazon Monitron that sends an event to SAP Advanced Event Mesh once abnormal condition is detected and the Event to Business Actions framework process the event and enriches it will relevant business context using decision tables from SAP Build Process Automation and creates a maintenance notification in SAP S/4HANA.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can watch a&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_ezyna9ne" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;demo here&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;that showcases the PoC scenario&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--85235130"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In Closing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We hope this blog has given you a brief idea on how to integrate events generated from industrial equipment to trigger different business actions/workflows/process in SAP backend systems.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On the SAP side,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Many thanks to &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/umaanbazhagan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Uma Anbazhagan&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;from SAP for driving this topic by collaborating with all the stakeholders involved in the engagement, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/swati-maste/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Swati Maste&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ajit-kumar-panda-22ba1953/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Ajit Kumar Panda&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; for supporting the development of this solution, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/netmadan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Madankumar Pichamuthu&lt;/A&gt; for enabling collaboration and finally&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/-anirban-majumdar/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Anirban Majumdar&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/pavankumarpvn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;PVN Pavan Kumar&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/siva-kumar-n/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Sivakumar N&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for leadership support for this project.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On the Amazon AWS side,&lt;/STRONG&gt; Many thanks to &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/soulat-khan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Soulat Khan&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madganesh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Ganesh Suryanarayanan&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sunnypatwari/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Sunny Patwari&lt;/A&gt;, Renga Sridharan, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/aiyappa-machanda-3803b420/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Aiyappa Machanda&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhikray/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Abhik Ray&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/suresh-pulivarthi-86b58a10/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Suresh Pulivarthi&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kramadoss/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Krishnakumar Ramadoss&lt;/A&gt; and the SAP APN Partner Innovation team for their support in this project.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To learn more about SAP BTP, see the learning journey on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journey?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-BTP-free-sap-skill-development-for-all-earn-sap-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;called&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journey/discover-sap-business-technology-platform?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-BTP-developer-consultant-adminstrator-architect-can-build-sap-btp-skills-and-intelligent-enterprise-strategy-for-free-and-earn-sap-certification" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Discover SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt;, a great introduction to BTP and the Intelligent Enterprise strategy to see what it’s all about for free.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As part of the global partnership between SAP and AWS, we have jointly developed an&amp;nbsp;openSAP&amp;nbsp;course titled “&lt;STRONG&gt;Build Resilient Applications on SAP BTP with Amazon Web Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;[Registration link] &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://open.sap.com/courses/aws1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://open.sap.com/courses/aws1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;By joining this free&amp;nbsp;openSAP&amp;nbsp;course&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you'll delve into multiple Joint Reference Architecture patterns, gain in-depth knowledge of the architectural patterns and also have the opportunity to enhance your skills through hands-on exercises.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To learn more about Amazon AWS, visit &lt;A href="https://aws.amazon.com/training/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;AWS training&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For more information about this topic&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;or to ask a question, please contact us at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:paa@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;paa_india@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/aws-and-sap-joint-reference-architecture-for-iot-scenarios-using-amazon/ba-p/13580723"/>
    <published>2023-11-14T14:30:24+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-network-asset-collaboration-and-classification-content-by/ba-p/13588270</id>
    <title>SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration and Classification Content by ECLASS: FAQs</title>
    <updated>2024-02-05T08:12:27.272000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Diana_Divya</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/41233</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This FAQ blog deals with questions related to the partnership of SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration and the classification content provider ECLASS. Main aspects are how the ECLASS classification is made available in SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration, how customers can get access to the ECLASS classification content in SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration, and what to do if you are missing ECLASS classification content either in SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration or in ECLASS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;See Also&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Blog on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2019/10/23/classification-standards-in-sap-intelligent-asset-management/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Classification Standards in SAP Intelligent Asset Management&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-964996856"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-768483351"&gt;General Questions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-959218003"&gt;What is ECLASS?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;ECLASS is a cross-industry product-data standard for the classification and unique description of products and services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;For more information on the company and the standard, please refer to the official ECLASS Web pages (&lt;A href="https://eclass.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://eclass.eu/&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-762704498"&gt;How does SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration work with ECLASS?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration and ECLASS have a partnership, and ECLASS acts as a Content Provider in SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration. This means that ECLASS is a participant in the network and ECLASS classification objects get created by ECLASS in their account and will be shared by ECLASS with their licensees in the network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-178942836"&gt;Content-Related Questions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-369677488"&gt;Which ECLASS version is available with SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;ECLASS versions 10.1 and 12.0 are currently available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-173163983"&gt;Which ECLASS objects will be available in SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;ECLASS classification objects will be loaded as SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration Template objects, i.e., classes, subclasses, attribute groups, nested structures, attributes, and code lists.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; In ECLASS version 10.1, you can still see ECLASS model templates. These were used as a temporary workaround to realize the loading of ECLASS aspects when SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration (then SAP Asset Intelligence Network) did not have the nested structures functionality yet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;With ECLASS version 12.0, ECLASS Blocks and Aspects are represented as nested structures in SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration.&lt;BR /&gt;The obsolete Model Templates (= representation of Aspects) are still visible in version 10.1 but should not be used anymore.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;In the beginning the following ECLASS segments will be available in the productive landscape:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Segment 19&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Information, communication and media technology)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Segment 23&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Machine element, fixing, mounting)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Segment 27&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Electric engineering, automation, process control engineering)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Segment 36&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Machine, apparatus)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Segment 37&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Industrial piping)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;More segments will be made available in upcoming releases. The sequence/priority of additional segments will be decided based on customer requests (see below).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--23349522"&gt;It looks like ECLASS is currently only available in English and German language? Will there be other languages available?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Yes, ECLASS classification is currently available in languages English and German. Further languages supported by ECLASS can be made available for version 12.0 upon request (see below).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--219863027"&gt;What can I do if I need additional ECLASS segments or additional ECLASS languages in the SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration productive landscape?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Please create an incident under component SBN-AIN-ACF-CNT and request the segment or language you need. ECLASS will then upload the requested segment(s) as soon as possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;You should only create such a segment request for ECLASS if you already have an ECLASS license (see LICENSING section below).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--416376532"&gt;What can I do if I need additional classification content in ECLASS?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Missing content can be requested from ECLASS. Please follow the general process of submitting Change Requests to the ECLASS standard (refer to&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://eclass.eu/support/guides/change-request" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://eclass.eu/support/guides/change-request&lt;/A&gt;). For questions, please contact directly ECLASS Office:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:info@eclass.de" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;info@eclass.de.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--652883837"&gt;Licensing Questions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1729606363"&gt;Does ECLASS classification content come for free with SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;A subset of ECLASS structural elements will be made available for a free Trial in the Test and Demo system. The classification content (= ECLASS segments) which is available as free trial are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Segment 19&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Information, communication and media technology)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Segment 27&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Electric engineering, automation, process control engineering)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Segment 36&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Machine, apparatus)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Segment 37&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Industrial piping)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;To use this free trial content, please create a connection request with ECLASS e.V. in the Test and Demo system. ECLASS will then trigger the sharing of the free trial content for your account. For productive use – i.e., in SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration Production landscape – you require a dedicated license from ECLASS to be able to model business objects using ECLASS content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;There will be no migration possible from the free trial version to the productive system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1926119868"&gt;How can I license ECLASS and what are the costs?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Licensing of ECLASS classification content is handled by ECLASS. You can view the available licensing models on the ECLASS Web site (&lt;A href="https://eclass.eu/en/eclass-standard/licenses" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://eclass.eu/en/eclass-standard/licenses&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;BR /&gt;For direct inquiries regarding the exact licensing options for your company, please directly contact the ECLASS office (&lt;A href="mailto:info@eclass.de" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;info@eclass.de&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--2122633373"&gt;My company already has an ECLASS license. Can I use this for SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration as well?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;ECLASS will share their objects with their licensees based on their customer list. So, if you already have an ECLASS license this will also be valid for use of ECLASS in SAP Business Network Asset collaboration.&lt;BR /&gt;As an ECLASS licensee, please create a connection request with ECLASS e.V. in the Production system. ECLASS will then trigger the sharing of their content for your account. For any license-related questions (including ECLASS sharing via SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration) you can also contact ECLASS directly (e-mail: &lt;A href="mailto:info@eclass.de" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;info@eclass.de&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1975820418"&gt;I have a Premium account in SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration, and I want my Invitee accounts to create classification content based on ECLASS classification. Will my Invitees need an own ECLASS license for this?&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;If objects are to be modelled based on ECLASS classification objects a dedicated ECLASS license is required independent of the SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration account type. Therefore, Invitees who model objects in SAP Business Network Asset Collaboration based on ECLASS classification content need an own ECLASS license.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-network-asset-collaboration-and-classification-content-by/ba-p/13588270"/>
    <published>2024-02-05T08:12:27.272000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/jowat-seamless-just-in-time-operations-with-sap-digital-manufacturing-to/ba-p/13617183</id>
    <title>Jowat: Seamless Just-in-Time Operations with SAP Digital Manufacturing to Make Better Decisions</title>
    <updated>2024-02-23T15:58:30.269000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karin_fent</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/198077</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.jowat.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Jowat photo 2 .jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/70004i6354E29E579FB0E7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Jowat photo 2 .jpg" alt="Jowat photo 2 .jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Jowat Group&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; is one of the world’s top adhesive manufacturers for industrial use. Tradition and experience from 100 years of corporate development and experience allow it to act as leading company in technology and innovations, in numerous markets and application areas.&lt;SPAN&gt; Jowat SE’s annual production amounts to 100,000 tons of industrial adhesives. Their production is complex and requires high volumes of specialized chemicals and a tremendous amount of power. With raw materials and energy costs skyrocketing, premium manufacturer Jowat looked to get a tighter grip on its inventory management and production processes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To ensure maximum efficiency, Jowat requires enough raw materials to fulfil orders, while minimizing waste and inventory costs. Moreover, the company needs smooth workflows as any delay in order placement, production, or the delivery of raw materials can have huge cost implications for the company.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a result, Jowat works hard to ensure that its 24/7 manufacturing processes always run like clockwork. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With demand for industrial adhesives surging, the company was eager to ensure that its production processes could scale to meet increasing order numbers and still deliver optimum efficiency. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-987130642"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Targeting Seamless Digital Workflows &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Originally established in 1919, Jowat is no stranger to innovation. Leaders at Jowat identified that the next stage of the company’s evolution would require a radical digital transformation of its production and inventory management processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Our factory workers relied heavily on paper-based processes,” explained Dirk-Alexander Segger, Detmold Plant Manager at Jowat. “For instance, when employees had finished mixing and decanting adhesives, they handwrote notes to track the volume and type of raw materials that they used during the process. Shortly after decanting, workers would then input the information from their notes into our inventory management and manufacturing execution systems—adding to their workload and increasing the risk of errors.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tracking materials usage manually created both time-delay, and potential for human errors, as well as discrepancies between the stock amounts recorded in Jowat’s inventory system and the actual volume of raw materials available on the factory floor. Moreover, with information stored across multiple systems and in different formats, plant managers had no clarity to identify process bottlenecks or potential enhancements.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Annette Podleschny-Borchardt, Project Lead at Jowat, commented: “To enhance efficiency, improve transparency, and prepare for growth, we decided it was time to go entirely paperless. Building digital processes would give us a more detailed, up-to-date picture of our stock position, which would help to drive smarter raw materials purchasing decisions as well as production improvements.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“We aimed to take a more proactive approach to our manufacturing processes. Developing robust, reliable, end-to-end digital workflows was the perfect way to achieve this goal,”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;explained Christine &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Künne&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&lt;/SPAN&gt; Head of IT and Business Process Services at Jowat SE&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-790617137"&gt;Embracing Digital Transformation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To find the best solution to support its digital transformation initiative, Jowat invited multiple technology vendors to outline the strengths of their solutions. To keep customization low, Jowat targeted a solution that it could easily adapt to meet the highly specialized nature of just-in-time chemicals manufacturing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After reviewing 15 different solutions, Jowat selected &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/digital-manufacturing-cloud.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Digital Manufacturing&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (SAP DM). As well as providing a solid foundation for digitalization, SAP Digital Manufacturing also integrates seamlessly with Jowat’s existing SAP solutions, including &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/s4hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/extended-warehouse-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Extended Warehouse Management&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“We were immediately interested in SAP Digital Manufacturing because it is a cloud-native solution,” commented Dirk-Alexander Segger. “Previously, we used on-premise solutions that required us to carry out extensive and disruptive updates. With SAP Digital Manufacturing, we get instant access to the latest features thanks to the quarterly release schedule.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Jowat also valued SAP’s proactive engagement with the chemicals manufacturing industry. “We really appreciate that SAP is eager to co-innovate with industry leaders like Jowat to develop next-generation manufacturing solutions,” said Annette Podleschny-Borchardt. “Through the SAP Customer Engagement Initiative, we can help expert developers at SAP build smart factory solutions that meet the needs of our sector down to the finest detail.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-594103632"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sticking with the Experts&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To ensure a smooth implementation of SAP Digital Manufacturing, Jowat relied on support from SAP Services and Support. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Whenever we hit a stumbling block, the experts helped us work through the issues. For instance, we wanted to develop a dedicated production operation dashboard, which would give plant managers fast access to key production metrics. As this was uncharted territory, it naturally took a lot of time and energy to work through and SAP was behind us every step of the way,” said Dirk-Alexander Segger. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Currently, Jowat is completing the first phase of the SAP Digital Manufacturing implementation at its Detmold factory before expanding the solution across all plants. Christine Künne explained: “With a phased implementation we can ensure that the processes we build at our Detmold plant are tried-and-tested to deliver maximum efficiency. This will give us the best chance of success when we roll out these processes across all our facilities.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Consultants from SAP Services and Support brought not only their expertise to the project, but also the willingness to listen to the needs and the challenges of our industry. Because of this, we were able to collaborate extremely effectively,” added Annette Podleschny-Borchardt&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-397590127"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Driving Efficient Manufacturing with High-quality Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With SAP Digital Manufacturing, Jowat left error-prone, manual processes behind and benefits now from seamless digital &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;workflows with end-to-end transparency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;This increases quality and eases work for shop floor operators. The activity confirmation is automatically done in the SAP system enabling real-time inventory insight.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consequently, Jowat gained the following benefits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;100% digitalized&lt;/STRONG&gt; manufacturing process&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;One source of truth&lt;/STRONG&gt; for detailed production information&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Time savings&lt;/STRONG&gt; of 3 person days per week through &lt;STRONG&gt;automated raw material consumption updates&lt;/STRONG&gt; allowing employees focus on higher value activities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;100% &lt;STRONG&gt;accurate inventory&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dirk-Alexander Segger said: “Today workers feed consumption information at the point of production. Previously, it would take one full-time employee three days a week to track raw materials consumption. With SAP Digital Manufacturing, we have a real-time, accurate picture of our raw materials usage and needs. This is helping us optimize usage and reduce costs.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Annette Podleschny-Borchardt added: “Production processes are so much faster now that we have built streamlined digital processes. Before, our paper-based ways of working could add up to five days to production timelines. With SAP Digital Manufacturing, we’ve shaved off this time, allowing us to produce and distribute products to our customers much faster&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;—&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;boosting satisfaction.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-201076622"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Planning ahead for an AI-driven Future&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With reliable, up-to-date information in SAP Digital Manufacturing, plant managers and leaders at Jowat have &lt;STRONG&gt;full visibility across the entire manufacturing cycle&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Christine Künne said: “SAP Digital Manufacturing has helped &lt;STRONG&gt;improve the traceability of our products&lt;/STRONG&gt; and given us a much more detailed understanding of our manufacturing operations. Ultimately, that helps to enhance planning and provides new insights into potential process improvements.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Jowat’s plans for SAP Digital Manufacturing go far beyond a global rollout. The company is already exploring the potential to scale and streamline manufacturing processes further with artificial intelligence (AI) and Internet of Things (IoT) technologies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“AI holds tremendous potential for us,” reflected Annette Podleschny-Borchardt. “We’re excited to explore how it can help us to ensure consistently excellent quality across heavily customized product lines, and how we can enhance production uptime with IoT-driven predictive maintenance. Having an AI-ready solution like SAP Digital Manufacturing at the heart of our operations makes taking these next steps in our innovation journey much easier.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Summarizing the overall benefits, Christine Künne concluded “With the implementation of SAP Digital Manufacturing through SAP Services and Support, we see ourselves on the way to becoming a transparent factory with a reduction in risks, errors, and process costs thanks to optimized processes.”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-391811274"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/customer-stories/smart-press-shop.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; to see what benefits other companies have gained including improving quality with AI-assisted visual inspection. Be sure to listen to a &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/console/apollox/mainEvent?&amp;amp;eventid=4294893&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;username=&amp;amp;partnerref=web&amp;amp;format=fhvideo1&amp;amp;mobile=&amp;amp;flashsupportedmobiledevice=&amp;amp;helpcenter=&amp;amp;key=2A85021F45D14DF9C657C622AA74D180&amp;amp;newConsole=true&amp;amp;nxChe=true&amp;amp;newTabCon=true&amp;amp;consoleEarEventConsole=false&amp;amp;text_language_id=en&amp;amp;playerwidth=748&amp;amp;playerheight=526&amp;amp;eventuserid=626283838&amp;amp;contenttype=A&amp;amp;mediametricsessionid=550094581&amp;amp;mediametricid=6052808&amp;amp;usercd=626283838&amp;amp;mode=launch" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;webinar&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; how a renowned manufacturer revolutionizes manufacturing with Industry 4.0. Also, read a &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/cmp/dg/risk-resilient-supply-chain-manufacturing/typ.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;report&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; from Oxford Economics enabling you to make your supply chain more resilient and sustainable.&lt;/H5&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/jowat-seamless-just-in-time-operations-with-sap-digital-manufacturing-to/ba-p/13617183"/>
    <published>2024-02-23T15:58:30.269000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/oliver-schreiber/ba-p/13588026</id>
    <title>Oliver Schreiber</title>
    <updated>2024-02-29T14:55:22.990000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanieMarley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;A href="https://groups.community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6776" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;About Oliver Schreiber&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;SAP Mentor since 2015&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Oliver Schreiber.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/56640iA7D6636996AA2FC3/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Oliver Schreiber.png" alt="Oliver Schreiber.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Oliver is a business and solution architect with strong focus on platform-based&amp;nbsp;services leveraging SAP Business Technology Platform. Active startup entrepreneur with B2B SaaS services and the FinTech solution LiquidityHub on SAP AppCenter! Long term history as SAP partner in many roles and a strong network in the SAP Ecosystem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Topics of interest:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP BTP, SaaS, PaaS, cloud architecture, platform-based business models, partner business models, SAP HANA, Kyma, IoT, cloud operation&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Oliver, what inspired you to become an SAP Mentor?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="handshake .png" style="width: 68px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52491i8E9D2FFB3C7BC293/image-dimensions/68x68?v=v2" width="68" height="68" role="button" title="handshake .png" alt="handshake .png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;When I founded my company in early 2015 to leverage the upcoming platform-based business on SAP platform technology, I was asked to join the SAP Mentor team to bring in my skills of working with SAP for more than 20 years in different partner roles internationally. I was very excited and honored to become part of such an unbelievably nice, experienced, international team of experts that works so well together, stays honest and always has a lot of fun. I was very impressed with the overall experience and that our input and feedback was taken seriously by the SAP board and management which then led to real improvements in several areas.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What advice would like to share with other SAP community members?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" style="width: 65px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52495i64D82195EFF8CCB9/image-dimensions/65x65?v=v2" width="65" height="65" role="button" title="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;We never had better circumstances and easy access to enabling technologies to design and establish new software solutions and businesses to start something new. Building a new business as a startup or a new solution based on SAP platform technologies is possible with limited investment for skilled people today. Always do that with a real customer as a pilot and properly analyse that there is a real market for it and how to reach it. Whether you are a developer or architect, or even a sales representative, it doesn’t matter, as long as your role fits your personal strengths and desire and you build the right team around it. And the community might be the right forum to find them and get early feedback.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/oliver-schreiber/ba-p/13588026"/>
    <published>2024-02-29T14:55:22.990000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/eduardo-chagas/ba-p/13653603</id>
    <title>Eduardo Chagas</title>
    <updated>2024-03-29T18:49:39.614000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanieMarley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125190" target="_blank"&gt;About Eduardo&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;SAP Mentor since 2013&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Eduardo Chagas.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/88555iFB118668EC55273A/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Eduardo Chagas.png" alt="Eduardo Chagas.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;Professional with over several years of experience in the field of Information Technology, with a great passion for IT and continuous improvement. I enjoy being part of a dynamic and fast-growing environment where I can apply all my knowledge and skills to new challenges every day. Excellent interpersonal relationships and a strong commitment to achieving goals.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Topics of interest:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA, Supply Chain, Logistics, Transportation Management, Warehouse Management, Logistics Business Network, Yard Management, Transportation Resource Management, IoT, AI &amp;amp; Machine Learning&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Eduardo, what inspired you to become an SAP Mentor?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="handshake .png" style="width: 68px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52491i8E9D2FFB3C7BC293/image-dimensions/68x68?v=v2" width="68" height="68" role="button" title="handshake .png" alt="handshake .png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;I was inspired by other professionals such as Henrique Pinto, Marlo Simon and Tobias Hofmann who were already SAP Mentors and who, in addition to their technical knowledge, did a lot to build and develop the SAP community in Brazil.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What advice would like to share with other SAP community members?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="4"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" style="width: 65px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52495i64D82195EFF8CCB9/image-dimensions/65x65?v=v2" width="65" height="65" role="button" title="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Hard work! If you want results in your business, whether personally or professionally, you need to dedicate yourself and go further! Having discipline and consistency is essential to get results. Another important point in my opinion is... you should ask yourself at all times "How can I add value to my client? To the process?". We cannot simply deliver a solution but rather ensure that it returns value to the customer.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/eduardo-chagas/ba-p/13653603"/>
    <published>2024-03-29T18:49:39.614000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/iot-ultimate-data-cyber-security-with-enterprise-blockchain-and-sap-btp/ba-p/13676981</id>
    <title>IoT - Ultimate Data Cyber Security - with Enterprise Blockchain and SAP BTP 🚀</title>
    <updated>2024-04-22T11:07:39.454000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AndySilvey</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1397601</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;It wasn't that long ago that Cyber Security and Resilience translated to High Availability and Disaster Recovery. Driven by the Sensitivity, Confidentiality, and Availability requirements of the Data, Systems and Applications were built to have the highest possible availability. That requirement came from the times when an entire end to end Business Process ran in a single standalone Application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fast forward to today, end to end Business Processes can begin in one Application on one side of the world and pass through Applications somewhere else in the world and finish in Applications in an altogether different location in the world. The beginning of the Business Process can be Sensors and Things at the Edge, producing Data, Events, something has happened and triggered the Business Process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This creates several problems&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Protect the Originality &amp;amp; Integrity of the Data&lt;/STRONG&gt; - When the Thing, the IoT Sensor, let's say critical infrastructure, something like a Base Station in a Telco Network, or a piece of the Electrical Grid for a Utility Company, when the Thing, the IoT Sensor creates the&amp;nbsp; piece of Data, a Record of something that just happened we need to make sure that piece of Data cannot be modified or destroyed and therefore protect the originality and integrity of the Data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Moving the Data from the Edge to the SAP Application in the Cloud or DataCenter and at the same time&amp;nbsp;Protect the Originality &amp;amp; Integrity of the Data&lt;/STRONG&gt; - we need to get the Data from the Thing, the IoT Sensor, to the SAP Application in the Cloud or DataCenter and we need to be sure, to have surety that the Data which arrives in the SAP Cloud or DataCenter is exactly the same Data that was created at the Edge at the Thing, the IoT Sensor. If this Data gets changed in any way, we won't be able to &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;trust&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; the Business Processes and Insights which are depending on that Data. And so, in the activity of moving the Data we need to make sure that that piece of Data cannot be modified or destroyed&amp;nbsp;and therefore protect the originality and integrity of the Data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And so, here we are, the biggest threat to Enterprise SAP Applications is no longer the High Availability, the Server crashing, that's all under control and possible to take care of,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The biggest threat to IoT &amp;amp; Enterprise SAP Applications is Cyber Security and Cyber Attacks&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A common thought is that a hacker, or cyber attacker wants to modify Data for their own financial benefit, for example change the destination bank account number for invoice payments, yes those threats are still there, but biggest threat is that a hacker or cyber attacker deletes or modifies Master and Transaction Data resulting that the Master and Transactional Data does not have integrity and cannot be used, and if the attacker succeeded to modify the Backup as well, then&amp;nbsp; the Enterprise could be out of business for a long time trying to pick up the pieces and get up and running again.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The biggest threat to IoT &amp;amp; Enterprise SAP Applications is Cyber Attacks rendering the Master and Transaction Data un-trustworthy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And that's where the Enterprise Blockchain comes in, and this blog is going to explain why.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ok let's go&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Welcome to the eighth blog in this series on Enterprise Blockchain and SAP. If you have been following the previous blogs then you'll be familiar with the blog template. We'll begin by talking about and framing the problem, in this case &lt;EM&gt;Data Cyber Security for IoT and SAP&lt;/EM&gt; and then go in to identifying the enabling technology which will have the best capabilities and be the most appropriate to solving the problem all the way through to the reference solution architecture to be able to implement the solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The blog is going to break the subject down in to three sections:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Section 1.0: The What is it of IoT &amp;amp; SAP, and Enterprise Blockchain&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Section 2.0: The Why is it, of IoT &amp;amp; SAP, and Enterprise Blockchain&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Section 3.0: The How is it,&amp;nbsp;of IoT &amp;amp; SAP, and Enterprise Blockchain&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;tl:dr&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to protect the originality and integrity and confidentiality of IoT data, from the Edge to Insights and SAP Business Processes, then the answer is an Enterprise Blockchain Database, where the Enterprise Blockchain Tenants are running on Edge Hosts/Servers and in the SAP BTP Business Technology Platform, enabling Enterprise Blockchain Database to protect the Data from the Edge Hosts/Servers to the SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99480iB1B098FECFF5F4B7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io .png" alt="IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[&lt;EM&gt;the finer technical details of getting the data from the Enterprise Blockchain to SAP Asset Management and S/4HANA will be &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blogs-by-sap/best-practices-for-using-current-sap-apm-rules-for-condition-monitoring/bc-p/13673307#M5681" target="_self"&gt;clearer possibly&lt;/A&gt; after &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire.html?source=ppc-us-sapphire-splash-promo&amp;amp;campaigncode=crm-ya24-int-2331870&amp;amp;source=ppc-1na-googleads-search-71700000117657864-58700008674879759-xsolutionarea_saf-x-x-aam&amp;amp;gad_source=1&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjw8pKxBhD_ARIsAPrG45kRZmQXtXaCvFDWwZJlxgsMVyhEEarnGfainO9me0RUrJK4HokVZI0aAqZFEALw_wcB&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sapphire Orlando in June&lt;/A&gt;. In the mean time there are a number of ways to get the Data in and out of the Enterprise Blockchain running on the SAP BTP Kyma Service&lt;/EM&gt;]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Blockchain is both:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. a Secure Store&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. a Secure Communication Channel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Blockchain is the Cyber Security for Enterprise IoT Data from the Edge to Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;and now.... the long answer...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Section 1.0: The What is it of IoT &amp;amp; SAP, and Enterprise Blockchain&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/what-is-iot.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What is IoT Internet of Things ?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-992649663"&gt;History of IoT&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;In 2021, there were over&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://dataprot.net/statistics/iot-statistics/#:~:text=In%202021%2C%20there%20were%20more,to%20the%20internet%20per%20minute." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;10 billion IoT devices&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;in the world, and by 2025, the IDC expects global data generation to exceed&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://blogs.idc.com/2021/01/06/future-of-industry-ecosystems-shared-data-and-insights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;73 zettabytes&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– which is equal to 73 trillion gigabytes. Although we can’t really quantify digital data in physical terms, we can say that if all that data were converted into 1990s floppy disks – and they were laid out end to end – they could go to the moon and back over 5,000 times.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[Source:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/what-is-iot.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What is IoT? The Future of Business | SAP&lt;/A&gt;]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/what-is-iot.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_0-1713698558262.png" style="width: 764px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99481i923459207E9A6CC1/image-dimensions/764x273?v=v2" width="764" height="273" role="button" title="AndySilvey_0-1713698558262.png" alt="AndySilvey_0-1713698558262.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-796136158"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/mckinsey-explainers/what-is-the-internet-of-things" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;What are some IoT applications?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking at IoT applications, which are sometimes described as use cases, can help ground the discussion about what IoT is. Broadly,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/mckinsey-digital/our-insights/the-internet-of-things-the-value-of-digitizing-the-physical-world" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;IoT applications occur in one of nine settings&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Human health.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Devices can be attached to or inserted inside the human body, including wearable or ingestible devices that monitor or&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/the-next-normal/wellness" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;maintain health and wellness&lt;/A&gt;, assist in managing diseases such as diabetes, and more.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Home.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Homeowners can install devices such as home voice assistants,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/mckinsey-digital/our-insights/a-smart-home-is-where-the-bot-is" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;automated vacuums&lt;/A&gt;, or security systems.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Retail environments.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Devices can be installed in&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/retail/our-insights/how-tech-will-revolutionize-retail" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;stores&lt;/A&gt;, banks, restaurants, and arenas to facilitate self-checkout, extend in-store offers, or help optimize inventory.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Offices.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;IoT applications in offices could entail&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/industrials-and-electronics/our-insights/laying-the-foundation-for-success-in-the-connected-building-era" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;energy management&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;or security for buildings.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Standardized production environments.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;In such settings, including&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/mckinsey-digital/our-insights/a-manufacturers-guide-to-generating-value-at-scale-with-industrial-iot" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;manufacturing plants&lt;/A&gt;, hospitals, or farms, IoT applications often aim to gain operating efficiencies or optimize equipment use and inventory.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Custom production environments.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;In customized settings like those in mining, construction, or oil and gas exploration and production, IoT applications might be used in&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/operations/our-insights/a-smarter-way-to-digitize-maintenance-and-reliability" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;predictive maintenance&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;or&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/people-and-organizational-performance/our-insights/overcoming-limiting-mind-sets-to-improve-safety" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;health and safety efforts&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Vehicles.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;IoT can help with condition-based maintenance, usage-based design, or presales analytics for&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/automotive-and-assembly/our-insights/unlocking-the-full-life-cycle-value-from-connected-car-data" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;cars and trucks&lt;/A&gt;, ships, airplanes, and trains.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Cities.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;IoT applications can be used for adaptive traffic control, smart meters, environmental monitoring, or&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/quantumblack/our-insights/iot-comes-of-age" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;managing resources&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Outside.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;In urban environments or other outdoor settings, such as railroad tracks, autonomous vehicles, or flight navigation, IoT applications could involve real-time routing, connected navigation, or shipment tracking.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/technology-media-and-telecommunications/our-insights/laying-the-foundation-to-accelerate-the-enterprise-iot-journey" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;real-world examples abound&lt;/A&gt;. IoT solutions are being used in myriad settings: in refrigerators, to help restaurants optimize their food-compliance processes; in fields, to track livestock; in offices, to track how many and how often meeting rooms are used; and beyond.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-599622653"&gt;&lt;A href="http://What%20is the economic impact of IoT? The potential value of IoT is large and growing. By 2030, we estimate it could amount to up to $12.5 trillion globally. That includes the value captured by consumers and customers of IoT products and services.  The potential economic value of IoT differs based on settings and usages, with factory settings and human health applications representing outsize shares of this total. Factory settings could generate $1.4 trillion to $3.3 trillion by 2030, or just over a quarter of the total value potential. IoT economic impact in human health settings could reach around 14 percent of the total estimated value.  Another way of looking at IoT’s value is to explore use-case clusters (similar uses adapted to different settings). Some of the most common use cases account for a sizable share of IoT’s potential economic value:  operations optimization, which is basically making the various day-to-day management of assets and people more efficient (41 percent) health (15 percent) human productivity (15 percent) condition-based maintenance (12 percent) Other clusters include sales enablement, energy management, autonomous vehicles (the fastest-growing cluster), and safety and security." target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;What is the economic impact of IoT?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The potential value of IoT is large and growing.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/mckinsey-digital/our-insights/iot-value-set-to-accelerate-through-2030-where-and-how-to-capture-it" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;By 2030, we estimate it could amount to up to $12.5 trillion globally&lt;/A&gt;. That includes the value captured by consumers and customers of IoT products and services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The potential economic value of IoT differs based on settings and usages, with factory settings and human health applications representing outsize shares of this total. Factory settings could generate $1.4 trillion to $3.3 trillion by 2030, or just over a quarter of the total value potential. IoT economic impact in human health settings could reach around 14 percent of the total estimated value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another way of looking at IoT’s value is to explore&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/mckinsey-digital/our-insights/iot-value-set-to-accelerate-through-2030-where-and-how-to-capture-it" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;use-case clusters&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(similar uses adapted to different settings). Some of the most common use cases account for a sizable share of IoT’s potential economic value:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;operations optimization, which is basically making the various day-to-day management of assets and people more efficient (41 percent)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;health (15 percent)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;human productivity (15 percent)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;condition-based maintenance (12 percent)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other clusters include sales enablement, energy management, autonomous vehicles (the fastest-growing cluster), and safety and security.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;[Source:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/mckinsey-explainers/what-is-the-internet-of-things" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;What is IoT: The Internet of Things explained | McKinsey&lt;/A&gt;]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/what-is-iot.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_1-1713698788363.png" style="width: 778px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99482iB4EB5AC0112FEAFE/image-dimensions/778x428?v=v2" width="778" height="428" role="button" title="AndySilvey_1-1713698788363.png" alt="AndySilvey_1-1713698788363.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Like everything else we do in Enterprise IT,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;IoT Internet of Things is about Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/what-is-blockchain.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What is Enterprise Blockchain ?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enterprise Blockchain is both:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. a Secure Store&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. a Secure Communication Channel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;McKinsey &amp;amp; Company, in their&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/mckinsey-explainers/what-is-blockchain" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;December 2023 Featured Insights Publication&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, gave a beautiful description of what is unique and special about Blockchain, "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Blockchain is a secure database shared across a network of participants, where up-to-date information is available to all participants at the same time&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;". If we just pause for a moment and let that sink in, and think about what that means, to Business Processes, to Collaboration, to System Resilience, we start to see what is so special about Blockchain Databases and Distributed Ledger Technology.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In these previous blogs, I made a deep dive in to what Enterprise Blockchain is and why we should be positioning it in our Enterprise Architecture:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-members/why-i-love-sap-and-blockchain-databases-and-why-you-should-too/ba-p/13625869" target="_blank"&gt;Why I love SAP and Blockchain Databases and why you should too&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-members/sap-enterprise-architecture-positioning-blockchain-database-as-an/ba-p/13629842" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Enterprise Architecture: Positioning Blockchain Database as an Enterprise Technology Standard&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-members/sap-enterprise-architecture-let-the-use-case-find-the-blockchain/ba-p/13632458" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Enterprise Architecture: Let the Use Case find the Blockchain &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IoT Internet of Things and SAP - Enterprise Blockchain is the next generation Data Cyber Security Protection - atkrypto.io" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99489i784CF7AD0620178E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IoT Internet of Things and SAP - Enterprise Blockchain is the next generation Data Cyber Security Protection - atkrypto.io .png" alt="IoT Internet of Things and SAP - Enterprise Blockchain is the next generation Data Cyber Security Protection - atkrypto.io" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;IoT Internet of Things and SAP - Enterprise Blockchain is the next generation Data Cyber Security Protection - atkrypto.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;and in a nutshell, Enterprise Blockchain is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. The Digital Transformation of Information Security into Cyber Security&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. The Next Generation Data Integrity, Originality, Confidentiality Protection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. Re-imagining Information Security&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. Natively, out of the box, due to its special characteristics the strongest, hardest, most resilient Enterprise Database product&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To wrap up this section:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Iot Internet of Things is about Data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;. Enterprise Blockchain is about Cyber Security of Data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Section 2.0: The Why is it, of IoT &amp;amp; SAP, and Enterprise Blockchain&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, why does IoT, Internet of Things, in the Enterprise IT, when implemented in conjunction with SAP Applications need Enterprise Blockchain ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IoT is about Data, and the Data in most cases originates from the Edge and outlying parts of the Network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The problem is the Cyber Security of getting the Data from the Edge and outlying parts of the Network to the safe zones of the SAP Cloud and yours or SAP's DataCenters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;IoT's biggest risk is that the Data coming from the IoT Devices is not trustworthy. In the same way as asking the wrong person for directions can leave you going all around the houses, if the Data coming from the IoT Devices, has been changed/contaminated/modified/poluted/made unreliable, whether purposefully through malicious acts or cyber attack, or accidentally, the result will be IoT's Data insights which cannot be trusted, and the result of that could be catastrophic. Just imagine not being able to trust the temperature of refrigeration during pharmaceutical and food production !&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If we cannot protect and the originality and integrity of IoT Data, secure it, then how can we trust IoT Data ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As &lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/technology-media-and-telecommunications/our-insights/cybersecurity-for-the-iot-how-trust-can-unlock-value" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mckinsey &amp;amp; Company say&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/technology-media-and-telecommunications/our-insights/cybersecurity-for-the-iot-how-trust-can-unlock-value" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_0-1713702593375.png" style="width: 883px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99501i07B879945532E48E/image-dimensions/883x424?v=v2" width="883" height="424" role="button" title="AndySilvey_0-1713702593375.png" alt="AndySilvey_0-1713702593375.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IoT is about the Data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, if we are going to do IoT and include IoT Data in our Business Processes and Insights, then we need to care for and protect the Data that is coming from IoT Devices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine, as described in the previous blog, when we&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-members/sap-enterprise-architecture-let-the-use-case-find-the-blockchain/ba-p/13632458" target="_self"&gt;let the Use Case find the Enterprise Blockchain&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;, we have a Business Requirement, a Business Demand, to make IoT Data trustable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we look in our Enterprise Technology Standards, and we look for the Technology Standard in our Enterprise Portfolio which is&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-members/sap-enterprise-architecture-positioning-blockchain-database-as-an/ba-p/13629842" target="_self"&gt;positioned to bring the strongest protection to Data, we find the Enterprise Blockchain&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_1-1713703070065.png" style="width: 826px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99502iC524A0F83A222353/image-dimensions/826x417?v=v2" width="826" height="417" role="button" title="AndySilvey_1-1713703070065.png" alt="AndySilvey_1-1713703070065.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Comparison Enterprise Blockchain Database and Traditional Legacy Database - atkrypto.io&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the previous blogs, we have discussed in detail about the special characteristics of Enterprise Blockchain and just why it natively out of the box protects the integrity of data to a level that legacy database products cannot do, in a nutshell....&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;IoT is about Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;IoT is about the Data that goes in to the SAP Applications in the Cloud and Data Centers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This means IoT Device Data depends on a Database or a Datastore&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What kind of Database do IoT Devices produces ? What capabilities does the Database for the IoT Devices Data need to have ?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. It must not be possible to modify the Data in the Database which comes from the IoT Devices - the Database needs to be immutable&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. The Data in the Database, the integrity and originality of that Data must be protected to the highest level that is technically possible&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. The Data must be available with the highest availability, the Database must be resilient to attack&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When we look in our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-members/sap-enterprise-architecture-positioning-blockchain-database-as-an/ba-p/13629842" target="_self"&gt;Enterprise Technology Standards we find 1 Technology Standard&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the Enterprise which has those capabilities, and that is..... Enterprise Blockchain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enterprise Blockchain ticks those three boxes...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_2-1713703204488.png" style="width: 16px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99503iDB4656E3EE6F0658/image-dimensions/16x16?v=v2" width="16" height="16" role="button" title="AndySilvey_2-1713703204488.png" alt="AndySilvey_2-1713703204488.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Immutable - tick that box&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_2-1713703204488.png" style="width: 16px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99503iDB4656E3EE6F0658/image-dimensions/16x16?v=v2" width="16" height="16" role="button" title="AndySilvey_2-1713703204488.png" alt="AndySilvey_2-1713703204488.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integrity must be protected to the highest level - tick that box, thanks to the Enterprise Blockchain Hash Mechanism and the Enterprise Blockchain Consensus Mechanism&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_2-1713703204488.png" style="width: 16px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99503iDB4656E3EE6F0658/image-dimensions/16x16?v=v2" width="16" height="16" role="button" title="AndySilvey_2-1713703204488.png" alt="AndySilvey_2-1713703204488.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Highest level of resilience and availability - tick that box thanks to the Distributed and Decentralised nature of the Enterprise Blockchain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is why, Enterprise Blockchain is the enabler of trustable outcomes from Enterprise IoT Devices' Data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_5-1713703204734.jpeg" style="width: 852px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99506i419C536501B5D416/image-dimensions/852x426?v=v2" width="852" height="426" role="button" title="AndySilvey_5-1713703204734.jpeg" alt="AndySilvey_5-1713703204734.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;atkrypto.io what is a blockchain&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But there's more than that, IoT Devices can produce a lot of data, and the volumes of data can be big.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And this is why, in this blog we take the Enterprise Blockchain Technology story one level further and we introduce the:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Enterprise Blockchain Wallet&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Off-Chain Data Storage&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Enterprise Blockchain Platforms, the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet is used for Off-Chain storage of big data and in the following paragraphs we will explain why.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What is the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet, and what is Off-Chain Data Storage and why would we use them and why do we need them ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we have explained&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-members/why-i-love-sap-and-blockchain-databases-and-why-you-should-too/ba-p/13625869" target="_self"&gt;in a previous blog&lt;/A&gt;, the Enterprise Blockchain Database, the Distributed Ledger, can be looked at simply as a Database Table (which is replicated and synchronised across multiple Servers) and in principle it stores the Data like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_6-1713703204813.jpeg" style="width: 790px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99507iE8967130B58A8005/image-dimensions/790x401?v=v2" width="790" height="401" role="button" title="AndySilvey_6-1713703204813.jpeg" alt="AndySilvey_6-1713703204813.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Blockchain is a very simple form of database atkrypto.io&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is fine, and suited to what we call&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://aws.amazon.com/compare/the-difference-between-structured-data-and-unstructured-data/#:~:text=Structured%20data%20is%20data%20that,files%20and%20large%20text%20documents." target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Structured Data&lt;/A&gt;, and as AWS nicely describe,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://aws.amazon.com/what-is/structured-data/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Structured Data&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;is information like words and numbers. This kind of data is perfectly suited to being stored in an Enterprise Blockchain Database and also a legacy Database. Examples of the data would Names, Addresses, Phone Numbers, Product Information etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But, IoT Devices can produce a lot of Data, for example, there could be photographs proving that general waste was tipped at the correct certified location, photographs and in large volumes would&amp;nbsp;be too big to be stored on the Enterprise Blockchain Database itself.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And that's ok, Enterprise Blockchain Platforms are ready for that, and have been designed to store both Structured Data and Data which is in files which are so big that they cannot be stored in the Enterprise Blockchain Database itself, for example the photographs from a Waste Truck's onboard camera proving that waste was responsibly tipped in the correct location and taken at the same time as recording GPS location coordinates proving the location of the Waste Truck.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, if we can't store the large photographs files in large quantities to the Enterprise Blockchain Database, then how, in an Enterprise Blockchain Platform do we store large files of Data ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Voila.... bring in the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Wallet. The best Enterprise Blockchain Platform products include what is called the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Wallet, or to make it shorter, the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Enterprise Blockchain Wallet enables us to store large Data, like large Files safely and securely off the chain, or '&lt;A href="https://www.bitdegree.org/crypto/learn/crypto-terms/what-is-off-chain" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Off-Chain&lt;/A&gt;'.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But if we store the large Data files Off-Chain in the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet, then how do we also have them some how on the Enterprise Blockchain Database ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The way this works is elegant, in any decent Enterprise Blockchain Platform, the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet location is completely configurable, and could be anywhere from&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/norway/products/technology-platform/hana/features/cloud-data-lake.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud (Data Lake)&lt;/A&gt;, or for example&amp;nbsp;multiple hyperscaler object stores, such as Amazon S3, OSS (Alicloud Object Storage&lt;BR /&gt;Service), SAP HANA Cloud, Data Lake, and Azure Blob Storage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The configurable Enterprise Blockchain Wallet of the Enterprise Blockchain Platform looks like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_7-1713703204779.jpeg" style="width: 793px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99508i9C1349C576211BAD/image-dimensions/793x443?v=v2" width="793" height="443" role="button" title="AndySilvey_7-1713703204779.jpeg" alt="AndySilvey_7-1713703204779.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Enterprise Blockchain Platform - Enterprise Blockchain Wallets - Configurable Enterprise Wallets - atkrypto.io&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ok, so we've got the IoT Data stored in the (configurable) Enterprise Blockchain Wallet, but what about securing the IoT Data ? Obviously the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet storage location has built in security, for example the SAP HANA Cloud, the AWS S3 Buckets, but we need more than the out of the box security of these products, the reason we are using the Enterprise Blockchain Database is because of the amazing security strengths that it natively out of the box has, and so, what about the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet, doesn't the Enterprise Blockchain Platform have some cool super hard way of protecting the data in the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Well yes it does, this is the magic of Enterprise Blockchain Database 'Off-Chain' storage in the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet. This is so unique to Blockchain Technologies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What happens is this, when store data in the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet, the Enterprise Blockchain Platform software runs a hash algorithm over the data that we have stored and the data, and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://codesigningstore.com/what-is-hashing-algorithm-how-it-works#:~:text=In%20cryptography%2C%20hashing%20is%20a,output%20of%20the%20same%20length." target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;the large file gets hashed&lt;/A&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_8-1713703204730.png" style="width: 768px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99510iF3509D05E84B5D07/image-dimensions/768x227?v=v2" width="768" height="227" role="button" title="AndySilvey_8-1713703204730.png" alt="AndySilvey_8-1713703204730.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The data or the file in the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet gets hashed, and then, that hash is stored in the Enterprise Blockchain Database.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means we now have a unique hash of that data or file, and if anybody or anything makes even the tiniest teeniest change to that data or file, next time we run a hash over that data or file the result will be different that the original hash which is safely stored in the Enterprise Blockchain Database and this is how we will know that the data has been changed and we cannot trust the Data and therefore we cannot use it for our Enterprise IoT Data processing and Insights..&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the other hand, if just before we load the data in to the SAP Enterprise Applications, eg SAP Asset Performance Management and SAP S/4HANA,&amp;nbsp; from the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet, if we run a hash over the data and the hash result is the same as we have in the Enterprise Blockchain Database, then we will know we can trust the Data and we can use it in our SAP Applications and we will have trustable IoT Data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AndySilvey_9-1713703204724.jpeg" style="width: 789px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99509i72AFA7B052607252/image-dimensions/789x444?v=v2" width="789" height="444" role="button" title="AndySilvey_9-1713703204724.jpeg" alt="AndySilvey_9-1713703204724.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Enterprise Blockchain Wallet Data Hashes Stored in the Enterprise Blockchain Database - atkrypto.io&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;And this is why, for all of these reasons,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trustable Enterprise IoT Data depends on Data being stored in the Enterprise Blockchain&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But that's not the end of the Why IoT Data needs Enterprise Blockchain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we showed at the beginning of the blog in this picture:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99516i78EE68F5BDA0E88C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io .png" alt="IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As the picture shows, we have an Enterprise Blockchain Database Tenant installed on a Server Host at the Edge of the Network AND we have an Enterprise Blockchain Data Tenant installed on the SAP BTP Kyma Runtime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The consequence of this is that we have a distributed Enterprise Blockchain Database table which stretches from the Edge of the Network where the IoT Devices are all the way across the Network to the SAP BTP and DataCenter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means we have Enterprise Blockchain Data Protection from the source where the IoT Devices are to the Insights and Business Processes where the SAP Applications are.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have taken the Enterprise Blockchain to the Data at the source at the IoT Devices instead of taking the IoT Device's Data across all of the Networks to the safety of the SAP BTP and DataCenter. This is because we need to store the Data in the Enterprise Blockchain as close as possible to the source of the Data. The closer the Enterprise Blockchain Tenant is to the source of the Data, the safer the Data will be, it's as simple as that. Enterprise Blockchain is the next generation Cyber Security for IoT Data, and we need to minimise the amount of exposure IoT Data has to previous generation security technologies and approaches.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And this is why we say, Enterprise Blockchain is a Secure Communication Channel, because instead of integrating Applications sending and replicating Data across Networks, we are sharing the Data across the Enterprise Blockchain and the Enterprise Blockchain is the Secure Communication Channel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IoT Internet of Things and SAP - Enterprise Blockchain is the next generation Data Cyber Security Protection - atkrypto.io" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99524iE0B4E3EA19DF35AE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IoT Internet of Things and SAP - Enterprise Blockchain is the next generation Data Cyber Security Protection - atkrypto.io .png" alt="IoT Internet of Things and SAP - Enterprise Blockchain is the next generation Data Cyber Security Protection - atkrypto.io" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;IoT Internet of Things and SAP - Enterprise Blockchain is the next generation Data Cyber Security Protection - atkrypto.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To conclude this section, the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Why to, of IoT and Enterprise Blockchain&lt;/EM&gt;, IoT Data&amp;nbsp; needs to Trustable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enterprise Blockchain, due to its native super strong security strength when used as a store of Data enables IoT Data to be Trustable, and the Enterprise Blockchain Software needs be installed as close as possible to the source of the IoT Data, as close as possible to the IoT Devices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Section 3.0: The How is it,&amp;nbsp;of IoT &amp;amp; SAP, and Enterprise Blockchain&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that we know why trustable Enterprise IoT needs the Enterprise Blockchain Database to protect the integrity and originality of the Data, how do we implement it today ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Well that's easy, here are the ingredients and the recipe...&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ingredients, you're going to need:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Data Source(s) eg&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;IoT Devices which are either REST or MQTT (this could be other protocols and transfer mechanisms depending upon the required Adapters)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP and IoT IoT Devices sending Data to MQTT Broker in the Edge Host Instance of the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Database Tenant - atkrypto.io" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99519i3605FA3152934DB4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP and IoT IoT Devices sending Data to MQTT Broker in the Edge Host Instance of the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Database Tenant - atkrypto.io.png" alt="SAP and IoT IoT Devices sending Data to MQTT Broker in the Edge Host Instance of the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Database Tenant - atkrypto.io" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP and IoT IoT Devices sending Data to MQTT Broker in the Edge Host Instance of the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Database Tenant - atkrypto.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP and IoT IoT Devices sending Data to REST Endpoint in the Edge Host Instance of the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Database Tenant - atkrypto.io" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99521iA1FCD76FA6CB022C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP and IoT IoT Devices sending Data to REST Endpoint in the Edge Host Instance of the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Database Tenant - atkrypto.io.png" alt="SAP and IoT IoT Devices sending Data to REST Endpoint in the Edge Host Instance of the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Database Tenant - atkrypto.io" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP and IoT IoT Devices sending Data to REST Endpoint in the Edge Host Instance of the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Database Tenant - atkrypto.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Large Storage for Large Data and the Enterprise Blockchain Wallet&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/norway/products/technology-platform/hana/features/cloud-data-lake.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud (Data Lake)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Enterprise Blockchain Platform and specifically one which is capable of running Tenants as close to the Source of the IoT Data as possible at the Edge. We do NOT want to send the IoT Data across the Internet to a Blockchain somewhere in the Cloud, that would defeat the object of the exercise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These are the basic ingredients, the data from the IoT Devices will be stored either Off-Chain in the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/norway/products/technology-platform/hana/features/cloud-data-lake.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(Data Lake) which will also be the Enterprise Blockchain Platform (configurable) Wallet, or On-Chain in the Enterprise Blockchain Platform Database Ledgers, this Enterprise Blockchain Database Ledger will be running from the Edge to the SAP BTP and DataCenters and then&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Applications like SAP Asset Performance Management and SAP S/4HANA will be able use the Data in Business Processes and Insights.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And your Technical Reference Architecture will look something like this:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/99523i77F022B729519D92/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io .png" alt="IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;IoT Internet of Things Edge Data Cyber Security and SAP Asset Performance Management BTP Protected by Enterprise Blockchain - atkrypto.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And that's how you do it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Wrapping up, conclusions:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. Trustable Enterprise IoT depends on Data being stored in the Enterprise Blockchain at the Edge and in the SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Blockchain is:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Digital Transformation of Information Security to Cyber Security&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. The Next Generation Data Integrity, Originality, Confidentiality Protection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. Re-imagining Information Security&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. Natively, out of the box, due to its special characteristics the strongest, hardest, most resilient Enterprise Database product&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise Blockchain is both:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. a Secure Store&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;. a Secure Communication Channel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The configurable Enterprise Blockchain Wallet enables you to store Big Data 'Off-Chain' and the hashes of the IoT Data are stored safely and securely on the Enterprise Blockchain Database.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The good news is, as we discussed in the previous blog, this is no longer hype, we can do all of this today,&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;and now, within the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/norway/partners/partner-program/build.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Partner Edge Open EcoSystem&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;there are enabling technology Blockchain Products designed and built by SAP Experts specifically for the needs of SAP Customers to make doing Blockchain and SAP easy, and so you can do SAP and Blockchain, today it's real and there's nothing stopping you.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So what are we waiting for ? Oh yeah, more use cases, ok, that will be the next blog.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What do you think, are the words IoT, Blockchain, Web3, Distributed Ledger Technology, starting to appear in your Company's visions and technology visions ? What use cases are you looking at ? Let's chat about it in the comments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For now, over and out.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Andy Silvey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Independent SAP Technical Architect and CEO of atkrypto.io&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Author Bio:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Andy Silvey is a 25 years SAP Technology veteran&amp;nbsp;[&lt;EM&gt;15 years SAP Basis and 10 years SAP Tech Arch including Tech, Integration, Security, Data from 3.1H to S/4HANA PCE on RISE and the BTP and everything in between, and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-blog-posts/andy-silvey-scn-moderator-spotlight/ba-p/13054438" target="_self"&gt;former SCN Moderator and Mentor alumni&lt;/A&gt;].&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Andy is also co-Founder of &lt;A href="http://www.atkrypto.io" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;atkrypto&lt;/A&gt; inc, an startup whose ambition is to make Blockchain easy for Enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;atkrypto.io's flagship product is the atkrypto Enterprise Blockchain Platform for SAP,&amp;nbsp; and atkrypto.io is a SAP Partner Edge Open EcoSystem Partner.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;atkrypto Enterprise Blockchain Platform for SAP has been designed by SAP Independent Experts for the needs of SAP Customers and to be deployed on the SAP BTP Kyma Runtime Service and leverage native integration to SAP Products.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;atkrypto&amp;nbsp;Enterprise Blockchain Platform for SAP has a number of unique qualities, including being the only Blockchain software in the world which has a DataCenter version and a light mobile version which can run on Edge/IoT/Mobile devices and enables data to be written to the Blockchain at the Edge where that same Blockchain is running on a Server in the DataCenter, protecting the integrity and originality of data from the Edge to Insights. Taking Blockchain to the Data at the Edge instead of taking the Data to the Blockchain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All of this makes atkrypto,io the DePIN Decentralised Physical Infrastructure Network solution for Enterprise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;atkrypto is one of the &lt;A href="https://dtw.tmforum.org/next20-startup-program" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Next20 startups&lt;/A&gt; being featured at &lt;A href="https://dtw.tmforum.org/explore/exhibitors/atkrypto-io-119" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;TM Forum's DTW Ignite in Copenhagen in June&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you will be at DTW24 come and talk to us about Cyber Security of SAP Data with Enterprise Blockchain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/iot-ultimate-data-cyber-security-with-enterprise-blockchain-and-sap-btp/ba-p/13676981"/>
    <published>2024-04-22T11:07:39.454000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/uncorking-the-supply-chains-how-ai-embedded-cloud-erp-makes-your-wine-taste/ba-p/13784236</id>
    <title>Uncorking the Supply Chains: How AI-Embedded Cloud ERP Makes Your Wine Taste Better</title>
    <updated>2024-08-06T13:25:51.290000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Oyku_Ilgar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140157</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;From frost challenges in merging vineyards in Essex, UK, to the looming threats of atmospheric rivers in California, environmental unpredictability is reshaping the wine production landscape, forcing winemakers to not only be masters of fermentation but also adaptation.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;As a result, forward-thinking vintners are embracing a high-tech revolution, integrating&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/06/16a5f932-c17e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html?source=social-glo-dsc-forbes-winesupplychain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI to cloud ERP systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;into their operations. These advanced technologies can now influence acidity, sugar levels, and bitterness and perhaps reduce the likelihood of a headache.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Let’s uncork more insight around how AI and cloud ERP are more than just buzzwords as they represent the wine industry's resilience and fusion of tradition with cutting-edge technology.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1022135876"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-825622371"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Harnessing AI to Enhance Efficiency and Adaptability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The wine industry is facing significant challenges due to climate change, with production levels fluctuating dramatically. Last year, global wine production&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.beveragedaily.com/Article/2024/04/30/Global-wine-production-down-9.6-as-extreme-climatic-conditions-severely-impact-vineyards" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;decreased by 9.6%&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;compared to the year before due to adverse climatic events, including early frost, heavy rainfall, drought, and widespread fungal diseases:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Italy experienced a 23.2% decrease in production&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Spain saw a 20.8% decline&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Australia's production fell by 26.2%&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;South Africa's production decreased by 10%&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Greece faced a significant 34.4% reduction due to heavy spring rainfall causing downy mildew, followed by elevated temperatures and drought&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Weather conditions significantly impact the quality and flavor profile of wine worldwide. Warmer temperatures are leading to earlier bud bursts, making vines more susceptible to spring frosts. Changes in ripening patterns are affecting the balance of sugar, acid, and secondary compounds in grapes, leading to wines with higher alcohol content and lower acidity, resulting in wines that taste flabby or lack freshness.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;All facets of wine production must be carefully controlled to create quality wine. Such variables as temperature, weather changes, timing, fermentation, sugar, and acidity levels have a tremendous impact on the finished wine.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-629108866"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exploring the Impact of Supply Chain Innovations on Sustainability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/06/16a5f932-c17e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html?source=social-glo-dsc-forbes-winesupplychain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-embedded cloud ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;systems empower various industries to not just survive but thrive in the face of unexpected challenges. According to the recent IDC Infographic,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/06/16a5f932-c17e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html?source=social-glo-dsc-forbes-winesupplychain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;50% of organizations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;run their operations digitally, underpinned by an AI-powered cloud ERP system that supports digitally transformed operations and supply chains. Having end-to-end visibility is helping wineries and distributors navigate the complex journey from vineyard to glass with unprecedented precision and adaptability.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Predictive analytics and machine learning (ML) algorithms&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for climate adaptation enable winemakers to anticipate future trends and take proactive measures to mitigate the impacts of climate change, such as adjusting planting schedules or implementing protective measures against extreme weather events.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-time monitoring and automating responses&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to protect crops based on real-time data on critical factors like soil moisture, temperature, and wine health. For example, during unexpected frost events, these systems can automatically trigger protective measures like wind machines or heaters, preserving grape quality and preventing crop loss.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Optimizing harvest timing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;based on historical data and grape maturity enables winemakers to determine the optimal harvest time, ensuring grapes are picked at their peak for maximum flavor and balance.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitoring fermentation conditions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;and automatically adjusting parameters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;like temperature ensures a consistent and controlled process in real time.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quality control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;with real-time&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;tracking of grape parameters during harvest&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;alerts winemakers to any deviations from desired quality metrics; which enables them to quick decisions on sorting and processing based on the grape quality. They also blend across vintages to achieve consistency in flavor profiles, balance out variations between years, or create unique and complex wines.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Traceability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;enables tracking of which vineyard blocks are harvested and when. So they can link harvested grapes to specific batches of wine for quality control and compliance purposes.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;These systems also help create efficient harvest schedules, coordinate transportation, and manage grape flow into the winery. By leveraging these capabilities and technology-driven approaches, winemakers can achieve more precise decision-making, potentially improving wine quality and resource efficiency during critical periods.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-432595361"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-236081856"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discovering the sustainable revolution in every drop with AI Embedded ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Having end-to-end visibility into the entire&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;supply chain&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;enables producers to track their environmental impact at every stage. With the usage of&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/sap/2024/02/04/learn-how-the-green-ledger-best-practice-supports-sustainability-goals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;green ledger&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, wineries can track their carbon emissions throughout the supply chain. This helps them to identify areas for improvement and implement greener practices, from reducing water usage in vineyards or procurement processes to optimizing transportation routes for lower emissions.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;By implementing AI-embedded cloud ERP solutions, organizations can achieve a&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/06/16a5f932-c17e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html?source=social-glo-dsc-forbes-winesupplychain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;23%&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;improvement in sustainability practices.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/extended-warehouse-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Inventory management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;also takes on a green hue with AI-embedded cloud ERP. It helps producers to minimize waste by accurately predicting the demand and optimizing stock levels. This not only reduces the carbon footprint associated with overproduction but also ensures resources are used efficiently.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In the face of climate challenges and disruptions that can occur at any time, you cannot have a supply ch&lt;STRONG&gt;AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;n without&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Leveraging&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/06/16a5f932-c17e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html?source=social-glo-dsc-forbes-winesupplychain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-embedded cloud ERP within supply chains&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, industries are not just producing great products, but they are cultivating a sustainable future.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-168651070"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--156945154"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Discover how cutting-edge technologies like AI-embedded cloud ERP can supercharge your business.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/06/16a5f932-c17e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html?source=url_id=social-glo-dsc-sapcommunity-winesupplychain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Download the infographic: “Powering Operations with AI-Embedded Cloud ERP”&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-blog-posts-by-sap/uncorking-the-supply-chains-how-ai-embedded-cloud-erp-makes-your-wine-taste/ba-p/13784236"/>
    <published>2024-08-06T13:25:51.290000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/utilization-of-sap-integration-suite-to-incorporate-satellite-iot-data-into/ba-p/14132061</id>
    <title>Utilization of SAP Integration suite to incorporate satellite IOT data into SAP Systems.</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T10:04:36.856000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Swaita_Banerjee</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2148248</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We can be able to integrate SAP Integration suite with the satellite IoT Data Providers which is an innovative as well as an emerging concept that has vast applications in logistics, defense and agriculture. It involves capturing of the data from satellites which includes geolocation, weather and asset movement while integrating it into the SAP systems like S/4 Hana, EWM and TM via SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;USECASE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagining a logistics company with the fleets operating in some remote areas where GSM/4G signals are not available. Now, satellite IoT devices are often installed on the devices that could send telemetry data like location, temperature via satellite to a cloud provider or ground station. SAP Integration suite can then&lt;BR /&gt;ingest, process and roue this data into the SAP backend systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Architecture Overview:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Swaita_Banerjee_1-1749403006538.png" style="width: 441px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/271472i1C0A067BCDA491F4/image-dimensions/441x337?v=v2" width="441" height="337" role="button" title="Swaita_Banerjee_1-1749403006538.png" alt="Swaita_Banerjee_1-1749403006538.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Flow:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Swaita_Banerjee_2-1749406245831.png" style="width: 482px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/271484iE91B8D9E318ED8C5/image-dimensions/482x284?v=v2" width="482" height="284" role="button" title="Swaita_Banerjee_2-1749406245831.png" alt="Swaita_Banerjee_2-1749406245831.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Swaita_Banerjee_3-1749406311058.png" style="width: 428px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/271485iDFFC21523710D1DD/image-dimensions/428x254?v=v2" width="428" height="254" role="button" title="Swaita_Banerjee_3-1749406311058.png" alt="Swaita_Banerjee_3-1749406311058.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;i-Flow&amp;nbsp;Design Steps in SAP Integration Suite:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/U&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sender: HTTP Receiver from cloud IoT platform with the JSON&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;payload.​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Content Modifier: Extracting GPS, temperature as well as&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;timestamp​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Router: For applying the conditional logic.​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Mapping: Conversion of the data type formats which can include&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;JSON-&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;XML&amp;nbsp;or it can be JSON-&amp;gt; SAP OData Format.​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Receiver: Pushes data&amp;nbsp; into SAP backend using HTTP or OData&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;destination.​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;TESTING:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;​&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We can simulate IoT platform using tools like Postman.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This integration would open doors to the smarter asset tracking as well as real-time decision making areas where GSM (Global System for Mobile Communication) is not available.&amp;nbsp; Hence, SAP Integration Suite makes it possible to diminish the gap between remote IoT data as well as the enterprise systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/utilization-of-sap-integration-suite-to-incorporate-satellite-iot-data-into/ba-p/14132061"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T10:04:36.856000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/gagan-mohan-singh/ba-p/14152377</id>
    <title>Gagan Mohan Singh</title>
    <updated>2025-07-15T13:45:02.432000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanieMarley</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/109</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma, arial, helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;Gagan&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;New Delhi, India&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;SAP Mentor since 2025&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Follow Gagan on &lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gaganmohansingh/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Gagan Mohan Singh.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/286870i3DEBC1EDD68AE625/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Gagan Mohan Singh.png" alt="Gagan Mohan Singh.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Gagan &lt;/STRONG&gt;is a seasoned SAP ERP Cloud architect, business relationship manager, presales strategist and an SAP storyteller with 18+ years of hands-on delivery and quota-carrying sales experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Gagan started his career at IBM where he cut his SAP teeth inside the Global Business Services unit, rolling out ECC for CPG and pharma clients across India. He also rolled out several Continuous Improvement and Key Control Initiatives for PepsiCo, modernised omnichannel retail at Page Industries (Jockey &amp;amp; Speedo), bootstrapped an online FMCG retail start-up, worked on Presales and Program Management at NEC Corporation India and is now responsible for SAP S/4HANA (RISE and GROW)sales and Program Management at Deloitte India. He loves talking about RISE/GROW programmes in SAP and translates deep technical detail into vivid business narratives for his 65,000+ SAP related LinkedIn followers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Topics of interest:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;S/4HANA │ RISE with SAP │ GROW WITH SAP │ SAP BTP Extension &amp;amp; Integration │ SAP Signavio │Omnichannel Retail &amp;amp; CPG │ Presales Craft &amp;amp; Storytelling │ IOT │ AI&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gagan, what inspired you to become an SAP Mentor?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="handshake .png" style="width: 68px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52491i8E9D2FFB3C7BC293/image-dimensions/68x68?v=v2" width="68" height="68" role="button" title="handshake .png" alt="handshake .png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;I’ve always loved sharing what I learn, and giving constructive feedback, so the SAP Mentor program felt like the perfect way to scale that habit. It offers a direct, two-way channel with SAP product managers and leadership—meaning the lessons I pick up in real projects can tangibly shape future releases—and it surrounds me with a community that’s just as passionate about raising the bar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As someone who geeks out over the whole SAP portfolio—especially &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA, RISE with SAP, and Signavio&lt;/STRONG&gt;—I’m thrilled by the prospect of getting an early window into the new products and changes SAP is bringing to market. That behind-the-scenes insight, coupled with the chance to funnel field feedback right back to the engineers, is the part I love most.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What advice would like to share with other SAP community members?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" style="width: 65px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/52495i64D82195EFF8CCB9/image-dimensions/65x65?v=v2" width="65" height="65" role="button" title="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" alt="298874_collaborate_blue (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Give back—consistently and generously. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Whether it's by participating in events, answering questions, or sharing your own learnings, every contribution strengthens the SAP ecosystem. It’s not just a way to show appreciation for what the community has given you—it’s a way to multiply value for everyone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Make contribution a habit. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Whether you're posting on SAP Blogs, writing on LinkedIn, or speaking at an Inside Track, regular engagement helps you enjoy your own work more, navigate challenges better, and build meaningful connections across the globe&lt;STRONG&gt;.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;And always remember:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Amplify others. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Celebrate their wins, share their work—it grows your network and theirs. Ultimately we win together.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Share the full story. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Don’t just post highlights; detail it out, your lessons from failures are often what help others most.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Stay curious. &lt;/STRONG&gt;Make time to explore new SAP tools and innovations—this industry rewards those who keep learning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/gagan-mohan-singh/ba-p/14152377"/>
    <published>2025-07-15T13:45:02.432000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
