<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/NW-ABAP-User-Administration-and-Authorization-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - NW ABAP User Administration and Authorization</title>
  <updated>2025-09-18T11:11:29.287700+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/NW ABAP User Administration and Authorization/pd-p/856729761471794137198600667374174" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>NW ABAP User Administration and Authorization blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/consuming-a-business-technology-platform-service-from-an-s-4-hana-system/ba-p/13557416</id>
    <title>Consuming a Business Technology Platform service from an S/4 HANA system using SM59 destination with OAuth</title>
    <updated>2023-05-19T20:17:30+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mani_P_S</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131162</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;PRE&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;EDIT Oct 2023 - This feature is now available from release 750 with SAP note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3324172/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3324172&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-833115525"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc135214960" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;Scenario Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In this blog, I present an introduction to OAuth and explain how to implement and configure the consumption of an OAuth-enabled service provided by the SAP Business Technology Platform from an SAP S/4HANA system (here workflow service on cloud foundry is used as an example) using the CL_HTTP_CLIENT class and SM59 destination. The blog only focuses on the client credentials and SAML Bearer Assertion grant types.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
We create a simple runnable ABAP class consuming an SM59 destination pointing to the REST API offered by the workflow service for cloud foundry. This is used to get details of the workflow definitions in the subaccount on SAP Business Technology Platform. The SM59 destination shall be configured for using OAuth with client credentials or SAML Bearer flow, as desired.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Here, the workflow service’s REST API is used only for demonstration. In a real use case where you need to connect to the workflow service, there is a dedicated API for this. [&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/proxy-api-for-workflow-capability?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=Cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Read More…&lt;/A&gt;]&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-636602020"&gt;Introduction to OAuth&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In the traditional client-server authentication model, the client requests an access-restricted resource (protected resource) on the server by authenticating with the server using the resource owner's credentials (basic authentication).&amp;nbsp; To provide third-party applications with access to restricted resources, the resource owner shares its credentials with the third party.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/ClientServer.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic;font-family: 'SAPRegular', 'Helvetica Neue', Arial, sans-serif"&gt;Third-party application access in client-server model&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
This creates several problems and limitations such as:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Third-party applications may store the resource owner's credentials for future use, potentially as clear text or with poor encryption.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Servers are required to support password authentication, despite the security weaknesses inherent in passwords.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Third-party applications gain overly broad access to the resource owner's protected resources, leaving resource owners without any ability to restrict duration or access to a limited subset of resources&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Resource owners cannot revoke access to an individual third party without revoking access to all third parties, and must do so by changing the password&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Compromise of any third-party application results in compromise of the end-user's password and all the data protected by that password&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
OAuth addresses these issues by introducing an authorization layer and separating the role of the client from that of the resource owner. In OAuth, the client requests access to resources controlled by the resource owner and hosted by the resource server. The client is issued a different set of credentials than those of the resource owner.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Instead of using the resource owner's credentials to access protected resources, the client obtains an access token -- a string denoting a specific scope, lifetime, and other access attributes.&amp;nbsp; Access tokens are issued to third-party clients by an authorization server with the approval of the resource owner.&amp;nbsp; The client uses the access token to access the protected resources hosted by the resource server. [Source: &lt;A href="https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc6749#page-4" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc6749#page-4&lt;/A&gt;]&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/OAuth.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic;font-family: 'SAPRegular', 'Helvetica Neue', Arial, sans-serif"&gt;Third-party application access with OAuth&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-440088515"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc135214961" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;OAuth Client Credentials v/s SAML Bearer Assertion&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
In this blog, I cover the client credentials and SAML Bearer assertion grant types. It is therefore important to know when to use each of these.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The Client Credentials grant type is used by clients to obtain an access token outside of the context of a user. [&lt;A href="https://oauth.net/2/grant-types/client-credentials/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Read more…&lt;/A&gt;]. This works with the client ID and client secret.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The OAuth SAML bearer assertion grant on the other hand can be used to propagate the principal (the logged on user) from S/4HANA to the Business Technology Platform. [&lt;A href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc7522" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Read more…&lt;/A&gt;]&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-243575010"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc135214962" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;How to use OAuth to connect from SAP S/4 HANA to an SAP Business Technology Platform service&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The following image shows the activities performed by different personas&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/ActivitiesPerformed1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic;font-family: 'SAPRegular', 'Helvetica Neue', Arial, sans-serif"&gt;Activities performed by different personas&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The steps broadly involve the following:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create OAuth 2.0 client profile in SE80&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Establish Trust between the S/4HANA system and the subaccount on SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create OAuth configuration with the appropriate type (SAML Bearer/Client Credentials/…) using the profile created above&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create destination to connect to the BTP service in SM59&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Consume the destination in code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The subsequent sections of this blog detail the steps listed above.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-47061505"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc135214963" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;1. Gather the necessary information needed for configuration&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--20369281"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc135214964" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;1.1. As security administrator of the subaccount on SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Download&amp;nbsp;SAML&amp;nbsp;metadata from&amp;nbsp;the subaccount on SAP Business Technology Platform, where the service instance to be consumed (workflow in our example) is created.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;As security administrator of the subaccount where the service resides, go to the “Trust Configuration” section in the menu and use the “Download SAML Metadata” button&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/downloadSAMLMetadata.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Open the SAML metadata file and note the following details. These details would be used in future steps&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;EntityID - This is the entity ID of the SAML service provider and will be used as&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAML&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Audience&lt;/STRONG&gt; for our OAuth SAML Bearer assertion configuration later&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/entityID.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Location of the SAML binding URI (which contains /oauth/token) - This would be our &lt;STRONG&gt;token service URL&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the configuration&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/locationOfSAMLURI-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--216882786"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc135214965" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;1.2. As space developer of the subaccount on SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Go to the Business Technology Platform service instance (workflow service in this example) and read the service key details. If a service key does not exist, you could create one as per the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/creating-service-keys" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt;. Following information is required from the service key:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--284313572"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc135214966" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;1.2.1. Client ID, Client Secret and URL&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;The Client ID and Client Secret would be used against the corresponding fields in the configuration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;The authorization endpoint in the configuration would be the URL from the service key followed by "/oauth/authorize" without spaces.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/clientidsecret.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--480827077"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc135214967" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;1.2.2. Endpoints - WORKFLOW REST URL&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/workflowresturl.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The host for our SM59 destination used to connect to the workflow service shall be this URL without the https://&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The part of this URL after “.com” shall form the &lt;STRONG&gt;path prefix&lt;/STRONG&gt; of our SM59 destination for a basic connection to the workflow service. To make this more meaningful, we will enhance this path prefix with the specific REST endpoint for the workflow definitions.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--806423301"&gt;&lt;A name="_Toc135214968" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;1.3. Using web browser to access the API Business Hub&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
To identify the specific path to the workflow-definitions endpoint, go to the API Business Hub (api.sap.com)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Search for the “Workflow service for cloud foundry”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to the &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/SAP_CP_Workflow_CF/resource/Workflow_Definitions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;API Reference section&lt;/A&gt; and pick a suitable &lt;STRONG&gt;path prefix&lt;/STRONG&gt; (example: workflow-definitions)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/apihub-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The summary of required details and where to find them is presented by the following image&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/summaryofdetails.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--362279442"&gt;2. Establish trust between the S/4HANA System and the Business Technology Platform&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--852195954"&gt;2.1. As administrator of the S/4HANA system&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This step can be skipped if client credentials grant type is used. See section OAuth configuration with client credentials.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
For the S/4HANA system to issue a SAML assertion and for the Business Technology Platform to validate this, we need to establish trust. To achieve this -&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Login to&amp;nbsp;the SAP S/4HANA&amp;nbsp; system and start the oa2c_config transaction&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Enable SAML 2.0 by clicking the “&lt;STRONG&gt;SAML 2.0 Enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt;” button&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Download SAML 2.0 metadata using the “&lt;STRONG style="font-size: 1rem"&gt;Download SAML 2.0 Metadata&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN style="font-size: 1rem"&gt;” button&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/samlmetadatas4h.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If the download button is not visible, apply SAP Note &lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/3229914" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3229914&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1048709459"&gt;2.2. As security administrator of the subaccount on SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Note: This step can be skipped if client credentials grant type is used. See section OAuth configuration with client credentials.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
To set the ABAP system as the SAML Assertion issuer for getting the credentials (Email) whenever a token is requested&lt;EM&gt;, &lt;/EM&gt;upload the&amp;nbsp;SAML&amp;nbsp;2.0 Metadata downloaded in step 3, to&amp;nbsp;the subaccount on SAP Business Technology Platform.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;As security administrator, go to the trust configuration section of the subaccount which contains the service instance you wish to use (in our example, workflow)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Click the “New Trust Configuration” button&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Upload the SAML 2.0 metadata downloaded from the OA2C_CONFIG transaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
After the upload, a new&amp;nbsp;identity provider (IDP)&amp;nbsp;would be listed with the name specified in the form&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/newidp.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Note: We do not need this identity provider (IDP) for user logon. Therefore, make sure to disable the “Available for user logon” checkbox.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1245222964"&gt;2.3. Add SSL/TLS digital signature certificate to the certificate list of the SSL Client Anonymous PSE (Personal Security Environment)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
To establish a trusted relationship using the OAuth 2.0 client with SAP Business Technology Platform, you must use an SSL/TLS communication channel between your service provider (SAP BTP) and the SAP S/4HANA System. For this purpose, the service provider (SAP BTP) and the SAP S/4HANA System must trust each other. This is achieved by placing the SSL/TLS digital signature certificate of the service provider (SAP BTP) in the certificate list of the SSL Client Anonymous PSE (Personal Security Environment) of the SAP S/4HANA system.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1735139476"&gt;2.3.1. Using web browser in the SAP Business Technology Platform,&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;To achieve this, open the subaccount and from the address bar of the browser, click the lock icon&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/lockicon.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Go to “Connection is secure”-&amp;gt;” Certificate is valid”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Go to the details tab and export the certificate for the root CA of the certificate hierarchy&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/certificateexport.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1931652981"&gt;2.3.2. As administrator in the S/4HANA system&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;In the S/4HANA system, go to transaction STRUST and open the edit mode&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Under the SSL Client (Anonymous), double click the subject. Scroll down to the certificate section and click the import certificate button&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/strustanonym.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Import the certificate exported above and save&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1541360472"&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;Configure connection to the BTP service via OAuth&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
To make sure that users access only the resources that are exposed to them, you can restrict access through scopes in an OAuth client profile. An OAuth 2.0 scope represents a list of resources that can be accessed by remote applications.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--2031276984"&gt;3.1. As developer on the S/4HANA system&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;In the SAP S/4HANA system, use transaction SE80.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Under your development package, create an OAUTH 2.0 Client Profile. This is used to define the scopes. For simplicity, I do not specify any scopes in our example&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/samlprofile.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Specifying the wildcard * under scopes is NOT the same as not specifying any scopes. Specifying such a wildcard could cause errors.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-2067176807"&gt;3.2. As Administrator on the S/4HANA system&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Next, we need a client for our communication. The communication between OAuth 2.0 client and server is secured by an HTTPS connection. The end users can then use services and resources offered by the service provider&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Use T-code OA2C_CONFIG to create an OAUTH 2.0&amp;nbsp;client.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;When requested for OAUTH profile name, use the profile name created SE80. Use Client ID copied from the information gathering stage.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/SAMLClient.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;We now can choose the OAuth method we wish to use. In the current blog, we restrict the explanation to only the Client Credentials and SAML Bearer Assertion approaches.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1577260295"&gt;3.2.1. OAuth Configuration with Client Credentials&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Provide the following details based on the results of the information gathering section&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Client Secret&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Authorization Endpoint&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Token Endpoint&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Remaining Details:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Client Authentication: Form Fields&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Resource Access Authentication: Header Field&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Selected Grant Type: Client Credentials&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1548930481"&gt;3.2.2. OAuth Configuration with SAML Bearer Assertion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Provide the following details based on the results of the information gathering section&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Client secret&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Authorization Endpoint&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Token Endpoint&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;SAML&amp;nbsp;2.0 audience&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;SAML&amp;nbsp;2.0 recipient: &amp;lt;Auto populated using Token endpoint&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Remaining Details:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Client Authentication: Form Fields/Basic&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Resource Access Authentication: Header Field&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Selected Grant Type: Current User Related&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Grant Type (Current User Related): SAML 2.0 Bearer Assertion&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;User Email for SAML 2.0 Name ID: 000&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/samlbearerconfig.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Once configuration is done and saved, a test could be done using T-Code OA2C_GRANT. Select the profile and click on the button “Request OAUTH 2.0 Token”. If everything is configured correctly, the “Access Status” column will be green and “Receive Date”, “Receive Time” would be filled&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/oa2cgrant1.png" /&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/oa2cgrant2.png" /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The OA2C_GRANT transaction, shown under administrator activities on SAP S/4HANA can only be used to request access tokens for user-related grant types, i.e. SAML Bearer Assertion grant type (see section OAuth configuration with SAML Bearer Assertion) and Authorization Code grant type (not covered in this blog). The OA2C_GRANT app cannot be used to request an access token for OAuth configurations where the Client Credentials grant type is selected&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Since we are propagating the email ID for single sign-on, users in&amp;nbsp;the S/4HANA system&amp;nbsp;should have email id maintained. Use transaction SU01 to verify this&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/su01.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1645819983"&gt;3.3. As Security Administrator on the Business Technology Platform&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Assign Roles/Role Collections to&amp;nbsp;S/4HANA&amp;nbsp;On Premise specific users (by using the new&amp;nbsp;IDP&amp;nbsp;we set up).&lt;BR /&gt;
This step is only needed if you chose the OAuth SAML Bearer Assertion in the previous step&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/workflowroles.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1449306478"&gt;3.4. As Administrator in the S/4HANA system, create SM59 destination with OAuth settings&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;On the S/4HANA System, go to transaction SM59 and create a destination of type G (HTTP connections to external server). We use Type G since we wish to connect to BTP which is external.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Under the technical settings tab, provide the following details:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Host: api.workflow-sap.cfapps.sap.hana.ondemand.com (Obtained in the information gathering section)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Path Prefix: /workflow-service/rest/v1/workflow-definitions (Here, and /v1/workflow-definitions is the additional path we use to get the workflow-definitions)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Port: 443 (Default HTTPS port)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/technicalSettings.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Under the Logon and Security tab,&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Use the OAuth Settings button to link the OAuth configuration we did earlier with the SM59 destination&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Click the button and provide the OAuth profile name and OAuth configuration names as defined in corresponding steps&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/logonsecurity.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI style="list-style-type: none"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Scroll down to the security options and under “Status of Secure Protocol”, ensure the following:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;SSL: Active&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;SSL Certificate: ANONYM SSL Client (Anonymous)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/SSLAnonym.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Perform a connection test to ensure everything is set up correctly. If all configuration is correct, you should get a status code 200&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/SM59Test.png" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1546195980"&gt;4. Use the destination in ABAP Code&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
The SM59 destination, now linked to the OAuth configuration can be used in ABAP code as demonstrated in the following runnable class (created as developer in the S/4HANA system)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;PRE class="language-abap"&gt;&lt;CODE&gt;class ZCL_OAUTH_BTP_WF definition&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
public&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
final&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
create public .&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
public section.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
INTERFACES IF_OO_ADT_CLASSRUN.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
protected section.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
private section.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
ENDCLASS.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
CLASS ZCL_OAUTH_BTP_WF IMPLEMENTATION.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
METHOD IF_OO_ADT_CLASSRUN~MAIN.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
TRY.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
* Create HTTP client using the SM59 Destination with log-on configured using OAuth&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
CALL METHOD cl_http_client=&amp;gt;create_by_destination&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
EXPORTING&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
destination = 'S4H_2021_BTP_WF' "Name of SM59 Destination&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
IMPORTING&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
client = DATA(http_client).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
IF sy-subrc &amp;lt;&amp;gt; 0.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
out-&amp;gt;write( 'Could not create http client' ).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
ENDIF.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
* In productive code, handle potentially raised exceptions better. Not handled here for brevity&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
http_client-&amp;gt;send( ).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
http_client-&amp;gt;receive( ).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
http_client-&amp;gt;response-&amp;gt;get_status( IMPORTING&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
code = DATA(status_code)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
reason = DATA(http_status_description) ).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
out-&amp;gt;write( 'HTTP Status: ' &amp;amp;&amp;amp; status_code ).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
* Read the parsed character data from the HTTP response&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
DATA(workflow_definition_data) = http_client-&amp;gt;response-&amp;gt;get_cdata( ).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
out-&amp;gt;write( workflow_definition_data ).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
* Generic exception handling done for brevity&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
IF http_client-&amp;gt;oauth_last_err_txt IS NOT INITIAL.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
out-&amp;gt;write( http_client-&amp;gt;oauth_last_err_txt ).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
ENDIF.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
CATCH cx_root INTO DATA(exception).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
out-&amp;gt;write( exception-&amp;gt;get_longtext( ) ).&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
ENDTRY.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
ENDMETHOD.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
ENDCLASS.&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Executing this class, provides the details of workflow definitions in the subaccount&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/output.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
For some troubleshooting guidance in case of issues and to share your experiences with issues you may face, please refer the following blog:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/05/19/troubleshooting-errors-when-connecting-to-a-service-on-sap-business-technology-platform-through-oauth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Troubleshooting errors when connecting to a service on SAP Business Technology Platform through OAuth&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
What is your experience with OAuth in SAP software? Looking forward to discussions in the comments section!</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/consuming-a-business-technology-platform-service-from-an-s-4-hana-system/ba-p/13557416"/>
    <published>2023-05-19T20:17:30+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/troubleshooting-errors-when-connecting-to-a-service-on-sap-business/ba-p/13557536</id>
    <title>Troubleshooting errors when connecting to a service on SAP Business Technology Platform through OAuth</title>
    <updated>2023-05-19T20:28:08+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mani_P_S</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131162</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Motivation:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In my earlier blog, &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/05/19/consuming-a-business-technology-platform-service-from-an-s-4-hana-system-using-sm59-destination-with-oauth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Consuming a Business Technology Platform service from an S/4 HANA system using SM59 destination with OAuth&lt;/A&gt;, I covered what it takes to connect to an SAP BTP service from S/4HANA on-premise using OAuth. Here, we look at some errors one may come across and how to troubleshoot them. This is by no means an exhaustive list and I encourage you to share the errors/issues you face in the comments section so over a period, this grows into a document that can help a lot of people&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Useful troubleshooting technique:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Run the report OA2C_GENERIC_ACCESS with SE38. This is a report that can be used to test the OAuth 2.0 client configuration/access tokens request (for all grant types). The report shows the complete raw error response which might be helpful for troubleshooting.&lt;BR /&gt;
Example:&lt;BR /&gt;
Error when trust configuration is missing/wrong on the Business Technology Platform:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/error1-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;Error when “&lt;EM&gt;&amp;lt;URL&amp;gt;&lt;/EM&gt;/oauth/token” is configured as token endpoint in OA2C_CONFIG instead of “&lt;EM&gt;&amp;lt;URL&amp;gt;&lt;/EM&gt;/oauth/token/alias/&lt;EM&gt;mytenant&lt;/EM&gt;” (from the downloaded SAML Metadata):&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/05/Error2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Some other errors/issues along with solutions:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Download SAML Metadata button not visible in t-code OA2C_CONFIG&lt;BR /&gt;
Solution: Apply SAP Note &lt;A style="font-size: 1rem" href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/3229914" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3229914&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN style="font-size: 1rem"&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL start="2"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;OA2C_GRANT does not return OAuth 2.0 token&lt;BR /&gt;
Solution: In OA2C_CONFIG, for the created configuration, verify if the following are correctly mapped:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Client ID/ Client Secret are as defined in the service key of the BTP service being connected to (workflow service in this example)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;The SAML 2.0 Audience is the "Entity ID" from the SAML Metadata of the sub-account which we are connecting to. The SAML metadata can be downloaded under "Trust Configuration" section of the sub-account&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;The Token End Point is the Location ID from the SAML metadata of the sub-account which contains "/oauth/token". Ensure the Location ID is copied along with alias&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL start="3"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Error: "Create Failed" when doing a connection test in SM59&lt;BR /&gt;
Solution: Check the token service URL in OA2C_CONFIG. Check if "https://" is repeated. Note: This is automatically added and while copy-pasting the URL, this needs to be done without https://&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL start="4"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Error: "Connection to &amp;lt;URL&amp;gt; broken" when doing a connection test in SM59&lt;BR /&gt;
Solution: Under the Logon and Security Tab of the SM59 destination, under status of secure protocol, make sure SSL is active and the right SSL certificate is chosen (where the certificate from BTP was imported)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Additional material for troubleshooting at the level of the XSUAA service on the Business Technology Platform:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Status Code 401:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ga.support.sap.com/dtp/viewer/index.html#/tree/2212/actions/28290:52819" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://ga.support.sap.com/dtp/viewer/index.html#/tree/2212/actions/28290:52819&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;SAML Issues:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ga.support.sap.com/dtp/viewer/index.html#/tree/2212/actions/28290" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://ga.support.sap.com/dtp/viewer/index.html#/tree/2212/actions/28290&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;E.g.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ga.support.sap.com/dtp/viewer/index.html#/tree/2212/actions/28290:48369" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://ga.support.sap.com/dtp/viewer/index.html#/tree/2212/actions/28290:48369&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ga.support.sap.com/dtp/viewer/index.html#/tree/2212/actions/28290:48362" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://ga.support.sap.com/dtp/viewer/index.html#/tree/2212/actions/28290:48362&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Trust Establishment in general (both SAML and OIDC):&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/establish-trust-and-federation-between-uaa-and-identity-authentication" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/establish-trust-and-federation-between-uaa-and-identity-authentication&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Attribute Mapping (SAML):&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/federation-attribute-settings-of-any-identity-provider" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/federation-attribute-settings-of-any-identity-provider&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Looking forward to hearing your experiences with this setup, the issues/struggles you had or on the other hand, the great experience you had!&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/troubleshooting-errors-when-connecting-to-a-service-on-sap-business/ba-p/13557536"/>
    <published>2023-05-19T20:28:08+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/should-we-use-sap-standard-roles-or-not/ba-p/13564853</id>
    <title>Should we use SAP Standard Roles or not.</title>
    <updated>2023-07-25T22:13:28+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>nishusingh123</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/691811</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
As SAP security practitioners, we frequently encounter a critical decision-making process concerning the effective management of user access. Today, we will explore a pivotal subject that often sparks debates within the SAP community: &lt;STRONG&gt;The utilization of SAP Standard Roles&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP Standard Roles are predefined roles provided by SAP for each of its applications or modules, identifiable by their nomenclature starting with "SAP*."&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP's Recommendation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP advises against direct usage of standard roles and instead recommends utilizing them as a reference for creating customized roles within the client namespace. It is not mandatory for the client namespace to be designated as Z* or Y*, as long as the roles created do not commence with SAP* and are tailored to suit the specific requirements of the client.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In fact, any attempt to create a role starting with SAP will result in an error message stating: "Role SAPXXX... is not in the customer namespace."&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Rationale for Avoidance:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;EM&gt;The suggestion to avoid employing SAP standard roles is based on several reasons:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security Risks&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP standard roles are generic and grant extensive authorizations, potentially exposing sensitive data and functionalities unnecessarily.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compliance Concerns&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Standard roles may not align with industry-specific compliance requirements, leading to potential audit failures and legal consequences.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Limited Flexibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Standard roles may not cater to an organization's unique business processes and security needs, hindering the ability to customize authorizations effectively.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Complex Role Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;: As the organization expands, managing and updating standard roles can become cumbersome, whereas custom roles can be more efficiently maintained.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reduced Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP standard roles often provide more access privileges than required, compromising user efficiency and increasing the risk of misuse.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conflict Resolution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Addressing segregation of duties (SoD) conflicts or user access issues with standard roles can be challenging due to their generalized nature.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Impact of SAP Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAP system upgrades may modify standard roles, potentially disrupting user access and necessitating additional configuration efforts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommended Approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
To overcome these challenges, it is advisable to implement custom roles based on the principle of least privilege. Custom roles offer more precise control over user access, aligning authorizations with specific job duties and ensuring compliance with industry regulations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Engaging in a Professional Discourse - Welcome Your Valuable Contributions! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":briefcase:"&gt;💼&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
I cordially extend an invitation to SAP enthusiasts, security experts, and professionals to participate in a constructive conversation. Together, let us exchange insightful thoughts, valuable experiences, and industry best practices pertaining to SAP access management. We encourage you to share success stories, encountered challenges, and innovative solutions in the comments section below. Your contributions will undoubtedly enrich the discussion and foster a collaborative learning environment.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/should-we-use-sap-standard-roles-or-not/ba-p/13564853"/>
    <published>2023-07-25T22:13:28+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/bw-4hana-security-sap-bw-4hana-migration-remote-conversion/ba-p/13575339</id>
    <title>BW/4HANA Security: SAP BW/4HANA Migration (Remote Conversion)</title>
    <updated>2023-08-06T05:44:48+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Krishan_Singh_Chauhan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-834902089"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP BW/4HANA is a next generation data warehouse solution developed by SAP. The underlying foundation of SAP BW/4HANA is the SAP HANA in-memory database, which means that the data is stored and processed in the main memory of the server resulting faster data retrieval, processing, and analytics compared to traditional disk-based databases.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP BW/4HANA simplifies data modeling, enables real-time analytics, and supports integration with advanced technologies like big data and machine learning. It helps organizations consolidate, manage, and analyze large volumes of data, providing timely insights for data-driven decision-making.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Organizations that have been using the earlier version of SAP BW can migrate to SAP BW/4HANA. The migration process involves converting the existing data models, objects, and applications to the new platform, taking advantage of the improved features and capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-767471303"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Scenario:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organization is planning to migrate from BW to BW/4HANA solution but they are keen to know the impact on security authorizations. Also, the security authorization activities to be carried out as a part of the migration. This article will help the organization to achieve their requirements in terms of security authorizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-570957798"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step1: Transport SU25 changes&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a transport request in BW system for customer tables.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transport the customer tables from BW to BW/4HANA system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-374444293"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step2: SAP BW Users.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discuss with the business about the SAP BW user master i.e. how they want to handle the users in BW/4HANA system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If business agrees for client copy via BW system then copy profile SAP_UONL (User Without Authorization Profiles and Roles) into BW/4HANA system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-177930788"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step3: Transport BW Analysis Authorizations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discuss with the business and identify the list of BW analysis authorizations which are in scope i.e. BW analysis authorizations which needs to be available in BW/4HANA system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transport the scoped analysis authorizations from BW to BW/4HANA system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--18582717"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step4: Transport BW roles&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discuss with the business and identify the list of BW roles which are in scope i.e. BW roles which needs to be available in BW/4HANA system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Transport the scoped roles from BW to BW/4HANA system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--215096222"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step5: Run SU25 Steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Execute SU25 steps i.e. Step 2A, 2B, 2D and 2C&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extract the list of impacted roles, discuss with the business and remediate the roles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--411609727"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step6: Execute Transfer of Authorizations into BW/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BW specific authorizations for object types get impacted when we convert SAP BW to SAP BW/4HANA system like InfoCubes and those must be replaced by authorizations for corresponding object types like ADSO.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Program “RS_B4HTAU_CREATE_RUN” gives you the list of impacted authorizations for the corresponding object types.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run Program “RS_B4HTAU_CREATE_RUN” into BW/4HANA system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/1-13.png" border="0" width="814" height="443" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create Rule ID to perform Transfer of Authorizations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/2-11.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.2&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add the required BW/scoped roles which needs to be analyzed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/3-10.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on the settings button to add the Suffix for the new BW/4HANA role i.e. when you execute this tool, system automatically creates new role with adjustment of authorizations for corresponding object types.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/5-5.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.4&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Selected BW/scoped roles with corresponding new BW/4HANA roles (with suffix) gets available in the Transfer of Authorizations tool.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/6-5.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.5&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on Initial Run and Delta Run to perform the analysis on the selected BW roles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/7-2.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.6&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The output of Initial Run and Delta Run gives you the following Action Types:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ASSUME: &lt;/STRONG&gt;No change in authorizations for object types i.e. Authorization will continue to work even after the conversion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/7-3.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.7&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ADJUST: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Check if there is any change in the values of authorization object and adapt it accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/8-4.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.8&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;REPLACE: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Change the Authorization Objects and adapt it's values accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/9-2.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.9&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/10-2.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.10&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;OBSOLETE: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Authorization object is not supported or obsolete, should be removed/deactivated from the role.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/11-3.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.11&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click on the Generate button to create and generate the new BW/4HANA role with defined suffix.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;IMG src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/12-1.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Fig.1.12&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Role gets created &amp;amp; generated into BW/4HANA system with automatically adjustments of All Action Types.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If there is a business requirement that not to create any new role and wants to make use of the existing role then based on the Action Types, existing roles must be modified manually via PFCG.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BW/4HANA has some Fiori Apps which can be enabled and mapped into the roles based on the business requirement.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--349957794"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;List of Important Notes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2383530" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2383530 - Conversion from SAP BW to SAP BW/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2468657" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2468657 - BW4SL &amp;amp; BWbridgeSL - Standard Authorizations&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2930058" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2930058 - FAQ - SAP BW/4 Conversions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--546471299"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;List of Important Links:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_BW4HANA/d3b558c9e49d4eb495c99c63a0ae549a/4f0b56878a585f86e10000000a42189b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Security Guide SAP BW∕4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Feedbacks, questions and comments are most welcome!!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Please follow my profile for future posts on SAP Security and GRC. Also, follow myself via&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/krishan-singh-chauhan-6bb474119/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Happy Learnings!&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Krishan Singh Chauhan&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/bw-4hana-security-sap-bw-4hana-migration-remote-conversion/ba-p/13575339"/>
    <published>2023-08-06T05:44:48+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/filter-table-maintenance-view-rows-based-on-user-authorizations/ba-p/13573814</id>
    <title>Filter table maintenance view rows based on user authorizations</title>
    <updated>2023-09-01T17:02:26+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Buddhinath</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/159583</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-963929964"&gt;Requirement&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;We have a custom Z-table with Sales Organization and Order Type as key fields.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;There's an associated maintenance view.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Users will be using this maintenance view to maintain entries in the table.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Users should only be allowed to display and edit records that belong to the sales organizations and certain order types that they are authorized to.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-767416459"&gt;The usual approach&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
As many of the articles would suggest, the most sought-after approach would be to create 2 authorization objects (one for sales org, one for order type) and then use maintenance view Events 01 (Before saving the data in the database) and AA (Instead of the standard data read routine) to check each row's data against the authorization object and remove unauthorized entries.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-829068392"&gt;Pros:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;If the authorization objects are already in place and assigned to the user, there's no work to be done from the authorization (BASIS) perspective.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;As this is purely a custom logic, this also gives freedom to introduce new error messages, extra validations, etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-632554887"&gt;Cons:&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;There is coding involved as the authorization check happens at the code level.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;As there's custom code involved, there will be increased unit test efforts for positive and negative scenarios to ensure that all scenarios (display, change, insert, delete) work as expected.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;If we don't authorize the maintenance view from standard auth objects (S_TABU_DIS), the user should have "change" access to the SM30 transaction. Then the coding will have to control everything else. With the user getting "change" permissions to SM30, other Z tables will also become changeable - which is not what we expect.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;One can't see from the authorization object assignment perspective whether there is an object assigned to the maintenance view or not.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-177875944"&gt;The better approach&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
We can use the two standard authorization objects and the maintenance view's authorization group to handle this requirement with no code changes.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The authorization checks, error handling, and everything is handled by the standard itself which takes a significant burden off our shoulders. Also, we can clearly see in user roles how the assignment is done.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Here are the steps:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-239527877"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authorization Group&lt;/STRONG&gt; setup&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
This is needed only if you don't have an Authorization Group created already.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI style="list-style-type: none"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Go to the table maintenance view generator, and create an &lt;STRONG&gt;Authorization Group&lt;/STRONG&gt; via &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Environment &amp;gt; Authorization &amp;gt; Authorization Group&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/2023-08-30_19-31-31-auth-grp.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;In the new screen, under object &lt;STRONG&gt;S_TABU_DIS&lt;/STRONG&gt;, create a new Authorization Group with a 4-character name that starts with Z. For this scenario, let's say it's &lt;STRONG&gt;ZAUT&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/2023-08-30_20-31-22-aut.jpg" height="184" width="294" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Go back, and assign this new Authorization Group in the Table Maintenance Dialog Genearator window.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/2023-08-30_19-30-28-auth-table.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-43014372"&gt;Authorization Object: &lt;STRONG&gt;S_TABU_LIN&lt;/STRONG&gt; setup&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Go to &lt;STRONG&gt;SPRO &amp;gt; IMG &amp;gt; SAP NetWeaver &amp;gt; Application Server &amp;gt; System Administration &amp;gt; Users and Authorization &amp;gt; Line-oriented Authorization &amp;gt; Define organizational criteria&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/2023-08-30_19-36-28-spro.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Create new &lt;STRONG&gt;Organization criteria&lt;/STRONG&gt; entry:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/2023-08-30_20-35-52-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;We don't need to do anything for the "Assignment of authority object to organizational c" step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Select the created entry, and go to "&lt;STRONG&gt;Attributes&lt;/STRONG&gt;". Then, hit "&lt;STRONG&gt;New Entry&lt;/STRONG&gt;". Here, we can list up to 8 attributes. The attributes are basically the key fields that we need to filter the records based on values that we define later. In this example, we need 2 attributes - VKORG, AUART. Create the first:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/2023-08-30_20-37-00-2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Hit the "&lt;STRONG&gt;Next Entry&lt;/STRONG&gt;" button and create the second attribute as well. Note that the "&lt;STRONG&gt;Authorization fld:&lt;/STRONG&gt;" value at the bottom of the screen is now changed to ORG_FIELD2 from ORG_FIELD1 for VKORG.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/2023-08-30_20-38-05-3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Then, go to "Table Fields" in the left-side tree. And create an entry specifying our custom table and field name that would align with this attribute.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/09/2023-09-05_18-00-44.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Do the same for the next field (Attribute 2) as well. And continue to do this for all the attributes you've defined.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Once done, save under a workbench TR and exit.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--153499133"&gt;Authorization Object configuration from BASIS&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Now, it's time to set the appropriate values for the respective authorization objects so the setup starts working as we want.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Set "Change" permission for the Authorization Group via the &lt;STRONG&gt;S_TABU_DIS&lt;/STRONG&gt; authorization object. To do so, set&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;ACTVT&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;= 02&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DICBERCLS = ZAUT &lt;/STRONG&gt;(authorization group assigned to the table)&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/STRONG&gt;This allows the user to access the tables with auth group ZAUT in change mode.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/2023-08-30_19-51-49-auth-dis.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Set row-level filtering via S_TABU_LIN authorization object. Set values as&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;ACTVT = 02&lt;BR /&gt;
ORG_CRIT = ZTESTAUTH &lt;/STRONG&gt;(this is the new organization criteria we created in SPRO)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;ORG_FIELD1 = &amp;lt;sales org&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
ORG_FIELD2 = &amp;lt;order type&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
With this setup, it says that the user can insert/change/delete the entries belonging to sales org 1030 and order type ZORD.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/08/2023-08-30_20-00-11-auth-lin.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;Assign these to respective roles and to the users as usual and let the standard take care of all the validations, etc.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--608178076"&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--804691581"&gt;Useful Links&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/HR_RENEWAL/28cb35be3518492c9ac9786bb7cf468d/db03dd5321e8424de10000000a174cb4.html?version=1.4.latest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP's documentation on S_TABU_LIN&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;A href="https://www.sapsecuritypages.com/sap-tables-s_tabu_lin/#google_vignette" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;A step-by-step guide on setting up S_TABU_LIN including the authorization assignment&lt;/A&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/filter-table-maintenance-view-rows-based-on-user-authorizations/ba-p/13573814"/>
    <published>2023-09-01T17:02:26+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/custom-tcode-management/ba-p/13580494</id>
    <title>Custom Tcode Management</title>
    <updated>2023-09-22T00:31:35+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shivkumar_B1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879151</uri>
    </author>
    <content>As an SAP Authorization Administrator would have come across with Functional/IT team creating Custom tcodes for a specific Business purpose and requesting Auth team to include into a suitable role.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
There are many projects/organizations still not managing custom tcodes methodically, leading to audit deficiency and in some cases misuse of critical access assigned via custom tcode.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Also, if custom tcodes technical name not based on functionality i.e Create/Change/Display, then it will be a tedious effort to categorize and also mapping into GRC ruleset for the first time, when there are hundreds of custom tcodes to be looked into.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Purpose&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This document provides information on managing Custom Tcodes in any organization from an SAP Authorization team perspective.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In SAP we have many modules and each module has specific tcodes in place to process Business data. There are few instances where Business team needs to be restricted with few fields or added more fields in a standard tcode provided by SAP. This type of requirement differs from Business to Business.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
There also few scenarios when Custom data managed in a custom table, needs to be given access to Business/IT teams for data processing.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Let’s take an example a Business team intend to restrict Company Code data field in the SAP standard tcode XK02 i.e changing Vendor. Hence based on Business requirement a Custom tcode copy of XK02 need to build with restricted Company Code Data field.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Based on my experience and per SAP best practice, i would suggest the below steps as a SAP Authorization Administrator.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Whenever there is a need for Custom development, make sure it is relevant, unless the business requirement cannot be fulfilled/managed by SAP standard tcode. If there is an alternative tcode, suggest Business team to leverage with the same and avoid custom development.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP Functional/ABAP team should involve Authorization team from the initial discussions since Business team mostly contact Functional team. This will help Auth team to understand the requirement in terms of auth checks, objects, table access requirement etc.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Upon the requirement is finalized, let there be a Functional/Technical Spec document for Custom tcode which includes Custom program names, objects, tables, Custom tcode and most important functionality i.e Create/Change/Display type of the tcode. As per SAP best practice it is suggested to use SAP standard objects within custom program and it is fine to create custom tables if needed.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Also, insist ABAP team to name custom tcode based on the nature of tcode i.e ending with 01 for create/ending with 02 for change etc. and update suitable Tcode description as per the type, since this will help to identify type of tcode if there is no proper documentation.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Upon ABAP/Functional team completes necessary developments in Dev system, Authorization team can build a test role with new Custom tcode added and assign test role to a test user for further testing from Functional team.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Enable Auth trace for the test user to capture the auth check objects within the trace.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If no objects traced when tcode successfully executed, it means there is no Authority check enabled in the Custom Program and hence inform ABAP team to include suitable objects under Authority-Check section of the custom program. Relevant Auth objects can also be identified if custom tcode is a copy of standard tcode in SU24 and same can be enabled for Custom tcode program.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Scenario 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If objects are populated in the Auth trace as missing auth, then relevant object can be added into test role to make sure it executes successfully. Later inform ABAP team to include in the Authority-Check section with relevant objects, if not enabled in the custom program. Please make note of these objects which required to be added into SU24.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Other option to get objects relevant by executing program &lt;STRONG&gt;RS_ABAP_SOURCE_SCAN&lt;/STRONG&gt; with below mentioned search strings and based on the results ,we could classify Change/Display tcode ,based on objects with Activity i.e Change/Display.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
AUTHORITY-CHECK&lt;BR /&gt;
BDC_INSERT&lt;BR /&gt;
CALL FUNCTION&lt;BR /&gt;
Call Transaction&lt;BR /&gt;
Call Method&lt;BR /&gt;
Submit Report&lt;BR /&gt;
Submit&lt;BR /&gt;
Update table/Database&lt;BR /&gt;
Delete from&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Maintain relevant Auth objects identified from previous steps into SU24 with required Values as well.&amp;nbsp; After saving the changes, it will request for a Workbench transport request and capture in the same.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 6: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Assign custom tcode into desired Business Role and make sure Auth objects are populated into the role, which were included in SU24.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 7: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Get the necessary Unit testing performed to make sure Custom tcode functionality works as expected and proceed further with Quality for UAT.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Also update into GRC Ruleset if tcode is a Business sensitive Access (BSA) with relevant Risk id &amp;amp; objects and its values mapped and check for SOD conflict with existing tcodes in the role.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Please follow the sequence of ABAP/Functional changes to be moved first and followed by Security i.e SU24 and Role changes into Production system.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Take Aways&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
- Auth team involvement from early stage of requirement gathering.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
- Avoid custom development if standard functionality is not available/possible.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
- Suitable Naming Conventions, Authority-check enablement in Custom program by ABAP team.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
- Update into SU24 with relevant objects/values and GRC Ruleset if tcode is BSA.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
- Follow Sequencing of ABAP/Functional changes followed by Auth changes into Production system.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/custom-tcode-management/ba-p/13580494"/>
    <published>2023-09-22T00:31:35+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/relation-between-sap-s-4hana-system-upgrade-migration-conversion-and-sap/ba-p/13579632</id>
    <title>Relation between SAP S/4HANA System Upgrade | Migration | Conversion and SAP Security Upgrade</title>
    <updated>2023-12-20T00:13:38+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karthikj2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148163</uri>
    </author>
    <content>In the ever-evolving world of SAP, it is indispensable to update Security and Authorizations as per Standard and Latest Controls. &lt;STRONG&gt;Upgrade | Migration | Conversion&lt;/STRONG&gt; collectively known SAP Landscape Maintenance are the Core Project Transitions in SAP.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
It is significant for a Security Consultant to understand | distinguish the above.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In this blog, I will present a crisp knowledge on Upgrade | Migration | Conversion and discuss how does it impact SAP Authorizations and when &lt;STRONG&gt;Security Upgrade&lt;/STRONG&gt; should be performed.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;What is SAP SECURITY UPGRADE?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
SAP introduces New | Updated authorizations (Transaction Code | Authorization Object | Authorization Field | Authorization Check Indicator) to SAP Tables – USOBT | USOBX during Core Component Upgrade.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;SU25 – Security Upgrade Tool&lt;/STRONG&gt; will be used to update the authorizations to Customer Tables – USOBT_C | USOBX_C. Impact of Security Upgrade will be reflecting in roles post execution of Upgrade Steps – 2A, 2B, 2D and 2C.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Note :&lt;/STRONG&gt; As of Dec 2023, customer can Upgrade | Convert to SAP S/4HANA 2020 &amp;amp; above versions (Reference SAP Note: 3338941)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;CONVERSION :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Customer who is in SAP ERP Central Component &lt;STRONG&gt;(ECC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; getting CONVERTED to Latest SAP S/4HANA version&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/SAP-Conversion.png" height="253" width="517" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;SAP Conversion&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UPGRADE :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Customer who is already in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; getting UPGRADED to Latest SAP S/4HANA version&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/SAP-Upgrade-1.png" height="282" width="589" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;SAP Upgrade&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Database Migration :&lt;/STRONG&gt; This can be categorized into three approaches, and it accords &lt;SPAN style="text-decoration: underline"&gt;only&lt;/SPAN&gt; to Database.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lift &amp;amp; Shift :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Homogeneous Migration of SAP Database without changing the Database type in source and target host.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Export &amp;amp; Import :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Migrating Database from one host to another host where source and target host &lt;STRONG&gt;may or may not have&lt;/STRONG&gt; same Database type.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Database Migration Option :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Popularly known as DMO, is an option in Software Update Manager (SUM) to move the data from Non-HANA Database to HANA Database. SUM meanwhile offers Homogeneous DMO for SAP HANA to SAP HANA Migration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2023/12/SAP-Migration.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align: center;font-style: italic"&gt;SAP Migration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;SUMMARY :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;It is fundamental to perform Security Upgrade for &lt;STRONG&gt;Conversion&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Upgrade&lt;/STRONG&gt; scenarios as there is change | upgrade in SAP ABAP Component Version.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;When &lt;STRONG&gt;Software Provisioning Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt; (SWPM) is used for Homogeneous and Heterogenous Database Migration - &lt;STRONG&gt;Security Upgrade is not required&lt;/STRONG&gt; as there is no change in SAP ABAP Component Version.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;When &lt;STRONG&gt;Software Update Manager&lt;/STRONG&gt; (SUM) is used for Database Migration &lt;SPAN style="text-decoration: underline"&gt;combined&lt;/SPAN&gt; with Upgrade or Conversion - &lt;STRONG&gt;Security Upgrade is required&lt;/STRONG&gt; as there will be change in SAP ABAP Component Version.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/relation-between-sap-s-4hana-system-upgrade-migration-conversion-and-sap/ba-p/13579632"/>
    <published>2023-12-20T00:13:38+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-user-access-reviews-best-practices/ba-p/13575463</id>
    <title>SAP User Access Reviews: Best practices</title>
    <updated>2024-01-13T11:28:39+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GRCwithRaghu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/600573</uri>
    </author>
    <content>Let’s understand with a use case:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
A global enterprise that uses SAP for its operations employed an executive who sensitive customer and financial information as part of his job. He was later promoted to a different position and was given new authorizations to carry out new tasks as part of his job duties. Unfortunately, while the new access was granted, no one looked at what he has or revoked the previous authorizations that are no longer relevant. As a result, this individual continued to retain both sets of authorizations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
He started utilizing these authorizations by creating numerous fake vendor accounts and subsequently approved payments to these non-existent vendors. Surprisingly, these actions went unnoticed within the company until an internal audit unearthed this irregularity.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Although this scenario may seem uncommon, many enterprises encounter similar situations. So, how to have a control on these kind of scenarios? Does SAP provide any tools/solutions to implement better controls?&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Many compliance frameworks mandate period authorization reviews. Performing regular User Access Reviews holds importance in maintaining a secure and efficient system within an organization. Here are some of the advantages of conducting periodic User Access Reviews:&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2024/01/Picture-1-3.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align:center;font-style:italic;, Arial, sans-serif"&gt;Advantages of conducting User Access Reviews&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
Additionally, in recent years, many regulations such as SOX/JSOX, ISMS and GDPR has mandated enterprises to perform User Access Reviews. However, executing these controls can be exceedingly time-consuming, potentially impeding core business activities.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
This article puts a spotlight on User Access Reviews, offering insights into optimizing and streamlining this pivotal process for your organization's benefit.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Why are SAP User Access Reviews crucial?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Principally, User Access Reviews are primarily conducted for audit purposes. Mandates such as Sarbanes Oxley (SOX) and JSOX necessitate periodic User Access Reviews, commonly performed annually or semi-annually by listed organizations.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
The crux of User Access Reviews lies in validating the relevance of SAP access that is provided to a user over a period of time at a later stage. For instance, if the user has requested access to ME21N (Create Purchase Orders) transaction code and it was approved few years back, does that access remain pertinent today, considering potential job function changes or role adjustments?&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Consequently, User Access Reviews afford organizations the chance to reassess a user's access, ensuring its continued relevance amidst potential shifts in roles or job functions. An added benefit is correcting and ensuring that SAP authorizations are well managed.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
Nonetheless, for many organizations, conducting a User Access Review solely to fulfil audit requirements, especially given the significant effort required from business users. However, there's a pressing need to shift the mindset surrounding User Access Reviews from a mere audit checkbox to an effective tool for managing access risks.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;How can this mindset change be fostered?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
To encourage a shift in thinking within organizations, it's crucial to emphasize the consequences of not performing the reviews. If the access control process is perceived as complex, the initial step is to simplify it and set up the right process of managing accesses and regular review procedures. This not only limits the authorizations, but also helps in identifying the users with unnecessary authorizations and further contributes insights for restructuring and streamlining the authorization processes. For instance, you can pinpoint users with access to critical permissions and remove those permissions when they are no longer necessary for their job duties.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2024/01/Picture-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align:center;font-style:italic;, Arial, sans-serif"&gt;Diagram that show the Mindset Shift in enterprises wrt Authorization Reviews&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
After simplifying the access control process and setting up regular reviews, the next step is to implement an automated system. Various solutions such as &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/4374b09eddfe468cb80b77b4ad83e80b/12.0.03/en-US/AC12_UAR_Reference_Guide%20SP00.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP GRC Access Control User Access Review&lt;/A&gt; (UAR), or &lt;A href="https://togglenow.com/solutions/review-now/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;ReviewNow&lt;/A&gt; streamline User Access Reviews by providing comprehensive information, aiding users in making informed decisions. Such tools can be configured to expedite the process and present technical SAP role language in user-friendly terms.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;How to achieve better output?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P style="overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 0px"&gt;&lt;IMG class="migrated-image" src="https://community.sap.com/legacyfs/online/storage/blog_attachments/2024/01/How-to-achieve-better-output-with-UAR.png" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P class="image_caption" style="text-align:center;font-style:italic;, Arial, sans-serif"&gt;How to achieve better output with User Access Reviews&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role Design&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Many organizations adapt to role design approaches that are complex to understand and manage. For example: Enabler roles. It is highly recommend to simplify the SAP role design to aid users in comprehending user access easily. A descriptive role design facilitates informed decisions by users during the review process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Role Methodology&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Opt for a role methodology that reduces the number of role assignments, making the User Access Review less arduous for business users. Consider methodologies like task based and value based roles to streamline access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rule-set Customization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Customized rule-sets empower business users to better understand the potential access risks, aiding informed decisions during the review.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Split Reviews&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Consider segregating reviews into User Access Reviews, Critical Authorization Reviews, Reviews for key business users and so on. This enhances the focus and efficiency of each review.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
 	&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Iterative Reviews&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Divide large annual reviews into smaller, more manageable reviews across geographical regions, risk levels, user groups, or SAP modules. This minimizes certification fatigue among reviewers and enhances efficiency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
By implementing these strategies and emphasizing the value of User Access Reviews beyond mere audit compliance, organizations can effectively manage access risks while ensuring the process remains user-friendly and impactful.&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;BR /&gt;
In conclusion, SAP User Access Reviews are critical to safeguard the organization from potential inside and outside attacks and adhere to compliance with regulations like SOX and JSOX. While these reviews offer benefits, a mindset shift is needed to view them not just as audit checkboxes but as tools for effective access risk management. The article suggests simplifying access processes, establishing systematic reviews, and emphasizing the consequences of neglect. Automation tools like SAP GRC Access Control User Access Review or ReviewNow can streamline and simplify the process. Practical strategies include role design simplification, efficient methodologies, rule-set customization, and iterative reviews. Implementing these recommendations ensures a user-friendly and impactful User Access Review process that aligns with business goals.</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/sap-user-access-reviews-best-practices/ba-p/13575463"/>
    <published>2024-01-13T11:28:39+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/basis-monitoring-amp-tcodes-with-key-notes/ba-p/13591678</id>
    <title>Basis Monitoring &amp; Tcodes with Key notes</title>
    <updated>2024-02-05T14:25:53.980000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Williams43</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/779356</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am thrilled to have the opportunity to connect with all of you through this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The purpose of this blog is to aid newcomers in Basis in gaining knowledge about Basis-related Tcodes, including key notes and their usage and frequency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I believe this will be beneficial for those who are beginning their careers in SAP Basis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I wish you good luck and welcome to SAP Basis Team&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Daily Monitoring Basis-related Tcodes, their uses, and their related Tcodes are utilised for any future investigation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Williams43_0-1706804899073.png" style="width: 744px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/58793i4CB3310AB78C7F03/image-dimensions/744x591?v=v2" width="744" height="591" role="button" title="Williams43_0-1706804899073.png" alt="Williams43_0-1706804899073.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tcodes that pertain to operating systems and databases, their usage, and any future process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Williams43_1-1706804947991.png" style="width: 742px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/58794i7E5F56EA3241CB97/image-dimensions/742x365?v=v2" width="742" height="365" role="button" title="Williams43_1-1706804947991.png" alt="Williams43_1-1706804947991.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Basis Admin is accountable for tuning performance. These Tcodes are associated with performance analysis at the application level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Williams43_2-1706805022361.png" style="width: 746px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/58795i8A61F0C50689AC15/image-dimensions/746x389?v=v2" width="746" height="389" role="button" title="Williams43_2-1706805022361.png" alt="Williams43_2-1706805022361.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ticketing tools vary widely between organizations, including SAP ITSM (SOLMAN), Non SAP (ServiceNow, Zendesk), and others.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;User Management, Role Management, and Transport Management will receive the majority of daily ticketing. Here are the Tcodes that pertain to these areas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Williams43_3-1706805139574.png" style="width: 744px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/58796i2E0110DFFF1343D9/image-dimensions/744x331?v=v2" width="744" height="331" role="button" title="Williams43_3-1706805139574.png" alt="Williams43_3-1706805139574.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tcodes that pertain to SAP Software Maintenance and related OS and other tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Williams43_4-1706805213692.png" style="width: 744px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/58797i9884C518C59B06AB/image-dimensions/744x536?v=v2" width="744" height="536" role="button" title="Williams43_4-1706805213692.png" alt="Williams43_4-1706805213692.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Programs that are useful for administrative tasks related to Basis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Williams43_5-1706805251462.png" style="width: 742px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/58798i23076894A6D415DC/image-dimensions/742x407?v=v2" width="742" height="407" role="button" title="Williams43_5-1706805251462.png" alt="Williams43_5-1706805251462.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for taking the time to read the blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAPBasis #Basis &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Basis+Technology/pd-p/7bf2eaed-4604-44ae-bad7-d2d2d5c58c54" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1129-1"&gt;Basis Technology&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/EWM+-+Basis/pd-p/192798129450263425409096799593312" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="941-1"&gt;EWM - Basis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/NW+ABAP+Monitoring+Tools/pd-p/a414317d-3ddc-487c-9d84-af75d27c65f6" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1010-1"&gt;NW ABAP Monitoring Tools&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+EarlyWatch+Alert/pd-p/f811a31e-b1e7-42ac-9f17-9051d8410d93" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1192-1"&gt;SAP EarlyWatch Alert&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+HANA+Cloud%25252C+SAP+HANA+database/pd-p/ada66f4e-5d7f-4e6d-a599-6b9a78023d84" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="40-1"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Advantage+Database+Server/pd-p/67838200100800005437" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="393-1"&gt;SAP Advantage Database Server&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Oracle+Database/pd-p/266216885309448000234589693334884" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="258-1"&gt;Oracle Database&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/73554900100800000266" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="799-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+NetWeaver+Application+Server+for+SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/73554900100800000376" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="736-1"&gt;SAP NetWeaver Application Server for SAP S/4HANA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; #Dailymonitoring &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/NW+Java+Security+and+User+Management/pd-p/837756977247372160663651537216525" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1021-1"&gt;NW Java Security and User Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Defense+and+Security/pd-p/159367983329805292011158" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="275-1"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SOLMAN+Setup%25252FConfiguration%25252FLMDB/pd-p/773921536755532122004239005965168" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1098-1"&gt;SOLMAN Setup/Configuration/LMDB&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/NW+ABAP+Monitoring+Tools/pd-p/a414317d-3ddc-487c-9d84-af75d27c65f6" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1010-2"&gt;NW ABAP Monitoring Tools&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SOLMAN+System+Monitoring/pd-p/212358834767912649313917434384826" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1099-1"&gt;SOLMAN System Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/basis-monitoring-amp-tcodes-with-key-notes/ba-p/13591678"/>
    <published>2024-02-05T14:25:53.980000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/user-types-in-sap-abap-stack-systems/ba-p/13622465</id>
    <title>User types in SAP ABAP Stack Systems</title>
    <updated>2024-02-28T14:30:09.735000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>gsaiprasad1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/11356</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog will outline the various user types found in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ABAP Stack Systems&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;User Types&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;In SAP systems, Users play a pivotal role in accessing and utilizing the various functionalities provided by the system.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;In the Transaction SU01- user management system, we primarily categorize users into five distinct types: &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;1.Dialog&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;2.System&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;3.Communication&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;4.Reference&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;5. Service&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="ravishankarp_0-1709124721205.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/72681iA14F2D39E6A79B14/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ravishankarp_0-1709124721205.png" alt="ravishankarp_0-1709124721205.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dialog Users (A)&lt;/STRONG&gt;: These are regular users who interact with the SAP system through the graphical user interface (GUI) or web interface ( SAP GUI for HTML). They perform tasks such as entering data, running reports, and executing transactions relevant to their roles assigned to them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multiple logon is checked.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System Users(B)&lt;/STRONG&gt;: System users are typically used for background tasks, such as running batch jobs, executing automated processes, or performing system-to-system communication. They do not require direct interaction with the GUI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;Multiple logon is allowed, Only an administrator user can change the password.&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Communication Users (C )&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; : Communication users are primarily used to establish connections and facilitate communication between SAP systems or between SAP systems and external applications, services, platforms and integration scenarios such as RFC (Remote Function Call), SOAP (Simple Object Access Protocol), HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol), IDoc (Intermediate Document), ALE (Application Link Enabling), EDI (Electronic Data Interchange), and more .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Logon with SAPGUI is not possible&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reference Users (L) &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;:Reference users are special types of user accounts that serve as templates or blueprints for creating new user accounts with predefined settings, roles, authorizations, and other attributes. They are used to streamline the process of user creation and ensure consistency across user profiles within the SAP system&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;No logon possible.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Users (S) : &lt;/STRONG&gt;Service users are considered technical users because they are primarily used for technical tasks rather than human interaction. They are often assigned specific technical roles and authorizations required for performing their designated tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;unlike regular dialog users who interact with the SAP system through the graphical user interface (GUI), service users typically do not require direct interaction with the GUI. They may communicate with the system through interfaces, APIs (Application Programming Interfaces), or background processes.however SAP GUI logon is Possible&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multiple Log on allowed.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="6"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Master Record&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;User Master Record in SAP is a fundamental component that stores and manages information about individual users who access the SAP system&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Creation of user accounts in SAP systems is client-dependent, meaning that&lt;STRONG&gt; user master records&lt;/STRONG&gt; must be established separately in &lt;STRONG&gt;each client &lt;/STRONG&gt;where users need access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ravishankarp_1-1709125740747.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/72703i5D31B5A19A1F8820/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ravishankarp_1-1709125740747.png" alt="ravishankarp_1-1709125740747.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;User Master Record in SAP contains a variety of information pertaining to individual users who access the SAP system. This information is crucial for managing user access, permissions, and preferences within the SAP environment. These are the&amp;nbsp; key components typically found in a user master record:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;User Details Like Name, Department, function, responsibilities, user group, user type and License&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;User Details with Validity ,Lock Status, and authentication properties&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;User Settings Like parameters, spool requests, time zone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note : User details, such as user IDs, hashed passwords, authorizations, and related information, are stored in the USR02 table&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="5"&gt;User Deletion&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ravishankarp_2-1709126014622.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/72708i0B3CC7FE54287CAB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ravishankarp_2-1709126014622.png" alt="ravishankarp_2-1709126014622.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;User deletion is always possible and can be done using the transactions SU01 or SU10. During the deletion, all of the personal data belonging to the user master is deleted&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deletion Effects:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Deleting a user account in SAP has several effect such as&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;The user's access to the SAP system is immediately revoked.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Any active sessions associated with the deleted user account are terminated&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;Authorization objects and roles assigned to the user are removed.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;User-related data stored in tables such as USR02 (User Master Record) is deleted.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT face="tahoma,arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;After deleting a user account, administrators may need to perform additional tasks, such as reassigning responsibilities to other users, updating documentation, or communicating the deletion to relevant stakeholders&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;#basis #abapstack #netweaver #ECC &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA/pd-p/73554900100800000266" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="799-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/user-types-in-sap-abap-stack-systems/ba-p/13622465"/>
    <published>2024-02-28T14:30:09.735000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-extracting-user-email-addresses-from-standard-tables/ba-p/13697756</id>
    <title>SAP S/4HANA - Extracting User Email Addresses from Standard Tables</title>
    <updated>2024-05-10T15:09:30.362000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karthikj2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148163</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What are we discussing here?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When working with SAP systems, it is fundamental to need / verify user &lt;FONT size="4"&gt;email&lt;/FONT&gt; addresses for various purposes. Whether it is to send Automated Notifications, facilitating communication between users, or Generating Reports, having accurate and up-to-date email addresses is crucial. However, extracting the email address from SAP system is not as easy as we think. In this blog post, we will explore the simplest method to extract / find email addresses of users from SAP Standard tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note : There is no direct transaction code or program to extract email addresses of users&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How are we going to achieve it?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The primary table that stores user information in SAP is &lt;STRONG&gt;USR21&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This table contains User Master Data, including Personal Numbers (&lt;STRONG&gt;PERSNUMBER&lt;/STRONG&gt;) associated with each user. To retrieve email addresses, we will link this table with the address data table &lt;STRONG&gt;ADR6&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is USR21?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;USR21 is a standard table in SAP ERP system that assigns User Names and Address Keys.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is ADR6?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The ADR6 table in SAP ERP system is a standard table that stores email addresses (Business Address Services) for any address record.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Procedure to Extract Email Address from SAP Tables&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Execute table view transaction code: &lt;STRONG&gt;SE16&lt;/STRONG&gt; -&amp;gt; Enter Table Name : &lt;STRONG&gt;USR21&lt;/STRONG&gt; -&amp;gt; Execute&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide the list of User ID(s) through Multiple Selection for &lt;STRONG&gt;BNAME &lt;/STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; Execute&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="karthikj2_5-1715344388432.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/108676iCEC89D0CE48CCB7B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="karthikj2_5-1715344388432.png" alt="karthikj2_5-1715344388432.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Copy the list of Personnel Number &lt;STRONG&gt;(PERSNUMBER)&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the users&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="karthikj2_6-1715344388441.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/108674iCC1979566995EEFE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="karthikj2_6-1715344388441.png" alt="karthikj2_6-1715344388441.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Execute table view transaction code: &lt;STRONG&gt;SE16&lt;/STRONG&gt; -&amp;gt; Enter Table Name: &lt;STRONG&gt;ADR6&lt;/STRONG&gt; -&amp;gt; Execute&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide the list of Personnel Number(s) through Multiple Selection for &lt;STRONG&gt;PERSNUMBER &lt;/STRONG&gt;-&amp;gt; Execute&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="karthikj2_7-1715344388447.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/108675i7E1876E52EBE5A3D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="karthikj2_7-1715344388447.png" alt="karthikj2_7-1715344388447.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SMTP_ADDR&lt;/STRONG&gt; column of ADR6 table will provide the list of email address for users&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="karthikj2_8-1715344388454.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/108680i9911656A2E120BA1/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="karthikj2_8-1715344388454.png" alt="karthikj2_8-1715344388454.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP also offers to extract the list into Spreadsheet from this screen&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tip :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ensure to select ALV Grid Display in User Specific Settings at initial screen of ADR6&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="karthikj2_9-1715344388461.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/108681iA9B307175988C370/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="karthikj2_9-1715344388461.png" alt="karthikj2_9-1715344388461.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What are other options?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another approach for SAP S/4HANA is to leverage the built-in Core Data Services&lt;STRONG&gt; (CDS)&lt;/STRONG&gt; view.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Table :&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;PUSER002&lt;/STRONG&gt; can also be used | BNAME = UserName | Ensure column &lt;STRONG&gt;SMTP_ADDR&lt;/STRONG&gt; is visible&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Word of Caution&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Avoid Unintended Disclosure&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When querying SAP tables, be cautious not to inadvertently disclose email addresses to unauthorized users or external sources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Limit access to relevant personnel and follow proper authorization procedures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remember, accurate and secure email addresses contribute to smooth business processes and effective communication within your organization. Handle them responsibly, and always prioritize data protection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any further questions or need assistance, do not hesitate to comment on this blog. Happy SAP querying!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Feel free to share this article with your colleagues and peers who work with SAP systems.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-extracting-user-email-addresses-from-standard-tables/ba-p/13697756"/>
    <published>2024-05-10T15:09:30.362000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/unlocking-the-power-of-rsusr-lock-users-report-in-sap/ba-p/13706854</id>
    <title>Unlocking the Power of RSUSR_LOCK_USERS Report in SAP</title>
    <updated>2024-05-20T16:11:52.741000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GRCwithRaghu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/600573</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Are you finding it challenging to use EWZ5 for locking and unlocking users during upgrade activities? Have you discovered that this transaction code is now obsolete and are you relying on a custom program? If so, consider using the ABAP program &lt;STRONG&gt;RSUSR_LOCK_USERS&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This program simplifies the user locking and unlocking process, making it an invaluable tool for managing user accounts efficiently during system upgrades.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understanding RSUSR_LOCK_USERS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;RSUSR_LOCK_USERS is a simple yet effective program that is built on top of RSUSR200 program. Here is the list of options available in the program screen:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRCwithRaghu_0-1716213232320.png" style="width: 536px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/112958i2D7D8D6A7127A033/image-dimensions/536x720?v=v2" width="536" height="720" role="button" title="GRCwithRaghu_0-1716213232320.png" alt="GRCwithRaghu_0-1716213232320.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As highlighted in the picture, the RSUSR_LOCK_USERS report offers the following sections:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="640px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="135.836px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Section&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="460.164px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What it offers?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="135.836px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;User Selection&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="460.164px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section offers the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Selection of specific users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Group for Authorization&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Uses SU01 user group assignments and picks the users based on the group assignment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security Policies&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Uses the Security Policy assigned to the user in SU01.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Days Since Last Logon&lt;/STRONG&gt; – To specify the no.of days since last login (for eg: If you wish to lock the users who haven’t logged-in to the system in the last 90 days, enter the value as 90).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Days Since Password Change&lt;/STRONG&gt; – To select users based on last password change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="135.836px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selection by Validity of users&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="460.164px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selection by Validity of users can be filtered by today's validity or by a specific period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Today (current date)&lt;/STRONG&gt; – This option will specifically check for valid and invalid users of current date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users Valid Today – Consider the valid users of current date&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users Invalid Today – Consider the Invalid users of current date&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Validity Period &lt;/STRONG&gt;– This option will specifically check for valid and invalid users over a specified period of time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users Valid &amp;lt;From&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;To&amp;gt; - Consider the valid users within the time period specified in the input.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users Not valid &amp;lt;From&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;To&amp;gt; - Consider the Invalid users within the time period specified in the input.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="135.836px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selection by Locks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="460.164px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This option facilitates filtering users based on their lock status. Below are the lock criteria that can be considered. Selecting one of these options is mandatory (Radio button selection).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Differentiation of Locks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All users with Administrator or Password Locks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Only Users without Locks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Differentiation of Locks &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User Locks (Administrator)&lt;/STRONG&gt; – When the value "Set" is selected, it will include the list of users who have been locked by the administrator, with lock statuses of 32 and 64.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRCwithRaghu_1-1716213376801.png" style="width: 465px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/112959i931A644633DAACFC/image-dimensions/465x114?v=v2" width="465" height="114" role="button" title="GRCwithRaghu_1-1716213376801.png" alt="GRCwithRaghu_1-1716213376801.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When the value " Not Set" is selected, it will exclude the list of users who have been locked by the administrator, with lock statuses of 32 and 64&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRCwithRaghu_2-1716213376803.png" style="width: 479px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/112960i2DDBAF33812CA456/image-dimensions/479x109?v=v2" width="479" height="109" role="button" title="GRCwithRaghu_2-1716213376803.png" alt="GRCwithRaghu_2-1716213376803.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Password Lock (Incorrect Logon)&lt;/STRONG&gt; – When the value "Set" is selected, it will include the list of users who have been locked due to incorrect logons with the status of 128 while when the value “Not Set” is selected, it will exclude the list of users who have been locked due to incorrect logons with the status of 128&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;All users with Administrator or Password Locks – &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;It will include all users who meet the condition of being locked by the administrator (with lock status 32 &amp;amp; 64) or having password locks (with lock status 128).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Only Users without Locks - &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;It includes users without any lock status (Active users)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="135.836px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selection by Login attempts&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="460.164px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section sorts users based on their login attempts to the SAP system. By default, all options are selected, and you can deselect a box to exclude. Alternatively, all boxes can be unchecked if you do not wish to use this option.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRCwithRaghu_3-1716213376804.png" style="width: 457px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/112961iF937FC96A2C4E234/image-dimensions/457x169?v=v2" width="457" height="169" role="button" title="GRCwithRaghu_3-1716213376804.png" alt="GRCwithRaghu_3-1716213376804.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users with incorrect Logon Attempts – Considers users who have made incorrect logon attempts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users with no Incorrect Logon Attempts – Considers users who have not made any incorrect logon attempts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;User Without Logon Date – Considers the users without any logon date in SU01&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="135.836px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selection by User Type&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="460.164px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selection by User Type filters users based on the user type defined in SU01. For example, you can lock only dialog users based on conditions specified within this program, such as users who have not logged into the system for a specific period of time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below are the user types available under this criteria:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dialog Users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Communication Users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;System Users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Service Users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reference Users&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;NOTE: By default, all options are selected, and you can deselect a box to exclude. Alternatively, all boxes can be unchecked if you do not wish to use this option.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="135.836px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Selection by status of password&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="460.164px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section will be considered the users based on the status of the user password.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;·Users with Production Password – Productive user&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users with Initial Password – Users who have never logged into the SAP system after the initial password was set by the admin.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users with Deactivated Password – Users who password is deactivated &amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;As selection type “Selection by Login attempts and Selection by User Type”, by default, all options are selected here as well, and you can deselect a box to exclude.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="135.836px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Activity selection&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="460.164px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once all the selection criteria are defined according to your requirements, you can proceed to the Activity selection option to specify your actions. Based on the conditions specified above, the result will now be executable. Below are the actions that can be taken when you execute the program.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Selection&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Test Selection presents the list of users on the output screen according to the criteria defined before any of the activities listed below are executed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lock Users (Local Lock&lt;/STRONG&gt;) – To Lock the user locally&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unlock Users (Local Lock)&lt;/STRONG&gt; – To unlock the user locally&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Set the End of the Validity Period to Today (Only for Valid Users)&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Validity of the user will be ended with today’s date&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Set the End of the Validity Period to Yesterday (Only for Valid Users)&lt;/STRONG&gt; – validity of the user will be ended with the yesterday’s date&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;As mentioned, RSUSR_LOCK_USERS aids in compliance and audit processes by providing a clear record of user account status and actions taken. This ensures that the organization can demonstrate adherence to security policies and regulations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Use RSUSR_LOCK_USERS?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Execute transaction code SA38 or SE38.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter “RSUSR_LOCK_USERS” in the program field and execute the report.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Complete the required selections such as specific users, lock/unlock conditions, and date ranges etc.,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Run the program to generate a list of users.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Consider the following condition for ending the validity of users as a reference. I have selected dialog users regardless of their password status—whether it's production, initial, or deactivated—and those who are already locked by the admin or due to password lock. Additionally, I have chosen users without logon data under "Selection by Logon Attempts." Once users meeting the defined criteria are identified, their ID validity should be set to end with yesterday’s date. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRCwithRaghu_4-1716213879816.png" style="width: 542px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/112964i1438C9BBEE2D5BF1/image-dimensions/542x584?v=v2" width="542" height="584" role="button" title="GRCwithRaghu_4-1716213879816.png" alt="GRCwithRaghu_4-1716213879816.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After executing the program, the output will display the User IDs for which changes were made.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRCwithRaghu_5-1716213907899.png" style="width: 666px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/112965iF0CE2F8C0F77C217/image-dimensions/666x223?v=v2" width="666" height="223" role="button" title="GRCwithRaghu_5-1716213907899.png" alt="GRCwithRaghu_5-1716213907899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Result:&lt;/STRONG&gt; According to the given criteria, user validity is ended with yesterday's date. The program was executed on 20.05.2024, so the user validity is set to end on 19.05.2024.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRCwithRaghu_6-1716213932140.png" style="width: 668px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/112967i82A71E94E2C6D398/image-dimensions/668x288?v=v2" width="668" height="288" role="button" title="GRCwithRaghu_6-1716213932140.png" alt="GRCwithRaghu_6-1716213932140.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, the program can be scheduled to run at regular intervals, ensuring that administrators are always aware of any locked user accounts. Automation can help in maintaining continuous oversight without manual intervention.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Steps to schedule the job in the background:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To automate the locking, unlocking, and validity ending of users without manual intervention, you can schedule this job to run in the background. This enables the program to execute automatically at specified intervals, ensuring users are locked or unlocked according to predefined criteria. It's recommended to thoroughly test the program in a non-production environment before scheduling it in a production system to ensure proper functionality and minimize potential disruptions. Follow the below steps to schedule the job in the background:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Execute transaction SE38 and input the program RSUSR_LOCK_USERS, then proceed to execute it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Define the criteria for locking/unlocking or ending the validity of the user. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click "Program" to schedule the job in the background or press F9&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRCwithRaghu_7-1716214002429.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/112968i51C44D2AA328D622/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="GRCwithRaghu_7-1716214002429.png" alt="GRCwithRaghu_7-1716214002429.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Specify the frequency at which the job should run and click Save.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you have multiple criteria to schedule in the background, specify your criteria and press Ctrl+S to save as a variant as shown below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GRCwithRaghu_8-1716214093015.png" style="width: 667px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/112969iEF8ECE5D181C07D6/image-dimensions/667x214?v=v2" width="667" height="214" role="button" title="GRCwithRaghu_8-1716214093015.png" alt="GRCwithRaghu_8-1716214093015.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After saving the variants, the job can now be scheduled in the background via transaction code SM36.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The RSUSR_LOCK_USERS program is an indispensable tool for SAP administrators, providing critical insights and control over user account management. By effectively utilizing this program, organizations can enhance their security posture, ensure compliance with regulations, and maintain smooth operational workflows. Regular use and prompt action on the findings of the RSUSR_LOCK_USERS report will help in minimizing user access issues and reinforcing overall system security.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-members/unlocking-the-power-of-rsusr-lock-users-report-in-sap/ba-p/13706854"/>
    <published>2024-05-20T16:11:52.741000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-authorization-audit-readiness-amp-critical-access-monitoring/ba-p/13741971</id>
    <title>Sap Authorization Audit Readiness &amp; Critical Access Monitoring!!!</title>
    <updated>2024-06-26T07:12:42.494000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shivkumar_B1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879151</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As an SAP Authorization consultant, year on year we go through Internal/External Audit trials and provide evidence/clarifications for the samples requested.&lt;BR /&gt;We need to justify if there a slippage in Process/Access assignments and leading to Audit Deficiencies failed to provide evidence.&lt;BR /&gt;Auditors will leave no chance to find a process gap like an eagle catching a fish which is just above the river &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To avoid Audit deficiencies, we need to have a detailed SOP (Standard Operating Process), religiously follow the process and document exceptions, if any.&lt;BR /&gt;The most important aspect is to monitor Critical authorization assignments on monthly(suggested) or quarterly to assess unwanted assignments and remediate even before noticed by Audit team.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have outlined most of the Critical Authorization monitoring controls as follows&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1018359265"&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Security Audit Parameters&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below table provides generic Audit Parameters to be configured in Production systems, which are most important with regards to Audit controls.&amp;nbsp; Below values specified are with respect to SAP best practices and may differ from individual organizations as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="299"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Password Parameters &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;login/min_password_lng&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;12&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;login/min_password_digits&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;login/min_password_lowercase&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;login/min_password_uppercase&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;login/min_password_specials&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;login/password_history_size&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;4&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Login and Session&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;login/failed_user_auto_unlock&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;login/fails_to_session_end&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;3&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;login/fails_to_user_lock&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;6&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;login/no_automatic_user_sapstar&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;rdisp/gui_auto_logout&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1800&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="216"&gt;&lt;P&gt;auth/object_disabling_active&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="83"&gt;&lt;P&gt;N&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-821845760"&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; SAP Standard User Password and Active Status&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sap Standard users such as SAP*, DDIC, TMSADM, SAPCPIC etc should have their initial password changed and keep locked these users in clients such as 000,001,066 &amp;amp; Prod client and in some cases TMSADM and DDIC will be kept unlocked in master clients.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To validate Execute Tcode &lt;STRONG&gt;RSUSR003&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-625332255"&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Critical Standard Profiles (SAP_ALL and SAP_NEW)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP standard critical authorization profiles SAP_ALL or SAP_NEW must not be assigned&lt;BR /&gt;to any users in any of the clients.&lt;BR /&gt;To check Go to SUIM--&amp;gt;Users by Complex Selection Criteria--&amp;gt;Roles/Profiles--&amp;gt;Profile Name SAP_ALL and SAP_NEW.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-428818750"&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Standard SAP Roles Assignment&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any users in Production client must not be assigned with SAP standard roles i.e Roles starting with SAP* or /*. To check go to SUIM--&amp;gt;Users by Complex Selection Criteria--&amp;gt;Roles/Profile--&amp;gt; SAP* or /*.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_0-1719312223537.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128493iB03DD6A17EB8B2C1/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_0-1719312223537.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_0-1719312223537.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-361387964"&gt;5&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access to Create User Master&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Access to create User master in Production should be restricted to Authorization team, since they need to create Service/System users. Dialog user creation should be via GRC system.&lt;BR /&gt;To Check SUIM &amp;gt;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt;S_USER_GRP ACTVT = 01&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_1-1719310006480.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128452iC7CE2937AA91FB90/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_1-1719310006480.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_1-1719310006480.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-164874459"&gt;6&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access to Change User Master&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This access is restricted to Authorization team and any other user should not be assigned with.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt;S_USER_GRP ACTVT = 02 or 06&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_2-1719310049757.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128453i4367756EB14F62C5/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_2-1719310049757.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_2-1719310049757.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--31639046"&gt;7&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access to Unlock Users or Reset Password&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In ideal scenario, IT/Business user login to Production system via SSO (Single Sign On). There are exceptions for password login such as IT Admin Users (Security &amp;amp; Basis) and few Business users, who need to connect to third party tools (example RF Gun) via Production user credentials. All the exceptions should be documented in SOP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt; User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt; S_USER_GRP ACTVT = 05&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_3-1719310084246.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128454i7596A47E761174FE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_3-1719310084246.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_3-1719310084246.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--228152551"&gt;8&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access to Debug with Change&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Debug change access must be restricted from any Dialog users in Production and it should be part of an FF user only.&lt;BR /&gt;To check SUIM report &amp;gt; User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt; S_DEVELOP ACTVT = 02&lt;BR /&gt;and OBJTYPE = DEBUG&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_4-1719310180390.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128455iE284630D38D48AAE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_4-1719310180390.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_4-1719310180390.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--424666056"&gt;9&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access to Import Transports&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Only Basis/Release team should have access to import access in Production system.&lt;BR /&gt;SUIM&amp;gt;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt;S_CTS_ADM &amp;gt; Value= IMPA or IMPS&lt;BR /&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt; User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt; S_TRANSPRT ACTVT = 60&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_5-1719310225520.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128456i46C747EA6D9DE6F2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_5-1719310225520.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_5-1719310225520.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_6-1719310232023.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128457iC3F4D8EB16500113/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_6-1719310232023.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_6-1719310232023.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--621179561"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Execute Access for All Programs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;No Users in Production should be assigned with all Program execute access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SUIM &amp;gt;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt;S_PROGRAM P_ACTION = SUBMIT &amp;amp; P_GROUP = #*&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_7-1719310277177.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128459i79CFB0CA67A7C252/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_7-1719310277177.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_7-1719310277177.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--892924435"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;11. Authorization Objects Added Manually or Changed in Roles&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;All authorization objects in the roles should be in Standard or Maintained status. Any exceptions should be documented. As per SAP best practice no objects should be added manually and there will be adverse effect during upgrades, since tcodes will fail which are dependent on manually added objects, but not linked via SU24.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_1-1719312362019.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128494i4834043C752A6254/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_1-1719312362019.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_1-1719312362019.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;12.&amp;nbsp;Custom Tcodes Without Authorization Object Linkage in SU24&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Custom Tcode must be associated with authorizations objects maintained in SU24.&lt;BR /&gt;To check, extract all custom tcodes from SE16--&amp;gt;TSTC--&amp;gt;Z*&lt;BR /&gt;Next copy tcodes from TSTC into table USOBT_C to check tcodes with SU24 object mappings and if tcodes not available in the report, then such custom tcodes must be added with suitable auth object into SU24.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_9-1719310410508.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128462iBBDBE333180C94AE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_9-1719310410508.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_9-1719310410508.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_10-1719310416783.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128463iD73564DF26674DCA/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_10-1719310416783.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_10-1719310416783.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1089437940"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;13.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Administrator Access for All Batch Jobs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Batch admin access with Administrator i.e Y access should be restricted to Basis team.&lt;BR /&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt; User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt; S_BTCH_ADM BTCADMIN = Y&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_11-1719310470116.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128464i52B6793FC6DA548A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_11-1719310470116.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_11-1719310470116.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1285951445"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;14.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access to Delete Batch Jobs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt;S_BTCH_JOB JOBACTION = DELE&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_12-1719310502785.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128465iD81E44580045553B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_12-1719310502785.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_12-1719310502785.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1482464950"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;15.&amp;nbsp;Access to Delete Logs or Jobs in Batch Input Processing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt; User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt; S_BDC_MONI BDCAKTI = REOG or DELE&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_13-1719310524675.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128466i3468FABD56D4DF96/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_13-1719310524675.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_13-1719310524675.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1678978455"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;16.&amp;nbsp;Access to All Batch Input Processing Sessions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt; User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt; S_BDC_MONI BDCGROUPID = #*&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_14-1719310542021.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128468iA64392A477C5C0CB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_14-1719310542021.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_14-1719310542021.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1875491960"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;17. RFC Administration Access&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This acccess should be restricted to either basis team or Batch Monitroing teams.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt; S_TCODE = SM59 and&amp;nbsp;S_ADMI_FCD = NADM&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_15-1719310572661.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128469i134BFF6D7CE1B42E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_15-1719310572661.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_15-1719310572661.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--2072005465"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;18.&amp;nbsp;Execute Access for All RFCs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This access should not be assigned to any Dialog users in Production system. For Batch job users also assign only required RFC authorization based on trace results, rather assigning full access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt; User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt; S_RFC = #* (or S_RFC = "*")&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_16-1719310592744.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128470i6B4157DBF4FEAC51/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_16-1719310592744.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_16-1719310592744.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-2026448326"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;19. Change Access for All Tables&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt;S_TABU_DIS ACTVT = 02 and DICBERCLS = #*&lt;BR /&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt;S_TABU_NAM ACTVT = 02 and TABLE = #*&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_17-1719310618145.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128471iE654450247120FA8/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_17-1719310618145.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_17-1719310618145.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_18-1719310644625.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128472i2E20BA66E2AE1F94/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_18-1719310644625.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_18-1719310644625.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1829934821"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;20. Display Access for All Tables&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;You may be wondering why display access is critical, this is because a business user with display access on all tables can view Business critical information and leading to Business loss/audit deficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt;S_TABU_DIS ACTVT = 03 and&amp;nbsp;DICBERCLS = #*&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt; S_TABU_NAM ACTVT = 03 and&amp;nbsp;TABLE = #*&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_19-1719310675075.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128473i391A999D04DE14E2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_19-1719310675075.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_19-1719310675075.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_20-1719310682089.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128474i062238A3FEB70A4F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_20-1719310682089.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_20-1719310682089.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1633421316"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;21.&amp;nbsp;Access to Modify Client Settings&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SUIM report User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt;S_TABU_DIS ACTVT = 02 and&amp;nbsp;DICBERCLS = SS&lt;BR /&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt;User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt;S_TABU_NAM ACTVT = 02 and TABLE = T000&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: Auth Group SS contains Security relevant tables and hence should be assigned to IT team only.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_21-1719310709720.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128475i63DF4F8CFA3A0D97/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_21-1719310709720.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_21-1719310709720.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_22-1719310717706.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128476i24F14384D1259910/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_22-1719310717706.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_22-1719310717706.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1605091502"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;22. Access to Tables Not mapped to Authorization Groups&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tables i.e Both Standard and Custom, that are not mapped to specific authorization groups, will be automatically assigned to &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;amp;NC&amp;amp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; group. We need to make sure no users should have change access to group &amp;amp;NC&amp;amp; in Production.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_23-1719310743149.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128477iA45596C892572CE7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_23-1719310743149.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_23-1719310743149.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1408577997"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;23. Access to Maintain Cross-Clients Tables&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SUIM report &amp;gt; User by Complex Selection Criteria &amp;gt; S_TABU_CLI&amp;nbsp;CLIIDMAINT = X&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_24-1719310773700.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/128478iEAD18659B1E5F077/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_24-1719310773700.png" alt="shivakumarbalaiah_balaiah_24-1719310773700.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Frequent monitoring of above critical access assignments will help to be prepared for Audit at any day and IT HPA (High Privilege Access) review as well, to make sure only relevant IT users assigned with privileged access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shivkumar&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-authorization-audit-readiness-amp-critical-access-monitoring/ba-p/13741971"/>
    <published>2024-06-26T07:12:42.494000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-your-sap-s-4hana-landscape-with-a-best-practice-role-concept/ba-p/13809622</id>
    <title>Optimizing Your SAP S/4HANA Landscape with a Best Practice Role Concept</title>
    <updated>2024-08-29T23:50:00.035000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>markus_griem</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/458611</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-914446904"&gt;Optimizing your SAP S/4HANA Landscape with a Best Practice Role Concept&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Experts familiar with SAP authorizations are well aware that quality issues and complexity of legacy role concepts often prompt the desire to start from scratch with a brand-new concept. However, the thought of the associated effort and high costs discourages many. What if there were a more efficient solution?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Typically, the following topics are initiators for a revision of authorization concepts:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA implementations in cloud or hybrid environments&lt;/STRONG&gt; usually require – following the "keep the core clean" strategy – a new SAP S/4HANA authorization concept as well as an authorization concept for the SAP Business Technology Platform.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA greenfield implementations&lt;/STRONG&gt; for new SAP customers as well as existing SAP customers developing new processes based on SAP S/4HANA require a new authorization concept that fits to their new process design and covers access to SAP Fiori Launchpad&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA brownfield implementations&lt;/STRONG&gt; that cause a redesign or at least an update of the existing authorization concept.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Audit and compliance requirements&lt;/STRONG&gt; that may result in a revision or redesign of the SAP authorization concept.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, we introduce the benefits of the “Automated Implementation of Role Concept” Service ("AIRC Service"), which shortens the efforts and duration of the projects by applying pre-defined roles and a high level of automation. Based on a clear methodology, the service has proven to be a key for the success of authorization projects within more than 200 customer projects over the past 15 years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-717933399"&gt;How does the use case look like for the implementation of a new authorization concept?&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="markus_griem_0-1725272449439.png" style="width: 650px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/160868i22780585450E30DA/image-dimensions/650x844?v=v2" width="650" height="844" role="button" title="markus_griem_0-1725272449439.png" alt="markus_griem_0-1725272449439.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When developing a new authorization concept, the initial scope is important, i.e. which applications (i.e. Transactions as well as Fiori Apps) should be part of the authorization concept. This is a task in the responsibility of the business departments, but AIRC service supports it by offering the following approaches:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;"Top-Down Approach" via SAP Signavio Extraction or manual upload:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;With the AIRC service, data can be automatically extracted from SAP Signavio. SAP Signavio is the recommended solution for the (re-) design of Business Processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If other tools for modelling business processes are in place, the data can be exported and used by AIRC Service.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Top-Down Approach is the preferred method for greenfield implementations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Reverse Engineering:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;By examining the transactions used in the SAP system, which can be extracted and used as a baseline for defining the new role proposal, the AIRC ensures that only the necessary functions are authorized. For customers moving from SAP ECC to SAP S/4HANA or upgrading their SAP S/4HANA, the following analyses are also helpful:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA Impact Analysis: This analysis checks applications for availability in the target release and lists any corresponding successor applications (transactions or apps).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fiori App Recommendations: This analysis lists which native Fiori apps can complement a defined range of SAP transactions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Business Reverse Engineering” is the preferred method for brownfield implementations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-521419894"&gt;Best Practice Role Proposal&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Over the years, SAP Services have developed a database consisting of proven best practice roles that meet the following quality criteria:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Functional role concept&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consideration of typical segregation of duty (SoD) requirements&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Display and maintenance roles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Module-specific roles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) authorization concept&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;and many more&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This database is constantly being expanded based on new applications (e.g. new Fiori apps) and continuously optimized based on customer feedback.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using the methods described above, we can quickly provide the customer with a customized role proposal from the intersection of the scope and our role database (often already at the project kick-off). We also offer role assignments for customer-specific applications using algorithms (partly AI-based).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The role proposal provides a solid framework that significantly reduces efforts in the business departments, enhances quality, and stipulates a unified format.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-324906389"&gt;Role Implementation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AIRC service considerably supports the implementation of roles through automation, greatly reducing the efforts required for implementation. &amp;nbsp;The following steps outline the implementation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creation of roles with corresponding applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Based on the authorization concept revised by the business departments, PFCG roles and Fiori catalogs, including assignment of transactions and Fiori apps, are generated using the AIRC service tool-based approach.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Maintenance of non-organizational authorization fields&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The corresponding authorization values in the roles are manually maintained with the help of standard proposals (SU24) and feedback from the business departments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generation of organizational or non-organizational supplementary roles&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Special authorizations require supplementary roles, consisting of distinct authorization objects (examples include release codes, order types, document types, etc.). We generate these roles from Excel files using a tool-based approach.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generation of role derivations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: We recommend using the SAP standard derivation concept. For each organization, so-called "orgsets" can be defined, which contain the specifications for the organizational restrictions of that organization (company code, plant, purchasing organization, sales organization, etc.). Role derivations can then be generated using the AIRC service based on these “orgsets”. This step is not feasible to perform manually for larger companies or projects involving around 20, 100, or 200 organizations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generation of SAP SAP BTP (Business Technology Platform) roles and role collections&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In "side-by-side extensions", business data can also end up in the SAP BTP, which can lead to many SAP BTP roles / role collections. The AIRC service offers tools necessary for generating and transporting these roles, protecting you from unpleasant surprises such as significant manual efforts just before Go-Live.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-128392884"&gt;Testing roles&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;For re-design projects, the SAP standard offers a very useful, currently not very well-known feature:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the transaction "STSIMAUTHCHECK" it is possible to simulate which authorization checks would fail when using new roles instead of old ones. In our experience, for new implementations, the classic method of testing and ad hoc correcting roles individually is one of the most effective. The AIRC service can also be used in conjunction with partner products that support the tests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--68120621"&gt;Assignment of roles to users&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;If usage data is available, we support the assignment of roles to test users and end users with role assignment proposal, structured according to the following procedure:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Allocation of default authorization roles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If an application has been used by a user that occurs in different roles, the less critical role is initially suggested.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Organizational assignments can be made based on the user's organizational assignments or based on the organizational assignments of the old roles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the customer does not have their own Identity Access Management tools, we support the implementation of the assignment with corresponding tools (ABAP and SAP BTP).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--264634126"&gt;Go-Live&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the use of "STSIMAUTHCHECK," you can conduct a secured Go-Live, which is carried out using old authorizations and logging of theoretical authorization errors caused by the new roles. For a re-design, the transition usually occurs in two to four increasingly larger user packages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--461147631"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--657661136"&gt;Do I also get support if I decide to rely on my former role concept?&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;If there are no major changes in business processes and the authorization concept of the customer is already at a high-quality level, customers might decide not to reimplement the authorization concept with SAP S/4HANA. &amp;nbsp;For all the new topics (e.g. roles for SAP BTP) the above steps can still be applied. For the existing role concept, the differences between SAP ECC and SAP S/4HANA or between different SAP S/4HANA releases can be derived by an Impact Analysis. We will not further describe this topic in this blog post, please contact us if you want to get further details on this topic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--854174641"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--280948063"&gt;Wrapping It Up: Key Takeaways&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AIRC service addresses the required re-design of permissions within upcoming changes such as cloud transformations, SAP S/4HANA projects, or tightened compliance requirements. With the AIRC service's help, the implementation efforts and runtime of authorization projects can be greatly reduced. You will receive a standardized and well-proven role concept that meets common compliance requirements. The service’s automations also support newer technologies like processing Fiori artifacts and SAP BTP Roles/Role Collections, preventing issues with newer technologies in upcoming projects.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-your-sap-s-4hana-landscape-with-a-best-practice-role-concept/ba-p/13809622"/>
    <published>2024-08-29T23:50:00.035000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/title-s-4hana-authorization-management-the-sap-activate-method-thought/ba-p/13903921</id>
    <title>Title: S/4HANA authorization management: the SAP Activate method thought differently</title>
    <updated>2024-10-24T11:46:58.908000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanBlaser</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/526407</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The implementation or redesign of SAP authorizations is often associated with long projects, complex requirements and high resource expenditure. Especially in times of crisis, the feeling of uncertainty when implementing such projects can be overwhelming. But does it really have to be like this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the wake of the current economic uncertainty, I have developed a completely new approach - the &lt;STRONG&gt;Rapid System Implementation (RSI) method ‘4i’&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This method is not only faster, but also eliminates many of the classic project risks. How does it work? By using established best practices in a way that minimises risks and drastically shortens the project duration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why is the crisis the right time for innovation?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Crises always mean opportunities! Richard David Precht summed it up perfectly: ‘If there is an opportunity to rethink, then there is an opportunity to rethink in a crisis’. For us, this means that especially in difficult economic times, the time has come to rethink old patterns and break new ground - even in the S/4HANA authorization world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The RSI 4i method - a new approach for SAP authorization projects&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Rapid System Implementation 4i method&lt;/STRONG&gt; is the key to a fast, secure and flexible implementation of SAP authorizations. Here are the four steps that make up this approach:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;information: &lt;/STRONG&gt;structured keycards are used to collect all relevant company information in order to optimally customize the SAP best practice building blocks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;installation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;The best practice package is installed immediately at all levels - including individual roles, catalogues and business roles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;integration: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Short test phases by key users ensure that everything works smoothly before we go live.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;implementation: &lt;/STRONG&gt;SOD-compliant roles are assigned in stages and without risk - thanks to the option of secure fallback.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What's special about this method?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speed&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The project timeframe is drastically reduced and we achieve the goals faster than ever before.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The RSI method eliminates many of the classic project risks. As we do not touch the old authorizations, there is always a fallback.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Efficiency&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The introduction of best-practice roles is structured and without the typical lengthy problems that often occur in complex projects.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;I&gt;Why SAP_BR* roles are not the answer&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An important note: The SAP_BR* &lt;I&gt;roles&lt;/I&gt; supplied by SAP are &lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; intended &lt;STRONG&gt;for productive use &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(see &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/b4447b6727684f13917622cf63e1eb98/2021/en-US/AdminGuideS4HANAImpl_HELP_EN.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Administration Guide to Implementation of SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/4cef93946a0b48ec89533b3c34443b85/88e84ba4d9b84c3c8fe43defe3d0f401-179.html?version=2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help&lt;/A&gt; etc.)&lt;/EM&gt;. These roles are intended for demo purposes only and do not fulfil any regulatory requirements. An individually adapted authorization concept is therefore essential - and this is precisely where we come in with the best practice approach using the RSI 4i method.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is possible to think differently about authorization projects and reach the goal faster - without the usual project pain. The RSI 4i method offers a real alternative that combines efficiency, security and speed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you too would like to think and act differently during the crisis, I invite you to a &lt;STRONG&gt;strategy meeting&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Together we can discuss your individual challenges and identify concrete solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Discussion &amp;amp; exchange&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I welcome your feedback and look forward to hearing your ideas and exchanging experiences on SAP authorizations - thinking differently.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you like, you are welcome to watch the video, which explains the method on a slightly less technical level: &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_s2SLvk7RwI&amp;amp;t=628s" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;S/4HANA authorization management thought differently&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#808080"&gt;Note: translated with DeepL&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/title-s-4hana-authorization-management-the-sap-activate-method-thought/ba-p/13903921"/>
    <published>2024-10-24T11:46:58.908000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/master-s-4hana-authorisation-issues-a-practical-guide-with-visio-overview/ba-p/13919084</id>
    <title>Master S/4HANA authorisation issues: A practical guide with Visio Overview</title>
    <updated>2024-10-29T12:19:43.221000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>StephanBlaser</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/526407</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1073076717"&gt;Master S/4HANA authorization issues: A practical guide with Visio overview&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Authorization issues in SAP S/4HANA can significantly impact your day-to-day work. As an SAP authorization expert, I would like to present a systematic troubleshooting overview that may help you to efficiently overcome these challenges.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-876563212"&gt;The challenge&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP authorizations are as diverse as the business processes they protect. Small mistakes can have far-reaching consequences. The trick is to develop a flexible but clearly regulated authorisation concept that can adapt to changing requirements without becoming inconsistent. The world of authorizations has not become any easier with S/4HANA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-680049707"&gt;A systematic approach to troubleshooting&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To effectively solve authorization problems, I have created an overview that structures the troubleshooting process from the client level to the backend system. Let's go through the key steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-483536202"&gt;1. client level (Fiori Launchpad)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fiori Launchpad App Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Provides important information such as the SAP Fiori ID, business server page name, service node and OData service, as well as any authorisation, gateway or runtime errors that have occurred.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Browser Developer Tools (F12)&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Elements: Check the loaded components&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Console: JavaScript errors and runtime problems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sources: Direct access to JavaScript code Custom code file debugging&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Network: Checking the OData HTTP URLs Requests, responses and error messages&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-287022697"&gt;2. Front-End Server (FES)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;/IWFND/MAINT_SERVICE (OData configuration)&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Model cache cleanup&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Metadata reload&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SICF configuration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Service addition and configuration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gateway client&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Cache cleanup, cache rebuild, request execution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Service Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Checking for errors or insufficient authorizations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RFC Connection (SM59)&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ensuring the correct configuration between the front end and the back end&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;/IWFND/ERROR_LOG (OData Error Log)&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Analysing data transfer problems between FES and BES&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-90509192"&gt;3. Back-End Server (BES)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;STAUTHTRACE&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Detailed analysis of authorization problems, including CDS view level&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FLP Content Manager (/UI2/FLPCM_CUST)&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Checking the Fiori catalogues and their configuration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;PFCGUPDATEROLEMENU&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Matching the catalogues with authorization roles&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Profile generation and user matching&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ensuring consistency&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--106004313"&gt;Fiori Apps Library: An indispensable tool&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Fiori Apps Library is invaluable at every stage of the analysis. It provides detailed information on prerequisites, installation requirements, component statuses and service configurations for each Fiori app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--302517818"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This structured approach makes it possible to systematically isolate and resolve authorization problems. Note that the order of the steps may vary depending on the specific error. Experience plays an important role, but even for experienced experts, this overview can serve as a valuable checklist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I invite you to download the S/4HANA authorization troubleshooting overview and use it in your daily work. Feedback and suggestions for improvement are explicitly encouraged, as we can all learn from each other.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Do you have any questions or comments? I look forward to your comments and a lively exchange!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#808080"&gt;Note: translated with DeepL&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/master-s-4hana-authorisation-issues-a-practical-guide-with-visio-overview/ba-p/13919084"/>
    <published>2024-10-29T12:19:43.221000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/abap-authority-check-explained-a-practical-guide-with-real-world-example/ba-p/14035570</id>
    <title>ABAP AUTHORITY CHECK Explained: A Practical Guide with Real-World Example</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T15:16:40.128000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Pradeep555</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1451114</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AUTHORITY-CHECK IN ABAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Is a concept which enables or allow users to perform certain functions/ activities in the SAP system&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, we will look for an example of such activity:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To create a material or sales order I suppose to have authorization&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System checks whether I am authorized for the task or not –then only the system will proceed further&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Suppose in a general scenario while talking a leave the manager needs to authorize the request of our leave approval .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What happens in SAP ?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In SAP basis person will assign the authorization object to user id to proceed it further&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Terminologies in authority-check.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Object class: it is a container for authorization objects&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Authorization object: object to check authorization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Authorization field: an authorization object has the authorization field which is used to define field values&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here the hierarchy goes like&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_0-1741257370050.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233859i37FE8B45BB5129C1/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Pradeep555_0-1741257370050.png" alt="Pradeep555_0-1741257370050.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;T-CODES:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Authorization field – SU20&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Object class and authorization object: SU21&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OVERVIEW:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The first and foremost thing is we need to check for authorization object class&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Which is a container for authorization object&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once we create the object --&amp;gt; we need to assign the filed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scenario:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Suppose we are using MM01 transaction to create a material, and we get an error&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At this moment we can inform BASIS people to check for the authorization in case we need any.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Step;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a material and put external BP&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_32-1741254513306.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233809i63DFC3D652DDB76B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_32-1741254513306.png" alt="Pradeep555_32-1741254513306.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;2.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Put breakpoint on statement AUTHORITY-CHECK .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here we can see auth object is ‘M_MATE_NEW’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Field – ‘DUMMY'&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Value - ‘*’&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_33-1741254513310.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233808i8D302FF6931CE099/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_33-1741254513310.png" alt="Pradeep555_33-1741254513310.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3.If we provide the field in SU20&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_34-1741254513311.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233811iB007D3FB4183F738/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_34-1741254513311.png" alt="Pradeep555_34-1741254513311.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whenever we execute sy-subrc will be zero – indicates that we are authorized&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Or else it will give sy-subrc&amp;nbsp; 12 indicating we are not authorized to create the material&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_35-1741254513313.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233812iFE3DF3F3F57218F9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_35-1741254513313.png" alt="Pradeep555_35-1741254513313.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here we have provided the field ACTVT—We shall have a glance about this&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_36-1741254513314.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233810i8ABAC03C981F8FFF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_36-1741254513314.png" alt="Pradeep555_36-1741254513314.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The filed ACTVT has some permitted values—click on the status icon beside ACTVT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_37-1741254513315.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233813i8DC5E9FE2CD357BA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_37-1741254513315.png" alt="Pradeep555_37-1741254513315.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;01- IT IS CREATE&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;02- CHANGE&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;03- DISPLAY&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Suppose if we provide a material and put external bp –we get same authorization value&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_38-1741254513315.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233814i9E71B1F0F711FCCC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_38-1741254513315.png" alt="Pradeep555_38-1741254513315.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7.So, in the ACTVT we saw 02- for change and same for display&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The ACTVT holds value-03 and here we can see the field value&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_39-1741254513317.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233815iB6A77161F4E88D92/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_39-1741254513317.png" alt="Pradeep555_39-1741254513317.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now let's take real time scenario:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Implementing authorization checks in ABAP program is crucial to ensure that only authorized users can perform operations like &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;INSERT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;UPDATE&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, or &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DELETE&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on your cylinder data, which includes delivery charges, stock, and cylinder types. Here's how you can set up and demonstrate an &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AUTHORITY-CHECK&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; based on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;cylinder batch ID&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Steps:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create authorization object class in SU21&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_40-1741254513320.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233816i5569442585DF5DCD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_40-1741254513320.png" alt="Pradeep555_40-1741254513320.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_41-1741254513321.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233817iA3C46FACB1C24066/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_41-1741254513321.png" alt="Pradeep555_41-1741254513321.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2.Save it&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_42-1741254513322.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233818i2C3732D1210E3662/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_42-1741254513322.png" alt="Pradeep555_42-1741254513322.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;3.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Crate the authorization field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_43-1741254513323.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233819i2F2672AE3A7EEEE4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_43-1741254513323.png" alt="Pradeep555_43-1741254513323.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;4.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select the operation you want to do on DB &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_44-1741254513324.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233820i651106810EDDC4C2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_44-1741254513324.png" alt="Pradeep555_44-1741254513324.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;5.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select the activity and save it &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_45-1741254513325.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233821i45446D8A6FF34AA6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_45-1741254513325.png" alt="Pradeep555_45-1741254513325.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scenario – in the report we have stock table and&amp;nbsp;particular&amp;nbsp;user can&amp;nbsp;delete&amp;nbsp;update insert Once we are done&amp;nbsp;with&amp;nbsp;auth object—basis person will create a role using t code&amp;nbsp;pfcg&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If we goto to the t code SU01 – AND CLICK ON role we can be able to see the assigned roles&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_46-1741254513326.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233823iCF446CEC128A6331/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_46-1741254513326.png" alt="Pradeep555_46-1741254513326.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Authorization filed and value will be&amp;nbsp;assigned by BASIS&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;will reflect here&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;After&amp;nbsp;assigning&amp;nbsp;role&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_47-1741254513328.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233822iE8669B6A409D5CE9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_47-1741254513328.png" alt="Pradeep555_47-1741254513328.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; code &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;REPORT zpd_rp_auth_chek. 
 
TYPES : BEGIN OF lty_BID, 
          cylinder_batch_id TYPE zpd_de_batch_id, 
        END OF lty_BID. 
 
DATA : lwa_data TYPE zpd_t_stock. 
DATA : zpd_de_batch_id TYPE TABLE OF lty_BID. 
DATA : lwa_bid TYPE  lty_BID. 
DATA : lt_bid TYPE  TABLE OF lty_bid. 
 
 
TYPES : BEGIN OF lty_display, 
          delivery_charge TYPE zpd_de_charge, 
          cylinder_type   TYPE zpd_de_cylinder_type, 
          stock           TYPE zpd_de_stock, 
        END OF lty_display. 
 
DATA : lwa_display TYPE lty_display. 
DATA : lv_objectid TYPE cdhdr-objectid. 
*DATA : lwa_bid TYPE zpd_t_stock. 
 
 
 
PARAMETERS : p_id TYPE zpd_de_batch_id OBLIGATORY. 
PARAMETERS : p_charge TYPE  zpd_de_charge  . 
PARAMETERS : p_type TYPE zpd_de_cylinder_type . 
PARAMETERS : p_stock TYPE  zpd_de_stock MODIF ID a3. 
PARAMETERS : p_r1 TYPE c RADIOBUTTON GROUP r1  USER-COMMAND abc . 
PARAMETERS : p_r2 TYPE c RADIOBUTTON GROUP r1 . 
PARAMETERS : p_r3 TYPE c RADIOBUTTON GROUP r1.. 
 
 
 
START-OF-SELECTION. 
 
*Insert 
  IF p_r1 = 'X'. 
 
    AUTHORITY-CHECK OBJECT 'ZAUTHBID' 
ID 'ACTVT' FIELD '01'. 
  ENDIF. 
  IF sy-subrc &amp;lt;&amp;gt; 0 . 
    MESSAGE e005(zmsg_auth). 
 
    lwa_data-cylinder_batch_id =  p_id. 
    lwa_data-delivery_charge =  p_charge. 
    lwa_data-cylinder_type =  p_type. 
    lwa_data-stock =  p_stock. 
 
    INSERT zpd_t_stock FROM lwa_data. 
    IF sy-subrc = 0. 
      WRITE : TEXT-000. 
    ELSE. 
      WRITE : TEXT-001. 
    ENDIF. 
  ENDIF. 
 
 
 
*Delete. 
  IF p_r2 = 'X'. 
    AUTHORITY-CHECK OBJECT 'ZAUTHBID' 
ID 'ACTVT' FIELD '02'. 
  ENDIF. 
  IF sy-subrc &amp;lt;&amp;gt; 0 . 
    MESSAGE e007(zmsg_auth). 
 
 
 
    SELECT SINGLE * FROM zpd_t_stock INTO lwa_data WHERE cylinder_batch_id = p_id. 
    lwa_data-cylinder_batch_id = p_id. 
    DELETE zpd_t_stock FROM lwa_data. 
    IF sy-subrc = 0. 
      WRITE : TEXT-003 , ' :' , p_id. 
    ENDIF. 
  ENDIF. 
 
 
*Update 
  IF p_r3 = 'X'. 
 
    AUTHORITY-CHECK OBJECT 'ZAUTHBID' 
ID 'ACTVT' FIELD '06'. 
  ENDIF. 
  IF sy-subrc &amp;lt;&amp;gt; 0 . 
    MESSAGE e006(zmsg_auth). 
 
 
    lwa_data-cylinder_batch_id = p_id. 
    lwa_data-delivery_charge = p_charge. 
    lwa_data-cylinder_type = p_type. 
    lwa_data-stock = p_stock. 
 
    UPDATE zpd_t_stock FROM lwa_data. 
    IF sy-subrc = 0. 
      WRITE : TEXT-004, ' :' , p_id. 
    ENDIF. 
  ENDIF. 
 
 
 
 
 
AT SELECTION-SCREEN. 
  IF p_r1 = 'X'. 
    SELECT cylinder_batch_id 
    FROM zpd_t_stock 
    INTO TABLE lt_bid 
    WHERE cylinder_batch_id = p_id. 
 
    IF sy-subrc = 0. 
      MESSAGE e003(zmsg_auth) WITH p_id. 
    ENDIF. 
 
  ENDIF. 
 
  IF p_r2 = 'X'. 
 
    SELECT SINGLE cylinder_batch_id 
    FROM zpd_t_stock 
    INTO lwa_bid 
    WHERE cylinder_batch_id = p_id. 
    IF sy-subrc NE 0. 
      MESSAGE e004(zmsg_auth) WITH p_id. 
    ENDIF. 
  ENDIF. 
 
  IF p_r3 = 'X'. 
 
    SELECT SINGLE cylinder_batch_id 
    FROM zpd_t_stock 
    INTO lwa_bid 
    WHERE cylinder_batch_id = p_id. 
    IF sy-subrc NE 0. 
      MESSAGE e004(zmsg_auth) WITH p_id. 
    ELSE. 
      SELECT SINGLE   delivery_charge  stock 
      FROM zpd_t_stock 
      INTO lwa_display 
      WHERE cylinder_batch_id  = p_id. 
    ENDIF. 
  ENDIF. 
 
 
AT SELECTION-SCREEN OUTPUT. 
 
 
 
  LOOP AT SCREEN. 
    IF screen-group1 = 'A1' OR screen-group1 = 'A2'  OR screen-group1 = 'A3' OR screen-group1 = 'A4'. 
      screen-active = 0. 
      MODIFY SCREEN. 
    ENDIF. 
 
  ENDLOOP. 
 
 
  IF p_r3 = 'X'. 
    p_type = lwa_display-cylinder_type. 
    p_charge = lwa_display-delivery_charge. 
    p_stock = lwa_display-stock. 
 
  ENDIF. &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_48-1741254513329.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233824i94C5BE5D2A997A8C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_48-1741254513329.png" alt="Pradeep555_48-1741254513329.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_63-1741255387340.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233844i73CBB832C173E3ED/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_63-1741255387340.png" alt="Pradeep555_63-1741255387340.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_49-1741254513330.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233825iD91D2ED75636C2C5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_49-1741254513330.png" alt="Pradeep555_49-1741254513330.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_50-1741254513331.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233826i57FE223164F9331F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_50-1741254513331.png" alt="Pradeep555_50-1741254513331.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Same in case of &amp;nbsp;delete ..&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So now lets dicuss about the key parameters present in the authorization &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP_ALL :&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The composite profile SAP_ALL contains all SAP authorizations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It means that a user with this profile can perform all tasks in the SAP system &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The user which is having SAP_ALL authorization has the rights to administer the SAP system &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In projects, it is recommended to have only one user with SAP_ALL authorizations, rest all users have the authorization based upon their role&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_51-1741254513332.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233827i346ED86C190FBE7F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_51-1741254513332.png" alt="Pradeep555_51-1741254513332.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_52-1741254513335.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233828iE0698B66AAFD4EA1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_52-1741254513335.png" alt="Pradeep555_52-1741254513335.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here I have authorization for&amp;nbsp;SAP_ALL means I have sap all system authorization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;IN CASE:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Even though I have SAP_ALL&amp;nbsp;authorizations .then why is it not&amp;nbsp;possible&amp;nbsp;to create the&amp;nbsp;records&amp;nbsp;in previous program?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When we created object, we need to add that new object in SAP_ALL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And&amp;nbsp;SAP_ALL&amp;nbsp;has all many predefined authorizations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To add that we need to regenerate&amp;nbsp;SAP_ALL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_53-1741254513336.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233830i04F2BC58F37CFF77/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_53-1741254513336.png" alt="Pradeep555_53-1741254513336.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So once we&amp;nbsp;regenerate&amp;nbsp;it – it will be the part of&amp;nbsp;SAP_ALL&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now if we try to insert a record it will show –&amp;nbsp;sy-subrc&amp;nbsp; will be 0&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_54-1741254513340.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233829iAE42EEAA2C877A3A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_54-1741254513340.png" alt="Pradeep555_54-1741254513340.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now let's see the requirement of assigning authorization for a particular field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Suppose I want to assign auth for a custom field delivery charge – only certain people can&amp;nbsp; see the&amp;nbsp;delivery &amp;nbsp;charges&amp;nbsp;change the&amp;nbsp;delivery charges&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I have a custom table of cylinder data &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_55-1741254513341.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233833i6878B2036F5AB115/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_55-1741254513341.png" alt="Pradeep555_55-1741254513341.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;2.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Su20 – create field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_56-1741254513343.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233832i1E3A6BEB91D23F7F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_56-1741254513343.png" alt="Pradeep555_56-1741254513343.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;3.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Su21&amp;nbsp;create&amp;nbsp;auth obj class—and use already existing&amp;nbsp;class&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_57-1741254513345.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233831i6F2AB95CE2FCE761/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_57-1741254513345.png" alt="Pradeep555_57-1741254513345.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4.Here I'm providing authorization on displaying the details of delivery charges&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_58-1741254513346.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233834i9E94237A03B4D79D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_58-1741254513346.png" alt="Pradeep555_58-1741254513346.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_59-1741254513347.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233836i5D7C3BDB18AADCCE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_59-1741254513347.png" alt="Pradeep555_59-1741254513347.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Code :&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;TYPES : BEGIN OF lty_display, 
          delivery_charge TYPE zpd_de_charge, 
          cylinder_type   TYPE zpd_de_cylinder_type, 
          stock           TYPE zpd_de_stock, 
        END OF lty_display. 
 
 
DATA : lt_data TYPE TABLE OF lty_display, 
       wa      TYPE lty_display. 
 
PARAMETERS : p_dc TYPE zpd_de_stock. 
 
START-OF-SELECTION. 
  SELECT delivery_charge 
          cylinder_type 
           stock FROM zpd_t_stock 
  INTO TABLE lt_data 
   WHERE delivery_charge = p_dc . 
 
  LOOP AT lt_data INTO wa. 
    WRITE : wa-delivery_charge , wa-cylinder_type , wa-stock . 
 
  ENDLOOP. 
 
  AT SELECTION-SCREEN . 
   AUTHORITY-CHECK OBJECT  'ZDELICHRG' 
   ID 'ACTVT' FIELD '03' 
   ID 'DELIVCHARG' FIELD P_DC. 
   IF SY-SUBRC &amp;lt;&amp;gt; 0. 
     MESSAGE e008(ZMSG_AUTH) WITH p_dc. 
     ENDIF. &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;5.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We can see that we are getting sy-subrc = 12&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_60-1741254513349.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233835i7B978AA9A7B5E0DC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_60-1741254513349.png" alt="Pradeep555_60-1741254513349.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;6.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So when we try to display the records with particular delivery charge we get an error&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Pradeep555_61-1741254513351.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/233837i6B712B0C8340D028/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Pradeep555_61-1741254513351.png" alt="Pradeep555_61-1741254513351.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here are some simple conclusion points:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Secure Data Access:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Using AUTHORITY-CHECK ensures that only authorized users can update, delete, or insert cylinder data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Granular Permissions:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Instead of giving broad access (like SAP_ALL), you assign rights for specific fields (like a cylinder batch ID) to limit who can change data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Role-Based Control:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;By creating roles in PFCG with precise authorization objects, you control access based on business needs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Risk Reduction:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fine-grained authorizations help reduce the risk of accidental or unauthorized data changes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ongoing Review:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Regularly reviewing and updating roles ensures that permissions stay relevant and secure.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/abap-authority-check-explained-a-practical-guide-with-real-world-example/ba-p/14035570"/>
    <published>2025-03-11T15:16:40.128000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/limited-time-activation-of-virtual-super-user-sap/ba-p/14104637</id>
    <title>Limited Time Activation of virtual Super-User - SAP*</title>
    <updated>2025-05-20T16:26:58.773000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Agrawal_Himanshu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/494787</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Note 3303172&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Time-limited client-specific activation of the virtual super-user SAP*, available &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;as of kernel release 790&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Logon to the operating system of an application server using &amp;lt;sid&amp;gt;adm user.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start the interactive tool dpmon with menu option u to activate the virtual client-specific super-user SAP* in a chosen client. Define a period of between 10 and 30 minutes as validity. You will obtain a one-time password after successful activation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Logon using user SAP* and the one-time password you have obtained on any currently running application server.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-10-7_14-59-48.png" style="width: 686px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/262668i22751A7454E17461/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image-2024-10-7_14-59-48.png" alt="image-2024-10-7_14-59-48.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Point to be noted :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Any password based logon attempt for user SAP*, regardless if successful or not, invalidates the one-time password immediately.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can (re-)activate the user using dpmon any time and will obtain a new one-time password. This is needed for example if you had a typo in your attempt to use the one-time password and could not logon.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Within dpmon you have further the possibility to see in which clients a virtual super-user does currently exist, which one still has a one-time password, their remaining existence and you are able to delete them prematurely.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;An existing user SAP* (and an emergency super-user SAP* activated by the second option) is superimposed by an existing virtual super-user SAP* in a client.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A maximum of 20 virtual super-user SAP* can exist in parallel in different clients.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;There is no need for an application server restart as no static profile parameter needs to be changed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The user has no hardcoded known password but gets a new random one-time password after each activation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The user is activated client-specific.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The user existence is limited in time, its validity is chosen during its activation within dpmon(the allowed period is between 10 and 30 minutes), and the user can also be deleted within dpmon already before its expiration. Bear in mind: a user deletion has no influence on an already established session. A session does continue to run.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both activation and usage of the virtual super-user are logged in the security audit log event EUP (purpose 2).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security Audit Log for virtual user &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP*&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-10-7_14-56-36.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/262667i50509967A63A2237/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image-2024-10-7_14-56-36.png" alt="image-2024-10-7_14-56-36.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/limited-time-activation-of-virtual-super-user-sap/ba-p/14104637"/>
    <published>2025-05-20T16:26:58.773000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/strengthening-sap-security-a-closer-look-at-authorizations-and-access/ba-p/14109254</id>
    <title>Strengthening SAP Security: A Closer Look at Authorizations and Access Control</title>
    <updated>2025-05-22T13:35:36.332000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Xenia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/899</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As promised in my previous &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/a-holistic-approach-to-sap-security-introducing-the-secure-operations-map/ba-p/14084296" target="_self"&gt;post&lt;/A&gt; , it's time to explore the different domains of the SAP Secure Operations Map (SOM). This series aims to highlight key areas that deserve attention and showcase tools and services that can support your company on its journey toward a more secure SAP environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We'll begin with a topic that most professionals associate as the cornerstone of SAP security:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Authorizations and Access Control&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="The cornerstone of SAP Security: Authorizations and Access Control" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265053i8B35076B83CC206A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Xenia_0-1747913258541.png" alt="The cornerstone of SAP Security: Authorizations and Access Control" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;The cornerstone of SAP Security: Authorizations and Access Control&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1730625498"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Challenge: Keeping Authorization Concepts Current&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of the biggest pain points in this domain is that authorization concepts often become outdated almost immediately after implementation. You may have defined a comprehensive concept at a certain point in time, but if your access control processes are not actively maintained and updated, that concept quickly loses its relevance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This issue is especially prevalent in ERP systems, which offer a vast range of highly specific authorization options. While SaaS applications may be less complex in this regard, challenges still arise—particularly when defining business roles that span multiple systems. Consider a purchaser who uses S/4HANA for procurement, SAP Ariba for supplier collaboration, and SAP Analytics Cloud for reporting. Understanding and managing the authorization requirements across such a landscape is far from straightforward.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1534111993"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Risks and Red Flags&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Proper access control isn't just about functionality—it’s about minimizing risk. For example:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Critical Authorizations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Users should not have direct access to sensitive system elements such as table contents unless absolutely necessary.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Segregation of Duties (SoD)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: A single user should not have the ability to execute multiple critical steps in a process. For instance, allowing a purchaser to both create purchase orders and maintain vendor master data could open the door to fraud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1337598488"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Where to Begin? Start with Your Access Control Processes!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To build a resilient access control framework, begin by asking key questions about your current processes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How are access control tasks handled today?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are access risk definitions actively managed?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How are roles assigned—manually or through tools?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are authorizations maintained regularly?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Are there ongoing checks for SoD (segregation of duties) conflicts?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do users only retain appropriate authorizations when their roles or positions change?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How are privileged operations (e.g., "firefighter access") managed?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once you’ve answered these questions and established clear processes, you can explore opportunities for optimization—such as automation or dedicated tools like&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Access Control&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;and&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Identity Access Governance (IAG)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Begin by asking key questions about your current access control processes" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265055i8DE0B83242C42CA6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Xenia_1-1747913457207.png" alt="Begin by asking key questions about your current access control processes" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Begin by asking key questions about your current access control processes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1141084983"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Role Optimization and Reducing Privilege Creep&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of your access control maturity, role optimization is a logical next step. If your processes haven’t been streamlined in the past, it’s likely that "privilege creep"—the gradual accumulation of excessive authorizations—has taken hold.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One powerful tool based service to support role optimization is&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AIRC ("Automated Implementation of Role Concept")&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. AIRC generates role proposals based on actual system usage, helping you accelerate the development of a new role concept. With AIRC, time to value can be as short as three months. For more details, take a look at this informative blog post by Markus: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-your-sap-s-4hana-landscape-with-a-best-practice-role-concept/ba-p/13809622" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Optimizing Your SAP S/4HANA Landscape with a Best Practice Role Concept&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AIRC can also support your&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;authorization journey. Learn more about that here: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/authorizations-for-sap-business-technology-plattform-a-quick-start/ba-p/13924776" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Authorizations for SAP Business Technology Platform – A Quick Start&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-944571478"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Need Support?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you need help setting up or optimizing your access control processes, we’re here to support you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next up, for the next post in this series, where I’ll take a deeper look at SAP Access Control and SAP IAG—and how they can be effectively leveraged across a hybrid SAP landscape.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/strengthening-sap-security-a-closer-look-at-authorizations-and-access/ba-p/14109254"/>
    <published>2025-05-22T13:35:36.332000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/authorization-group/ba-p/14113648</id>
    <title>Authorization group</title>
    <updated>2025-05-28T13:34:19.131000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Slowly_Going</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1911117</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1860456809"&gt;How They Work&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When a user attempts to access an SAP object, the system checks two things:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_1:"&gt;1️⃣&lt;/span&gt;Whether the user has the necessary authorization (through roles and profiles)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":keycap_2:"&gt;2️⃣&lt;/span&gt;Whether the user is authorized for the specific authorization group assigned to that object&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If an object belongs to an authorization group that the user cannot access, the system will deny access even if the user has other relevant permissions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1663943304"&gt;Common Use Cases&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Table Protection&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Database tables containing sensitive information (like payroll data, financial records, or personal information) are assigned to specific authorization groups. Only users with appropriate clearance can access these tables through transactions like SE16 or development tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slowly_Going_0-1748430501461.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266907i71DD81780AFB3B52/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Slowly_Going_0-1748430501461.png" alt="Slowly_Going_0-1748430501461.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slowly_Going_3-1748430775401.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266913i77765117DEF110E9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Slowly_Going_3-1748430775401.png" alt="Slowly_Going_3-1748430775401.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Program Security&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Custom programs or reports can be assigned authorization groups to ensure only designated users can execute them, particularly useful for programs that manipulate critical business data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slowly_Going_1-1748430614824.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266909i7789C9FEE7021523/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Slowly_Going_1-1748430614824.png" alt="Slowly_Going_1-1748430614824.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slowly_Going_2-1748430675749.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266912i6FCC8235801CF0D7/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Slowly_Going_2-1748430675749.png" alt="Slowly_Going_2-1748430675749.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1467429799"&gt;Configuration and Assignment&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Authorization groups are typically defined in customization tables and then assigned to objects through various methods depending on the object type. Users are granted access to authorization groups through their roles, which contain authorization objects (like S_TABU_DIS for table access) that specify which authorization groups they can access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1270916294"&gt;Demo&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create new authorization group in the SM30, view name&amp;nbsp;V_TPGP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slowly_Going_4-1748431013328.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266916i599A38B78680A785/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Slowly_Going_4-1748431013328.png" alt="Slowly_Going_4-1748431013328.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add this group to the program (see explanation above). Now if the user without&amp;nbsp;appropriate clearance try to execute the report the error message will be appears.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slowly_Going_9-1748431747109.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266930iDE1DA885B2D49BED/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Slowly_Going_9-1748431747109.png" alt="Slowly_Going_9-1748431747109.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add the group to the related field of the object.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slowly_Going_6-1748431412532.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266924i043BCE6CCD1F13D1/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Slowly_Going_6-1748431412532.png" alt="Slowly_Going_6-1748431412532.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The role should be assigned to the user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slowly_Going_7-1748431482438.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266927i47B5EB5D550ECAF2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Slowly_Going_7-1748431482438.png" alt="Slowly_Going_7-1748431482438.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now the program can be executed&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Slowly_Going_8-1748431648733.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266929i8E431491931D1D3B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Slowly_Going_8-1748431648733.png" alt="Slowly_Going_8-1748431648733.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/authorization-group/ba-p/14113648"/>
    <published>2025-05-28T13:34:19.131000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
