<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Ariba-Invoice-Management-qa.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Ariba Invoice Management</title>
  <updated>2025-09-26T11:11:51.257133+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Ariba Invoice Management/pd-p/fb10da9a-0e4f-4893-9978-b915d0210ec5" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Ariba Invoice Management Q&amp;A in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-network-invoicing-with-ocr/qaq-p/13947345</id>
    <title>Ariba Network Invoicing with OCR</title>
    <updated>2024-11-25T08:11:13.929000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Velu_V</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1724767</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Has anyone worked on Ariba network invoicing with OCR Functionality? Is there a pre-integrated 3rd party solution available for Invoicing over Ariba Network? If so, has anyone been able to use this and any references or materials or experience that you can share on how to get this started or where exactly the Third-Party solution will get integrated with Ariba network i,e buyer side or supplier side or on the Ariba Invoice management in Ariba B&amp;amp;I?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone please confirm if "CloudTrade"(Which is acquired by Advanced) is still an active Partner for SAP Ariba for PDF Invoicing?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Velu&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-network-invoicing-with-ocr/qaq-p/13947345"/>
    <published>2024-11-25T08:11:13.929000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/balance-in-transaction-currency-error-while-posting-invoice-from-ariba-to/qaq-p/13949331</id>
    <title>Balance in Transaction Currency error while posting Invoice from Ariba to ECC(message: RW033)</title>
    <updated>2024-11-27T04:54:34.480000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Surendra10</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1664999</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi All,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;we are getting the below push back error while posting invoice from Ariba to ECC. can you please help understand this error&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Surendra10_0-1732679622849.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/195820i29F87EECC9E2482B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Surendra10_0-1732679622849.png" alt="Surendra10_0-1732679622849.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/balance-in-transaction-currency-error-while-posting-invoice-from-ariba-to/qaq-p/13949331"/>
    <published>2024-11-27T04:54:34.480000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/invoices-in-business-network-failing-incorrectly/qaq-p/13952747</id>
    <title>Invoices in Business Network failing incorrectly</title>
    <updated>2024-12-02T06:24:04.717000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Velu_V</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1724767</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are implementing Ariba Invoice Management solution for a Non-SAP ERP, as part of this, after the realm baseline, we started creating test transactions from Ariba Invoice Management (AIM) to network (Non-PO Invoices) and were able to validate only for a couple of invoices that it all went fine (from AIM to Network). But after those couple of non-po invoices any non-po invoice we create is getting rejected at Network with the error - "&lt;SPAN&gt;Invoice could not be created from InvoiceDetailRequest. Reason = Duplicate invoice number."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; We tried creating multiple combinations, by replicating the same data as the ones that were successful by changing quantity and amount and copying the existing Non-PO invoices from AIM, but all invoices seems to be getting this error, although there is no duplicate of invoices here, all the invoices have different Invoice Numbers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are trying to raise a support request on this, i want to check in this group if anyone has encountered this error during implementation or support and what steps have been taken to resolve this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note, we don't have CIG in place here, we are creating the invoices from AIM and validating the statuses in Business Network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any help on this would be much appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Velu&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/invoices-in-business-network-failing-incorrectly/qaq-p/13952747"/>
    <published>2024-12-02T06:24:04.717000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/attachments-on-remittance-or-payment-status-information/qaq-p/13955303</id>
    <title>Attachments on Remittance or Payment status information</title>
    <updated>2024-12-04T13:07:33.097000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Velu_V</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1724767</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have a requirement to send Check Copies on Remittance status information from Non-SAP ERP System to Ariba Invoice Management system. Is anyone aware that we can send attachments over the Remittance status/Payment status file from Non-SAP ERP to Ariba Network/Ariba Invoice Management solution?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If so, could you please share your experience or any guidance around this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that, since this is with Non-SAP system, we don't have CIG and we have SAP BTP in scope.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Velu&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/attachments-on-remittance-or-payment-status-information/qaq-p/13955303"/>
    <published>2024-12-04T13:07:33.097000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/commerce-automation-with-non-sap-erp-commodity-codes/qaq-p/13959976</id>
    <title>Commerce Automation with Non-SAP ERP Commodity codes</title>
    <updated>2024-12-10T12:23:38.258000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Velu_V</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1724767</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Trying to understand the best possible ways to handle the commodity code (Taxonomy) in Ariba Invoice Management. We are implementing Commerce Automation and Ariba Invoice Management for a Non-SAP ERP backend, as part of this, we have a list of custom commodity codes that are used as Product groups in non-SAP ERP. I am aware of the 4 commodity code files (commodity export, Classification code map, ERP Commodity codes/Partition commodity code and CEME). But in our case, since the POs will be initiated from Non-SAP ERP System, when the invoices reach the Network, we expect the suppliers to submit invoices over the network. When suppliers submit the invoices over the network, it should flow to Ariba Invoice Management solution, and we should be able to capture the Commodity code details from the PO to Invoice Reconciliation document which will drive the accounting combination in Ariba Invoice Management as per the CEME (Commodity Export Map Export) combination.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the above scenario, when the PO is created in Non-SAP ERP, we will not have the Commodity code (UNSPSC) captured anywhere on the PO Output to Network, but we may be able to send the ERP Commodity code / ERP Product group code. But when an invoice is submitted via network, will the Commodity code be determined automatically based on the ERP Product group code in Ariba Invoice Management?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Am looking for the best practices in this case on how we can leverage the Commodity code files in SAP Ariba Invoice Management while connecting with Non-SAP ERP System.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that, since backend system is Non-SAP ERP, the Ariba Invoice Management solution is a Generic Variant provided to us and hence CIG is Out of scope, and we have BTP as middleware.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any help or suggestions or how you have handled the above scenarios while enabling commerce Automation for PO Collaboration and Ariba Invoice Management for a Non-SAP ERP would be very much appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Velu&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/commerce-automation-with-non-sap-erp-commodity-codes/qaq-p/13959976"/>
    <published>2024-12-10T12:23:38.258000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/import-supplier-data-and-account-information-for-generic-ariba-variant/qaq-p/13965507</id>
    <title>Import Supplier Data and Account Information for Generic Ariba Variant</title>
    <updated>2024-12-17T10:40:15.517000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Velu_V</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1724767</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are aware that the Supplier Data and the General ledger files can be automated from SAP ECC or S/4 HANA to SAP Ariba B&amp;amp;I through the Master data export program. But we have the backend System as non-SAP ERP and we have Ariba Invoice Management Solution (Not the B&amp;amp;I suite but only Ariba Invoice Management) as Generic Variant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone please confirm if we can import/Automate the Supplier Data and the Account (General Ledger) information from Non-SAP ERP System to Ariba Invoice Management provided we have SAP BTP as the middleware. Is this possible, was anyone able to perform the Batch Import of Supplier and Account information from Non-SAP ERP to Ariba Invoice Management/Ariba B&amp;amp;I?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Velu&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/import-supplier-data-and-account-information-for-generic-ariba-variant/qaq-p/13965507"/>
    <published>2024-12-17T10:40:15.517000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/po-accounting-split-value-by-amount-error/qaq-p/13967360</id>
    <title>PO Accounting Split Value by Amount Error</title>
    <updated>2024-12-18T14:50:49.072000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FK244</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1761753</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Running into an issue when creating a PO with accounting split by Amount (over 10 splits) and when invoice is ready to be processed manually in Ariba for the amount less than the PO amount, we receive an error that &lt;STRONG&gt;Line Item 1, Accounting: The Split values amount is more than total amount.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;But when creating a PO with accounting split by Percentage (over 10 splits), invoice is manually processed successful without any errors. But when invoices are processed via ICS Paper Invoice method, both PO scenarios by amount or percentage accounting splits are successfully processed and integrated to Ariba.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/po-accounting-split-value-by-amount-error/qaq-p/13967360"/>
    <published>2024-12-18T14:50:49.072000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/commerce-automation-po-and-gr-from-non-sap-to-ariba-network-and-to-ariba/qaq-p/13968529</id>
    <title>Commerce Automation PO and GR from Non SAP to Ariba Network and to Ariba Invoice Management Solution</title>
    <updated>2024-12-19T15:52:58+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Velu_V</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1724767</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone please confirm if the below scenarios are possible? Our landscape is we use Non-SAP ERP for creating Purchase Orders and Goods Receipts and we have SAP BTP as middleware. We have Commerce Automation and Ariba Invoice Management solutions with us.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Purchase Orders created, Updated and Cancelled from Non-SAP ERP System to Ariba Network and then to Ariba Invoice Management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Goods Receipt created, updated or Reversed from Non-SAP ERP System to Ariba Network and then to Ariba Invoice Management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Can someone please confirm if you have worked on the above scenarios in Ariba when dealing with a Non-SAP ERP System and how would you capture the PO updates and GR updates to send to Network and from there or directly from BTP, can we bring the PO and GR and their relevant updates to Ariba Invoice Management? Any help or guidance on this would be much appreciated?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also, if you have any documentation or guidance on how to get the PO Copy from Network to Ariba Invoice Management solution, please guide.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks,&lt;BR /&gt;Velu&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/commerce-automation-po-and-gr-from-non-sap-to-ariba-network-and-to-ariba/qaq-p/13968529"/>
    <published>2024-12-19T15:52:58+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/external-supplier-review-approval-in-service-entry-sheet-ses-workflow/qaq-p/13982992</id>
    <title>External Supplier review/approval in Service Entry Sheet (SES) workflow</title>
    <updated>2025-01-10T20:49:38.903000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anugoonj</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1928806</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello community members,&lt;BR /&gt;I have a query related to a specific business use case and need your input.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The buyer will create a PR request for lab and when lab submits their SES (Service Entry Sheet), we need an external Supplier to review/confirm/pre-approve the SES before it is sent to buyer for final approval.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;How can this be configured in SES approval workflow ?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/external-supplier-review-approval-in-service-entry-sheet-ses-workflow/qaq-p/13982992"/>
    <published>2025-01-10T20:49:38.903000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/anyone-please-share-sap-ariba-functional-consultant-all-materials/qaq-p/13991169</id>
    <title>Anyone please share SAP Ariba Functional consultant all materials</title>
    <updated>2025-01-20T17:38:39.286000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Prem1802</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1947607</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hi, Anyone please share SAP Ariba Functional consultant all learning materials. Like PDF, Word, Video etc.,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-learning-q-a/anyone-please-share-sap-ariba-functional-consultant-all-materials/qaq-p/13991169"/>
    <published>2025-01-20T17:38:39.286000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/some-extracted-ariba-invoice-line-item-data-via-procurement-api-does-not/qaq-p/13997887</id>
    <title>Some Extracted Ariba Invoice Line Item Data via Procurement API Does Not Match with Order Line Item</title>
    <updated>2025-01-27T12:53:54.214000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>_r0y</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1800564</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the Invoice Line Item table extracted from Ariba via the Procurement API, there are records created from purchase orders where the purchase order line item number does not match the invoice line item number. The ratio of unmatched records is 20.89%, with 80,373 out of 384,822 records affected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See below:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="OrderLineItemNumInInvoiceLineItemTableChanged.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/217559iA751D6A8CACD9192/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="OrderLineItemNumInInvoiceLineItemTableChanged.png" alt="OrderLineItemNumInInvoiceLineItemTableChanged.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bold columns are foreign keys that join the Invoice Line Item Table to the Purchase Order Line Item Table in SQL. In the yellow cell, it returns "2" as an Order line item number(&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;OrderLineItem_NumberInCollection&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;), but the original purchase order line item number was "1". There is no other record that has "1" for the purchase order line item number. The original purchase order line item number "1" is not cancelled or rejected, although its price was changed by a supplier. I need to know when an overwrite of the original purchase order line item number in the Invoice Line Item Table occurs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/some-extracted-ariba-invoice-line-item-data-via-procurement-api-does-not/qaq-p/13997887"/>
    <published>2025-01-27T12:53:54.214000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/posting-cxml-invocie-from-postman-with-pdf-attachment-to-sap-ariba/qaq-p/14016482</id>
    <title>Posting CxML Invocie from postman with PDF attachment to SAP Ariba Procurement</title>
    <updated>2025-02-13T19:13:09.579000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMMED_TAMBOLI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491646</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hallo Team&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Greeting!!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I am looking for an inputs how to post cxml invoice with attachment from postman to ariba procurement. I saw the document which is mentioned below&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;-------&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;lt;Attachment&amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;lt;URL&amp;gt;cid:1735239107.1592222922946@cxml.org&amp;lt;/URL&amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;lt;/Attachment&amp;gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;-----&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;How can I encode or create URL with cid&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;URL&amp;gt;cid:1735239107.1592222922946@cxml.org&amp;lt;/URL&amp;gt; to update the cxml payload&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thank you.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/posting-cxml-invocie-from-postman-with-pdf-attachment-to-sap-ariba/qaq-p/14016482"/>
    <published>2025-02-13T19:13:09.579000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/operational-reporting-for-procurement-synchronous-api/qaq-p/14053737</id>
    <title>operational reporting for procurement synchronous api</title>
    <updated>2025-03-23T02:56:48.354000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMMED_TAMBOLI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491646</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hallo Team/Experts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have the base URL for Operational Procurement API&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://openapi.au.cloud.ariba.com/api/procurement-reporting-view/v2/prod" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://openapi.au.cloud.ariba.com/api/procurement-reporting-view/v2/prod&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like frame the URL to fatch present invoice status from Ariba from Jan 2025 to Present. I am not aware to frame the URL for the requirement and need help if anyone can provide input to frame the URL which will be greatful as I am new working with API's.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Still need any additonal information I can provide.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/operational-reporting-for-procurement-synchronous-api/qaq-p/14053737"/>
    <published>2025-03-23T02:56:48.354000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/estricting-invoice-quantity-field-to-whole-numbers-in-sap-b-amp-i/qaq-p/14071569</id>
    <title>estricting Invoice Quantity Field to Whole Numbers in SAP B&amp;I</title>
    <updated>2025-04-09T22:32:56.763000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BinaryMonk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1980968</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I'm new to SAP and currently working with a generic implementation of SAP B&amp;amp;I integrated with our ERP system. I was wondering if there's a way to restrict the &lt;EM&gt;invoice quantity&lt;/EM&gt; field to accept only whole numbers (i.e., integer values).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Any guidance or suggestions would be greatly appreciated!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/estricting-invoice-quantity-field-to-whole-numbers-in-sap-b-amp-i/qaq-p/14071569"/>
    <published>2025-04-09T22:32:56.763000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/report-for-paying-failed-invoices/qaq-p/14091395</id>
    <title>Report for Paying Failed invoices</title>
    <updated>2025-05-01T17:26:56.877000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FheaMaranan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/156424</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We've been monitoring Paying Failed invoices for years already and to get the failed reason, we are opening manually the paying failed invoices one by one. Is there a way that we can capture the list via Analytical Report?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/report-for-paying-failed-invoices/qaq-p/14091395"/>
    <published>2025-05-01T17:26:56.877000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/advance-payment-invoices/qaq-p/14142766</id>
    <title>Advance payment invoices</title>
    <updated>2025-07-02T16:10:11.696000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anastasia80</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1711805</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to know if there is an APP - for SPA 4/H private cloud RISE - to manage the advance payments from customers to usefor italianian company.This APP must consider the advance payments invoices from customers without applying VAT (for customers that they are habitual exporters subject to declaration of intent to the Revenue Agency).The partner propose a custom to manage the advance payment in SD Module, but this custom doesn't maganed the VAT exsemption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anastasia&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/advance-payment-invoices/qaq-p/14142766"/>
    <published>2025-07-02T16:10:11.696000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/digital-certificate-authotication-for-sap-ariba/qaq-p/14149640</id>
    <title>Digital Certificate authotication for SAP Ariba</title>
    <updated>2025-07-10T16:14:40.875000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMMED_TAMBOLI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491646</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hallo Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am looking to post cxml invoice from postman through digital certificate authentication for testing. But the challenge is as per Ariba, the certificate has to be procured from SAP Ariba trusted company. As I am looking for testing purpose, I would like know is there any possible to get digital certificate for testing so that I can test from Postman application and later conclude for procuring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/digital-certificate-authotication-for-sap-ariba/qaq-p/14149640"/>
    <published>2025-07-10T16:14:40.875000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-carbon-copy-invoice-issue/qaq-p/14150549</id>
    <title>Ariba : Carbon copy Invoice issue</title>
    <updated>2025-07-11T18:23:26.975000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dhinesh_thirugnanam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/219203</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a question related to Carbon Copy Invoice for an Indirect PO(PO created from Guided Buying)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Steps:&lt;BR /&gt;1) Supplier creates a OC and ASN&lt;BR /&gt;2) CC invoice is processed in VIM and a Remittance payment is also done.&lt;BR /&gt;3) Remittance record is there in IDOC&lt;BR /&gt;4) In CIG tracker,I could see the Remittance record.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But in SBN ,supplier is not seeing the Invoice reference number for that PO.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My Question:&lt;BR /&gt;1)Once VIM process the record,do we have a IDOC generated for CC invoice?&lt;BR /&gt;2) Do we see any Invoice related record in CIG tracker?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My issue is I am not seeing the Invoice created in SBN for the PO.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any idea what could be the reason&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dhinesh_thirugnanam_0-1752250931501.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285545i9866F1EB4BDC2807/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dhinesh_thirugnanam_0-1752250931501.png" alt="dhinesh_thirugnanam_0-1752250931501.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dhinesh_thirugnanam_1-1752250943081.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285546i38213FEC732AD5CB/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dhinesh_thirugnanam_1-1752250943081.png" alt="dhinesh_thirugnanam_1-1752250943081.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dhinesh_thirugnanam_2-1752250955690.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285547i5EAF1DEEFC0A2B56/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dhinesh_thirugnanam_2-1752250955690.png" alt="dhinesh_thirugnanam_2-1752250955690.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;ERS is showing in Yellow.Where can I check for the reason?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="dhinesh_thirugnanam_0-1752254495498.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/285632i049373529BE01C98/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="dhinesh_thirugnanam_0-1752254495498.png" alt="dhinesh_thirugnanam_0-1752254495498.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-carbon-copy-invoice-issue/qaq-p/14150549"/>
    <published>2025-07-11T18:23:26.975000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/which-api-should-be-used-to-create-an-invoice-and-also-pull-in-trading/qaq-p/14178812</id>
    <title>Which API should be used to create an Invoice and also pull in Trading Partner(VBUND)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-12T16:58:10.210000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>goody-1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/486809</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are trying to use API to pull in details for creating an invoice.&amp;nbsp; Trading Partner is a requirement.&amp;nbsp; Which API can be used that would include Trading Partner(VBUND)?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-q-a/which-api-should-be-used-to-create-an-invoice-and-also-pull-in-trading/qaq-p/14178812"/>
    <published>2025-08-12T16:58:10.210000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-rejection-approval-flow-doesn-t-trigger-on-irs/qaq-p/14226735</id>
    <title>Ariba: Rejection approval flow doesn't trigger on IRs</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T12:17:09.333000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cathykostova</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122333</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Has anyone implemented a specific approval to trigger if someone in the IR approval flow clicks on Reject? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We've turned Application.Invoicing.RejectRequiresNoMoreApprovals to No and we've tried using InvoiceReconciliation.IsForReject and&amp;nbsp;InvoiceReconciliation.cus_MarkforReject&amp;nbsp;on our approval rules to have a specific approval after rejection. When using the testing tab of the IR Approval Flow, we see the wanted behavour.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But on the actual approvable document, unless something else is first changed in the IR, after clicking on Reject, the approval flow is not resubmitted and regenerated as we need it to.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ariba Support suggest to log a customisation request based on what's written at the bottom here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/approval-process-management-guide/default-approval-process-for-invoice-reconciliation-documents-for-credit-memos-6b941434c1da101496f78f16a2c6b546" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/approval-process-management-guide/default-approval-process-for-invoice-reconciliation-documents-for-credit-memos-6b941434c1da101496f78f16a2c6b546&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But this talks about adding an approval group to rejected IR documents without exceptions. In our cases, we have exceptions and that makes no difference. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I'm confused as to what sort of customisation will trigger the resubmit of the approval flow after the Reject button is pushed. If anyone here has enabled such a customisation, could you please describe it?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;thanks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cathy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-rejection-approval-flow-doesn-t-trigger-on-irs/qaq-p/14226735"/>
    <published>2025-09-24T12:17:09.333000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
