<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Analytics-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-10-09T05:00:19.734031+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Analytics Cloud/pd-p/67838200100800006884" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Analytics Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-blog-posts/unlocking-a-cleaner-and-greener-energy-future-with-ai/ba-p/14220956</id>
    <title>Unlocking a Cleaner and Greener Energy Future with AI</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T14:06:33.793000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>parikh_sagar</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/603242</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) mandate rapid clean energy adoption to combat climate change. However, many utilities still face hurdles integrating renewables such as solar, wind, and hydropower into increasingly intelligent, distributed grids. Digital transformation, powered by AI, can enable accurate forecasting, predictive analytics, and IoT-driven self-healing grids, unlocking a sustainable future at scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Gartner projects that by 2027, over 50% of enterprise AI models will be industry-specific, up from about 1% in 2023.&amp;nbsp;For utilities, this shift toward domain-tuned AI accelerates adoption in forecasting, asset performance, and customer operations. IDC’s Utilities predictions and Forrester’s Generative AI outlook similarly point to a pivot from pilot to production, with measured value in core operational use cases&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Use Cases and SAP Utilities Solutions:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced Renewable Forecasting:&lt;/STRONG&gt; AI brings together historical generation, weather, and grid conditions to predict renewable output, enhance grid stability, and optimize dispatch. SAP enablers: SAP Energy Data Management (EDM), SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC), SAP Datasphere for data fabric, and SAP S/4HANA Utilities for integration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent Demand-Side Management:&lt;/STRONG&gt; AI dynamically adjusts loads across sectors - smart appliances, EVs, industrial processes balancing supply and reducing peaks. SAP enablers: SAP Cloud for Utilities, SAP BRIM and SAP Subscription Billing for innovative tariffs, and SAC for optimization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proactive Predictive Maintenance:&lt;/STRONG&gt; AI-driven anomaly detection improves asset reliability and avoids costly outages. SAP enablers: SAP Asset Performance Management (APM), SAP Asset Intelligence Network (AIN), SAP Field Service Management (FSM), and SAP S/4HANA Asset Management.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What are the opportunities of converging AI and SAP Solutions?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reliability &amp;amp; Predictive Maintenance at Scale&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;AI models fuse SCADA, asset history, and condition data to detect anomalies early, optimize spares, and move from time-based to condition-based maintenance - cutting SAIDI/SAIFI and truck rolls.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP enablers:&lt;/U&gt; SAP Asset Performance Management (APM), SAP Field Service Management (FSM), SAP S/4HANA Asset Management, SAP Asset Intelligence Network (AIN), and SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) for predictive insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DER Orchestration, Flexibility &amp;amp; Market Settlement&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Forecasting and dispatching behind-the-meter solar, storage, EVs, and microgrids; forming virtual power plants (VPPs)&amp;nbsp; and optimizing participation in flexibility/ancillary markets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP enablers:&lt;/U&gt; SAP Energy Data Management (EDM) for metering and settlement, SAP Billing and Revenue Innovation Management (BRIM) and SAP Subscription Billing for new tariffs and flexibility services, SAP S/4HANA Utilities for end-to-end customer-to-cash, and SAP Analytics Cloud for forecast optimization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer &amp;amp; Prosumer Experience (CX) and Personalized Energy Services&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Hyper-personalized advisory, usage insights, TOU nudges, EV-smart-charging offers, and prosumer engagement that drive satisfaction and reduce churn.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP enablers:&lt;/U&gt; SAP S/4HANA Utilities, SAP BRIM for complex pricing/bundles, SAP Subscription Billing, SAP Customer Data Platform (CDP), SAP Service Cloud, and SAP Marketing Cloud for tailored engagement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sustainability, Emissions &amp;amp; “Green AI” Operations&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;AI to optimize dispatch, reduce losses, and cut emissions; automated Scope 1–3 tracking and audit-ready reporting; and energy-efficient AI practices to minimize compute footprints.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP enablers:&lt;/U&gt; SAP Sustainability Control Tower (SCT) for KPI governance, SAP Product Footprint Management (PFM) for footprint calculations, SAP Environment, Health, and Safety (EHS) for operational compliance, and SAP Signavio for process redesign.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workforce Productivity, Safety &amp;amp; Knowledge Capture&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;AI copilots for planners/dispatchers; mobile assistants for field technicians (procedures, PPE checks, hazards); automated close-outs and claims; and computer vision for safety observance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP enablers:&lt;/U&gt; SAP Field Service Management (FSM) (mobile work), SAP Asset Performance Management (APM) (procedures &amp;amp; failure modes), SAP EHS (permits/safety), SAP Build Work Zone and SAP Enable Now for just-in-time guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Revenue Innovation &amp;amp; Margin Protection&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;AI-informed margin management (hedging, loss reduction), prosumer/VPP monetization, dynamic pricing, flexibility services, and performance-based programs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP enablers:&lt;/U&gt; SAP BRIM, SAP Subscription Billing, SAP Profitability and Performance Management (PaPM), SAP Analytics Cloud, and SAP Datasphere (data fabric for scenario modeling).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Let's look at the challenges and practical mitigations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Foundations, Quality &amp;amp; Interoperability:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Model performance hinges on clean, timely, connected data across OT (SCADA, AMI, APM) and IT (billing, CRM).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Mitigations with SAP&lt;/U&gt;: Establish a utility data fabric with SAP Datasphere; unify meter/market data via SAP EDM; standardize models in SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP); use SAP Integration Suite for OT/IT connectors; govern with SAP Master Data Governance (MDG).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Risk, Governance &amp;amp; Model Compliance (AI TRiSM/Responsible AI):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Bias, drift, explainability, safety, and regulatory scrutiny (especially for GenAI and automated decisioning).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Mitigations with SAP:&lt;/U&gt; Use SAP BTP with SAP AI Core and AI Launchpad for lifecycle control; log lineage and approvals; embed human-in-the-loop; instrument KPIs in SAC; codify policies in Signavio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cybersecurity &amp;amp; Critical Infrastructure Protection:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Expanded attack surface across DERs, edge devices, mobile crews, and market interfaces; GenAI introduces new vectors (prompt injection, data leakage).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Mitigations with SAP:&lt;/U&gt; Apply least-privilege and policy-based access on SAP BTP; integrate security analytics; segment OT/IT interfaces; harden APIs with SAP Integration Suite; capture end-to-end audit trails.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Compute, Energy Footprint &amp;amp; “Green AI”:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Training/serving advanced models can inflate energy use, potentially conflicting with utility decarbonization goals.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Mitigations with SAP:&lt;/U&gt; Favor smaller, domain-tuned models hosted efficiently on SAP BTP; leverage inference optimization, demand-response scheduling of batch jobs, and carbon-aware routing; track emissions in SAP Sustainability Control Tower and Product Footprint Management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Talent, Change &amp;amp; Operating Model:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;AI value stalls without product-centric teams, MLOps, and business ownership of outcomes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Mitigations with SAP:&lt;/U&gt; Establish an AI value office; use SAP Signavio for process redesign; adopt MLOps on BTP/AI Launchpad; embed copilot-assisted work in SAP FSM and SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Regulatory, Market &amp;amp; Ethical Constraints:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Rate design, model explainability, and consumer data use are under tightening scrutiny.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;U&gt;Mitigations with SAP:&lt;/U&gt; Keep explainability artifacts for decisions (SAC narratives, model cards in AI Launchpad); enforce privacy-by-design with SAP CDP and consent management; maintain audit trails across EDM/BRIM/market processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631757582"&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Conclusion:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt;AI&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT size="3"&gt; is the cornerstone for clean energy transformation. By leveraging SAP’s intelligent utilities solutions and TCS’s innovation, utilities can boost efficiency, integrate renewables, and drive decarbonization. The path to a greener future lies in combining advanced technology with strategic energy management and robust governance. For CXOs, this means making informed, data-driven decisions, ensuring regulatory compliance, and creating sustainable value for customers and shareholders alike. Those who act decisively today will not only navigate the energy transition successfully but also set the benchmark for resilient, future-ready utilities. &lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-for-utilities-blog-posts/unlocking-a-cleaner-and-greener-energy-future-with-ai/ba-p/14220956"/>
    <published>2025-09-19T14:06:33.793000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/basic-tips-for-beginners-in-sap-analytics-cloud-sac-with-bw-live/ba-p/14222816</id>
    <title>Basic Tips for Beginners in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) with BW Live</title>
    <updated>2025-09-20T07:28:43.171000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RajuRao</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/879655</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Beginner Tips for SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) with BW Live Connection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While working in SAC, I faced some common challenges. Here are the problems and how I solved them:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Story and Page Filters with BW Live Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Problem:&lt;/STRONG&gt; I was not sure whether SAC filters process locally or in BW.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Filters always trigger BW to recalculate and send back results. Only cosmetic changes (sort, format, hide columns) happen in SAC.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Scripting – Dynamic Input Handling&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Problem:&lt;/STRONG&gt; When using input fields, numbers were treated as text and gave wrong results in calculations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Convert string to number:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;var numberValue = ConvertUtils.stringToNumber(InputField_1.getValue());&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Debugging Data in a Widget&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Problem:&lt;/STRONG&gt; I could not see what exactly my table widget was holding in the backend.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use ResultSet in script:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; var resultset = Table_1.getDataSource().getResultSet();&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; console.log(resultset);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This showed me all members and values in console.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Performance Issue with Dimensions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Problem:&lt;/STRONG&gt; My story was very slow though I used only few attributes in the widget.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reduced unnecessary attributes in the model → story became faster.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;These are small but practical solutions that helped me when starting SAC development. I hope this helps other beginners too.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/basic-tips-for-beginners-in-sap-analytics-cloud-sac-with-bw-live/ba-p/14222816"/>
    <published>2025-09-20T07:28:43.171000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/build-a-data-driven-enterprise-with-sap-s-data-amp-analytics-advisory/ba-p/14224035</id>
    <title>Build a Data-Driven Enterprise with SAP’s Data &amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T12:01:30.126000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>gauravdey</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183532</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="gauravdey_0-1758534693911.png" style="width: 711px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317823i94654445CE65DF7A/image-dimensions/711x222?v=v2" width="711" height="222" role="button" title="gauravdey_0-1758534693911.png" alt="gauravdey_0-1758534693911.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is SAP BTP Guidance Framework: The Guidance Framework provides clear direction and a structured approach to adopting SAP technologies. With this guidance, you can develop intelligent applications using advanced analytics, equipping your organization with a robust foundation to support agile innovation. For more details read this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-guidance-framework-a-compass-for-architects-developers-and/ba-p/14138635" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog post, we will look into how to build a Data-Driven Enterprise with SAP’s Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology under SAP BTP Guidance Framework. You can find this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/guidance-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; pillar under SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It’s imperative that in today’s economy, data is more than just numbers—it’s the foundation of innovation, strategy, and growth backed by AI. Yet many organizations still struggle to unlock the full potential of their data and give it purpose. SAP’s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; under SAP BTP Guidance Framework offers a structured, four-phase approach that helps enterprises transform raw data into actionable insights while building a strong data-driven culture.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="gauravdey_1-1758534693913.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317822i0ED9A8C45F754BDC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="gauravdey_1-1758534693913.png" alt="gauravdey_1-1758534693913.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Four Phases of SAP’s Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Scoping &amp;amp; Baseline Analysis: In this phase you can&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;set the foundation by:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Defining the scope of investigation across business processes, organizational units, and data domains.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Assessing current data architecture and capabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Identifying gaps, pain points, and opportunities for improvement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit of this phase is that your business will have a&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;clear baseline architecture, capability assessment, and prioritized opportunities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Business Outcomes &amp;amp; Solution Requirements: the focus in this phase shifts to aligning data with measurable business goals such as:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define specific, data-driven business outcomes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analyze use cases that trace how raw data transforms into business value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Identify required data products and map end-to-end integration flows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This phase allows to clearly define business outcome definitions and solution context diagrams.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;3.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Capability Map &amp;amp; Solution Architecture: this phase transforms requirements into a target architecture by:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Developing a capability map using SAP BTP Maturity Assessment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore architecture options through traditional capability mapping or solution diagrams from the SAP Discovery Center.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Validate the preferred architecture with proof-of-concepts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With this phase the target solution architecture is validated through capability mapping and pilots.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;4.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Governance &amp;amp; Roadmaps: this final phase ensures long-term sustainability:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conduct a maturity assessment for data governance and organizational roles.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define roles such as Chief Data Officer, Data Steward, and Governance Manager.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build a roadmap with clear clusters (e.g., implementation, operations, security).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The key benefit of this phase is to define Data governance framework, organizational structure, and a roadmap for execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What makes SAP’s Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology stand out is that it’s not just about technology—it’s about data, people and processes. By integrating governance, roles, and organizational change management, it ensures that data initiatives aren’t just implemented but also adopted across the enterprise. For organizations aiming to thrive in a data-driven economy, SAP’s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; provides more than a roadmap—it delivers a proven framework for turning data into business value and give it purpose. By combining architecture best practices with governance and cultural adoption, it helps enterprises evolve from simply managing data to truly innovating with it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To read more about SAP’s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;check out &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/guidance-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Organizations that adopt this framework position themselves to lead in the AI-driven economy”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Previous blogs in the series:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-ai-best-practices-your-ultimate-guide-for-building-ai-solutions/ba-p/14171864" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP AI Best Practices: Your Ultimate Guide for Building AI Solutions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-discovery-center-expands-and-welcomes-the-sap-btp-guidance-framework/ba-p/14162329" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Discovery Center Expands and Welcomes the SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-developer-s-guide-essential-best-practices-from-setup-to-scale/ba-p/14195253" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP Developer’s Guide: Essential Best Practices from Setup to Scale&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-sap-application-extension-methodology-version-2-4/ba-p/14174737" target="_blank"&gt;Introducing SAP Application Extension Methodology version 2.4&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stay tuned for the next blog post in our ‘Exploring the SAP BTP Guidance Framework’ series!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Technology+Platform/pd-p/73555000100700000172" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1215-1"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Data+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100700003531" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1249-1"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/RISE+with+SAP/pd-p/1e76886f-86ac-4839-9833-8bf95f5eb775" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="29-1"&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Suite/pd-p/673127e5-8a50-46c5-8528-7ea141417160" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1250-1"&gt;SAP Business Suite&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Data+Management/pd-p/b74f6ff6-7d1b-45cb-87ec-03c305c7ffc6" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1283-1"&gt;Data Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/build-a-data-driven-enterprise-with-sap-s-data-amp-analytics-advisory/ba-p/14224035"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T12:01:30.126000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/your-spreadsheet-on-steroids-6-powerful-new-features-for-the-sac-excel-add/ba-p/14224630</id>
    <title>Your Spreadsheet on Steroids: 6 Powerful New Features for the SAC Excel Add-in</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T21:40:30.186000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>N1kh1l</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124370</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;For data analysts and planners, the debate between the flexibility of Microsoft Excel and the governed power of enterprise platforms like SAP Analytics Cloud is a familiar one. Excel offers unparalleled freedom for ad-hoc analysis, while SAC provides a single source of truth, robust security, and collaborative scale. This often creates a clunky workflow, forcing users to manually rebuild analyses as they move between environments.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Recent updates to the SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) add-in for Microsoft Excel are fundamentally changing this dynamic, bridging the gap between these two worlds in powerful and surprising ways. This post highlights four of the most impactful new features that are transforming the add-in from a simple data connector into an indispensable tool for serious analysis and planning.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;1. From Polished Story to Powerful Spreadsheet in a Single Click&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;A significant update in the Q3 / 2025.17 release introduces the ability to transfer a table directly from an SAP Analytics Cloud story into Excel. This isn't just a static copy-paste of values; the transferred table is fully functional within the add-in. It retains the same data source, navigation state (including all dimensions, measures, rows, and columns), filters, and variables that were configured in the story.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This creates an immediate, frictionless pivot from a high-level presentation in a Story to a granular, what-if analysis in Excel. Analysts can now investigate an anomaly they spot in a dashboard without losing a moment of momentum or context rebuilding the query.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Note: You need to migrate your table to the New table experience available from 2025 QRC3 release. The option to open the story in a Excel Add-in needs to be enabled in Table properties in the Builder Panel.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_0-1758567035587.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318181i5C8E87482998B6FA/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_0-1758567035587.png" alt="N1kh1l_0-1758567035587.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;This enables Open in Excel Add-in option in Table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_1-1758567141816.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318182i3E9D3D7B67947986/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_1-1758567141816.png" alt="N1kh1l_1-1758567141816.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Eureka, Story opens in Excel with structure and calculations migrated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_2-1758567306206.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318183iB00D7B0002A4BE0A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_2-1758567306206.png" alt="N1kh1l_2-1758567306206.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2. Your Data Now Has a Voice: In-Cell Conversations Arrive&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The 2025.15 release brings collaboration directly to your data cells with the introduction of data point comments. Users can now view and create comments on specific data cells within their Excel tables. Critically, these comments are fully synchronized with SAP Analytics Cloud, meaning a comment added in Excel is immediately visible in the web application, and vice versa.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;To make this even more powerful, the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP.GETDATACOMMENT&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;formula (introduced in version 2025.17) allows you to retrieve these comments programmatically. If multiple comments exist for a data point, the formula returns the last comment of the thread. This development marks a shift from static reporting to true collaborative analysis. The addition of the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP.GETDATACOMMENT&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;formula elevates these comments from simple annotations to query able metadata. This unlocks the ability to build exception reports, dashboards, or even KPIs based on the presence and content of commentary, creating a powerful new layer of qualitative analysis.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Enable data point comments from the Table Option in Designer Panel&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_3-1758567589816.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318184iCF72295D1573280C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_3-1758567589816.png" alt="N1kh1l_3-1758567589816.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will enable a comment widget to add comments&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_4-1758567773862.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318185i4FFA3250B782A731/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_4-1758567773862.png" alt="N1kh1l_4-1758567773862.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;The comments are in sync and can be viewed in web stories also and vice versa.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;3. Enterprise-Grade Guardrails for Your Planning Spreadsheets&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;For organizations using the add-in for financial planning, the 2025.17 release delivers a crucial governance enhancement. Data Access Controls (DCS) and Validation Rules that are defined in the central SAP Analytics Cloud model are now automatically applied and visualized directly within the Excel add-in.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;This is a critical update because it de-risks the use of Excel for enterprise planning. It allows finance teams to leverage the full flexibility of their preferred tool while ensuring that every input automatically inherits the security, data integrity rules, and governance defined in the central SAC model. The "Wild West" spreadsheet is officially tamed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;4. A Faster, More Intuitive Way to Build Your Analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;A pair of recent user experience enhancements have combined to make the process of building and modifying analyses significantly faster and more intuitive. First, version 2025.13 introduced a resizable builder panel that features a permanent pane listing all available dimensions and measures. This allows for easy browsing and searching of the data source objects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Building on that foundation, version 2025.19 added drag-and-drop functionality. Users can now simply drag objects from the permanent list and drop them into the desired pane (e.g., rows or columns) to build out their table. These&amp;nbsp; updates work together to reduce clicks and streamline the entire analysis design process, letting users get to insights more quickly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_5-1758568798554.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318187iCED6CF6B92DB8847/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_5-1758568798554.png" alt="N1kh1l_5-1758568798554.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;5. Make your sheets colorful&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Now you can add styling and thresholds to your Excel tables. This helps applying corporate colors or creating a more visual appealing layouts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;You can use a list of SAC predefined cell styles or create custom cell styles by duplicating and existing cell styles.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_6-1758569109764.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318189i18B6782C99E760F6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_6-1758569109764.png" alt="N1kh1l_6-1758569109764.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can choose the styling as well as the area of the table layout where it should be applied.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_7-1758569244763.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318190iED9B27D54B3AF3A1/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_7-1758569244763.png" alt="N1kh1l_7-1758569244763.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;6. Create Calculated Measure ( Episode 1 : Restricted Measure support)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The long awaited feature of the ability to create calculated measures for your business calculation is now available also in Excel. As a first feature set, only restricted measures are supported. The steps are very similar to how we define calculations in web story. Currently only value based restrictions are supported ( both dimension and attributes). No support for dynamic restrictions for date dimensions like Current Period, prior Period etc. readily available in web stories. Never the less its a good start and I wish to see the remaining features soon. Both restricted accounts and restricted measures are supported.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_8-1758569572788.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318191i8DB2E570DC228C3D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_8-1758569572788.png" alt="N1kh1l_8-1758569572788.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="N1kh1l_9-1758569674780.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318192iC6515F06B3A7B8E0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="N1kh1l_9-1758569674780.png" alt="N1kh1l_9-1758569674780.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;Already defined Calculations can also be edited if required.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Conclusion: A Final Thought&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The SAP Analytics Cloud add-in for Excel is rapidly evolving. It's moving beyond its origins as a simple data connector to become a fully-featured, collaborative, and secure extension of the core platform. By bringing enterprise governance and modern collaboration features into the familiar grid of a spreadsheet, it offers a powerful new paradigm for analysis and planning.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;With these new capabilities fusing the best of Excel and the cloud, what established workflow are you now ready to rethink?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Thanks for reading. I hope you enjoyed the blog.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check the SAP Analytics Cloud topic page for more up to date information&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/cloud-analytics" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/topics/cloud-analytics&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;follow and read other informative blog posts on SAC browse the below link&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/tags/67838200100800006884/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://blogs.sap.com/tags/67838200100800006884/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Nikhil&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/your-spreadsheet-on-steroids-6-powerful-new-features-for-the-sac-excel-add/ba-p/14224630"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T21:40:30.186000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-from-provisioning-to-intelligent-applications/ba-p/14224669</id>
    <title>SAP Business Data Cloud - From Provisioning to Intelligent Applications</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T23:57:28.150000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hkaur</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83605</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction to SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, we will try to go over the Introduction to SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) and then the Components and Building Blocks of SAP BDC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BDC is a fully managed software-as-a-service (SaaS) offering from SAP designed to address this need of managing vast volumes of data originating from diverse systems. It consolidates and governs all SAP data while seamlessly integrating third-party sources, delivering contextualized, trusted data to business leaders for more impactful decision-making. By harmonizing mission-critical data into a unified semantic layer, the platform eliminates the overhead of data extraction and replication.&amp;nbsp; Supporting a wide range of use cases across industries and business functions, SAP BDC ensures that data is consistently accessible, secure, and ready for advanced analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Aspects of SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Intelligent Applications:&lt;/EM&gt; AI-driven apps that leverage your data and business context to automate processes, adapt dynamically, and drive transformative outcomes in real time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Data Products&lt;/EM&gt;: Prebuilt, customizable, and governed data assets that come enriched with business semantics, documentation, and APIs—accelerating deployment across a wide range of use cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Business Data Fabric&lt;/EM&gt;: A comprehensive data and analytics foundation that integrates SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, modernized SAP Business Warehouse, data engineering capabilities, and AI/ML innovations through SAP Databricks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;AI-Enriched Decision Making:&lt;/EM&gt; Enterprise-grade tools that deliver responsible, context-aware AI for reporting and analytics —empowering smarter, faster decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Components of SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Source Systems:&lt;/EM&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP BDC connects seamlessly to various source systems—such as SAP S/4HANA—to identify and extract key business data entities. These include tables, views, and other structures that contain mission-critical data across domains like HR, finance, supply chain. By integrating with these systems, SAP BDC ensures that foundational business data is readily available for analytics, governance, and intelligent application development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Foundational Services in SAP Business Data Cloud:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Within SAP BDC, data extracted from source systems flows into the Foundation Services layer. This foundational component is responsible for ingesting, integrating, cleansing, and harmonizing both structured and unstructured data. It ensures that the data is properly aligned and enriched as part of SAP-managed Data Products, forming the backbone of trusted, analytics-ready information across the SAP BDC landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Datasphere:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Datasphere serves as the modeling and governance layer atop the BDC Semantic Layer. It provides a robust set of tools for designing analytical data models, defining business logic, managing data lineage, enforcing governance and security.&amp;nbsp;In addition to its core modeling capabilities, SAP Datasphere supports machine learning and AI extensions, making it a foundational component for advanced analytics and intelligent decision-making.&amp;nbsp;Datasphere acts as the data engine behind SAP Analytics Cloud, feeding it with both prebuilt and custom insights for reporting and visualization.&amp;nbsp;It also enables customers to create custom data products using the SAP Datasphere Object Store, which supports zero-copy data access via the Delta Sharing Protocol - ensuring efficient, secure, and scalable data sharing across the enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Databricks:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Databricks is a specialized integration of the Databricks platform embedded directly within SAP BDC. It combines industry-leading capabilities in AI, machine learning, data science, and data engineering with semantically rich, business-ready data from SAP applications.&amp;nbsp;This component significantly enhances analytics by enabling generative AI scenarios—without the need for complex data pipelines. Through zero-copy Delta Sharing, SAP Databricks connects directly to SAP Data Products, allowing seamless access and enrichment of data without replication.&amp;nbsp;By bridging enterprise-grade SAP data with the flexibility of Databricks, organizations can accelerate innovation, streamline operations, and unlock deeper insights across their business landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt; SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/EM&gt; empowers business analytics by directly consuming integrated data from the SAP Datasphere component within BDC. It supports rich visualization, reporting, and AI-driven analytics across the enterprise—all within a unified, cloud-based SaaS environment.&amp;nbsp;By leveraging semantically aligned data from Datasphere, SAC enables organizations to generate actionable insights, build dynamic dashboards, and drive informed decision-making at scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP BW and SAP BW/4HANA Integration:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; To support legacy compatibility, SAP BW and SAP BW/4HANA objects can be technically onboarded into SAP BDC. This integration enables organizations to migrate data and maintain hybrid use cases—bridging traditional data warehousing with modern cloud-based analytics—until the official end-of-support timeline for BW systems.&amp;nbsp;By incorporating BW artifacts into BDC, businesses can preserve existing investments while gradually transitioning to a unified, governed, and AI-ready data landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building Blocks of SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Provisioning an SAP Business Data Cloud Tenant&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An SAP BDC tenant is provisioned via the SAP for Me portal using a guided, self-service workflow. This process enables organizations to activate and configure the components of SAP Business Data Cloud according to their commercial entitlements. The provisioning journey begins with the BDC Core Component or Cockpit, which serves as the central management interface for the entire SAP BDC landscape.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2.png" style="width: 936px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318201i2A1FD77C8913CE6C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.png" alt="2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the BDC cockpit is provisioned, the next step is to provision (from SAP for Me) the core capabilities and applications, including: SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Databricks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="3.png" style="width: 936px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318202iA5701E426BFF6EA2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.png" alt="3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After these systems are successfully provisioned through SAP for Me, users can&amp;nbsp; begin creating Formations—structured configurations that define how data products and applications are orchestrated across the landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Formation in SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A Formation in SAP Business Data Cloud is a logical grouping of SAP systems and related components designed to support specific business scenarios or integration use cases. Formations simplify connectivity and provide a unified view of all systems, making it easier to manage integrations, extensions, and orchestrate data across the SAP BDC landscape.&amp;nbsp; Formations are created by selecting the required SAP systems—these must first be provisioned via the SAP for Me portal. Once provisioned, they appear in the Systems tab of the portal and can be included in one or more formations.&amp;nbsp;Each formation can consist of multiple systems such as SAP BDC Core, SAP S/4HANA Cloud, SAP BW, SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Databricks.&amp;nbsp;These systems are synchronized within the formation to enable streamlined operations and cohesive business processes. Multiple formations can be created to support extended or complex business scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="4.png" style="width: 624px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318203i511CFE0F987849C2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4.png" alt="4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Benefits of Using Formations&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simplified Integration: Centralizes the grouping and management of systems required for a business scenario.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scalability and Flexibility: Easily add or remove systems as organizational needs evolve.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Governance and Control: Enables centralized configuration and oversight, improving compliance and reducing maintenance overhead.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Data Products in Business Data Cloud&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An SAP Data Product is a curated and refined dataset derived from data ingested from SAP solutions. It encompasses a Business Data Set that includes master data, transactional records, analytics datasets, and configuration data—all semantically aligned to ensure consistency and usability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These datasets are enriched with meaningful metadata and documentation, making them easily consumable and understandable. Within the SAP BDC, Data Products serve as the core building blocks for Intelligent Applications, enabling advanced analytics and decision-making.&amp;nbsp; SAP delivers and manages these Data Products as part of its SaaS offering, maintaining full lifecycle ownership. However, customers can customize them to suit specific business needs. Each Data Product includes all necessary artifacts—such as CDS views, connectors, flows, jobs, and lifecycle management tools—required to support its associated use cases within SAP BDC. They are easily discoverable through the SAP BDC product catalog.&amp;nbsp;These products are designed by line-of-business experts to help organizations maximize the value of their data.&amp;nbsp;Types of Data Products&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Primary Data Products: Directly sourced from applications, representing original data from systems like SAP S/4HANA. They are not derived from other data products.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Derived Data Products: Built by SAP using existing datasets or APIs. This offer added value by combining or transforming data from multiple sources.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Custom or Customer Managed Data Products :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;SAP BDC also supports custom data products, which can be curated within SAP Datasphere. These leverage the Datasphere Object Store and Delta Sharing Protocol, enabling zero-copy data access for efficient and secure data sharing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="5.png" style="width: 936px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318204iDAF60D3D21DD512B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.png" alt="5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Intelligent Applications in SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Intelligent Applications are AI-driven, visualization-centric solutions designed to address specific business scenarios. Unlike general-purpose analytics tools, these applications are built with SAP-managed analytical assets and functionalities that deliver value through process, domain, or analytical intelligence. They typically include data products, semantic models, and SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) stories.&amp;nbsp;These applications foster collaboration between analytics and data science teams by providing ready-made dashboards enriched with AI-generated insights. Their embedded business logic and contextual data models eliminate the need for organizations to build complex analytical frameworks from scratch—saving time and resources.&amp;nbsp;The core structure of Intelligent Applications includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAC Stories&lt;/EM&gt;: Serve as the front-end interface, offering rich visualizations tailored to specific analytics use cases.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Datasphere Models and Views&lt;/EM&gt;: Includes the backend logic and data orchestration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Semantic Models and Story Templates&lt;/EM&gt;: Combined to deliver reusable, customizable dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These applications are cataloged within the SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC), making them easy to discover, deploy, and extend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Installation and Customization&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To explore and install Intelligent Applications:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Log in to the SAP BDC Cockpit. Browse the available applications and their documentation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Upon installation, a suite of artifacts is deployed across SAP Datasphere and SAP Analytics Cloud, including Data Products, Replication Flows, Tables and Views, Analytic Models, Roles and Dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Customization Guidelines&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP-managed applications and their dependencies are read-only, but users can copy and adapt components.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC Stories can be duplicated and tailored to meet specific business needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For advanced scenarios, users may replicate and modify the underlying analytic models ( within SAP Datasphere).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Changes to models will affect both the original and copied stories, so version control and impact analysis are recommended.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Key Differentiation between Business Content and Intelligent Applications&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Content provides a set of pre-built models and other artifacts, but customers manage the implementation, configuration and maintenance of these solutions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intelligent Applications are fully managed and curated by SAP and delivered as software-as-a-service designed to cater specific business use cases or scenarios.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="6.png" style="width: 631px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/318206i3E791D381E766A91/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6.png" alt="6.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hope this helps you understand the basics and get started on SAP Business Data Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-from-provisioning-to-intelligent-applications/ba-p/14224669"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T23:57:28.150000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-amp-analytics-p-amp-a-is-an-essential-part-of-sap-business-data/ba-p/14223762</id>
    <title>Planning &amp; Analytics (P&amp;A) is an essential part of SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T16:13:39.184000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>BlazZabukovec</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5083</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In today’s fast-paced business world, the ability to effectively steer and lead an organisation is crucial for achieving strategic goals and maintaining a competitive edge. The capacity to fully harness and derive value from organisational data is key success criteria. However, many companies struggle with data problems (fragmented information, outdated systems, and the challenge of preparing data for emerging technologies like AI).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our blog series will provide valuable insights for decision-makers seeking to harness SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) to enhance operational efficiency, optimise resource allocation, and achieve long-term objectives. By featuring detailed planning &amp;amp; analytics topics, the series will illustrate the transformative impact of SAP BDC in addressing the operational complexities of today’s business environment. The second blog post will summarise key arguments why Planning &amp;amp; Analytics (P&amp;amp;A) is an integral part of SAP BDC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 1: SAP BDC Intelligent Application - Working Capital" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317691iFA916358F2168297/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BlazZabukovec_0-1758526967241.png" alt="Picture 1: SAP BDC Intelligent Application - Working Capital" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 1: SAP BDC Intelligent Application - Working Capital&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;There are several blog posts in the series that will cover advantages of SAP BDC in the context of business steering, so please stay tuned for the upcoming blogs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-in-the-context-of-business/ba-p/14165827" target="_blank"&gt;The value of SAP BDC in the context of business steering&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Analytics is an essential part of SAP BDC &lt;STRONG&gt;(THIS BLOG POST)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Key Planning &amp;amp; Analytics components of SAP BDC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is AI going to “retire” a dashboard?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simulations, a game changer in today’s volatile world&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Extend existing planning scenarios of SAP BPC/BW-IP in SAP BDC&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Real-time steering with LIVE planning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP PaPM - The role of business calculation engine in business steering&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Self – service analytics and real time business steering&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business steering powered by AI agents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leverage data products in the context of planning &amp;amp; forecasting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Introducing AI/ML capabilities by SAP Databricks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BDC is equipped with powerful data management, planning &amp;amp; analytics (P&amp;amp;A), and innovative AI capabilities to tackle all these challenges and P&amp;amp;A is an essential part of SAP BDC. It provides transformative insights, seamless integration, AI augmentation, and enhanced data quality. These capabilities are crucial for effective business decision-making and strategic planning. Here are the key reasons why P&amp;amp;A is vital within SAP BDC:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 2: SAP BDC high level architecture &amp;amp; flows in the context of business steering" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317692iE7A343942B6F2956/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BlazZabukovec_1-1758527062480.jpeg" alt="Picture 2: SAP BDC high level architecture &amp;amp; flows in the context of business steering" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 2: SAP BDC high level architecture &amp;amp; flows in the context of business steering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transformative Insights:&lt;/STRONG&gt; P&amp;amp;A uncovers hidden insights using advanced analytics and planning applications across all lines of business. This capability allows organisations to make informed decisions based on comprehensive data analysis.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless Integration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; It combines SAP and third-party data to unify diverse data sources, enabling comprehensive analysis and a holistic view of business operations. This integration is crucial for maintaining data consistency and accuracy across the enterprise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Augmentation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The integration of business AI, such as SAP’s AI copilot Joule, enhances decision-making by providing augmented insights and predictive capabilities. This helps businesses anticipate future trends and make proactive decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Data Quality:&lt;/STRONG&gt; P&amp;amp;A automatically connects data across the business, ensuring accuracy and accelerating time to insight. This is essential for maintaining high data quality and reliability in business processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Agile Modelling and Predictive Analysis:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Planning &amp;amp; Analytics supports agile data modelling aligned with analytics. It uses AI and machine learning to facilitate predictive analysis and simulation, enabling businesses to adapt quickly to changing conditions and optimise their strategies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;End-to-End Visibility:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Planning &amp;amp; Analytics offers a 360-degree view of critical business processes with fully-managed, curated data products. This comprehensive visibility and control over operations provide businesses with a clear understanding of their performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture 3: SAP BDC - AI-powered Live-Planning &amp;amp; Analytics in SAP BDC" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317693iCEBDB91779D8513F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="BlazZabukovec_2-1758527062490.jpeg" alt="Picture 3: SAP BDC - AI-powered Live-Planning &amp;amp; Analytics in SAP BDC" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 3: SAP BDC - AI-powered Live-Planning &amp;amp; Analytics in SAP BDC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Analytics is an essential part of SAP BDC, empowering organisations with the tools and insights needed to drive strategic initiatives, improve efficiency, and enhance decision-making across the enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The usage of Planning &amp;amp; Analytics (P&amp;amp;A) is therefore closely connected to the performance of an organisation and creation of business value through several key mechanisms that enhance decision-making, efficiency, and strategic alignment. Here’s how P&amp;amp;A impacts organisational performance:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-Time Insights:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The ability to access real-time data and insights allows organisations to respond quickly to market changes and operational challenges. This agility is crucial for maintaining competitive advantage and optimising performance, especially in turbulent times like today.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strategic Alignment:&lt;/STRONG&gt; By aligning financial and operational plans with strategic objectives, P&amp;amp;A ensures that all parts of the organisation are working towards common goals. This alignment is critical for achieving long-term success and improving overall performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data-Driven Decision Making: &lt;/STRONG&gt;P&amp;amp;A tools provide a single source of truth for data, reducing the need for manual reconciliation and enabling more accurate and timely decision-making. This shift from manual processes to automated data integration enhances efficiency and reduces errors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved Forecasting Accuracy:&lt;/STRONG&gt; P&amp;amp;A tools, such as SAP Analytics Cloud, enable organisations to conduct predictive forecasting and scenario planning. This improves the accuracy of financial and operational forecasts, providing a forward-looking view of performance. This allows leaders to react promptly, leading to better resource allocation, strategic planning, and improved performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Collaboration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; By integrating planning processes across different departments, such as HR and finance, P&amp;amp;A fosters collaboration and alignment within the organisation. This integration helps create a unified approach to achieving business goals and improves communication across teams.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Increased Efficiency: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Automation of planning processes reduces the time and effort required for data collection and analysis, allowing employees to focus on higher-value tasks such as strategic analysis and decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, Planning &amp;amp; Analytics enhances organisational performance by improving forecasting accuracy, fostering collaboration, providing real-time insights, enabling data-driven forward looking decision-making, ensuring strategic alignment, and increasing efficiency. These benefits collectively contribute to a more agile, informed, and strategically aligned organisation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do you want to embark on a journey? Please reach out to your SAP representative and register for your SAP BDC Discovery Workshop!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In our next blog post,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7476"&gt;@Nektarios_Vasileiou33&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; will take you behind the scenes to&amp;nbsp;unbox the &lt;STRONG&gt;key Planning &amp;amp; Analytics components of SAP BDC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;— solutions that help businesses streamline planning, enhance decision-making, and foster cross-department collaboration. By exploring SAP BDC capabilities, you’ll see how they drive more effective enterprise planning and analysis. Get ready for insights that unlock &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;sharper strategies and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;smarter decisions. Stay tuned!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-amp-analytics-p-amp-a-is-an-essential-part-of-sap-business-data/ba-p/14223762"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T16:13:39.184000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/saml-sso-configuration-in-sap-analytics-cloud-sac/ba-p/14217526</id>
    <title>SAML SSO configuration in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T13:22:10.473000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>fidan_karimovaa</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/893204</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760121380"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Configure SAML on SAP Analytics Cloud Tenant Using IAS as a Custom IDP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With &lt;STRONG&gt;SAML 2.0 Single Sign-On (SSO)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you can simplify authentication for your &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; users while improving security and reducing password fatigue. By integrating SAC with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Identity Authentication Service (IAS)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(or any other identity provider) as a custom Identity Provider (IdP), you gain centralized control over user access and streamline the login experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this guide, we’ll walk through the process of setting up SAML-based SSO step-by-step — &lt;STRONG&gt;from prerequisites to verification&lt;/STRONG&gt; — ensuring a smooth configuration process for administrators.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563607875"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What You’ll Learn&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This guide is divided into three main sections:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Everything you need to prepare before starting the configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step-by-Step Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Detailed steps to set up SAML SSO between SAC and IAS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Verification and Go-Live&lt;/STRONG&gt; – How to verify and finalize your configuration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Troubleshooting&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;–&amp;nbsp;Common issues, tips, and SAP Knowledge Base Articles (KBAs) to help you quickly resolve errors during or after setup.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;By the end, you’ll have a fully functional SAML-based authentication setup, ready for production.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367094370"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuring SAML SSO with IAS&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow these steps carefully to configure SAML authentication for your SAC tenant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Before you begin, make sure the following requirements are met.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt; for SAC configuration:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You must have an IdP that supports SAML 2.0 protocol.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You must be able to configure your IdP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You must be assigned to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;System Owner&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;role in&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;. For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/e61ce06c6bb2428eb649fb6ccba73c79.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=release" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Standard Application Roles&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;can be hosted either on SAP data centers or on non-SAP data centers. Determine which environment&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;is hosted in by inspecting your&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;URL:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A single-digit number, for example us1 or jp1, indicates an SAP data center.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A two-digit number, for example eu10 or us30, indicates a non-SAP data center.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If your users are connecting from Apple devices using the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;mobile app, the certificate used by your IdP must be compatible with Apple's App Transport Security (ATS) feature.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Follow help page to enable SAML SSO : &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/3651184dad944aa2b361ad029a7a8cae.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enable a Custom SAML Identity Provider (Legacy Custom IdP)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1299663584"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configuration steps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;1. Login to SAP Analytics Cloud tenant as &lt;U&gt;System Owner&lt;/U&gt; with Default IDP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture1.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314537i0CE11F569E18F618/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="Picture1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;2. Navigate to &lt;STRONG&gt;“&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;System -&amp;gt; Administration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;”.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Picture2.png" style="width: 576px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314538iEBE52A82FF4E0613/image-dimensions/576x321?v=v2" width="576" height="321" role="button" title="Picture2.png" alt="Picture2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;3. From &lt;STRONG&gt;“&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Administration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; tab switch to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Security&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; page, click on Edit button on the right corner and switch to SAML Single Sign-on SSO from SAP Cloud Identity (default).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture3.png" style="width: 775px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314539iE6C3960C5C624B3E/image-dimensions/775x313?v=v2" width="775" height="313" role="button" title="Picture3.png" alt="Picture3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;4. Download metadata file mentioned under Step 1 “Download Service Provider metadata” in SAC and save it to your local machine.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. Upload the&amp;nbsp;SAP Analytics Cloud&amp;nbsp;metadata file to your SAML IdP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;To complete this step, you will need to login to Cloud Identity Provisioning Services (IAS) and navigate to the following path “Applications &amp;amp; Resources -&amp;gt; Application -&amp;gt; Select your IAS application -&amp;gt; SAML 2.0 Configuration”. Under “Define from Metadata” section click on Browse and upload the metadata file which was downloaded from SAC in step 3 above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture4.png" style="width: 768px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314540iD3983874DAB88B70/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture4.png" alt="Picture4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;6.&amp;nbsp; Map your SAML IdP user attributes and roles&lt;STRONG&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;After SAC metadata has been uploaded into IAS, navigate to &lt;SPAN&gt;“Applications &amp;amp; Resources -&amp;gt; Application -&amp;gt; Select your IAS application -&amp;gt; Attributes”&amp;nbsp; and configure SAML mapping as it is defined in step 7 in help page&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/3651184dad944aa2b361ad029a7a8cae.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enable a Custom SAML Identity Provider.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; - For SAML attributes to be recognized it is also important that the &lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;“Groups”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt; attribute contains the value of &lt;STRONG&gt;“sac''&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Picture5.png" style="width: 585px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314542iAF5753BF2015BC21/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture5.png" alt="Picture5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;7. In IAS, navigate to Tenant Settings tab under&lt;STRONG&gt; ''Application &amp;amp; Resources.''&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Under Single Sign-on section, click on SAML 2.0 Configuration tab, and download metadata file from there.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="fidan_karimovaa_5-1757937626974.png" style="width: 583px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314514iDD775EAF2B27A07E/image-dimensions/583x502?v=v2" width="583" height="502" role="button" title="fidan_karimovaa_5-1757937626974.png" alt="fidan_karimovaa_5-1757937626974.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="fidan_karimovaa_6-1757937626975.png" style="width: 650px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314515i50218E9C30FA0129/image-dimensions/650x310?v=v2" width="650" height="310" role="button" title="fidan_karimovaa_6-1757937626975.png" alt="fidan_karimovaa_6-1757937626975.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Switch back to SAC tenant and continue &lt;U&gt;Step 2 “Upload Identity Provider metadata”&lt;/U&gt;, upload the metadata file there.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;8. Now we need to define User Attribute in Step 3 “Choose a user attribute to map to your identity provider” in SAC. It should map to User ID, Email, or a custom attribute. You can view your SAP Analytics Cloud user attributes in Security Users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="fidan_karimovaa_7-1757937626978.png" style="width: 651px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314516i16CC10F5F2EE7DB6/image-dimensions/651x299?v=v2" width="651" height="299" role="button" title="fidan_karimovaa_7-1757937626978.png" alt="fidan_karimovaa_7-1757937626978.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The attribute will be used to map users from your Custom IDP (in this case IAS)&amp;nbsp; to SAP Analytics Cloud. The user attribute you select must match the NameID (Subject Name Identifier) used in your custom SAML assertion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;In IAS tenant navigate to “Applications &amp;amp; Resources -&amp;gt; Application -&amp;gt; Select your IAS application -&amp;gt; Subject Name Identifier” and select same User Attribute for&amp;nbsp; “Select a basic attribute”, which was defined in SAP Analytics Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="fidan_karimovaa_8-1757937626984.png" style="width: 773px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314517i7134A2BF57745695/image-dimensions/773x471?v=v2" width="773" height="471" role="button" title="fidan_karimovaa_8-1757937626984.png" alt="fidan_karimovaa_8-1757937626984.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="fidan_karimovaa_9-1757937626986.png" style="width: 733px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314519iE1916113EA087568/image-dimensions/733x115?v=v2" width="733" height="115" role="button" title="fidan_karimovaa_9-1757937626986.png" alt="fidan_karimovaa_9-1757937626986.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;9. In&amp;nbsp;Step 4, enter&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;lt;Your Unique Identifier&amp;gt;&lt;/EM&gt;. This value must identify the&amp;nbsp;SAP Analytics Cloud&amp;nbsp;system owner. The&amp;nbsp;Login Credential&amp;nbsp;provided here will be automatically set for your user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="fidan_karimovaa_10-1757937626986.png" style="width: 736px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314518iE7C5A73ABA4E4B35/image-dimensions/736x90?v=v2" width="736" height="90" role="button" title="fidan_karimovaa_10-1757937626986.png" alt="fidan_karimovaa_10-1757937626986.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Which means if attribute is set to email in step 3, then System Owner’s email should be defined in step 4 as per screenshot below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="fidan_karimovaa_11-1757937626990.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314520i878EA484A57C24D6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="fidan_karimovaa_11-1757937626990.png" alt="fidan_karimovaa_11-1757937626990.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;10. After above steps have been completed, click on “Verify Account”. You can copy the URL by selecting&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Copy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please Note that:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You must use a &lt;U&gt;private session (Incognito)&lt;/U&gt; to log onto the URL; for example, Guest mode in Chrome. This ensures that when you log on to the dialog and select&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/SPAN&gt;, you are prompted to log in and do not reuse an existing browser session.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="fidan_karimovaa_13-1757937626992.png" style="width: 650px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314522i1DCE978856FD013D/image-dimensions/650x381?v=v2" width="650" height="381" role="button" title="fidan_karimovaa_13-1757937626992.png" alt="fidan_karimovaa_13-1757937626992.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;11. In the&amp;nbsp;Verify Your Account&amp;nbsp;dialog, select&amp;nbsp;Check Verification. If the verification was successful, a green border should appear around the&amp;nbsp;Login Credential&amp;nbsp;box.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="fidan_karimovaa_14-1757937626993.png" style="width: 689px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314523iFAA056D00F66DFE9/image-dimensions/689x314?v=v2" width="689" height="314" role="button" title="fidan_karimovaa_14-1757937626993.png" alt="fidan_karimovaa_14-1757937626993.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;12. After verification was successful, click on save and conversion to SAML SSO should be completed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;By following all these steps, we have successfully configured SAML SSO on SAP Analytics Cloud tenant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="HowToEnableSAMLSSOwithIASasCustomIdP-WhatisIdentityProviderAdministrationTool?" id="toc-hId-974067360"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is Identity Provider Administration Tool?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Identity Provider Administration tool allows system owners to manage the custom identity provider configured with&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;. Through the tool, the system owner can choose to upload new metadata for the current custom identity provider or revert to using the default identity provider.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can read more about this tool here:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/8eba80371d744a3abe145583d707d81a.html?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Access the Identity Provider Administration Tool&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="HowToEnableSAMLSSOwithIASasCustomIdP-Howtoaccess/useIdentityProviderAdministrationTool?" id="toc-hId-777553855"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to access/use Identity Provider Administration Tool?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following, we’ll use Identity Provider Administration tool can be used to update metadata from custom IDP and how to revert &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tenant back to default IDP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pre-requisites:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) must&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;already be configured to use a custom identity provider.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You must be the system owner.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Procedure&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Log in with an S-user that has the same email address as the system owner of your system. If you don't yet have such an S-user, you can click the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Register”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;button and create a S-user.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;If you create a new S-user, you'll receive an email with an activation link that will let you set your password.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Access the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Identity Provider Administration&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;tool using the following URL pattern:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://console.&amp;lt;data&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;center&amp;gt;.sapanalytics.cloud/idp-admin/&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, if your&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt; system is on&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;eu10&lt;/STRONG&gt;, then the URL is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://console/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://console&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;STRONG&gt;eu10&lt;/STRONG&gt;.sapanalytics.cloud/idp-admin/&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt; system is on cn1, then the URL is:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://console.cn1.sapanalyticscloud.cn/idp-admin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://console.cn1.sapanalyticscloud.cn/idp-admin/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If your tenant is on EUDP:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://console-eudp.eu1.sapanalytics.cloud/idp-admin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://console-eudp.eu1.sapanalytics.cloud/idp-admin/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://console-eudp.eu2.sapanalytics.cloud/idp-admin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://console-eudp.eu2.sapanalytics.cloud/idp-admin/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once you're logged in, you'll see a list of&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;systems for which you are the system owner.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-8-9_15-9-23-1.png" style="width: 713px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314547i0D67C566469A6F1D/image-dimensions/713x300?v=v2" width="713" height="300" role="button" title="image-2024-8-9_15-9-23-1.png" alt="image-2024-8-9_15-9-23-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the system you want to work on by clicking on its row.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Once you're in the settings page for your system, you can see information about your current custom identity provider. If you need to reacquire your system's metadata, you can click the&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;“Service Provider Metadata Download”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-8-9_15-9-44-1.png" style="width: 568px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314579i688CD36B50CFD718/image-dimensions/568x338?v=v2" width="568" height="338" role="button" title="image-2024-8-9_15-9-44-1.png" alt="image-2024-8-9_15-9-44-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you don't want to manage your custom identity provider through Identity Provider Administration, you can disconnect your system by clicking&lt;U&gt;&amp;nbsp;“Disconnect IdP Admin from your system”.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To proceed with either reverting to the default identity provider or updating the current custom identity provider, select the corresponding radio button and then click&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Step 2”&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;(Optional) Revert to the default identity provider.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choose this option if you're having problems logging in with your custom identity provider and would like to revert to the default identity provider. Once the reversion has finished, you can exit the Identity Provider Administration tool and log in to your&amp;nbsp;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) to reconfigure your custom identity provider.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the “Revert to default IdP” radio button to revert to the default IdP.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-8-9_15-15-43-1.png" style="width: 969px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314578iCE381BBAD56F5352/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image-2024-8-9_15-15-43-1.png" alt="image-2024-8-9_15-15-43-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select&amp;nbsp;“Yes”&amp;nbsp;in the confirmation dialog to revert your authentication method back to the default IdP.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-8-9_15-16-6-1 (1).png" style="width: 732px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314593iA363F5A7CDD386A2/image-dimensions/732x444?v=v2" width="732" height="444" role="button" title="image-2024-8-9_15-16-6-1 (1).png" alt="image-2024-8-9_15-16-6-1 (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click “Step 3” to proceed to the validation step.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-8-9_15-16-27-1.png" style="width: 739px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317973iFCE59473DCABC405/image-dimensions/739x427?v=v2" width="739" height="427" role="button" title="image-2024-8-9_15-16-27-1.png" alt="image-2024-8-9_15-16-27-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt; &lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To re-upload the metadata file, use “Update IdP Metadata” button.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;On step 2, when prompted, browse for new metadata file and re-upload it.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-8-9_15-19-45-1.png" style="width: 762px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314560i271E3E29FDCC4280/image-dimensions/762x434?v=v2" width="762" height="434" role="button" title="image-2024-8-9_15-19-45-1.png" alt="image-2024-8-9_15-19-45-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Relevant KBA:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://i7p.wdf.sap.corp/sap/support/notes/2908073" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;2908073 - How to use the IdP Admin Tool to make changes to IdP Configuration in SAP Analytics Cloud when no access is available to the tenant&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/2975954" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2975954&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Implement multiple Identity Providers (IdP) in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="HowToEnableSAMLSSOwithIASasCustomIdP-Troubleshooting" id="toc-hId-581040350"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;If there is any issue/error that comes up when trying to login or when configuring SAML/SSO within SAC, please make sure following is configured correctly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Correct Metadata is uploaded within SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) from custom IDP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Certificate is not expired within Metadata.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Correct “NameID” is passed from Custom IDP to SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If email is used as NameID, make sure the case matches between custom IDP and SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If User ID is used as NameID, make sure it’s all in Capitals&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;During configuring SAML within SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) make sure to run verifying URL within INCOGNITO Browser window.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example&lt;/STRONG&gt;: After configuring SAML within SAC Users are not able to login and are getting errors:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-8-9_15-21-5-1.png" style="width: 686px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314590iB2773BC678B83C52/image-dimensions/686x369?v=v2" width="686" height="369" role="button" title="image-2024-8-9_15-21-5-1.png" alt="image-2024-8-9_15-21-5-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-8-9_15-21-19-1.png" style="width: 725px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314581iD70FE1695B5FFE40/image-dimensions/725x133?v=v2" width="725" height="133" role="button" title="image-2024-8-9_15-21-19-1.png" alt="image-2024-8-9_15-21-19-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;To debug the above error message, please do the steps below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Collect SAML traces as per KB&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2461862" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2461862 - Collecting SAML traces with Chrome, Edge or Firefox&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open SAML Trace file (.json) within SAML Tracer tool, using “Import” button&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Once opened look for calls with SAML Tags&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select “POST” call with SAML Tag and make sure all the required attributes are passed and in correct format. Pay attention to “NameID” and that it’s in correct format.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-8-9_15-23-31-1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314582i3C05F2BE16AB54AE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image-2024-8-9_15-23-31-1.png" alt="image-2024-8-9_15-23-31-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image-2024-8-9_15-23-40-1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/314583iA96288B6533F6656/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image-2024-8-9_15-23-40-1.png" alt="image-2024-8-9_15-23-40-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the above example trace you can see that there is no&lt;STRONG&gt; “Groups”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; attribute is passed and therefore User is not able to login.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Another point which can be checked is the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;1. To ensure the NameID attributes are matching between the 2 applications you may use the following URL:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://%3Csystem-name%3E.authentication.%3Clandscape%3E.hana.ondemand.com/config?action=who&amp;amp;details=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://&amp;lt;system-name&amp;gt;.authentication.&amp;lt;landscape&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand.com/config?action=who&amp;amp;details=true&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;2. Run the URL in &lt;STRONG&gt;an incognito browser session&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. It should redirect to the logon page of the Custom IdP (in this case, IAS) linked to the SAC tenant. After successful logon via the IdP credentials, look for UserName and ExternalId fields.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;U&gt;ExternalId&lt;/U&gt; - The value that the IdP forwards towards SAC as Subject Name Identifier (Name ID)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;UserName - The value that is actually being compared to the SAC SAML attribute. This is due to one of the HANA services caching the value of ExternalID and storing it as UserName for faster authentication.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;3. If UserName is not matching the SAC SAML attribute - authentication should fail.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;NameID should be changed to ensure match between the 2 applications. If userName and SAC SAML attribute is matching - authentication should be successful&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-384526845"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Integrating &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Identity Authentication Service&lt;/STRONG&gt; using &lt;STRONG&gt;SAML SSO&lt;/STRONG&gt; brings a host of benefits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Centralized authentication management&lt;/STRONG&gt; across systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced security&lt;/STRONG&gt; through standardized protocols.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved user experience&lt;/STRONG&gt; with seamless, passwordless access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;By following this step-by-step guide, you’ve successfully configured a robust and secure SAML connection between SAC and IAS. Your users can now enjoy a &lt;STRONG&gt;simplified login experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;, while you maintain full control over authentication and role management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Relevant KBAs: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2487567" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2487567 - Troubleshooting SAML assertions when configuring SAML SSO in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2922448" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2922448 - SAML Attribute Mapping in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) &amp;amp; SAP Digital Boardroom Master KBA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2908073" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2908073 - How to use the IdP Admin Tool to make changes to IdP Configuration in SAP Analytics Cloud when no access is available to the tenant&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2879161" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2879161 - How to update the SAML IdP Signing Certificate or Metadata.xml in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/saml-sso-configuration-in-sap-analytics-cloud-sac/ba-p/14217526"/>
    <published>2025-09-24T13:22:10.473000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/unsupported-features-with-sap-datasphere-live-connections-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14228053</id>
    <title>Unsupported Features with SAP Datasphere Live Connections in SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T12:53:10.600000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kartheekkkota</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/227849</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Cloud folks,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to share some of the information that i searched for..&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I faced lot of question after implementing SAC Stories on Live connection and this article helps to them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;when working with an SAC live connection to SAP Datasphere, you experience certain product limitations in SAC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In general, any SAP Datasphere system can be connected to any SAC system via the SAP Datasphere live connection in SAC.&lt;BR /&gt;Live connections between SAC and SAP Datasphere can be established across tenants . When using the SAC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;– Datasphere live connection, We can build SAC stories or analytical applications that, at the same time, use data from a SAP&lt;BR /&gt;Datasphere space, multiple SAP Datasphere spaces, multiple SAP Datasphere spaces in multiple SAP Dataspheres as well as&lt;BR /&gt;any additional data sources that you have connected to SAC&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When using the SAC – Datasphere live connection, SAC currently has the following product limitations:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Below are the list of&amp;nbsp; features that are not supported&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Custom Shapes for Geo Maps are not supported&lt;BR /&gt;Version based variance features are not supported on SAP Datasphere data.&lt;BR /&gt;Version Mapping is not supported for SAP Datasphere data.&lt;BR /&gt;Blending is not supported.&lt;BR /&gt;Scheduling a Publication is not supported on SAP Datasphere data.&lt;BR /&gt;Linked Dimension is only supported for SAP Datasphere models from the same Space. It is not supported across Spaces.&lt;BR /&gt;R-Visualizations are not supported. Note: you can vote for this enhancement request here.&lt;BR /&gt;Comment Widgets are not supported&lt;BR /&gt;Copy Widgets between stories is not supported&lt;BR /&gt;Import Pages from Stories that contain Datasphere models is not supported&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;JustAsk :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;On-the-fly search with Datasphere models is supported.&lt;BR /&gt;Indexing Datasphere models in SAC JustAsk is not supported.&lt;BR /&gt;Open in Data Analyzer is not supported&lt;BR /&gt;Copy widget to Story is not supported&lt;BR /&gt;Stories in Classic Experience&lt;BR /&gt;Blending is supported for the following scenarios&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Datasphere data with local SAC data&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Datasphere data with SAP Datasphere data from the same Datasphere space.&lt;BR /&gt;Blending information across Datasphere spaces, or across Datasphere tenants, or blending of Datasphere data with&lt;BR /&gt;other Live Connections is not supported.&lt;BR /&gt;Using Hyperlinks with the option "Apply selected dimension as filter" enabled across Stories using SAP Datasphere Live&lt;BR /&gt;Connections is not supported.&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Datasphere Analytic models are not supported&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere Data Types&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The following SAP Datasphere Data types are currently not supported in SAP Analytics Cloud:&lt;BR /&gt;Bigint&lt;BR /&gt;Binary&lt;BR /&gt;hana.binary&lt;BR /&gt;Large Binary&lt;BR /&gt;Large String&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAC Planning data can now be stored in Datasphere with seamless planning However, planning&lt;BR /&gt;still requires the &lt;STRONG&gt;import of data into the SAC model&lt;/STRONG&gt; and is &lt;STRONG&gt;not based on the SAP Datasphere live connection&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Smart Insights are not supported on SAP Datasphere data. .&lt;BR /&gt;Smart Discovery is not supported on SAP Datasphere data.&lt;BR /&gt;Smart Predict is not supported on SAP Datasphere data.&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Digital Boardroom&lt;BR /&gt;Stories built on top of SAP Datasphere live data are not supported in SAP Digital Boardroom.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kartheek Kota&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Reference:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2832606" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/2832606&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/unsupported-features-with-sap-datasphere-live-connections-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14228053"/>
    <published>2025-09-26T12:53:10.600000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-sap-analytics-cloud-best-practices-and-performance/ba-p/14229397</id>
    <title>Optimizing SAP Analytics Cloud – Best Practices and Performance</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T21:21:21.678000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hkaur</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83605</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) offers powerful capabilities for planning, analytics, and business intelligence—all in one unified platform. But to truly unlock its potential, it's essential to follow best practices that ensure optimal performance, scalability, and maintainability.&amp;nbsp;In this blog, we’ll explore some of the insights and recommendations across four key pillars of SAC:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics &amp;amp; Planning Modeling:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Structuring your models for flexibility, performance, and future growth.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculations:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Designing efficient formulas and leveraging SAC’s calculation engine wisely.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Automating planning workflows with precision and minimal overhead.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Story Building:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Crafting intuitive, responsive, and insightful dashboards that drive decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Performance Considerations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Performance in SAC isn’t a post-implementation concern—it must be a core priority from the very beginning of your project. Striking the right balance between rich functionality and responsive performance is essential. While functional requirements drive business value, they must be matched by a system that performs reliably and efficiently. Performance optimization touches every layer of your SAC solution: from backend data architecture and model design to story layout, user concurrency, and even device and network configurations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Model Design&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Model Scope:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Clearly define the model’s scope, type (planning or analytics), required metrics, and data granularity based on business objectives. This clarity prevents over engineering and ensures alignment with user needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reusability:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Build modular models that can be reused across multiple stories and planning scenarios. Reusability reduces duplication, simplifies maintenance, and accelerates development cycles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lean Model Structure:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Key performance drivers include the number of measures, dimensions, hierarchies, and members per dimension. Reducing unnecessary dimensions and avoiding overly complex hierarchies directly improves query performance and system responsiveness. Focus on dimensions that are essential for data collection. Attributes such as geographic area or gender can often be derived rather than modeled as standalone dimensions. Evaluate whether static dimensions can be converted into attributes, and consider splitting large models into smaller, purpose-driven ones. Simpler models are easier to maintain, faster to calculate, and more memory efficient. Avoid adding dimensions or calculations unless they deliver clear business value.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understanding Model Types:&lt;/STRONG&gt; From a performance perspective, Analytic Models connected to live data sources place minimal demand on SAC infrastructure, as most of the processing load is handled by the source system itself. In contrast, Analytic Models using acquired data rely on the embedded HANA database, primarily for read operations. While this does introduce some system load, it tends to be moderate and more CPU-intensive than memory-intensive. Planning Models with acquired data, however, offer richer functionality but come with higher resource requirements—impacting both CPU and memory. Their performance is heavily influenced by model design factors such as the number of exception aggregations, the complexity and volume of dimensions, and the breadth of the user’s security context during data entry operations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Additional performance-critical factors include the number of &lt;STRONG&gt;concurrent users&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the volume and structure of the &lt;STRONG&gt;data&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and the frequency and complexity of &lt;STRONG&gt;scheduled jobs&lt;/STRONG&gt; or data actions also play a significant role in determining system responsiveness and scalability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Measure Based Model:&lt;/STRONG&gt; When designing models in SAC, opting for a Measure-Based Model is highly recommended due to its significant advantages in performance, calculation flexibility, and overall modeling efficiency.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Performance &amp;amp; Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Measure-based models are optimized for faster processing and reduced complexity, especially in large-scale planning scenarios.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Flexible Structure:&lt;/STRONG&gt; These models support both accounts and measures, with the account dimension now optional giving you greater design freedom.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reusable Calculations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: You can define base measure calculations that simplify logic reuse across stories and planning workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced Aggregation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Measures can be aggregated more efficiently, improving responsiveness and reducing load times.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expanded Data Type Support&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Measure-based models accommodate a wider range of data types, enhancing versatility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multi-Currency Planning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; With base currency measures, currency conversion becomes seamless, enabling planning across multiple currencies with ease.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dimension Design&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leverage Public Dimensions:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use the Public Dimension feature to manage master data independently, allowing for centralized updates and reuse across models. Avoid importing all source system tables—focus only on dimensions relevant to data entry and planning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dimension hierarchies and members:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Deep hierarchies can be resource intensive. Limit the number of levels to reduce complexity and improve query performance. Keep the number of members in each dimension—including the Account dimension—lean. Import only valid members and apply filters to exclude irrelevant data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date Dimension:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use SAC’s standard date dimension with SAP-managed hierarchies (Year–Quarter–Month–Day) to minimize performance impact.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning Area&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;planning area&lt;/STRONG&gt; defines the specific slice of data within a model that end users can interact with—whether through stories or data actions. When users plan on a public version in a story, SAC automatically creates an &lt;STRONG&gt;implicit private version&lt;/STRONG&gt; behind the scenes. This version isn’t visible to the user but introduces system overhead, especially in models with large datasets or when multiple users are editing simultaneously. To mitigate this, it’s crucial to &lt;STRONG&gt;explicitly define the planning area&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in the model settings and enable it within the story. Doing so significantly reduces resource consumption during public version edits. Key recommendations include:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure a Targeted Planning Area&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Set a focused scope based on business needs, using data access control, data locking, or both to restrict editable data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Avoid Full Dataset Scope&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Limiting the planning area prevents unnecessary data loading and improves performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Data Access Control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;(DAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Define which users can write to specific dimensions—such as company codes or profit centers—to ensure secure and relevant access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apply Data Locking&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Protect actuals from being overwritten by locking them from edits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable Dynamic Planning Area&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Set “Auto-generate based on table context” as the default. This allows the planning area to adjust automatically based on filters, story context, or table layout—ensuring users only load what they need.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAC Planning Best Practices &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Unbooked Data selectively&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Enable unbooked data only when necessary—typically for planning use cases. Since it triggers resource-intensive backend queries, it's best disabled for reporting scenarios to preserve performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implement DAC:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Always activate DAC on relevant dimensions to enforce row-level security. This ensures users only see and interact with data within their authorized scope, reducing system load during public version edits. DAC should be configured during the model design phase. DAC can be turned ON in the Model Dimension through the Read/Write Property or the Data Access Filter in Role by turning the Model Data Privacy ON so DAC can be combined with role-based restrictions. Use DAC primarily on planning-relevant dimensions (E.g. Cost Center, Profit Center, Region), not on all dimensions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Complement with Data Locks :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;While DAC governs who can read/write data, Data Locks control when data can be modified (e.g., freezing approved budgets). This combination enhances performance, especially in multi-user environments. Minimize driving dimensions when using data locking to reduce overhead.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define Validation Rules:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ensure users can only edit valid combinations of dimension members. This is particularly important for models with large dimension tables and helps maintain data integrity while improving performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Limit Private versions:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Excessive private versions—especially when multiple users are editing simultaneously—can strain system resources. Regularly clean up unused private versions to maintain system efficiency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Date Granularity:&lt;/STRONG&gt; For models with day-level granularity, consider isolating them into separate models. Use cross-model copy data actions to transfer aggregated data, reducing complexity and improving performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Modeler option ‘Optimize Story Building Performance’&lt;/STRONG&gt; : This prevents the automatic refresh of data during story design. When importing or writing back datasets, use filters or pre-aggregation to reduce data volume&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculations/Data Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prioritize Model-Level Formulas:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Define calculations within the modeler rather than at the story level to reduce query load and improve responsiveness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Offload Complex: Logic to Data Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use data actions for advanced formulas and heavy computations instead of embedding them directly in stories.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Restrict Execution Scope:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use the MEMBERSET statement to narrow the scope of data actions. A tightly defined scope minimizes processing time and resource usage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Limit Iteration Range:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Keep calculation loops (IF, FOREACH) as focused as possible. Broad iteration across dimensions can degrade performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Aggregate at the Highest Logical Level:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Design calculations to occur at the most aggregated node feasible to reduce data volume and complexity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Avoid Copying Calculated&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Accounts:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Copying calculated accounts or non-standard aggregations is resource intensive. Prefer copying raw fact data when possible.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure Advanced Formulas Thoughtfully:&lt;/STRONG&gt; All steps in advanced formulas execute sequentially and materialize in the model. Use variable members to streamline logic and avoid unnecessary commits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Minimize Query Calls:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reduce the number of DATA() and RESULTLOOKUP() statements—each call triggers a backend query.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Restricted Measures Over Exception Aggregations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Exception aggregations (e.g., MIN, MAX, AVERAGE across hierarchies) are computationally expensive. Use restricted measures and advanced formulas when possible.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplify Formula Structures&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Avoid breaking formulas into too many sub-steps, which increases processing overhead.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recompile After Model Changes: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;If performance drops after model updates, re-save the advanced formula or data action to trigger recompilation and optimization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Centralize Execution for Large Volumes: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Run data actions centrally via an admin user when handling large datasets. For decentralized execution, ensure scope is tightly defined.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trigger Actions Judiciously: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Avoid frequent or unnecessary data action runs. Execute only when required to conserve resources.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monitor Execution&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Time: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Use the Data Action Monitor to track duration and identify slow-running actions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Job Monitor for Diagnostics:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Regularly review run history and step-level details to pinpoint bottlenecks and optimize performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplify IF Statements&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Reduce reliance on IF statements by using logical operators like AND or applying filters. Each IF creates a subquery, so use sparingly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leverage Predictive Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Use predictive features to generate accurate forecasts based on historical data, accelerating planning cycles and improving decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Backend HANA/BW considerations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HANA modelling&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Optimize HANA Views&lt;/STRONG&gt; by following guidelines for modelling and performance tuning.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Perform Calculations Post-Aggregation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Whenever possible, structure views to calculate after aggregation to reduce data volume and improve speed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Join on Indexed Columns:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use keys or indexed columns for joins instead of calculated fields to enhance query performance.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Push Logic to HANA:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Keep calculations and logic within HANA to leverage pushdown capabilities and minimize SAC-side processing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blend in HANA, Not SAC&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Perform data linking and blending operations in HANA to reduce complexity and improve responsiveness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apply Filters Early:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Early filtering reduces data load and improves query execution time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hide Unused Dimensions in SAC&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Remove unnecessary metadata from SAC models to streamline performance and reduce clutter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BW modelling&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Design Efficient Queries:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Limit the number of dimensions and hide unnecessary key figures to reduce query payload and improve responsiveness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use BW Variables Over SAC Filters:&lt;/STRONG&gt; BW variables are processed server-side and offer better performance than applying filters within SAC stories.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Define Restricted Key Figures&lt;/STRONG&gt;: in BW Avoid creating restricted key figures in SAC remote models. Instead, configure them directly in BW for optimized execution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Minimize Cascading Page Filters:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Page-level filters that trigger cascading effects across widgets can slow down performance. Use them sparingly and strategically.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable Query Merge:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Activate query merge to consolidate backend calls, reducing latency and improving load times.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable HTTP/2 Protocol:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Improves data transfer efficiency between SAC and BW, especially for large datasets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Increase Parallel Sessions:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Configure BW data sources to support more parallel sessions, enhancing concurrency and user experience.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apply BI Authorizations for Data Security:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use BW’s built-in data-level security to control access and ensure users only retrieve data relevant to their roles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Story Building Recommendations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Story Structure &amp;amp; Layout&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Optimized or Unified Story Experience:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Adopt the latest story building interface for enhanced performance, flexibility, and design capabilities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leverage Composites as Reusable Widgets:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Composites are stored as SAC artifacts and can be reused across stories. They support both canvas and responsive layouts and allow story-level features like filters and bookmarks to apply seamlessly. Benefits include faster story creation, reduced maintenance, standardized design, and support for parallel development.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Responsive Layouts:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Responsive pages automatically adjust to screen size and load faster. Unified stories offer advanced responsive rule configurations for precise control.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content Design &amp;amp; Performance Optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Request Only What’s Needed:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Break down information into manageable layers. Use summary or landing pages with hyperlinks to detailed views.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Minimize Page Count and Widget Load:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Reduce the number of pages and limit data-heavy widgets per page to improve load times and user experience.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Optimize Charts and Tables:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid charts with more than 500 data points.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Limit the number of charts per page to reduce backend requests.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Split large tables into smaller ones with fewer KPIs or measures.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Limit the number of cells and descriptive columns for readability.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid excessive formatting rules and in-cell charts/calculations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Lightweight Visuals:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Replace large image files with lightweight SVGs to reduce rendering time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Filtering &amp;amp; Data Handling:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Implement Filters Strategically:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Apply filters at the document level rather than creating generic views. Use page filters instead of individual chart filters. Avoid loading all data and filtering afterward.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Limit Hierarchy Depth:&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Filters Deep hierarchies can slow down performance—use only necessary levels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Minimize Data Blending:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Sources Keep the number of blended data sources low to reduce complexity and improve responsiveness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pause Data Refresh During Design:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use the “Pause Data Refresh” option to optimize story loading while building.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Security &amp;amp; Access Control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test With User Roles:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Validate story performance using roles with end user authorizations—not just the admin role—to simulate real-world usage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Apply Data Access Control (DAC):&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ensure users only see data relevant to their role. For example, use filters for company code and profit center rather than displaying all dimensions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning-Specific Tips&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use Fluid Data Entry Mode:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This default mode offers better performance and interactivity. Avoid Single Data Entry mode, which is slower.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable Planning Only Where Needed:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Activate planning features on tables only when required. Disable planning in the builder panel if not used.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Latest Performance Improvements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Table Build Experience:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Optimized Stories – Edit Mode Enhancements.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blended Tables&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Initial page loading is faster.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculations:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Automatically retained when tables are copied.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improved Filtering &amp;amp; Sorting:&lt;/STRONG&gt; More efficient workflows and reduced query errors.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ghost Table:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Instant layout preview before data loads&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Story Design Optimization&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Performance recommendations in Edit Mode available for story designers in the optimized story experience.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Available for widget, page, and stories levels.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Preload pages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It can be enabled in edit mode under&amp;nbsp;Data Refresh-&amp;gt;Loading Optimization Settings-&amp;gt; Preload Pages.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Preloading will initialize parts of the next and previous page, so switching to these pages will now be faster.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If performance issues persist despite optimization efforts, SAC offers a suite of diagnostic tools to help pinpoint the root cause. These tools provide visibility into query execution, data action performance, and story load behavior. For detailed guidance on using these diagnostics, refer to the official SAP Help documentation or reach out to SAP Support for expert help.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/optimizing-sap-analytics-cloud-best-practices-and-performance/ba-p/14229397"/>
    <published>2025-09-26T21:21:21.678000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/archive-sac-change-docs-into-datasphere/ba-p/14229415</id>
    <title>Archive SAC Change Docs into Datasphere</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T22:50:28.069000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>analytics</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15206</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Using SAC data change documents, you can track (audit) the data changes made to any planning model.&amp;nbsp;SAP Analytics Cloud&amp;nbsp;logs all changes to the transaction data of that model when users publish data from private versions to public versions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that a data change log has up to 2^31 (i.e., 2,147,384,648, or ~2 billion) records. When the data change log reaches its size limit, publishing data will fail, and you will see the following message:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;U&gt;Publish cannot be performed because the data audit table has reached the maximum number of rows.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To avoid this issue, consider periodically downloading log entries as a backup before deleting them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This document shows a design to back up SAC audit logs into Datasphere. Using Datasphere dataflow to back up change documents from the SAC Data Export Service via a Cloud Data Integration adapter-based connection, it can back up and preserve the SAC audit log history, which is necessary for regular housekeeping in SAC due to storage capacity limits.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_0-1758919421321.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320650i10EA431452A550B2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_0-1758919421321.png" alt="analytics_0-1758919421321.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;DES: data export service&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CDI: cloud data integration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In SAC seamless planning or in BDC, the SAC model definition and calculation logic remain within SAC, while the persistence for planning data and change documents are stored in SAP Datasphere, so that both systems are closely linked - without the effort of manual data transfers. Therefore, the solution might not be necessary if the SAC change documents are already stored in Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following steps outline the implementation of the solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC, System – Administration – App Integration, create an OAuth client with Access to the Data Export Service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_1-1758919421330.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320652i813A0493D702453C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_1-1758919421330.png" alt="analytics_1-1758919421330.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC, keep the OAuth Client URLs for later configuration of the connection in Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_2-1758919421332.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320651i21D1346CAD3D2BCE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_2-1758919421332.png" alt="analytics_2-1758919421332.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC, copy the OAuth Client ID and Client Secret for later configuration of the connection in Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_3-1758919421336.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320653iAE0A7B4F43EF351A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_3-1758919421336.png" alt="analytics_3-1758919421336.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Datasphere, in a space, create a Cloud Data Integration connection pointing to the SAC Data Export Service. The URL is in the format of&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;https://&amp;lt;your domain&amp;gt;/api/v1/dataexport/administration&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_4-1758919421340.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320655i72B6CE9A09BE7763/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_4-1758919421340.png" alt="analytics_4-1758919421340.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the connections management screen, validate the connection, and make sure the Data Flows feature is now enabled. It shall give the following message after validation on the connection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;U&gt;Connection “SAC DES Change Docs” is valid. – &lt;STRONG&gt;Data flows are enabled&lt;/STRONG&gt;. – Replication flows are not supported. – Remote tables are enabled.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAC, open the model with the Audit Data flag switched on, and note down the model ID in the rear part of the URL. For instance:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;https://&amp;lt;your domain name&amp;gt;/sap/fpa/ui/app.html?sap-ui-theme=sap_belize#/modeler&amp;amp;/m/model/&lt;U&gt;C4003n1icbi0loo9lvgv7t4pu41&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Datasphere, Data Builder- Create a Data Flow to load SAC audit logs into a target table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the model id to find the SAC source in the connection for the source node in the data flow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To make the daily backup more efficient, an exemplary expression implemented in the projection node can be: "Audit_Time" &amp;gt;= ADD_DAYS(NOW(), -1).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To preserve the audit logs history that might be regularly cleaned in SAC, use Append mode on the target table for UPSERT.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_1-1758923221730.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320664iF5A32561E50CDDC0/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_1-1758923221730.png" alt="analytics_1-1758923221730.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_0-1758923170403.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320663iA24B1203419A4079/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_0-1758923170403.png" alt="analytics_0-1758923170403.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Datasphere, execute the data flow to load SAC audit logs and verify that the data is now present in Datasphere. Then, delete the audit logs in SAC, execute the data flow again to check that the audit logs history has been preserved after cleansing audit logs in SAC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_0-1758922973229.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320660i796A98F8D0D15CC2/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_0-1758922973229.png" alt="analytics_0-1758922973229.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Last but not least, you may also develop an analytic model on top of the audit logs history table in Datasphere for analytics and build a report or visualization in SAC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;CDI connection type also supports the remote table as well as the data flow feature.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remote table can use the following replication types, but none of those replications can well preserve the change document history.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Replication (snapshot)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Replication (real-time)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/archive-sac-change-docs-into-datasphere/ba-p/14229415"/>
    <published>2025-09-26T22:50:28.069000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/choosing-the-right-sap-analytics-tool-features-benefits-and-strategy/ba-p/14230016</id>
    <title>Choosing the Right SAP Analytics Tool: Features, Benefits, and Strategy</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T08:48:09.273000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GiriRaaj</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/153675</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Within an organization's data and analytics strategy, SAP provides a portfolio of analytics solutions, including SAP S/4HANA Embedded Analytics, SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC), and SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC), each with a specific function. To assist clients in selecting the best option for their requirements, a comparative analysis of their salient characteristics and advantages is provided below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890837768"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP S/4HANA Embedded Analytics&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This solution, which is directly integrated into the SAP S/4HANA ERP system, offers real-time analytics on operational data without requiring data replication.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GiriRaaj_0-1759127524684.png" style="width: 592px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320922i4C4B404D79A8F548/image-dimensions/592x313?v=v2" width="592" height="313" role="button" title="GiriRaaj_0-1759127524684.png" alt="GiriRaaj_0-1759127524684.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-disc"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Reporting in Real Time:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Get the most recent information straight from the ERP system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Views of Core Data Services (CDS):&lt;/STRONG&gt; For customizable reporting, use virtual data models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Predefined KPIs and Dashboards:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use unconventional content to gain rapid insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fiori-Based User Interface:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enhanced user experience through intuitive design.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immediate Decision-Making&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Facilitates quick actions based on current data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified Infrastructure&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Eliminates the need for separate data warehousing solutions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Embedded within the core ERP system, ensuring consistency.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565241544"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497810758"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A cloud-based platform combining business intelligence, planning, and predictive analytics, SAC connects to various data sources, including SAP and non-SAP systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GiriRaaj_1-1759127661310.png" style="width: 575px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320924i99C5FE0993F046D8/image-dimensions/575x286?v=v2" width="575" height="286" role="button" title="GiriRaaj_1-1759127661310.png" alt="GiriRaaj_1-1759127661310.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Utilize AI-driven insights and predictive modelling.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Integrate financial planning and budgeting processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Collaboration Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Facilitate real-time discussions and decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mobile Accessibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Access analytics on-the-go through optimized dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comprehensive Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Consolidates data from multiple sources for holistic analysis.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Forecasting&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Improves accuracy in planning and budgeting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Cloud infrastructure supports growth and flexibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A fully managed SaaS solution that unifies and governs SAP and third-party data, enabling advanced analytics and AI-driven insights across the organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GiriRaaj_3-1759128045141.png" style="width: 667px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320928i4140F05E2A3791CE/image-dimensions/667x375?v=v2" width="667" height="375" role="button" title="GiriRaaj_3-1759128045141.png" alt="GiriRaaj_3-1759128045141.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Connects disparate data sources into a unified platform.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI and ML Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Leverages machine learning for predictive analytics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prebuilt Applications&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Offers industry-specific solutions and dashboards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Governance&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Ensures data quality and compliance across the organization.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerated Decision-Making&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Provides timely insights for informed decisions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reduced Complexity&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Simplifies data management and analytics processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Fosters cross-departmental data sharing and insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301297253"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104783748"&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comparative Study&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="GiriRaaj_0-1759126789879.png" style="width: 721px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320908i657DD56539F68920/image-dimensions/721x229?v=v2" width="721" height="229" role="button" title="GiriRaaj_0-1759126789879.png" alt="GiriRaaj_0-1759126789879.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommendation&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Choose SAP S/4HANA Embedded Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt; if your primary need is real-time, operational reporting directly within your ERP system, with minimal infrastructure overhead.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Opt for SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; when you require advanced analytics, predictive modeling, and planning capabilities across various data sources, with a focus on scalability and collaboration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consider SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; if your organization seeks a unified platform for data integration, governance, and AI-driven insights, encompassing both SAP and third-party data sources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your time.&amp;nbsp; Stay connected for further updates on Analytics !&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;-With Warm Regards :&amp;nbsp; GIRI&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/choosing-the-right-sap-analytics-tool-features-benefits-and-strategy/ba-p/14230016"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T08:48:09.273000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/use-btp-destination-service-to-call-sac-multi-actions-api/ba-p/14230819</id>
    <title>Use BTP destination service to call SAC multi-actions API</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T17:26:48.047000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>analytics</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/15206</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Based on the standard product document, this blog shows practical implementation steps to call SAC multi actions API from a BTP destination service that can be used in BTP CAPM service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/user-propagation-via-saml-2-0-bearer-assertion-flow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/connectivity/sap-btp-connectivity-cf/user-propagation-via-saml-2-0-bearer-assertion-flow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;1. In SAC System/Administration/App Integration, create an oAuth client with API Access and SAML2.0 Grant. Note down the Client ID and Secret. Some blogs say using Interactive Usage for the purpose, but the testing shows no return of SAC auth token.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_173-1759159087674.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321310iF96345D9A44E2810/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_173-1759159087674.png" alt="analytics_173-1759159087674.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.&amp;nbsp; Note down oAuth2SAML Token URLs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_174-1759159087675.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321308i0B7ABD973AA35D5D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_174-1759159087675.png" alt="analytics_174-1759159087675.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Note down your SAC multi-action URL&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_175-1759159087679.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321309i5DC9DF940B67D5B5/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_175-1759159087679.png" alt="analytics_175-1759159087679.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. In BTP Cockpit, create a BTP destination service that has a destination pointing to SAC oAuth Client and create a service key with a pair of client id and client credential. The service key is only used for Postman testing, but it’s unnecessary for the bound BTP app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_176-1759159087684.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321312iB00D30080CDEC927/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_176-1759159087684.png" alt="analytics_176-1759159087684.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5. Download BTP signing certificate and IDP metadata from BTP destinations at sub account level. Kindly note that a destination service is created in dev space and bound with an BTP application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_177-1759159087687.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321311iABEB2DBD3F9F4AB6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_177-1759159087687.png" alt="analytics_177-1759159087687.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;6. In SAC, create a trusted identify provider maintained accordingly. The provider name should come from Entity ID of the downloaded IDP metadata and the signing certificate should come the downloaded trust from BTP destinations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_178-1759159087692.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321313i5435A52F78A73226/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_178-1759159087692.png" alt="analytics_178-1759159087692.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;7. Add the userIdSource property to the BTP destination to allow passing the BTP access token attribute to SAC auth token.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_179-1759159087695.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321314i4703F2B6A04E3B6B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_179-1759159087695.png" alt="analytics_179-1759159087695.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;8. Get a BTP access token using password credentials grant type.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_180-1759159087699.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321316i9CE4F890F41C2054/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_180-1759159087699.png" alt="analytics_180-1759159087699.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;9. Verify the BTP access token if it contains the email attribute.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_181-1759159087703.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321315i5E067849586EE138/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_181-1759159087703.png" alt="analytics_181-1759159087703.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;10. Use the BTP access token to call BTP destination service to get a SAC auth token.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_182-1759159087708.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321317i262DC25898EFD8F3/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_182-1759159087708.png" alt="analytics_182-1759159087708.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;11. Use the SAC auth token to get a SAC CSRF token.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_183-1759159087712.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321319iFF9AB573E1DCD842/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_183-1759159087712.png" alt="analytics_183-1759159087712.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;12. Use both the SAC auth token and SAC CSRF token to execute SAC multi-action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_184-1759159087720.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321318i46C41A4BA0FCA5CE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_184-1759159087720.png" alt="analytics_184-1759159087720.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;13. Use the SAC auth token to get SAC multi-action execution status and verify it was successful.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="analytics_185-1759159087725.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321320iB6C92623313DE612/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="analytics_185-1759159087725.png" alt="analytics_185-1759159087725.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;14. How to allow BTP CAPM to use the destination service to call the SAC multi-action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;a. Update the package.json to have a reference to the BTP destination in the destination service that has been bound with the BTP app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; "cds": {&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "requires": {&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "uaa": {&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "kind": "xsuaa"&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; },&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "db": {&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "kind": "hana"&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; },&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "CapExDestinationForUI": {&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "kind": "rest",&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "credentials": {&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "destination": "sac-multi-actions-dest_CLONING"&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; },&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "csrf": {&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "method": "get",&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; "url": "&lt;A href="https://ps-trial.us10.hcs.cloud.sap/api/v1/csrf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://ps-trial.us10.hcs.cloud.sap/api/v1/csrf&lt;/A&gt;"&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; }&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; }&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; }&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; }&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;b. In a CAPM service event, connect to the destination and use POST method to call the multi action URL. It by default uses different Content-Type that might cause 415 Error, so pass application/json to overwrite the default to make sure it’s successful.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt; let service = await cds.connect.to('CapExDestinationForUI');&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#0000FF"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; let projects = await service.tx(req).send("POST", "/multiActions/t.16:9C88BE058AA23F014E86756BBDB404D3/executions", req.data, { "Content-Type": "application/json" });&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/use-btp-destination-service-to-call-sac-multi-actions-api/ba-p/14230819"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T17:26:48.047000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/full-page-fit-vs-scrollable-dashboards-in-sac-which-one-is-better/ba-p/14187381</id>
    <title>Full-Page Fit vs. Scrollable Dashboards in SAC which one is better?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T10:05:42.611000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Siva_Prakash_S</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1721011</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'd like to discuss a common dilemma developers face when it comes to designing a dashboard in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Should I design the dashboard such that it fits entirely within the browser window (Full-Page Fit)? or should I design the dashboard such that it has a scroll?&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Would the customer be okay with having to scroll up and down to see the contents of the dashboard?&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":face_with_rolling_eyes:"&gt;🙄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, the design process begins even before we decide to click Create Story.&lt;BR /&gt;To Tackle this problem, I will be elaborating both the scenarios for you to make an informed decision while designing your next dashboard.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Difference between both the Dashboard Fit:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assuming we are seeing the dashboard in a normal sized laptop screen [1366 x 768px] not a 1080p HD one. A&amp;nbsp;Full-Page Fit Dashboard&amp;nbsp;ensures all content is visible without scrolling, while a&amp;nbsp;Scrollable Dashboard&amp;nbsp;allows content to extend vertically or horizontally beyond the initial view, requiring user interaction to access additional information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This choice significantly impacts user experience and performance. Both has its own advantages and disadvantages. Let's dive deep to understand the pros and cons of each type.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Full-Page Fit Dashboard: (Everything visible in a single glance)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Full page.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317900i5A90E12A83002CEF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Full page.png" alt="Full page.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Here in the above screenshot, see how all the KPIs presented within a single screen and there is no scroll to the right and bottom of the dashboards. This means that it is well within the boundaries of our 1366 x 768 px canvas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advantages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All KPIs are visible at a single glance, enabling quick decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;No need to scroll, which is ideal for users who prefer a single-screen overview.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Each KPI has less room, potentially less real estate and more congestion.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All widgets are triggered simultaneously, sending backend requests that can strain system resources.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Heavy widgets like tables may take longer to load, making the dashboard appear sluggish.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Performance Statistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the KPIs visible in viewport have triggered a backend request and rendered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;It's like going to a restaurant and saying bring me everything you have, even when you know you won't be able to eat everything they bring. Wasteful.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_down:"&gt;👎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Total render time ~9.5s&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Loading Full.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317904iE1D9BEA549328C60/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Loading Full.png" alt="Loading Full.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the visible KPIs have triggered a backend request and are rendered at Frontend.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dashboard with Scroll (You gotta scroll to see what you want)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Scroll Section 1" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317901iE6AB518252E0B520/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Scroll1.png" alt="Scroll Section 1" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Scroll Section 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Scroll Section 2" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317902iED81895D82CF2D8D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Scroll2.png" alt="Scroll Section 2" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Scroll Section 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here in the above screenshot, see how we have a scroll to the right of the dashboard. This means that the KPIs are spaced out more and exceeds the page's default height of 768px, therefore the user would get a scroll when accessing the dashboard.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advantages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;More space per KPI allows for better viewability and detailed insights.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC’s viewport loading ensures only visible widgets are triggered, reducing initial load time and backend traffic.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Less frequently used or heavier components can be placed lower on the page.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users may miss the overall picture and need to scroll to compare KPIs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scrolling back and forth can hinder quick analysis and decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Performance Statistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All the KPIs that has been viewed initially have triggered a backend request and rendered. The Un scrolled portion doesn't trigger any backend request neither doesn't render until we preview it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;This is like going to the restaurant and placing an order and post eating the main course you get to decide if you want to take on dessert. Only what is required is being consumed here. Resourceful&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":thumbs_up:"&gt;👍&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Total render time ~8s&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Scroll perfo.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317903i27DD3CCB64A6F510/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Scroll perfo.png" alt="Scroll perfo.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Only KPIs visible during initial preview has been rendered&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finding the Middle Ground: Tab Strips&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To balance usability and performance, developers can use&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tab Strip. &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These are&amp;nbsp;container widgets used within a SAC story to organize content into separate, switchable tabs.&amp;nbsp;They allow users to view different components, such as charts or tables, within a single application by providing a navigation area to select and display the content of each tab.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tab strip - summary section" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317905iC348C2D7822E0019/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tab1.png" alt="Tab strip - summary section" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Tab strip - summary section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tab strip - Table section" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317906i1CC36323DF17C5D5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tab2.png" alt="Tab strip - Table section" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Tab strip - Table section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here in the above screenshot, see how the dashboard is still fitted within the canvas and also having the benefits of loading what is required.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we have also bifurcated the components into summary and table section. The heavier/Less frequently viewed KPIs are places in the subsequent tab strips, therefore reducing the initial load.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits of Tab Strips&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Essential KPIs are displayed upfront, while heavier or less frequently accessed components (e.g., raw data tables) are placed in separate tabs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAC’s default viewport loading ensures only visible components are triggered, reducing backend load and improving responsiveness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tabs offer a cleaner and better UI/UX.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Performance Statistics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Only the Default tab strip KPIs have triggered a backend request and has been rendered. The heavier KPIs which hasn't been previewed is still untriggered and unrendered.&lt;BR /&gt;Total render time ~7.5s&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tab perf1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317907i2530B4084DEE5820/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tab perf1.png" alt="Tab perf1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Only the Default tab strip KPIs have triggered a backend request and has been rendered&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Principle: "What You See Is What Loads"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAC's viewport optimization&lt;/U&gt; means that only the visible components are loaded initially. This explains why Full-Page Fit dashboards can be performance intensive as everything is triggered at once. In contrast, scrollable dashboards and tab-based layouts defer loading of non-visible components, enhancing performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;However, it’s important to note that once a user navigates to hidden sections or tabs, those components will be triggered, potentially causing a brief delay.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Final Take away&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The choice between a Full-Page Fit and a Scrollable Dashboard should be guided by user requirements and usage patterns. Developers must engage with users' early phases in the design process to understand:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which KPIs are most frequently accessed?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is a single-screen overview preferred?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Are users comfortable with scrolling or tab navigation?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope this article was helpful. Which one do you prefer? Let me know your doubts and opinions in the comments below!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;References:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/managing-performance-in-sap-analytics-cloud/using-the-loading-optimization-setting-on-a-story-level" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using the Loading Optimization Setting on a Story Level&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/full-page-fit-vs-scrollable-dashboards-in-sac-which-one-is-better/ba-p/14187381"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T10:05:42.611000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-data-and-analytics-forum-18-19-11-2025/ba-p/14232575</id>
    <title>SAP Data and Analytics Forum 18.-19.11.2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T13:34:20.076000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dirk_Mayrock</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1450581</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We look forward to welcoming &amp;nbsp;you on the &lt;STRONG&gt;18th to 19th. November&lt;/STRONG&gt; at this year’s &lt;STRONG&gt;German speaking SAP Data and Analytics Forum&lt;/STRONG&gt;. An exciting program with inspiring lectures awaits you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;There are two ways to participate in the event:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 1: You only visit the first day, in virtual format&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The first day is free and virtual. Current trends and developments in Data and Analytics are discussed here. From best practices to new technologies and applications such as SAP Analytics Cloud and SAP Datasphere, you will be able to gain valuable insights and expand your knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;Key sessions will cover the strategic direction and roadmap of the SAP Business Data Cloud, highlight the latest innovations and feature enhancements, and explore advanced planning capabilities enabled by seamless planning.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sign up &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/wdvdaf-sap-data-und-analytics-forum-virtuell-remoteclassroom-025-de-de/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; for the first free and virtual day.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option 2: Join Both Days in Walldorf or Virtually&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The second day will be delivered in a hybrid format, enabling participation either on site at the SAP Training Center in Walldorf or virtually. Building on the strategic and technological perspectives from day one, you will dive deeper into SAP’s data and analytics portfolio. Through expert-led sessions and live demonstrations, you will explore the SAP Business Data Cloud in detail – from its architecture and native data warehousing capabilities with SAP Datasphere to its integration with SAP Enterprise Architecture Designer, SAP Data Hub, SAP Embedded Analytics, SAP Analytics Cloud, and SAP Intelligent Applications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Between sessions, “&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet the Expert&lt;/STRONG&gt;” formats give you the opportunity to address your specific technical and business questions directly with SAP specialists.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You will also have the chance to join a guided tour of the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Experience Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;, illustrating sustainable value creation across an end-to-end solution landscape, and discover the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S.Mart Store&lt;/STRONG&gt; as a real-world example of applied retail innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The day will close with an evening networking event – the perfect opportunity to exchange ideas, share experiences, and build valuable connections in a relaxed setting.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register now for the 2-day SAP Data and Analytics Forum and secure 25% off your next SAP Certification. After registration, you will receive a discount voucher for the SAP certification exam, valid for two attempts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Sign up for the SAP Data and Analytics Forum right &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://training.sap.com/course/wdcdaf-sap-data-und-analytics-forum-hybrid-classroom-025-de-en/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. (&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/germany/documents/2025/09/fce204dc-1f7f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;preliminary Agenda&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SIX Product and Solution Learning,&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics Team&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-data-and-analytics-forum-18-19-11-2025/ba-p/14232575"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T13:34:20.076000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-analytics-cloud-modeling-extensions-amp-integration-qrc4/ba-p/14208685</id>
    <title>What's New in SAP Analytics Cloud Modeling Extensions &amp; Integration QRC4 2025 Release</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T10:32:04.203000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AmandaJMurphy</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46075</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AmandaJMurphy_0-1757071449064.png" style="width: 862px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309918i313C7F1F9A1F12F0/image-dimensions/862x440?v=v2" width="862" height="440" role="button" title="AmandaJMurphy_0-1757071449064.png" alt="AmandaJMurphy_0-1757071449064.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1888311515"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purpose&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Community Colleagues,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am delighted to share some fantastic new &lt;EM&gt;Data Integration&lt;/EM&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;EM&gt;Conversion&lt;/EM&gt; features made available inside the modeling area of SAP Analytics Cloud, within Business Data Cloud!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1691798010"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a short overview of each feature:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Data Export API – Master Data Hierarchies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Data Export API has been extended to support the export of master data parent-child and level-based hierarchies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Data Export API – Seamless Planning Support for Public Dimensions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Data Export API has been extended to support the export of master data from public dimensions that reside in a Datasphere workspace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Data Export API – Seamless Planning Support for Fact Data Delta&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Data Export API has been extended to support the export of fact data delta changes from a SAP Analytics Cloud standard model that resides in a Datasphere space.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Dimension Unit Property Enhancement &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In &lt;EM&gt;Unit Conversion&lt;/EM&gt;, a dimension containing a unit property now displays a &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;member selector dialog&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; consisting of a list of &lt;EM&gt;Unit Symbols &amp;amp; Unit Descriptions &lt;/EM&gt;that are contained in the &lt;EM&gt;Standard Unit&lt;/EM&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;EM&gt;Unit Description&lt;/EM&gt; tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. New Member Selector dialog in Modeling&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A new member selector dialog has been introduced into the Modeling area of SAC, replacing the previous member selection dialog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s now investigate each topic in further detail:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Data Export API – Master Data Hierarchies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;EM&gt;Data Export API&lt;/EM&gt; has been extended to support the export of Master Data &lt;EM&gt;Level-Based &lt;/EM&gt;&amp;amp; &lt;EM&gt;Parent-Child Hierarchies&lt;/EM&gt; that are part of a standard model residing in SAP Analytics Cloud.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This includes master data stored in public or private dimensions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The export of &lt;EM&gt;Master Data Hierarchies&lt;/EM&gt; is also supported for standard models that are saved on a Datasphere space.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Level-Based Hierarchies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To allow the export of &lt;EM&gt;Level-Based&lt;/EM&gt; hierarchies, a new endpoint has been created called&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;{BaseURL}/providers/{namespaceID}/{providerID}/{DimensionName}Master&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;:&lt;/EM&gt; Make sure to replace&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;{namespaceID}&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;{providerID}&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;with the correct IDs and to replace &lt;EM&gt;{DimensionName}&lt;/EM&gt; with the name of your dimension.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AmandaJMurphy_0-1757072180907.png" style="width: 420px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309930i26B361F24413C43B/image-dimensions/420x215?v=v2" width="420" height="215" role="button" title="AmandaJMurphy_0-1757072180907.png" alt="AmandaJMurphy_0-1757072180907.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#339966"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parent-Child Hierarchies&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To allow the export of Parent-Child hierarchies, a new endpoint has been created called &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;{BaseURL}/providers/{namespaceID}/{providerID}/{DimensionName}MasterWithHierarchy&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Make sure to replace&amp;nbsp;{namespaceID}&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;{providerID}&amp;nbsp;with the correct IDs and to replace {DimensionName} with the name of your dimension.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For each &lt;EM&gt;Parent-Child&lt;/EM&gt; hierarchy of the dimension, each row will have 3 additional columns compared to when using the &lt;EM&gt;{DimensionName}Master &lt;/EM&gt;endpoint.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These 3 columns are:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;{HierarchyName}_PARENTID - the id of the parent node in the hierarchy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;{HierarchyName}_PREVID - the previous node which shares the same parent as this one in the hierarchy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;{HierarchyName}_ORDERID - the index of this node in the list of nodes that share the parent node.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AmandaJMurphy_1-1757072310478.png" style="width: 525px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309932i4D2509E62ABB1879/image-dimensions/525x218?v=v2" width="525" height="218" role="button" title="AmandaJMurphy_1-1757072310478.png" alt="AmandaJMurphy_1-1757072310478.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Master Data Hierarchy&lt;/EM&gt; export jobs can be executed using 2-legged (machine to machine) or 3-legged (Authorized User) access. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Data Export API – Seamless Planning Support for Public Dimensions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;EM&gt;Data Export API&lt;/EM&gt; has been extended to support the export of &lt;EM&gt;Master Data&lt;/EM&gt; from &lt;EM&gt;Public Dimensions&lt;/EM&gt; that reside in a Datasphere workspace using the existing &lt;EM&gt;PublicDimensionData&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;endpoint.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;{BaseURL}/providers/{namespaceID}/{providerID}/PublicDimensionData&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;U&gt;Note:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Make sure to replace&amp;nbsp;{namespaceID}&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;{providerID}&amp;nbsp;with the correct IDs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 1: Sample export of Public Dimension Data on a Datasphere space using the PublicDimensionData Endpoint" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309939i895795B286A91191/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AmandaJMurphy_2-1757072502024.png" alt="Figure 1: Sample export of Public Dimension Data on a Datasphere space using the PublicDimensionData Endpoint" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 1: Sample export of Public Dimension Data on a Datasphere space using the PublicDimensionData Endpoint&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Public Dimension&lt;/EM&gt; export jobs can be executed using 2-legged (machine to machine) or 3-legged (Authorized User) access.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Authentication checks are in place, for 3-legged accounts, to ensure that access to the Datasphere space is permitted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 2: Authorization Check Prevents Export from a Datasphere Space." style="width: 793px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309946i422C88950B3C4F1F/image-dimensions/793x206?v=v2" width="793" height="206" role="button" title="AmandaJMurphy_0-1757072728543.png" alt="Figure 2: Authorization Check Prevents Export from a Datasphere Space." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 2: Authorization Check Prevents Export from a Datasphere Space.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This brings feature parity between the export of SAC public dimensions and those saved on a Datasphere space.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Data Export API – Seamless Planning Support for Fact Data Delta&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Data Export API has been extended to support the export of &lt;EM&gt;Fact Data Delta&lt;/EM&gt; changes from a SAP Analytics Cloud standard model that resides in a Datasphere space.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This includes support for &lt;EM&gt;Delta Difference&lt;/EM&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;EM&gt;Delta Aggregation&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The &lt;EM&gt;API Subscriptions&lt;/EM&gt; tab in the modeler has been enabled to allow for the delta extraction of models residing in a Datasphere space.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 3: API Subscriptions Dialog Visible for SAC Models residing in a Datasphere Space" style="width: 617px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/309951i65932238D95A107B/image-dimensions/617x369?v=v2" width="617" height="369" role="button" title="AmandaJMurphy_1-1757072878175.png" alt="Figure 3: API Subscriptions Dialog Visible for SAC Models residing in a Datasphere Space" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 3: API Subscriptions Dialog Visible for SAC Models residing in a Datasphere Space&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The existing Fact Data API endpoint names will also now work within this landscape using 2-legged and 3-legged authentications.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;/providers/{NamespaceID}/{ProviderID}/FactData&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;/providers/{NamespaceID}/{ProviderID}/FactDataAggregation&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;This brings feature parity between the delta extraction on SAC models and models saved on a Datasphere space.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See my previous blogs covering &lt;EM&gt;Fact Data Difference&lt;/EM&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;EM&gt;Fact Data Aggregation&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-analytics-cloud-modeling-extensions-amp-integration-qrc3/ba-p/13739005" target="_blank"&gt;What’s New in SAP Analytics Cloud Modeling Extensions &amp;amp; Integration QRC3 2024 Release&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-analytics-cloud-modeling-extensions-amp-integration-qrc3/ba-p/14130035" target="_blank"&gt;What's New in SAP Analytics Cloud Modeling Extensions &amp;amp; Integration QRC3 2025 Release&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Dimension Unit Property Enhancement &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In &lt;EM&gt;Unit Conversion&lt;/EM&gt;, a dimension containing a unit property now displays a &lt;EM&gt;member selector dialog&lt;/EM&gt; consisting of a list of &lt;EM&gt;Unit Symbols &amp;amp; Unit Descriptions &lt;/EM&gt;that are contained in the &lt;EM&gt;Standard Unit&lt;/EM&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;EM&gt;Unit Description&lt;/EM&gt; tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Previously, modelers had to navigate &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;to&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; the &lt;EM&gt;Standard Unit &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;table&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, to locate the correct &lt;EM&gt;Unit ID&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;Unit Symbol&lt;/EM&gt; and then switch to a dimension to enter the correct unit.&amp;nbsp; The &lt;EM&gt;member selector dialog&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;on unit properties of a dimension&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, in the grid view, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;reduces&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;the risk of data-entry errors.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 4: Value Help on Dimension Unit Property" style="width: 380px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311067iF4DA9E792D53D2A8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AmandaJMurphy_0-1757329013924.png" alt="Figure 4: Value Help on Dimension Unit Property" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 4: Value Help on Dimension Unit Property&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. New Member Selector dialog in Modeling&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A new member selector dialog has been introduced into the Modeling area of SAC, replacing the previous member selection dialog.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This improved flexible dialog provides an item ID and item description in the display. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure 5: New Member Selector in Modeling" style="width: 583px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313153i830B8BD759F0BD8A/image-dimensions/583x351?v=v2" width="583" height="351" role="button" title="AmandaJMurphy_0-1757599502730.png" alt="Figure 5: New Member Selector in Modeling" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Figure 5: New Member Selector in Modeling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new dialog can be found in the following areas:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Generic dimensions &amp;gt; Data Access Control, Hierarchies, Unit Property&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Account dimensions &amp;gt; Data Locking Ownership, Responsible column&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data Management &amp;gt; API Subscription filters&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Calculation Workspace &amp;gt; Grid view – Exception aggregation / Required dimensions, preview panel filters&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Formula Editor &amp;gt; Dynamic time dimension&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Model Structure &amp;gt; delete facts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Variables&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000080"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6. More new Modeling Features...&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some additional new and exciting features in the Modeling area of SAP Analytics Cloud coming in QRC4 2025 include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consuming a Datasphere view as an external version into an SAC Planning Model.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consuming Google Big Query as an external version into an SAC Planning Model.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Introduction of Clean and Replace Subset of Data option into the Data Upload Starter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1495284505"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In summary, the following new features and updates have been introduced to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Modeling Extensions and Integration&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;areas of SAP Analytics Cloud, within Business Data Cloud, as part of QRC4 2025 release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. The &lt;EM&gt;Data Export API&lt;/EM&gt; has been extended to support the export of master data &lt;EM&gt;parent-child&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;level-based&lt;/EM&gt; hierarchies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. The &lt;EM&gt;Data Export API&lt;/EM&gt; has been extended to support the export of master data from &lt;EM&gt;public dimensions&lt;/EM&gt; that reside in a Datasphere space.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. &lt;/SPAN&gt;The &lt;EM&gt;Data Export API&lt;/EM&gt; has been extended to support the export of&lt;EM&gt; fact data delta&lt;/EM&gt; changes from an SAP Analytics Cloud standard model that resides in a Datasphere space.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Dimension properties of type Unit now offer a &lt;EM&gt;member selector&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;dialog containing a list of &lt;EM&gt;Unit Symbols&lt;/EM&gt; and &lt;EM&gt;Unit Descriptions&lt;/EM&gt; obtained from the Standard Unit &amp;amp; Unit Description tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;5.&amp;nbsp;A new &lt;EM&gt;member selector&lt;/EM&gt; dialog has been introduced into the Modeling area of SAC&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A comprehensive list of SAC features for each QRC release can be found in our &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/42e4f84a0e5e458792b1047eaf81c31a" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What's New - 2025 Releases Guide&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to comment below or post a question to our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/cloud-analytics?ct=qa&amp;amp;lng=en&amp;amp;tab=content" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud Questions &amp;amp; Answers&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;forum.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See this&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://userapps.support.sap.com/sap/support/knowledge/E/2728183" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Knowledge Base Article&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;if you’d like to learn more about FastTrack and Quarterly Release Cycle releases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further information, visit our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/cloud-analytics" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud Community&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;pages to find more product information, best practices, and more.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To find out more about QRC release dates, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-tenants-on-quarterly-release-cycle-qrc-updates-in-2025/ba-p/14000629" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud tenants on Quarterly Release Cycle (QRC) updates in 2025&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Check out our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Road Map Explorer&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to see more upcoming features of SAP Analytics Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-analytics-cloud-modeling-extensions-amp-integration-qrc4/ba-p/14208685"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T10:32:04.203000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-customer-onboarding-newsletter-october-2025/ba-p/14233774</id>
    <title>SAP BTP Customer Onboarding Newsletter October 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T23:34:18.542000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FernandaFroelich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1410810</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear customers,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The mission of the SAP Customer Onboarding team is to deliver onboarding experiences that set you up for lasting success by providing early guidance, enablement, and resources to accelerate your path to first value realization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this in mind, we are pleased to share below the upcoming webcasts organized by the BTP Customer Onboarding team for October (2025), designed to help you get started with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100.00000000000001%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Live webcast&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Timezone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Language&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_ZKBZByNJQtuPeMDgrKbQYg#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;APJ/Europe&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 23&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_iUKkpgWXSiCW47lDJiqq7A?_ics=1759439499923&amp;amp;irclickid=~egdc6beafe-9~6YSWXMUKBCBqmgha98ZXOLRSIJDysie-31QIDAq&amp;amp;_gl=1*1g2b46h*_gcl_au*MTkzMTA2MjA2My4xNzU3MzU4NTM2LjcwMjU1NzIzLjE3NTkyMzMzMDIuMTc1OTIzMzMwMQ..*_ga*MzI4MzM0MzYxLjE3NDk1MDYwNjI.*_ga_L8TBF28DDX*czE3NTk0Mzk0MjkkbzkwJGcxJHQxNzU5NDM5NDk5JGo2MCRsMCRoMA.." target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Cockpit Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 22&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_Ht2rl8PDS3i06GzBo6nfZQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;English&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 14&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="24px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_kV2N_n0mRZuc8qYYn9fi8w" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="24px"&gt;APJ/Europe&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="24px"&gt;English&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="24px"&gt;Oct 07&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_ZWIvABa5S6-1QYNI6tg4Ig" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Datasphere Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Americas&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 28&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="41.56293222683264%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_K7NMNcvKTNeexWYa2ZEH0Q#/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Onboarding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="14.79944674965422%" height="30px"&gt;Americas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="16.73582295988935%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;English&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%" height="30px"&gt;Oct 14&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;We also invite you to review our recently published assets:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New videos for SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC)&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/xnUC9F3?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1235062" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Provisioning of SAP Business Data Cloud and its core components,&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/GQ3sAU4?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1232208" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Harnessing Intelligent Applications and Data Packages for Enhanced Efficiency&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New blog post for SAP Databricks:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/get-started-with-sap-databricks-introduction/ba-p/14219035" target="_blank"&gt;Get started with SAP Databricks: Introduction&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New page SAP Business AI:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center/business-ai.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business AI Onboarding Resource Center&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you’re looking for product content to help you get started, explore our &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/product/onboarding-resource-center.html?anchorId=section_copy_copy_co" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Onboarding Resource Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: your one-stop shop for everything related to onboarding!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have any questions regarding BTP onboarding, please send us a message through our email:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:SAP_BTP_Onboarding@sap.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP_BTP_Onboarding@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;#FirstExperiencesLast&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-customer-onboarding-newsletter-october-2025/ba-p/14233774"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T23:34:18.542000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/product-direction-and-evolution-of-the-new-table-build-experience/ba-p/14236050</id>
    <title>Product Direction and Evolution of the New Table Build Experience</title>
    <updated>2025-10-06T19:05:55.397000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GregBotticchio</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/186268</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1632851194"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This document reflects the status of the Table Build Experience in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) as of Q3 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It aims to guide story designers and stakeholders during the transition to the new experience and to provide visibility into its planned evolution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please note that some features and restrictions are temporary and subject to change as SAP continues to enhance SAC in upcoming releases.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1436337689"&gt;The New Table Build Experience&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the Q3 2025 release, SAP Analytics Cloud introduces the new Table Build Experience for the Optimized Design Mode.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This redesign marks a major step forward in how tables are created, configured, and consumed in SAC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new experience offers a more intuitive workflow for story designers, aligning closely with the Chart Builder, while also laying the foundation for future innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;All new capabilities and innovations introduced with this experience are detailed in the following SAP Community article:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-new-table-building-experience-in-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/14159483" target="_blank"&gt;The New Table Building Experience in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In short, the new Table Build Experience is not just a cosmetic update. It represents a strategic foundation for SAC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1239824184"&gt;Existing Unsupported Features and Restrictions&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;As with any major redesign, the initial release does not yet offer full feature parity with the legacy table, which is why the new Table Build Experience is currently available through an Opt-In option.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While the core capabilities are already in place, some features are still under development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The complete and up-to-date list of unsupported features and restrictions (as of QRC3 2025) is available in the official documentation:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/05e2a824958c45eab7d791cf27496ed0.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Unsupported Features and Restrictions: New Table Build Experience&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These limitations are important to keep in mind, especially when switching to the New Table Build Experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, they should be viewed in context: these limitations are temporary by nature and will progressively be removed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1043310679"&gt;Product Direction for the New Table Build Experience&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many of the current gaps are expected to be closed in the near future, with several already addressed as SAC continues to harmonize and extend its table capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following roadmap illustrates &lt;STRONG&gt;what&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;when&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP plans to lift the current restrictions and achieve full feature parity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="NTBE evolution.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323415i037E773E3C9186FA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NTBE evolution.png" alt="NTBE evolution.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-846797174"&gt;Share Your Feedback&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We want this transition to the New Table Build Experience to be as smooth and valuable as possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your feedback directly helps us improve both the product and its documentation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please let us know your thoughts, your input is highly appreciated and will actively influence future enhancements to SAP Analytics Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/product-direction-and-evolution-of-the-new-table-build-experience/ba-p/14236050"/>
    <published>2025-10-06T19:05:55.397000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extend-existing-planning-scenarios-of-sap-bpc-bw-ip-in-sap-bdc/ba-p/14234247</id>
    <title>Extend existing planning scenarios of SAP BPC/ BW-IP in SAP BDC</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T07:24:40.796000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>irinasheftelevich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/74514</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This blog post is a joint work of&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7476" target="_blank"&gt;@&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/74159" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;IsabelWichmann&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/74514"&gt;@irinasheftelevich&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Financial Planner´s Overview page in SAP Analytics Cloud" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323176iAD01FE234A6D3B7A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="irinashef_0-1759737584010.png" alt="Financial Planner´s Overview page in SAP Analytics Cloud" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Financial Planner´s Overview page in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MOTIVATION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today's fast-paced business world, the ability to effectively steer and lead an organisation is fundamental for achieving strategic goals and maintaining a competitive edge. A key success criterion is the capacity to fully harness and derive value from organisational data. Many companies struggle with data problems, such as fragmented information, outdated systems, and the super important task of preparing data for emerging technologies like AI. Recognising these challenges, we are excited to introduce a blog series dedicated to showcasing the substantial business value of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) in the context of planning and analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The motivation behind this initiative is to provide a comprehensive exploration of how SAP BDC capabilities as essential instruments, facilitating robust strategic alignment and guiding effective decision-making processes across diverse organisational requirements. We aim to illustrate how SAP BDC, equipped with powerful data management, planning, analytics and innovative AI capabilities, empowers organisations with enhanced business steering agility by providing real-time insights, streamlined data management, and automated decision support – going from insights to action, helps mainly leaders guide their businesses with precision.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our blog series will provide valuable insights for decision-makers seeking to harness SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) to enhance operational efficiency, optimise resource allocation, and achieve long-term objectives. By featuring detailed planning &amp;amp; analytics topics, the series will illustrate the transformative impact of SAP BDC in addressing the operational complexities of today’s business environment. This first introductory blog post will spotlight the strategic advantages of SAP BDC, particularly in the context of Business Steering, setting the stage for a deeper exploration of its benefits throughout the blog series.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are several blog posts in the series that will cover advantages of SAP BDC in the context of business steering, so please stay tuned for the upcoming blogs:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-in-the-context-of-business/ba-p/14165827" target="_self"&gt;The Value of SAP BDC in the context of business steering&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/planning-amp-analytics-p-amp-a-is-an-essential-part-of-sap-business-data/ba-p/14223762" target="_self"&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Analytics is an essential part of SAP BDC &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Key Planning &amp;amp; Analytics components of SAP BDC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is AI going to “retire” a dashboard?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Simulations, a game changer in today’s volatile world&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Extend existing planning scenarios of SAP BPC/BW-IP in SAP BDC&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(THIS BLOG POST)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Real-time steering with LIVE planning&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PaPM - The role of business calculation engine in business steering&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Self – service analytics and real time business steering&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business steering powered by AI agents&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Leverage data products in the context of planning &amp;amp; forecasting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Introducing AI/ML capabilities by SAP Databricks&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC) is a fully managed SaaS solution that unifies and governs all SAP data and seamlessly connects with third-party data, giving line-of-business leaders context to make even more impactful decisions. As an evolution of our industry-leading data, planning, and analytics solutions, SAP Business Data Cloud brings together SAP Datasphere, SAP Analytics Cloud, and SAP Business Warehouse with a unified experience that delivers transformational insights across all lines of business.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To fully leverage benefits of SAP BDC in the Planning and Analytics area, it is worth to consider modernizing the Planning engine. &amp;nbsp;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) is the component that delivers cutting-edge analytics and planning capabilities while providing real-time insights powered by AI and machine learning. It integrates seamlessly with SAP Datasphere to offer a unified data analysis experience (&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-value-of-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-in-the-context-of-business/ba-p/14165827" target="_blank"&gt;The Value of SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) in The ... - SAP Community)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But how to get there? For those customers who are searching for a new planning engine the situation is clear. SAC is the clear strategic direction for the planning processes and xP&amp;amp;A. For those customers who are now using an SAP BW based planning engine like SAP BPC or BW-IP the path can be not as straightforward, so we are recommending evaluating the possible ways to start with SAP BDC as the future-state landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BPC PLANNING SCENARIOS WITHIN SAP BDC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are three scenarios how you can go forward with SAP Business Planning and Consolidation (SAP BPC) as part of SAP BDC.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on insights from the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-bpc-move-to-sac-benefits-scenarios-of-moving-sap-bpc-planning-scenarios/ba-p/13557405" target="_blank"&gt;original SAP blog on moving from SAP BPC to SAC&lt;/A&gt;, we would like to refresh and update scenarios of moving from SAP BPC —into the world of SAP BDC and SAC.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SCENARIO 1: MOVE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 1: Moving to SAC planning at your own pace" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322607iB4558C164FBA2727/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="irinashef_2-1759488490265.png" alt="Picture 1: Moving to SAC planning at your own pace" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 1: Moving to SAC planning at your own pace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Target Landscape: SAC Planning + BDC as the data foundation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the option where planning use cases would be completely&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;moved&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;from SAP BPC into SAC. In this case we talk about re-implementation, but you can still reuse some of the things that you have created. For example, you could build a SAC planning model based on the query that is coming from your SAP BPC (embedded model, running on the SAP BW system). That way all relevant dimensions (including its members and hierarchies) could be recreated quite easily.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;What´s new with SAP BDC?&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/seamless-planning-between-sap-analytics-cloud-and-sap-datasphere-is-coming/ba-p/13877664" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, links SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) with SAP Datasphere so that SAC model data (facts &amp;amp; master data) can be stored directly in Datasphere. This reduces data duplication, ensures real-time availability, and allows further processing and extension via Datasphere’s capabilities. ( &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/seamless-planning-between-sap-analytics-cloud-and-sap-datasphere-is-coming/ba-p/13877664" target="_blank"&gt;Seamless planning between SAP Analytics Cloud and ... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt; )&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part of BW modernisation process&lt;/STRONG&gt;. SAP Analytics cloud can &lt;STRONG&gt;replace&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP BPC and BW-IP, become the new modern planning engine and reduce dependency on SAP BW. It can help to shrink BW and together with SAP Profitability and Performance management solution and Datasphere can provide a foundation for an End-to-End enterprise performance management process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SCENARIO 2: COMPLEMENT (=LIVE Planning)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 2: Live Planning" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324704iC4232C3A4841DBD2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image.png" alt="Picture 2: Live Planning" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 2: Live Planning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this scenario we are using SAC as a planning/forecasting data entry UX and as well for data analysis (variance analysis in reports and dashboards for example). In other words, users enter data via the SAC data entry form, and the data is being persisted directly in the SAP BPC embedded planning model. No data is being stored in SAC whatsoever. This scenario allows to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Retain existing BPC / BW-IP models&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Provide attractive &amp;amp; powerful UX to end users for:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data entry&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analysis&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mobile iOS / Android apps (analysis only)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use SAC Catalog for unified access to all content&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;What´s new with SAP BDC? &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP BPC can be first migrated with BW into SAP BDC, modernizing data architecture. SAC can be introduced gradually, being a front end to existing SAP BPC embedded models and planning logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SCENARIO 3: ADD (Extend SAP BPC with SAC for new functional plans)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 3: Extend SAP BPC with SAC for new functional plans" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324382i35F8449FECE2668F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="{3A5595C9-099A-44F3-A99F-8B432DCB3704&amp;amp;#125;.png" alt="Picture 3: Extend SAP BPC with SAC for new functional plans" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 3: Extend SAP BPC with SAC for new functional plans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this scenario, we can build new functional plans on top of SAP BPC with SAC and then we provide integration (data is replicated in both directions between SAP BPC and SAC). A simple example of such integration could be to bring an initial version of sales forecast from SAP BPC model into SAC model (model – dimensions &amp;amp; measures; with data is being replicated from SAP BPC into SAC). In the next step predictive time series forecasting would be applied on top of forecast data stored in SAC model. If needed, users could perform some manual adjustments or allocations and when done the updated forecast would be replicated back to SAP BPC model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;What´s new with SAP BDC? &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As with Live scenario, SAP BPC can be first migrated with BW into SAP BDC, modernizing your data architecture. SAC can be introduced gradually, not only as front-end, but also as a planning engine, allowing phased transition into strategic solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For scenario 2+3 withing SAP BDC: BPC should be moved into BPC PCE of SAP BDC architecture. &amp;nbsp;This move is supported for BPC NetWeaver as well as BPC on BW/4HANA. See picture below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture 4: Migration of SAP BPC versions to SAP BDC" style="width: 326px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324707i9848CD8D1043EE72/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Picture4Migration.png" alt="Picture 4: Migration of SAP BPC versions to SAP BDC" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Picture 4: Migration of SAP BPC versions to SAP BDC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BUT WHY MAKE THIS MOVE?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are several strategic and technical benefits of SAP BPC PCE in SAP Business Data Cloud:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strategic Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Fully aligned with SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Follow the clean core principle: reduce custom extensions management costs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Application and technical operations from one vendor&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mainstream maintenance until 2030 for SAP BPC 10.1 and 2040 for SAP BPC 11&amp;nbsp; (BPC/4HANA)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Support for hybrid planning with both SAP BPC and SAC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scalable platform&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Continue to leverage SAP BW capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FINAL THOUGHT&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAC/SAP BDC emerging as the new standard, now is the time to choose your path forward. Whether you go all-in on SAC, transition gradually via SAP BW PCE on SAP BDC, or start with seamless integration — SAP Business Data Cloud ensures your planning is built on a trusted, unified data foundation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Would like to know more?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check out the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/02/17/sap-bpc-move-to-sac-benefits-scenarios-of-moving-sap-bpc-planning-scenarios-to-sap-analytics-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;BPC MOVE blog series&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and this further information to learn more about the transition from SAP BPC to SAP Analytics Cloud:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enabling BPC Runtime-license:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/3150518" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/3150518&lt;/A&gt;The SAP Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/2969947" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2969947&lt;/A&gt;provides you the latest information of the supported and unsupported planning functionalities when using an SAC Model based on a BPC Live connection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easily transition from BPC to SAC-P:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/cloud-analytics/move-planning.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/cloud-analytics/move-planning.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Note&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/3308697" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3308697&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;with SAP BPC Standard Migration guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ready to take the next step?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Start your cloud migration journey. Contact us at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="mailto:movebpc@sap.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow"&gt;movebpc@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to learn more about using SAP Analytics Cloud for Planning to migrate your SAP BPC investment to the Cloud and accelerate your business &amp;amp; financial transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please check out also SAP Note&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/3308697" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3308697&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;with SAP BPC Standard and BPC Embedded Migration guide (two migration guides pdfs).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;(Fairly) new to SAP Analytics Cloud?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find out how to apply the basics of modelling, planning, analysing and administration with SAP’s free learning resources on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journey/explore-sap-analytics-cloud?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-ExplSAPAnalyticsCloud" href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journey/explore-sap-analytics-cloud?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-ExplSAPAnalyticsCloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;. The learning journey is designed for business users who want to upskill and boost their careers. Check out even more role-based learning resources and opportunities to get certified in one place on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng" href="https://learning.sap.com/?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning site&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extend-existing-planning-scenarios-of-sap-bpc-bw-ip-in-sap-bdc/ba-p/14234247"/>
    <published>2025-10-07T07:24:40.796000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/why-the-sac-excel-add-in-matters/ba-p/14237116</id>
    <title>Why the SAC Excel Add-in Matters</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T13:16:29.730000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>gunesbt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/181359</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today's finance world, despite the rise of cloud platforms and AI-driven analytics, Excel remains deeply embedded in how finance teams work. Research suggests this isn't changing soon. Many organisations still rely on Excel alongside FP&amp;amp;A solutions and spreadsheets remain critical for flexibility, scenario building, and rapid adjustments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From a consultant perspective, I see this reflected in SAP's product evolution as well. With cloud first strategy, the early years of SAC focused on strengthening core web features. Looking at the roadmap holistically, the last few years there seems a clear acceleration in the excel integration via SAC Excel Add-in as well. In the early years of SAC’s Excel Add-in, I was a bit cautious about recommending it to the clients because even the core features especially for planning were limited. Over the past 2–3 years, the add-in has matured significantly (with still some limitations in place).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today, it is becoming a strong enabler for adoption in projects where finance teams depend heavily on Excel. Even in some areas, it provides greater flexibility. As an SAP Planning consultant, I personally love being able to use the SAP’s excel library along with excel formulas while designing flexible input templates.&amp;nbsp; In this blog, we’ll take a closer look at the SAC Excel Add-in’s core features, how to position it in projects, and where it fits into SAP’s roadmap for analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Evolution of Excel Integration in SAP Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="gunesbt_0-1759943106017.png" style="width: 924px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324849i60B0A5DF8E05E74E/image-dimensions/924x254/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="924" height="254" role="button" title="gunesbt_0-1759943106017.png" alt="gunesbt_0-1759943106017.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Excel integration is not new for SAP but it has been in the agenda for decades:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On-premise era&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Excel based analytics tools like BEX Analyzer, BPC (EPM add-in) and Analysis for Office (AfO) run on premise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud-first shift&lt;/STRONG&gt;: SAC was launched as a cloud-first product in 2015&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Excel Integration for SAC accelerates&lt;/STRONG&gt;: the first SAC Excel add-in appeared in 2020 with beta version with rapid investment in the upcoming years.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP makes it clear that its current strategy is &lt;STRONG&gt;cloud-first. &lt;/STRONG&gt;In practice what we see in the FP&amp;amp;A project is a &lt;STRONG&gt;cloud first with Excel flexibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The web interface remains the primary platform offering the full breadth of features including advanced visualisations, AI/ML capabilities, mobile access, collaboration features, workflows. However, I observed many clients still ask for excel integration especially for cases captured in below parts of the blog. SAP appears to have responded to this situation with the SAC Excel Add-in improving significantly. The add-in positioned as the strategic Excel interface for SAC going forward. 2025 July BI statement of direction confirms that AfO remains supported, (and the main excel interface for BW and BPC customers ), but no new features will be delivered. However, SAC Excel Add-in represents SAP's primary excel interface for cloud-based analytics and planning. More details are available along with comparison with AfO &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/comparison-of-sap-analysis-for-microsoft-office-sac-edition-vs-sac-add-in/ba-p/13783155" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This positioning reflects a pragmatic approach: rather than forcing finance teams to abandon Excel entirely, SAC excel add in becomes a bridge that combines cloud platform benefits with the Excel interface that finance professionals know and trust.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Features, Benefits &amp;amp; Limitations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I've grouped the features into 3 comparing Excel Add-in capabilities with the web interface where relevant. Note that all features/limitations reflect the state as of September 2025. The Add-in evolves rapidly, so this focuses on core capabilities rather than an exhaustive list.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Planning &amp;amp; Data Entry&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is where the Excel Add-in has improved most significantly over the past two years with many core planning features now integrated making it a strong complement to the web interface.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bulk data entry with excel formula support.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP excel add in supports mass data entry mode but single and fluid entry mode are available on web interface only. These entry modes provide some flexibility for different cases but I personally find “bulk data entry” in SAC excel add in quite smooth. It is not super easy to bring your offline excel data into SAC web templates although now you can copy-paste multiple cells with recent improvements. But real life scenarios require deeper excel integration with offline excel files. Let’s say an opex planner inputting budget data for 100 cost centers might maintain detailed driver calculations offline (regional KPIs, granular assumptions not in the central SAC model). In these type of cases, I have seen that the clients download web template to excel, blend it with their offline data and paste the output back to web. With the Excel Add-in, planners can use native Excel functions (VLOOKUP, FILTER etc.) directly within SAC-connected template to prepare and validate data before submission. This helps bridging the gap between centralized SAC planning models and the localized dataset that remain in Excel during implementations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Top-down or bottom-up planning.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Disaggregation function is available on excel add in and works the same way with web. If the cells are empty, the system will disaggregate equally else proportionally.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Triggering SAC calculations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Triggering data actions are supported including selection parameters. Multi actions are not supported at the moment which makes some cross model copy / calculation steps less flexible but it is in roadmap for Q2-26&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAC Formula library for Excel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAC Excel Add-in provides SAC-specific formulas (functions with the SAP. prefix) that enable advanced template capabilities. For example, SAP.GETDATA fetches a specific dataset, which helps build reports at cell level. SAP.MEMBERPROPERTY returns the property value of a specific dimension in the frontend to consume these values further (such as version start and end date). There are many other formulas for specific scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Combining these SAC formulas with Excel's native formula library (IFs, VLOOKUPs, etc.) provides great flexibility. A powerful application of this flexibility is asymmetric filtering. For instance a finance planner starts the budget process with September closed actuals and needs an input template with 9 months actuals + 3 months forecast + 12 months budget (very typical), here the web's "forecast layout" functionality is quite helpful. However, asymmetric filtering in the SAC Excel Add-in takes this further allowing developers to manage different template sections independently, each with its own time horizon and formula logic. See this great &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/build-a-dynamic-rolling-forecast-with-sap-analytics-cloud-add-in-for/ba-p/13945105" target="_blank"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; for detailed guidance on asymmetric filter function in the SAC Excel Add-in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value Driver Tree:&lt;/STRONG&gt; VDT is a web feature so it is not accessible in excel interface.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comments :&lt;/STRONG&gt; Data point comments are supported, but don't work on tables where asymmetric filter functionality is used&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calendar:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Excel workbooks integrate with web-based calendars, but accessing the calendar requires the web interface&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Excel Add-in focuses on&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;tabular data analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;, giving finance users a familiar environment to explore SAC data with Excel's formatting and analytical capabilities. For dashboards and advanced visualizations, use the web interface—Excel is not a replacement for SAC's visualization layer&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Core analytical operations&lt;/STRONG&gt; : filters, drill-downs, sorting, and ranking available on SAC excel add in.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Formatting&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Applying conditional formatting and thresholds are supported. Custom formatting is also possible supported by pre-built styling rules similar with AfO. You can select a master data in the table and apply specific format such as displaying actuals as grey (to highlight it is locked )while keeping other versions white.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;High-volume mode&lt;/STRONG&gt; will support more than 1 million cells soon (a planned Q4-25 only for analytics but not for planning).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Restricted measures&lt;/STRONG&gt; are supported but calculated measures not yet. Although not the same thing, you can still use add rows / columns functionality and write formulas instead&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI / ML Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Just ask, predictive planning, smart insights etc are accessed only via web add in&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Advanced visualizations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Dashboards, charts, geo maps etc available on web only.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Collaboration Features&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Excel add in is not supported on mobile devices. Works on desktop or web version of Office 365&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data point comments: Supported in Excel Add-in (with limitation: doesn't work with asymmetric table functionality)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Calendar: Excel workbooks integrate with web-based calendars; accessing calendar requires web interface&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discussion Panel: Chat is possible via chat only, not available on excel&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;When to Recommend the Excel Add-in&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Excel Add-in is not designed to replace the SAC web interface. Instead, it complements it by providing a familiar interface for Excel-dependent users. It can serve as an adoption enabler and a functional extension of SAC's capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recommend the Excel Add-in for:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Bulk data preparation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Where finance teams need to manipulate large datasets, combine offline calculations with SAC data, use Excel functions to prepare data before submission.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance teams heavily reliant on excel&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Finance teams who work primarily in Excel and would face significant change management challenges with a web-only interface.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Specific cases&lt;/STRONG&gt; where excel add in provides more flexibility such as combining SAC's formula library with Excel's native capabilities enabling dynamic time horizons via asymmetric filtering described above.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Project guidance:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To maximize the value of the Excel Add-in:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prototype early, ideally during the Explore phase.&lt;/STRONG&gt; This allows you to position the Excel Add-in more accurately, identify which processes truly benefit, and set appropriate expectations with stakeholders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Assess processes criticality.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Not all planning processes require deep Excel integration—some may be better served by the web interface alone.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Frame it as 'SAC with Excel flexibility'&lt;/STRONG&gt; rather than an either/or choice, emphasizing the web as the primary platform with Excel as a strategic complement for specific scenarios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Excel is not disappearing from finance. The SAC Excel Add-in addresses this reality by providing a bridge between modern SAC platform and the tool that finance teams trust. The add-in has evolved significantly over the past 2-3 years, with robust planning and core analytics capabilities that make it a genuine complement to the web interface, not a workaround.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In practice, its value goes beyond Excel-dependent teams or bulk data preparation. It also helps organisations manage change, easing the transition to cloud planning &amp;amp; analytics by letting users work in a familiar environment. Framing it as &lt;EM&gt;“SAC with Excel flexibility” &lt;/EM&gt;where the web interface remains the primary platform creates the right balance between innovation and familiarity. This approach helps organisations modernise their planning and analytics while keeping the comfort and agility of Excel.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/why-the-sac-excel-add-in-matters/ba-p/14237116"/>
    <published>2025-10-08T13:16:29.730000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-model-size-analysis-in-sac/ba-p/14238307</id>
    <title>SAP Business Data Cloud - Model Size Analysis in SAC</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T15:30:22.573000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_fery</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/259114</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2020161668"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Clearer View of Your Data: Introducing the New Model Size and Analysis Dashboard for SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;For administrators and system owners of SAP Analytics Cloud, maintaining a high-performing and stable environment is a top priority. As organizations expand their use of SAC, managing the underlying data volumes becomes increasingly important.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A technical consideration in this context are the database tables, which have a system limit of 2 billion records. Reaching this limit has a significant consequence: it blocks all data publishing for planning models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Until now, gaining proactive visibility into this data growth has been a challenge. Administrators often faced key questions without easy answers:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which of our hundreds of models are the largest and contributing most to our data footprint?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is the growth coming from transaction data, or is the audit log expanding rapidly?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In our largest models, which specific versions (e.g., Forecast, Budget 2025) are consuming the most space?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today, we are pleased to introduce a solution designed to provide clear answers to these questions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to access:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Open the story in your tenant by going to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Side Menu &amp;gt; Performance &amp;gt; Model Size Statistics and Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_0-1759929912175.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324698i94B3E265E7AF6708/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="thomas_fery_0-1759929912175.png" alt="thomas_fery_0-1759929912175.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1823648163"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing the "Model Size Statistics and Analysis" Dashboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Available with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2025.QRC4 release&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we are delivering a new Story in SAC Content designed to give you the transparency and control you need to manage your SAC tenant's data footprint effectively. This Story serves as a central overview for monitoring, analyzing, and then to be able to take an informed action on data volumes before they become a critical issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_0-1759928975319.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324681iAB201907951E5049/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="thomas_fery_0-1759928975319.png" alt="thomas_fery_0-1759928975319.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Let's explore its key capabilities.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1627134658"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Capabilities: From Overview to Actionable Insight&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This new Story empowers you with a multi-layered analytical approach:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1559703872"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Instantly Identify Your Largest Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The dashboard presents a clear, ranked list of your&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Top 30 Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;by total record count. This immediately answers the fundamental question: "Where is my data?" This allows you to focus your attention where it's needed most, without guesswork or manual checks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1363190367"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understand Data Composition with Category Breakdowns&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Once you select a model, the dashboard reveals a breakdown by&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Category&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. You can clearly see the ratio of Transaction Data, Audit Data, Master Data, and more. This is crucial for understanding the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;nature&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;of your model's size. Is it growing because of massive data loads, or is it the audit trail from frequent planning activities?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1166676862"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Uncover Version-Level Insights (Even in Large Models)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;This is a significant enhancement. Previously, for models exceeding 100 million records, it was not possible to see the size of individual public versions within the Modeler. The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Model Size and Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;dashboard removes this limitation. You can now select a large model and see a clear chart showing which versions are the biggest contributors. This provides the information you need to target specific versions for cleanup or archiving&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_1-1759929036237.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324683i75008790B45AA47D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="thomas_fery_1-1759929036237.png" alt="thomas_fery_1-1759929036237.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-970163357"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Correlate Growth with System Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The dashboard provides historical charts that track record growth over time. More importantly, it overlays this data with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Import Jobs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Version Publish Events&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. You can now visually correlate a spike in data with a specific data load or a major publishing cycle, creating a clear cause-and-effect relationship. This helps you understand&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;why&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;when&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;your data is growing, enabling you to optimize your data management processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_2-1759929103872.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324684iD4E1C8EAC4DB52DF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="thomas_fery_2-1759929103872.png" alt="thomas_fery_2-1759929103872.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-644567133"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Business Value: More Than Just Numbers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This dashboard delivers tangible business value by transforming how you manage your SAC environment:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ensure Business Continuity:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;By proactively monitoring the Audit and Fact table limits, you can prevent a system-wide pause on planning operations, safeguarding critical business processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable Proactive Housekeeping:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Move from a reactive to a proactive stance. Analyze data growth trends, identify old or unnecessary versions, and perform timely cleanup actions to keep your tenant lean and performant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create Actionable Transparency:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The dashboard doesn't just provide data; it provides answers. You can now confidently explain data growth and justify housekeeping activities to business stakeholders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reduce Resource Consumption &amp;amp; Improve Performance:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;A well-maintained tenant with optimized data volumes naturally performs better. By cleaning up unnecessary data, you reduce the load on the system, leading to a better experience for all users.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get started today!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Once your tenant is updated to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2025.QRC4&lt;/STRONG&gt;, explore this new content and take command of your data. Empower yourself with the insight to ensure your SAP Analytics Cloud environment remains stable, performant, and ready for the future.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-model-size-analysis-in-sac/ba-p/14238307"/>
    <published>2025-10-08T15:30:22.573000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
