<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-S4HANA-Public-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-09-07T05:01:50.991221+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud/pd-p/08e2a51b-1ce5-4367-8b33-4ae7e8b702e0" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/now-available-earn-your-sap-central-business-configuration-badge/ba-p/14192474</id>
    <title>Now Available: Earn Your SAP Central Business Configuration Badge!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T10:47:44.961000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FabianAckermann</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131646</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We're excited to announce that you can now earn a badge for completing the &lt;A title="Configuring SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition with SAP Central Business Configuration" href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/configuring-sap-s4hana-cloud-public-edition-with-sap-central-business-configuration/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition with SAP Central Business Configuration&lt;/A&gt; course. This course was previously available as a learning journey but has now been transformed into a standalone course, bringing a major added benefit: a badge that verifies your knowledge and expertise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Course landing page" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305017i9971F0358880EFEF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="CBC Learning Course.png" alt="Course landing page" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Course landing page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The course is designed to guide you through the entire process of using SAP Central Business Configuration from end to end. Just like before, the course offers a mix of short texts, graphics, videos, and interactive tutorials, along with access to a practice system to enhance your learning experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What's New? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Upon completion of the course and successfully passing the knowledge quiz, you will receive a badge that attests to your mastery of the course content. This badge serves as a valuable addition to your professional profile, highlighting your skills and understanding of SAP Central Business Configuration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Badge receipt upon course completion" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305020i934D031EC70E3F74/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="CBC Learning Course Quiz Badge.png" alt="Badge receipt upon course completion" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Badge receipt upon course completion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Manage and Showcase Your Badge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;View your badge:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Once you've completed the course and passed the quiz, you can view your badge under &lt;EM&gt;My Learning &amp;gt; Activity &amp;gt; Completed&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add to LinkedIn profile:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Optionally, you can add the badge to your LinkedIn profile to showcase your achievement to your professional network.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Share on LinkedIn feed:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;You can also share your accomplishment directly on your LinkedIn feed to let your connections know about your new skill.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Download as PDF:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;You can also download your badge as a PDF for easy sharing and record-keeping.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We believe that this badge will not only recognize your hard work and knowledge but also add significant value to your professional credentials. Don't miss out on this opportunity to stand out in your field.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to Start? &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Log on to SAP Learning and enroll in the &lt;A title="Configuring SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition with SAP Central Business Configuration" href="https://learning.sap.com/courses/configuring-sap-s4hana-cloud-public-edition-with-sap-central-business-configuration/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configuring SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition with SAP Central Business Configuration&lt;/A&gt; course today.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you liked this blog, please leave us a thumbs up at the top. Also, make sure to follow the&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Central Business Configuration&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;tag or follow this dedicated&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="blog collection" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-central-business-configuration-blog-collection/ba-p/13580678" target="_blank"&gt;blog collection&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to stay up to date with the latest blog posts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/now-available-earn-your-sap-central-business-configuration-badge/ba-p/14192474"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T10:47:44.961000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/unpacking-the-new-sap-business-suite/ba-p/14191891</id>
    <title>Unpacking the new SAP Business Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T15:11:00.704000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marco_Valencia</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125232</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This blog intends to provide a quick explanation of the newly announced SAP Business Suite. The blog contains the latest information as of August 26th 2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In February 2025, SAP announced the new SAP Business Suite (&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/business-unleashed.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/business-unleashed.html&lt;/A&gt;), which was also covered in detail at our prime SAP SAPPHIRE events in Orlando, Madrid, and all the SAP Now events around the world. But you might be wondering what the new SAP Business Suite is.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Simply put, the SAP Business Suite helps our customers drive business innovation to achieve more valuable business outcomes in a constantly changing economy—by uniting core SAP business applications, data, and Business AI capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="New SAP Business Suite" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304875i868AF7C60AFE1285/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="A.jpg" alt="New SAP Business Suite" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;New SAP Business Suite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-suite/what-is-sap-business-suite.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Suite&lt;/A&gt; is not simply a harmonization of release and maintenance schedules for SAP’s portfolio of solutions. It serves as a transformation engine, helping customers generate rapid cycles of innovation and continuous improvement as a service. This enables organizations to deliver greater business value and achieve improved outcomes through end-to-end processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP’s Business Suite applications (like SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, SAP SuccessFactors, SAP Concur, etc.) and SAP Business Technology Platform aren’t just siloed applications; they are integrated along end to end business process, supporting you in every business decision and outcome. This integration ensures that every action taken within these applications generates trusted, business-critical data at its source.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Within the SAP Business Suite, we have also integrated the SAP Business Data Cloud. The SAP Business Data Cloud was also announced in February 2025 . The SAP Business Data Cloud centralizes, harmonizes, and enriches the data produced by the SAP applications and non-SAP applications. So the SAP Business Data Cloud helps us unify data into a single source of truth. Now if this data is contextualized, reliable, and accessible, this data becomes the fuel for advanced AI-driven insights. SAP Business AI, included in the SAP Business Suite, goes beyond basic automation. Through SAP Joule, our AI copilot and the embedded AI capabilities in our applications, employees can orchestrate intelligent agents to collaborate across functions or get enhanced scenarios to increase productivity. This strategy breaks down silos, driving real-time, cross-enterprise optimization. We know our customers are deploying AI in isolated projects, but with our SAP Business Suite strategy, we weave it throughout your organization, unlocking value and resilience at scale.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s get practical and explain how our customers consume the SAP Business Suite as a service. Next, I will cover the new SAP Business Suite Packages and the journey our customers can follow to implement them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP has created buying center-based packages which provide our customers with defined functional capabilities within our core applications portfolio, data, and Business AI. &amp;nbsp;The idea is that the package can provide all the necessary capabilities for this buying center and its teams to carry out their responsibilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="New buying center-based SAP Business Suite Packages" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304876i65048956486271C0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="B.jpg" alt="New buying center-based SAP Business Suite Packages" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;New buying center-based SAP Business Suite Packages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, SAP is providing two journeys for our customers so they can consume the SAP Business Suite as a service. The journeys are RISE with SAP and GROW with SAP. Before the February 2025 announcement, RISE with SAP was focused on our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition, and GROW with SAP was focused on our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Customer Journeys to New SAP Business Suite" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304877i7E7E30878320DBEC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="C.jpg" alt="Customer Journeys to New SAP Business Suite" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Customer Journeys to New SAP Business Suite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following the introduction of the SAP Business Suite, we have evolved our programs and made several enhancements to the commercial packages supporting these journeys to better serve our customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;RISE with SAP is a journey focused on existing SAP ERP on-premise customers who are looking to modernize their legacy systems with SAP Business Suite, while GROW with SAP is a journey focused on new SAP ERP customers looking to start fresh with SAP Business Suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We also made changes to some names to group our solutions. We now refer to everything relevant to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition and its extended capabilities offered in the SAP Business Suite Packages as "&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;," and everything relevant to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition and the extended capabilities offered in the SAP Business Suite Packages as "&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ERP Private&lt;/STRONG&gt;."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, how do we align the SAP Business Suite packages with the customer journeys?&amp;nbsp; In the figure, you can see that customers have options depending on their SAP journey and buying center. These packages can also be consumed by buying center or brought together for the entire company and buying centers. If you would like to learn more about our packages and what is included, I suggest you visit this link: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-suite/pricing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/business-suite/pricing.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Buying center-based packages that enable customer journeys to the new SAP Business Suite" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304878i4CFEAD6D9D91B6E7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="D.jpg" alt="Buying center-based packages that enable customer journeys to the new SAP Business Suite" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Buying center-based packages that enable customer journeys to the new SAP Business Suite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, I want to focus more on the journeys and packages that have traditionally covered ERP functionalities by highlighting the CIO buying center and the needs of a company-wide system, including other C-suite buying centers who rely on ERP as a comprehensive solution to streamline the introduction of this concept. I won’t cover other subscriptions like add-ons, data product packages, and AI packages included in the SAP Business Suite, etc., to keep it simple and easy to understand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's begin with &lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud ERP Private.&lt;/STRONG&gt; This package is designed to provide customers with tailored-to-fit functionality, a very flexible system in which they maintain the governance of the system while SAP supports operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; is included; however, this package encompasses many more capabilities and components compared to traditional ERP (SAP ERP 6.0). The following components are included:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Components included in Cloud ERP Private Package - This content is subject to change. For the most current details, please refer to the link below" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304879iCE22DA8C798804C2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1.jpg" alt="Components included in Cloud ERP Private Package - This content is subject to change. For the most current details, please refer to the link below" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Components included in Cloud ERP Private Package - This content is subject to change. For the most current details, please refer to the link below&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Management packages include many different SAP components supporting the CFO and COO buying centers in running their business responsibilities. Here is where you find &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a system designed to drive business standardization using a fit-to-standard approach, with rapid and agile innovation cycles, operated and governed by SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each of these packages includes two types of sub-packages: Base and Premium. The idea is to provide customers with flexibility when deciding on the main capabilities for each buying center. Below, I present the capabilities of the two packages:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Components included in SAP Finance Package - This content is subject to change. For the most current details, please refer to the link below" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304880iFB5712CF0FBC0B31/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.jpg" alt="Components included in SAP Finance Package - This content is subject to change. For the most current details, please refer to the link below" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Components included in SAP Finance Package - This content is subject to change. For the most current details, please refer to the link below&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Components included in SAP Supply Chain Package - This content is subject to change. For the most current details, please refer to the link below" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304881iD44CCB10162138BA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.jpg" alt="Components included in SAP Supply Chain Package - This content is subject to change. For the most current details, please refer to the link below" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Components included in SAP Supply Chain Package - This content is subject to change. For the most current details, please refer to the link below&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can see from the packages, the entitlements provided encompass more comprehensive capabilities and components compared to the standalone SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, offering greater business benefits and functional features.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To view the current packages and included latest capabilities, please refer to: &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-suite/pricing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/products/business-suite/pricing.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sample Customer Journeys:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP ERP 6.0 customer looking to move to the new SAP Business Suite.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This customer will use the &lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP customer journey&lt;/STRONG&gt; to move to the new SAP Business Suite. Here, the customer will have the option to select between various packages depending on their business needs. Considering that this customer runs full capabilities (FI-CO, SD, MM, PP, QM, etc.) in SAP ERP 6.0, below are the choices:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Customer Journey – RISE with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304882i737EA18862866304/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4.jpg" alt="Customer Journey – RISE with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Customer Journey – RISE with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP will support the customer with the selection of the right packages by using the SAP Digital Discovery Assessment (SAP DDA). The SAP DDA helps the customer assess functional needs and provides recommendations accordingly. However, it is important to note that the packages are meant to serve two distinct business purposes: &lt;EM&gt;Cloud ERP Private&lt;/EM&gt;—tailored-to-fit functionality with a highly flexible system where the customer maintains governance while SAP supports operations—and &lt;EM&gt;SAP Finance &amp;amp; SAP Supply Chain&lt;/EM&gt;, which is designed to drive business standardization using a fit-to-standard approach, featuring rapid and agile innovation cycles, and operated and governed by SAP. &amp;nbsp;While the SAP DDA assesses functional requirements, the customer must decide on their main strategy: whether to implement and operate their systems with a tailored-to-fit solution or embrace a fit-to-standard model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Digital Discovery Assessment" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304883iEC85A8B71AF26B82/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.jpg" alt="SAP Digital Discovery Assessment" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;SAP Digital Discovery Assessment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now let's talk a bit more in detail about the journey based on the package selection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud ERP Private&lt;/STRONG&gt; – An SAP ERP 6.0 customer needs tailored-to-fit functionality, with a very flexible system in which they maintain governance of the system while SAP supports operations. This customer has selected the Cloud ERP Private Package. Here, they first need to plan their journey to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Private Edition from SAP ERP 6.0 using one of the known transition paths: &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/recommendations-for-greenfield-implementations-of-rise-with-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/13566050" target="_blank"&gt;New Implementation&lt;/A&gt;, Selective Data Transition, or System Conversion. They will benefit from the use of transformation tools and services included in the package and can also take advantage of the other components included in the package.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the help of the transformation tools included in the package, in conjunction with the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/rise/methodology.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;RISE with SAP methodology&lt;/A&gt;, we recommend that our customers pursue a &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/rise/methodology/clean-core.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;clean core strategy&lt;/A&gt;, so they can remain technically ready in a cost-effective manner to be agile to consume new SAP innovations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Customer Journey – RISE with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite via Cloud ERP Private Package" style="width: 982px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304884i3FDF74C0DC781367/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6.jpg" alt="Customer Journey – RISE with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite via Cloud ERP Private Package" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Customer Journey – RISE with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite via Cloud ERP Private Package&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Management packages&lt;/STRONG&gt; – An SAP ERP 6.0 customer decided on a state-of-the-art system designed to drive business standardization using a fit-to-standard approach, with rapid and agile innovation cycles and operated and governed by SAP. This customer has selected the SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Management packages. Here, they first need to plan their journey to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition from &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerated-business-transformation-moving-from-sap-erp-6-0-to-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/13957993" target="_blank"&gt;SAP ERP 6.0 using a New Implementation&lt;/A&gt;. They will benefit from using SAP Activate, the SAP Signavio Process Navigator, and SAP Cloud ALM to drive their implementation, and can also take advantage of the other components included in the package (either base or premium).&amp;nbsp; And remember, SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition is clean core by definition, using &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/drive-competitive-advantage-through-differentiation-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud/ba-p/13569694" target="_blank"&gt;cloud extensibility&lt;/A&gt; included in the solution to help our customers differentiate.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Customer Journey – RISE with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite via SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Packages" style="width: 971px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304885i78841487AB19E192/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="7.jpg" alt="Customer Journey – RISE with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite via SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Packages" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Customer Journey – RISE with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite via SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Packages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make the most of all the components included in these packages, the SAP Activate Methodology has been enhanced, and there is now a new roadmap available for &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/new-sap-activate-provisioning-road-map-for-sap-business-suite-packages/ba-p/14154341" target="_blank"&gt;provisioning SAP Business Suite Packages&lt;/A&gt;. I highly recommend using it to take full advantage of the additional components offered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="New SAP Activate for provisioning new SAP Business Suite Packages" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304886i6BB36F1607E6D203/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="8.jpg" alt="New SAP Activate for provisioning new SAP Business Suite Packages" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;New SAP Activate for provisioning new SAP Business Suite Packages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;New SAP customer looking to move to the new SAP Business Suite.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This customer will use the GROW with SAP customer journey to move to the new SAP Business Suite. Here, the customer will be defaulted to the SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain packages, as our SAP Cloud ERP is the most transformational one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, if the new customer might be looking for more tailored-to-fit functionality—a very flexible system in which they maintain the governance of the system while SAP supports operations—the Cloud ERP Package can be offered after the review with the SAP Digital Discovery Assessment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Customer Journey – GROW with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite via SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Packages" style="width: 977px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304887i8B5AA04B4B95C755/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="9.jpg" alt="Customer Journey – GROW with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite via SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Packages" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Customer Journey – GROW with SAP – Final Destination SAP Business Suite via SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Packages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As indicated before to make the most of all the components included in these SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Management packages, the SAP Activate Methodology has been enhanced, and there is now a new roadmap available for &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/new-sap-activate-provisioning-road-map-for-sap-business-suite-packages/ba-p/14154341" target="_blank"&gt;provisioning SAP Business Suite Packages&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;o, what about the other SAP Business Suite packages—SAP Strategic Procurement, SAP Core HR, and SAP CX?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These packages were designed based on personas. They provide our customers with defined functional capabilities within our core applications portfolio, data, and Business AI for a specific line of business. However, in combination with the Cloud ERP Private Package or the SAP Finance &amp;amp; SAP Supply Chain Management Package, they can offer even greater business benefits.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So, as in the example above, if an SAP ERP 6.0 customer is also running a legacy SAP ERP HCM system, they can adopt the new package for SAP Core HR to run SAP SuccessFactors and help them manage strategic human resources with solutions like SuccessFactors Employee Central, SuccessFactors Employee Central Payroll, SuccessFactors Time Tracking, etc. SAP SuccessFactors is the next-generation cloud HR product, and this is where we are recommending our customers to move.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the SAP ERP 6.0 customer is running a legacy SAP SRM 7.0 or any other legacy system to manage strategic sourcing, contract management, or is looking to implement these capabilities, they can choose SAP Strategic Procurement—an integrated solution bundle for managing the source-to-contract process through sourcing, contract management, supplier lifecycle, and performance management. Included solutions are: SAP Ariba Sourcing, SAP Ariba Contracts, SAP Ariba Supplier Lifecycle and Performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the SAP ERP 6.0 customer is running a legacy SAP CRM 7.0 or any other legacy system to manage comprehensive sales management, service management, or marketing capabilities, then the SAP CX Package (to be delivered in Q3 2025) can help the customer leverage the latest CX portfolio, such as SAP Sales Cloud and SAP Service Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="All Business Suite Packages that are available to existing on-premises SAP ERP 6.0 customers through the RISE with SAP customer journey" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304888i7F606CB7D631E442/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="10.jpg" alt="All Business Suite Packages that are available to existing on-premises SAP ERP 6.0 customers through the RISE with SAP customer journey" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;All Business Suite Packages that are available to existing on-premises SAP ERP 6.0 customers through the RISE with SAP customer journey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The same availability of SAP Business Suite Packages can be provided to a new SAP customer to complement the SAP Finance and SAP Supply Chain Management Packages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="All Business Suite Packages that are available to new SAP customers through the GROW with SAP customer journey" style="width: 652px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304889i446A31EA12283A43/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="11.jpg" alt="All Business Suite Packages that are available to new SAP customers through the GROW with SAP customer journey" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;All Business Suite Packages that are available to new SAP customers through the GROW with SAP customer journey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As indicated before, the new SAP Business Suite is not just a harmonization of a release and maintenance schedule of SAP’s portfolio of solutions. It’s a transformation engine that helps customers create rapid cycles of innovation end-to-end and continuous improvement as a service. In this regard, SAP is planning to make running the SAP Business Suite easier for customers and is planning to manage the integration of components. Early next year, SAP plans to begin offering SAP Cloud ERP + SAP Core HR managed integration as a service and will continue to introduce more in the future. Of course, these plans are subject to change.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We believe the new SAP Business Suite will help our customers gain more business outcomes by unlocking value and resilience at scale by combining core applications, data and business AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to thank my colleagues, &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Daniel Kesenheimer, Elena Tewari, Matt Emmert &amp;amp; Marcus Venth&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;, for their review and feedback on this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your insights and opinions are valuable, so please don't hesitate to contribute by commenting on this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More Information on SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, release info&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud/product-releases" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Product videos on our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLWV533hWWvDnnyN2j-CcUheNN-GaNCb3H" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLWV533hWWvDnmdq6Ps2LZLybNjZWy5A2b" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;YouTube playlist&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA PSCC Digital Enablement Wheel&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://chart-bdmaicr0au.dispatcher.eu2.hana.ondemand.com/index.html?hc_reset" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Early Release Webinar Series&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2020/11/11/sap-s-4hana-cloud-early-release-series-watch-replays-on-demand/?preview_id=1218772" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Inside SAP S/4HANA Cloud Podcast&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/inside-sap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;openSAP Microlearnings for SAP S/4HANA&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://microlearning.opensap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Best practices for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/2408?region=DE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Community:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Feature Scope Description&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/7c9e0bbbd1664c2581b2038a1c7ae4b3/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What’s New&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/doc/ce01d82756b947a1a043a5d5a3204226/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Help Portal Product Page&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/p/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/solutions/grow-with-sap/about/test_demo.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition trial, test, demo, and development&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; (SAP partner access)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud-abap-environment" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud ABAP environment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Follow us via&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://twitter.com/sap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;@SAP&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and #S4HANA or follow&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/125232" target="_blank"&gt;@Marco_Valencia&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/unpacking-the-new-sap-business-suite/ba-p/14191891"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T15:11:00.704000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14193023</id>
    <title>Solution Order Management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T17:24:51.592000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Greg_Hutcheon1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131650</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Welcome to the 2508 update for everyone looking to grow their revenues with solution-based business models&amp;nbsp; powered by SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition! As always, there’s a lot to get excited about with this release of the cloud ERP and you can &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/highlights-of-the-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-release/ba-p/14163726" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;find out about a few of the spotlight features from head of Cloud ERP Product Success Bert Schulze&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. In this blog we’ll zoom in on new features in the Solution Order Management area which you can put straight into use to grow your solution selling prowess.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you’re short on time, my AI alter-ego gives a quick summary of the key highlights in the below video….&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_9n6b9c6j" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let's dive into the details of each feature.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Introducing Service Bundles in Solution Orders&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/advanced-solution-bundling-for-solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana/ba-p/13779621" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution bundles&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; have been supported since 2024, enabling the sale of pre-defined stand-alone packages which consist of a mixture of multiple item types, such as physical goods, services and subscription products. With 2502, we expanded on this capability more with the introduction of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2502/ba-p/14017340" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;bundle pricing for greater flexibility&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and now in 2508, we again grow the bundle selling capability of Solution Order Management by supporting Service Bundles. From this release, users can benefit from the inclusion of service bundles, either with a fixed-price or time-and-material service bundles, in their solution orders.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By selling pre-defined packages that can be automatically exploded into their individual components, you not only reduce manual maintenance effort but also minimize the risk of input errors. These service bundles offer robust capabilities similar to a standard service order, including contract determination, price calculation, and more. Once you release a service bundle—or a broader solution bundle containing one—the system automatically generates the corresponding follow-up service order, streamlining the entire fulfilment process from delivery of products to executing the service.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_ug72qy8p" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Flexible Quantity for Subscription Billing Items&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A key facet of solution orders is the ability to sell subscriptions alongside further item types in a single solution order. However, a significant limitation in previous releases was the inability to specify a quantity greater than one for subscription-based items in a solution order. If a customer wished to purchase 20 licenses for 20 different pieces of equipment in a solution order, the highly inefficient process of creating 20 separate subscription line items was required to record and bill corresponding usage data. This not only created excessive manual data entry but also resulted in bloated order documents and complex reporting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the 2508 release, we address this operational bottleneck. Within the `Manage Solution Orders` app, the quantity field for any line item categorized for subscription billing is no longer restricted. Users can now simply enter the desired quantity—for instance, 20—in a single line item. In the item view, you’ll see both the aggregated net price for all subscriptions in that item and a detailed breakdown for each individual subscription. Managing them is easier than ever, too: every generated subscription is clearly listed in the transaction history and fully visible in the progress monitor, so you can track execution from order entry through fulfillment with complete transparency. This simple yet critical change radically streamlines the sales process for multi-unit subscriptions and reduces the potential for data entry errors.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_8gp6ju5a" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution Bundle Pricing for Subscription Products&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whilst we’re on the subject of subscriptions, another key feature being rolled out with the 2508 builds on the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2502/ba-p/14017340" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;bundle pricing functionality linked above&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. With this release, we now support subscription products with bundle specific pricing meaning subscription products can now have special bundle-specific prices maintained directly in your Subscription Billing tenant, based on solution bundle information. Using the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Manage Lookup Table Data&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; app in master data, you can define tailored pricing for subscription items sold as part of a bundle and easily compare it to the price of the same product sold standalone. This flexibility lets you create more attractive offers that encourage customers to choose bundled solutions—driving higher revenue for your solution business. When you release a solution order containing a bundle, the follow-up subscription is generated automatically, with the bundle ID retained for accurate pricing application and easy tracking throughout the subscription lifecycle.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_j061qlkz" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Flexible determination of dates in solution order processing&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With 2508, we have enhanced the flexibility of solution selling by enabling the adjustment of certain date parameters in a solution order.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;In many industries, particularly those with long sales cycles or international operations, a single order date is insufficient. For example, a contract might be signed in one fiscal period, but delivery and invoicing occur in the next, requiring a different posting date for accurate operational reporting. Similarly, pricing might be fixed based on a promotional period that has already passed, or a customer may request a specific future delivery date that dictates logistics planning. Without the ability to set these dates independently, organizations resort to manual overrides or complex workarounds which could introduce a higher risk of errors in revenue recognition, customer billing, and supply chain execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With this in mind, we’ve enabled more flexible date entry within the `Manage Solution Orders` application. Users can now explicitly set and manage several key dates at the solution order header level and under the new enhanced date profile on the sales item level.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Posting Date: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Used for reporting and search purposes in the solution order.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pricing Date: Determines the exact date for which price conditions, exchange rates, and taxes are applied, allowing for precise control over contract profitability&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Billing Date: Sets the baseline date for generating billing documents, providing flexibility in scheduling customer invoices.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Requested Delivery Date: The date communicated by the customer for when goods or services should be received. This date is now a primary input for the Available-to-Promise (ATP) check and subsequent delivery scheduling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This granularity ensures that each downstream process—from logistics to finance—is driven by the correct temporal data, leading to greater accuracy and process automation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2508_datefields.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305195i7FF136F807B61A7B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2508_datefields.png" alt="2508_datefields.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tolerant Handling of Incomplete Sales Orders: Incompleteness Checks for Sales Orders from &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Solution Orders&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By using sales order type OR, you can create sales orders directly from a solution order even when some mandatory information is missing, thanks to built-in incompleteness checks. This means follow-up documents can still be generated, while the system flags any missing data for review. In the progress monitor, these sales orders appear in a distinct red status, making it clear that action is needed. Incompleteness procedures help you identify and address gaps before further processing, and any orders with incomplete information are clearly listed in the SAP Fiori app “List Incomplete Sales Documents”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2508_incompletenessChecks.png" style="width: 816px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305193iE2CBCD2819CC8AF8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2508_incompletenessChecks.png" alt="2508_incompletenessChecks.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Contract Accounts Supported for Service Contract Items&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the 2508 release, service contract items in Solution Order Management now support FI-CA (Contract Accounts Receivable and Payable)—a specialized subledger for high-volume billing and receivables. Building on functionality first introduced in 2502 for sales and subscription items, contract accounts can be maintained at both header and item levels, transferred to follow-up documents on release, and posted directly to FI-CA for streamlined invoicing, payment handling, and financial tracking. This integration centralizes financial data, improves billing accuracy, and provides a clear, consolidated view of customer transactions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pricing Analysis in Solution Orders&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In the 2508 release of Solution Order Management, a new price analysis capability makes it easier than ever to verify that pricing has been executed correctly on sales order items, service order items, and service contract items. A newly added Analyze button in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Price Details&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; view lets you drill down into a comprehensive price breakdown for each solution order item, with full visibility into how each price condition was determined. This gives you greater transparency, control, and confidence in your pricing—right where you need it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2508_PricingAnalysis.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305192i2DC3D8D96DFC5076/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2508_PricingAnalysis.png" alt="2508_PricingAnalysis.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Partner data enabled on item level for sales items&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A solution sale can often involve multiple stakeholders. With this in mind, in 2508, we enable the partner determination procedure `SAI00003` for sales item categories within solution orders. This enhancement allows users to navigate to any sales line item in the `Manage Solution Orders` app and specify unique partner functions. You can now have one line item with a specific ship-to party and end-user, and another line item within the same order with completely different partners. This information then flows seamlessly to all follow-up documents generated from the solution order, ensuring that deliveries are routed to the correct addresses and invoices are sent to the appropriate contacts, all while maintaining the integrity of the single, comprehensive solution order.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Solution Order Management OData API V4 Enhancements&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the previous release, we introduced the enhanced solution order OData V4 API. This updated API optimizes communication, reduces data transfer payloads, and enhances request handling for faster processing and lower resource use, leading to quicker response times and a better user experience. It supports full CRUD operations for managing solution order items, so with 2508 we have expanded its scope to include the new functions described above, including subscription items with greater quantities, and service bundles. Importantly, we have rounded-off the ability to create a solution order touch-free by now supporting subscription billing items via the API operations, enabling specialists to generate solution orders entirely via API containing all possible item types. Additionally, it is easier to identify the documents created from the solution order for further processing and set this up without manual intervention.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A further API enhancement we are excited to introduce with this release enables you to simulate a solution order in an external quotation system to get accurate and up-to-date values. This is a big step towards more seamless order entry, enabling customers to generate quotes with minimal revisions, delivering a faster turn-around time for quotation conversion and order fulfilment. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2508_API_Simu.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305194i8FEEC4BA8F339AE3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2508_API_Simu.png" alt="2508_API_Simu.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1276484453" id="toc-hId-1609673706"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;If you are interested in the latest and greatest blog posts on Manufacturing, please have a look at my&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-the/ba-p/13627530" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;collection blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and also take a look at the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud/solution-business" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;community page for solution business.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1756221650040.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305196i3659EA0C62E8FC3E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1756221650040.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_0-1756221650040.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the Replays of Our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;  &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From July 21 to July 25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for Enterprise Portfolio and Project Management as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– anywhere, anytime.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1756221650043.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305197i5785B72CB3839359/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1756221650043.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_1-1756221650043.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find All of Our Assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;  &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1756221650040.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305198i12870BB66CD356E4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1756221650040.png" alt="Greg_Hutcheon1_2-1756221650040.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/solution-order-management-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14193023"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T17:24:51.592000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/localization-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14194767</id>
    <title>Localization in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T10:35:37.441000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MirellaVorsprach</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1861399</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello and welcome to this blog covering the release highlights for localization in SAP S/4HANA Cloud 2508. In our mission to help you run your business everywhere, we are continuously expanding our global footprint and enhancing our solutions to meet the specific legal and business requirements of countries around the world. This release is packed with significant advancements, including a brand-new local version for Vietnam, a peek into the future with AI for tax calculations, major strides in our self-service localization tools, and expanded integration with Taulia.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1867875790"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Localization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Vietnam Local Version&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Beta Campaign AI understanding tax calculation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CLT GA and LaaSS&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Taulia Integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Help Documentation/ Release restriction Note&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s dive into the details!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1671362285"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expanding Our Global Reach: Welcome, Vietnam!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are very proud to announce the delivery of our latest local version for Vietnam. This addition empowers businesses to operate seamlessly within the Vietnamese market, ensuring full compliance with local financial regulations and business practices right out of the box.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value Proposition:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This new local version significantly reduces the complexity and risk of entering or operating in the Vietnamese market. By providing pre-configured content that adheres to local laws and standards, we enable you to accelerate your implementation, ensure compliance, and focus on your core business activities with confidence in your financial data and reporting.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Capabilities:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The Vietnam local version is a comprehensive package designed to meet your core financial needs. It includes a country-specific chart of accounts mapped to the Vietnamese Accounting Standards (VAS) and pre-configured VAT and withholding tax procedures. To meet statutory requirements, we deliver critical reporting capabilities, including the VAT report and declaration, and a specific withholding tax report (form 01/NTNN). You can also manage electronic invoicing for outbound scenarios and generate key financial statements like the trial balance, balance sheet, and profit and loss reports, all formatted according to VAS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1474848780"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Glimpse into the Future: AI-Powered Tax Calculation Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine a world where complex tax calculations are no longer a black box. We are currently running a beta campaign for a groundbreaking feature that uses the power of SAP Business AI and our digital assistant, Joule, to provide instant clarity on tax determination. This is a significant step forward in making tax management more transparent and user-friendly.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value Proposition:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This innovation empowers finance users by providing on-demand, easy-to-understand explanations for tax calculations directly within their workflow. This transparency saves valuable time, reduces the risk of posting errors, and allows for proactive corrections, ultimately leading to more accurate financial data and improved operational efficiency.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Capabilities:&lt;/STRONG&gt; With "Understanding tax calculations," users can ask Joule how the tax in a specific business document was calculated. Joule will provide a clear, contextual explanation of the tax determination, detailing the specific parameters and rules that influenced the outcome. This allows users to make informed decisions and any necessary corrections *before* an item is posted, moving from reactive problem-solving to proactive validation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Register for Beta testing here: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#campaign/3981" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Understanding Tax Calculations with Joule - Customer Influence Page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Testing scope is limited to Sales Order Posting for India&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1278335275"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Empowering You: Localization-as-a-Self-Service (LaaSS) and CLT General Availability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Flexibility and customer empowerment are at the heart of our strategy. With the 2508 release, we are thrilled to announce that the Configuration Localization Tool (CLT) is now generally available. This, combined with our ongoing Localization-as-a-Self-Service (LaaSS) innovations, gives you unprecedented control to extend SAP S/4HANA Cloud to countries beyond our standard delivered versions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value Proposition:&lt;/STRONG&gt; CLT and our LaaSS innovations provide you with the speed and agility to support your global business rollouts. You are no longer limited to the 60 SAP-delivered local versions. This self-service approach allows you and your partners to create compliant localizations for over 160 additional countries, dramatically accelerating project timelines and tailoring the system to your unique global footprint.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Capabilities:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The now generally available Configuration Localization Tool (CLT) enables you to create a new customer local version by using an SAP-delivered country version as a reference. The tool intelligently generates the necessary configuration, which you can then deploy to your system. We are further enhancing this with two new scope items (7VW and 7WP) that enable invoice-time withholding tax and bill of exchange processing for all CLT-created local versions. Additionally, we are pushing the boundaries of extensibility with a labs preview for using SAP Business AI to manage localized form templates and providing self-service configuration for electronic freight invoices in Brazil.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1081821770"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strengthening Your Financial Supply Chain: Taulia Integration Expands to Canada&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Optimizing working capital is a top priority for every CFO. Our seamless, embedded integration with Taulia helps you unlock liquidity trapped in your accounts receivable. With this release, we are excited to extend this powerful capability to our customers in Canada.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value Proposition:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The embedded Taulia Receivables Financing solution for Canada enables you to improve cash flow, reduce reliance on traditional debt, and strengthen your balance sheet. By converting receivables into cash within 24 hours, you can fund growth, manage seasonal fluctuations, and optimize financial metrics—all without ever leaving your SAP S/4HANA Cloud system.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Now available in Canada, this solution allows you to sell eligible receivables to a multi-funder network with just a few clicks. The process is seamless, from invoice creation in S/4HANA Cloud to AI-powered pricing and funding. The automated journal entries and payment records ensure touch-free reconciliation, freeing up your finance team for more strategic tasks. Furthermore, the financing is undisclosed, meaning your customer relationships are preserved while you gain the financial flexibility your business needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-885308265"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Help Documentation/ Release restriction Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3623970" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud 2508, Local Versions, Release Restriction Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Thank you for joining me for this overview of our 2508 localization highlights. We are committed to being your trusted partner on your journey to becoming an intelligent, sustainable enterprise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;  &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Between July 21 and July 25, we conducted a series of 21 engaging live sessions to showcase the thrilling innovations included in the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. If you missed the live sessions, don't worry! You can still access the whole series or select the sessions that interest you the most. Seize this opportunity to&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;at your convenience–anywhere, anytime. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/localization-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14194767"/>
    <published>2025-08-28T10:35:37.441000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/end-to-end-activation-guide-for-s-4hana-public-cloud-and-sap-business-ai/ba-p/14197005</id>
    <title>End to End Activation Guide for S/4HANA public Cloud  and SAP Business AI - Joule</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T13:18:45.298000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>julianbellarmin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1986283</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1738875529"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;SAP Business AI - Joule in S/4HANA public Cloud &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1671444743"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; End-to-End activation guide for SAP S/4 HANA and SAP AI-Copilot&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Introduction:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business AI is SAP’s integrated approach to bringing artificial intelligence directly into business processes, applications, and user experiences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Its core strength is contextual intelligence—leveraging master and transactional data while respecting each user’s role and authorizations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are two Main pillars in SAP AI Strategy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Custom AI Solutions via SAP BTP AI Services&lt;/STRONG&gt; – e.g., SAP AI Core, Launchpad services.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business AI&lt;/STRONG&gt; – native AI capabilities embedded across SAP’s applications.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_3-1756378942607.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305845i044C2ADFD27A7AFF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_3-1756378942607.png" alt="julianbellarmin_3-1756378942607.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In a previous blog, I covered building custom AI in BTP . “#&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/vectorize-your-data-for-infuse-ai-in-to-business-using-hana-vector-and/ba-p/13684158" target="_blank"&gt;Vectorize your data for Infuse AI in to Business using Hana Vector and Generative AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;”.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This post focuses on the second pillar—Starting from a clean SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition tenant activation and enabling Business AI - Joule (AI copilot) setup.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;2 On-Boarding process of SAP S/4HANA Cloud, public edition for TDD:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section covers entitlement ordering, system provisioning, tenant activation, identity services setup, and post-onboarding configurations for the Test, Demo &amp;amp; Development (TDD) edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.1 Order the CBC, IAS/IPS &amp;amp; S4 Tenants :&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Log in to SAP Partner Portal with your S-user. [ &lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://partneredge.sap.com/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/U&gt;].&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Request TDD license; admin receives &lt;STRONG&gt;welcome emails&lt;/STRONG&gt; with CBC, IAS/IPS &amp;amp; S/4 tenant URLs and admin credentials.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.2 Provisioning &amp;nbsp;the Technical System:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;System provisioning can be done &amp;nbsp;via 'SAP for Me’.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The sequence of system provisioning should be CBC , CIS Sync up[IAS/IPS], SAP S/4 HANA Dev and Customizing Tenant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.3 CBC Set up:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure &lt;EM&gt;Scope and Organisational Structure&lt;/EM&gt; in CBC.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create an &lt;STRONG&gt;Evaluation Project&lt;/STRONG&gt; (not Implementation).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign required CBC roles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select demo data during initial project setup.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure deployment targets point to your S/4HANA Public Cloud URL.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_4-1756378942613.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305846i92A3D930187546A6/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_4-1756378942613.png" alt="julianbellarmin_4-1756378942613.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.4 Additional CBC Set UP and guidelines: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Find CBC URL: CIS → Applications → XSUAA → CBC → Home URL.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Replicate CBC groups to CIS via IPS resync job.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assign correct CBC roles in IAS and maintain correct user IDs to avoid login issues.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Validate target system properties in CBC admin console.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_5-1756378942626.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305847i10921F61F96305E7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_5-1756378942626.png" alt="julianbellarmin_5-1756378942626.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_6-1756378942636.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305848i07807F9866F19314/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_6-1756378942636.png" alt="julianbellarmin_6-1756378942636.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2.5 User Setup in CIS &amp;amp; S/4:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once all the set ups are done , you can see the below FLP looks like this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_7-1756378942647.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305850iF9DEE9C841A8FDE2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_7-1756378942647.png" alt="julianbellarmin_7-1756378942647.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can use the identity access MGMT tile to onboard the new users , roles and groups.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By default, the &lt;STRONG&gt;Super Admin&lt;/STRONG&gt; is assigned the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_BR_Administrator&lt;/STRONG&gt; role along with other standard SAP roles in the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The best practice is to Create the custom roles from the template and assign to the user instead of assign the standard role.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To onboard a new user you can follow the below steps in CIS and SAP S/4 HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_8-1756378942649.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305849iDC324E3535BCE8DA/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_8-1756378942649.png" alt="julianbellarmin_8-1756378942649.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;3. Enabling Business AI Copilot (Joule) in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This purpose of this guide is to provide step-by-step instructions on how to set up a Joule that can work in SAP SAP S/4 HANA public Cloud Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.1 Validate the Joule service assignment.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;In BTP Entitlements, ensure Joule is assigned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add missing service plans and Save&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_9-1756378942654.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305852i010576C97FF6A58E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_9-1756378942654.png" alt="julianbellarmin_9-1756378942654.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.2 Validate SAP BTP Build Work Zone- Standard Edition.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add Work Zone in entitlements if missing.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure Joule and Work Zone are in the same global account, subaccount, and region where Joule is available.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;you need to carefully choose the right data center where Joule is available and nearest to your location.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_10-1756378942660.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305851iA1CD54C8F187DB6A/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_10-1756378942660.png" alt="julianbellarmin_10-1756378942660.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.3 Validate the System Registration in BTP : [Auto-Discovered / Manual]&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the SAP BTP cockpit, you can have the overview of all your&amp;nbsp;systems associated with your customer ID. These&amp;nbsp;systems can be registered or auto discovered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make sure that your SAP S/4 HANA DEV and Customizing Tenants , &amp;nbsp;CIS Tenant &amp;nbsp;and CBC Tenants which you are configured earlier are exists here . If not you need to add it manually in the BTP Global Account à System Landscape Systems link.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_11-1756378942663.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305853iC7DF9E558AC181D1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_11-1756378942663.png" alt="julianbellarmin_11-1756378942663.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.4 Get the token for your system from BTP and Register it in S/4HANA Cloud Tenant&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choose your SAP S/4 HANA public cloud Tenant in the system Landscape--&amp;gt;Systems--&amp;gt; Choose All Communication Scenarios --&amp;gt; Get Token&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_12-1756378942672.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305855i3BFAF90331690046/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_12-1756378942672.png" alt="julianbellarmin_12-1756378942672.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Capture the registration token and keep &amp;nbsp;and login in to SAP S/4 HANA cloud .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_13-1756378942681.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305854i052AB066040D2BA4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_13-1756378942681.png" alt="julianbellarmin_13-1756378942681.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Register this token in Maintain extension link and Click on Approve &amp;nbsp;button as YES.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_14-1756378942688.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305856i91C975C5DE029612/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_14-1756378942688.png" alt="julianbellarmin_14-1756378942688.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once this is completed , Refresh the system landscape button , and you can see your SAP S/4 HANA cloud system status shown as registered in green color.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_15-1756378942690.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305857i8DD4EE9FB63B5483/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_15-1756378942690.png" alt="julianbellarmin_15-1756378942690.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.5 Set up the subaccount , Spaces and Cloud Foundry.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As part of your sub account creation , make sure that you are going to choose the right region where joule data centers are available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once sub account has been created , create the Cloud Foundry and Space.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_16-1756378942693.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305859i9597B2DDD1E49B31/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_16-1756378942693.png" alt="julianbellarmin_16-1756378942693.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.6 Set up the Entitlement in the subaccount.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to your subaccount à Entitlements--&amp;gt; Add service Plan --&amp;gt;Search Joule and work zone and add those services.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_17-1756378942696.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305858i12604E7E9B5C6C6B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_17-1756378942696.png" alt="julianbellarmin_17-1756378942696.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_18-1756378942699.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305861iE63F2921BDB39BA4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_18-1756378942699.png" alt="julianbellarmin_18-1756378942699.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Setup Trust Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the Navigation Pane on the left, select&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trust Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Establish Trust&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the CIS &amp;nbsp;tenants, choose the one that is also used by your applications and click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;U&gt;Note:&lt;/U&gt; The tenant chosen here must be the same as the one used by SAP S/4 HANA Cloud application for which Joule is configured.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.7 Trust the Domain in BTP.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Need to&amp;nbsp; add the Trusted Domains. To do this, click on the&amp;nbsp;Settings&amp;nbsp;options in the Subaccount and click on&amp;nbsp;Add&amp;nbsp;under&amp;nbsp;Trusted Domain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_19-1756378942701.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305860i1284FB916C4E8B0F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_19-1756378942701.png" alt="julianbellarmin_19-1756378942701.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.8 Trust the Domain in SAP Cloud Identity Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on CISà Applications and Resources&amp;nbsp;-&amp;gt; select&amp;nbsp;Tenant Settings&amp;nbsp;-&amp;gt; and then click on&amp;nbsp;Customization&amp;nbsp;-&amp;gt; click on the&amp;nbsp;Trusted Domains&amp;nbsp;option -&amp;gt; add your SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition URLs&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_20-1756378942702.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305862i576FAA0CC506EA3E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_20-1756378942702.png" alt="julianbellarmin_20-1756378942702.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.9 Create the service key for SAP Build Work Zone, standard edition.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This&amp;nbsp; Service Key which will be used during the destination creations and for&amp;nbsp;SAP CIS – Identity Provisioning Services (source &amp;amp; target)&amp;nbsp;role mapping to your Work Zone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_21-1756378942708.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305864i319D40157CCB5E7C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_21-1756378942708.png" alt="julianbellarmin_21-1756378942708.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Assign the required roles as well for the users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_22-1756378942711.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305865iBAEA59B68006402B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_22-1756378942711.png" alt="julianbellarmin_22-1756378942711.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.10 Run the Joule Booster in the BTP Global account&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;BTP Global Account--&amp;gt; click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Boosters&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; search for&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Start&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;on Setting up Joule tile.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_23-1756378942714.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305863i1434684C5BE95F4D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_23-1756378942714.png" alt="julianbellarmin_23-1756378942714.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_24-1756378942718.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305867i0B0E8AA799A4E568/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_24-1756378942718.png" alt="julianbellarmin_24-1756378942718.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_25-1756378942723.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305868iC0A2469495865B8E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_25-1756378942723.png" alt="julianbellarmin_25-1756378942723.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally you will get the success message like this.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_26-1756378942726.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305866iA2929B1B93FC59F2/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_26-1756378942726.png" alt="julianbellarmin_26-1756378942726.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.11 Post Booster Validation.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The formation created here is a logical grouping of SAP&amp;nbsp;systems.&amp;nbsp;Once the formation is created, you can include an SAP solution system in it and change it anytime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_27-1756378942731.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305870i4506AD65EAA678BD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_27-1756378942731.png" alt="julianbellarmin_27-1756378942731.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.12 Create Navigation Service Destination&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need the destination services for Joule to&amp;nbsp;work with your LoB applications in SAP S/4HANA Cloud. To create this, SAP&amp;nbsp;BTP Subaccount, --&amp;gt; Connectivity&amp;nbsp;option --&amp;gt; Destination --&amp;gt; Create New Destination.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_28-1756378942739.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305871i76BC53C7CCF0EE9E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_28-1756378942739.png" alt="julianbellarmin_28-1756378942739.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You have to use the Service Key for the Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This contains client id , secret&amp;nbsp; Token URL..etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.13 SAP S/4HANA Destinations setup in BTP Subaccount&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate in to BTP Sub Account&amp;nbsp; --&amp;gt; Click&amp;nbsp;Connectivity -&amp;gt; Destinations&amp;nbsp;and confirm the destinations required for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition are successfully created in your BTP Subaccount. The following 5 destinations should already exist in your BTP S4HANA_PUB_SSO&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP S/4HANA SSO&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule Design time Destination&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule Run time Destination&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Runtime Default&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Runtime Datas&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Already you have created the “navigation service” manually.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_29-1756378942746.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305869iE58943719F08C77C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_29-1756378942746.png" alt="julianbellarmin_29-1756378942746.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.14 Validate the Communication Arrangements:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate in to &amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition System --&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; launch the&amp;nbsp;Communication Arrangements&amp;nbsp;Tile.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Confirm that Communication Arrangements with Scenario ID&amp;nbsp;SAP_COM_0647&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;SAP_COM_0882&amp;nbsp;are automatically added by the Joule booster.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_30-1756378942751.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305872iB39013FDD1EE4D42/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_30-1756378942751.png" alt="julianbellarmin_30-1756378942751.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Make sure SAP_COM_0647 exposure role collection is set to ALL.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_31-1756378942755.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305874i3790F1D2EFC45F21/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_31-1756378942755.png" alt="julianbellarmin_31-1756378942755.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The navigate in to Communication Systems&amp;nbsp;Tile.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can 4 new systems are created. The System ID and System Names will have cryptic values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_32-1756378942759.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305873iC194E790FC8FA5B1/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_32-1756378942759.png" alt="julianbellarmin_32-1756378942759.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.15 Create the Inbound Communication System:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to Communication system à Create the new one--&amp;gt;Specify the host name and port and create the communication user Id and proposed &amp;nbsp;password.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the communication arrangement choose SAP_COM_0193&amp;nbsp; and save it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_33-1756378942761.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305875iFC912C6010D61988/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_33-1756378942761.png" alt="julianbellarmin_33-1756378942761.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.16 Create Communication Use for the communication System step&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create the &amp;nbsp;Communication User . Navigate to --&amp;gt; Maintain Communication Users&amp;nbsp;-&amp;gt; Click on&amp;nbsp;New&amp;nbsp;and enter the details&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Capture this user id and password will be used in Source system creation step.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_34-1756378942764.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305876i61B0513127B2279C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_34-1756378942764.png" alt="julianbellarmin_34-1756378942764.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.17 Manage Content Security Policy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to SAP S/4 HANA Cloud--&amp;gt; Manage Content Security Policy&amp;nbsp;à Trusted Sites--&amp;gt; Managed By--&amp;gt; UI_RESOURCES_SCRIPTS --&amp;gt; Managed by Customer&amp;nbsp;tab--&amp;gt; Add the URL of the Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This Joule URL you can get it from the BTP cockpit – Joule Service.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_35-1756378942768.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305877i1B219DB5DA81A51E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_35-1756378942768.png" alt="julianbellarmin_35-1756378942768.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.18 Configure the IDP for SSO set up between Source and the Target System.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here the&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Source system is SAP S/4HANA Public cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Target system is SAP BTP Build zone standard edition.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You have option to create the system manually or upload the template of Source and Target System.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find the attachment of the ZIP file. &amp;nbsp;From this template you can easily create the source and target files.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_36-1756378942772.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305878i7DC5CCE0E0E5B92F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_36-1756378942772.png" alt="julianbellarmin_36-1756378942772.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to CIS console --&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; IDP --&amp;gt; Source System --&amp;gt; Click Add --.&amp;gt; Browse and Upload the Source File.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Update the properties as per screen shot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here you need to update the User and Password captured from the STEP 15 [Communication user creation step in S/4 HANA]&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_37-1756378942777.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305879i900440480F3BB3D8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_37-1756378942777.png" alt="julianbellarmin_37-1756378942777.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Target System Creation:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Upload Target JSON file by click on ADD button in the IDP--&amp;gt;Target system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Proceed the update the details and properties.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Source System - &amp;nbsp;Earlier you created.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;cflp.providerId :&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;ID&amp;nbsp;of the S/4 content provider created in Work Zone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;URL : portal-service&amp;nbsp;url from the from the &amp;nbsp;Work Zone instance in BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;OAuth2TokenServiceURL :&amp;nbsp; URL from the Work Zone instance in BTP should be ends woth oauth/token.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;User: clientid&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Password: clientsecret&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_38-1756378942781.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305880i47DCFAE691613AF9/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_38-1756378942781.png" alt="julianbellarmin_38-1756378942781.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.19 Provision Users and Groups from S/4HANA Cloud to Work Zone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate in to Identity Provisioning &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Source Systems--&amp;gt; Choose the system you created --&amp;gt; Job--&amp;gt; Read Job--&amp;gt; Click Run Now button.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_39-1756378942782.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305881i2D463EA2F9B9C77F/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_39-1756378942782.png" alt="julianbellarmin_39-1756378942782.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the provisioning Logs , verify the log status.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can find the status of the user and groups &amp;nbsp;in Work Zone channel manager by click on refresh button.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="julianbellarmin_40-1756378942796.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305882i3B734337FE0E5362/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="julianbellarmin_40-1756378942796.png" alt="julianbellarmin_40-1756378942796.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3.20 Verify Joule in SAP Fiori Launch Pad / Work Zone.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter the URL of the SAP S/4 HANA Public Cloud in the browser --&amp;gt; You can notice the DIAMOND icon of&amp;nbsp; JOULE in the TOP right corner.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open and enter your queries in the interactive assistant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;4 Conclusion:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post , I have covered the end-to-end steps for set up the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition tenant in TDD environment and activate the Business AI- Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following that I provided the detailed steps like Onboarding , Provisioning the system, CBC set up, CIS IAS /IPS set ups , BTP service activation , &amp;nbsp;Boosters for the service , System and user set up , Trust and SSO set ups.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/end-to-end-activation-guide-for-s-4hana-public-cloud-and-sap-business-ai/ba-p/14197005"/>
    <published>2025-08-28T13:18:45.298000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/actual-costing-in-sap-cloud-erp/ba-p/14199071</id>
    <title>Actual Costing in SAP Cloud ERP</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T12:25:34.776000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GraceZou</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/338556</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Actual Costing is available in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ERP (&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA Cloud, public edition) &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;with the scope item 33Q.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1738935324"&gt;How Actual Costing Works&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Actual costing valuates all goods movements (procurement, manufacturing, stock transfers, subcontracting, etc.) and collects any incurred variances for your materials within a period, and calculates their actual prices, which are usually more accurate than standard prices (S-price) and moving average prices (V-price) in reflecting actual costs of the products.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;At period end, the actual prices are also used to revaluate your consumption, e.g. COGS (cost of goods sold), and period-end inventory. Valuation at actual cost is not only helpful but also legally required in some countries/regions as your financial statements, such as Profit &amp;amp; Loss statement and Balance Sheet, can be updated with the actual costing results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Actual Costing helps you gain real-time insights into business performance and make informed decisions, especially in industries or organization with big fluctuations in raw material prices or volatile production processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, let’s look at a simplified example to better understand how it works.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1542421819"&gt;Example Process&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this example, various transactions are involved to demonstrate how price variances are collected from &lt;STRONG&gt;purchase&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the lower-level material and &lt;STRONG&gt;production&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the finished goods, how the variances are then &lt;STRONG&gt;allocated&lt;/STRONG&gt; to cost of sales and remaining inventory, and what revaluation journal entries are posted to reflect the real product profitability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s walk through each step to see how data is processed in Actual Costing:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Transactions in Example Process" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306662i74AE7BF9A65DFE99/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="1-Diagram.png" alt="Transactions in Example Process" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Transactions in Example Process&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1474991033"&gt;1. Create a Purchase Order&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Company code 1210 has EUR as its local currency (company code currency). The raw material RM124 has a standard price of 0.35 EUR/PC in plant 1210 in period 008/2025 as shown in the material master record below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Master Data of Raw Material" style="width: 703px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306663iD77E5EAD779F0128/image-dimensions/703x541/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="703" height="541" role="button" title="2-RM124Master.png" alt="Master Data of Raw Material" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Master Data of Raw Material&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A purchase order (4500000253) is created, ordering 100 pieces of RM124 with a net price of 0.50 USD/PC from a foreign supplier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Purchase Order of Raw Material" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306665i06D9A78E6DDE6D79/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3-PO.png" alt="Purchase Order of Raw Material" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Purchase Order of Raw Material&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that the total PO price of 50 USD is converted into 40.39 EUR with the exchange rate 1.23794 effective at PO creation. This leads to a price difference of 5.39 EUR between PO price and standard price (40.39 – 35.00 = 5.39 EUR).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Exchange Rate of Purchase Order" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306666iADFC7BDCE971FB8E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4-Ex1.png" alt="Exchange Rate of Purchase Order" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Exchange Rate of Purchase Order&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1278477528"&gt;2. Receive Goods for the Purchase Order&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following goods receipt of 50 PC of RM124 into inventory, you can see the price difference is collected in the Actual Costing app – &lt;STRONG&gt;Material Price Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; (CKM3N):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Goods Receipt in CKM3N" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306669iB5189E960C7AED86/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5-RM-PO.png" alt="Goods Receipt in CKM3N" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Goods Receipt in CKM3N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By selecting the goods receipt line and choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Source Document&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you will find the price difference of 5.39 EUR is debited as a net loss in a P&amp;amp;L account under transaction key PRD in the Accounting document:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Goods Receipt Journal Entry" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306672i1EA10FAE27962B62/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="6-PO-JE.png" alt="Goods Receipt Journal Entry" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Goods Receipt Journal Entry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1081964023"&gt;3. Receive Invoice for the Purchase Order&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we receive the invoice for the PO, the exchange rate from USD to EUR has changed to 0.9.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Invoice Receipt" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306674iB98F59560EDDE2B0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="7-Inv_JE.png" alt="Invoice Receipt" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Invoice Receipt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Therefore, the invoice value of 50 USD is converted into 55.56 EUR.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Exchange Rate of Invoice" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306676iBA98191B3E56AEFF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="8-InvEx.png" alt="Exchange Rate of Invoice" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Exchange Rate of Invoice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This results in an exchange rate difference of 15.17 EUR (55.56 – 40.39 = 15.17 EUR) debited under transaction key KDM in the Accounting document.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Invoice Journal Entry" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306677i4D00C9A6EC651934/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="9-KDMJE.png" alt="Invoice Journal Entry" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Invoice Journal Entry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Material Price Analysis (CKM3N) also receives the exchange rate difference in a separate line as below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Invoice Receipt in CKM3N" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306678i7961AB755C6AD8A7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="10-CKM3-Inv.png" alt="Invoice Receipt in CKM3N" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Invoice Receipt in CKM3N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-885450518"&gt;4. Create a Production Order&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that the required raw material RM124 has received into inventory, the plant 1210 is ready to starts its manufacturing of the product SG224-DEMO. For this, a production order (1011288) of 50 PC of SG224-DEMO is created:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Production Order" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306680i96CF5F64EFF5FDAA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="11-ProdO.png" alt="Production Order" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Production Order&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to bill of materials (BOM) and routing of SG224-DEMO, the following raw materials and production activities are required to manufacture 100 PC of SG224-DEMO:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Planned BOM and Routing" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306683i37C00068FBDAB853/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="12-planBOM.png" alt="Planned BOM and Routing" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Planned BOM and Routing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-688937013"&gt;5. Goods Issue, Time Confirmation, and Goods Receipt for the Production Order&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the actual manufacturing process, variances can happen in the consumption of components (input materials) and activities. In&amp;nbsp; this example, we confirm more working time for activities Setup (activity type 3), Machine (1), and Labor (11) than planned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Time Confirmation for Production Order" style="width: 419px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306684i59CCFB99F75E222D/image-dimensions/419x520/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="419" height="520" role="button" title="13-co11n.png" alt="Time Confirmation for Production Order" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Time Confirmation for Production Order&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Due to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Backflush &lt;/STRONG&gt;indicator, with the time confirmation above, the withdrawal (goods issue) of input materials (RM124) is posted automatically.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since the final operation 0020 has the &lt;STRONG&gt;Automatic Goods Receipt&lt;/STRONG&gt; indicator flagged, confirmation of 0020 also results in a full delivery (goods receipt) of 50 PC into inventory.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-492423508"&gt;6. Settle the Production Order&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since 1011288 is an event-based production order, full delivery automatically triggers the order settlement. We can check the production variances in app &lt;STRONG&gt;Order Costs Details - Event-Based:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Production Order Variances" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306686i5577FF84836B9A28/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="14-orderdetails.png" alt="Production Order Variances" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Production Order Variances&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The total production variance is 407.08 EUR, split into different variance categories, reflecting the causes of the variances. The variance is debited as a net loss in P&amp;amp;L account under transaction key PRD in the Accounting document.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Production Order Settlement Journal Entry" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306687iC7347AFA38544592/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="15-orderJE.png" alt="Production Order Settlement Journal Entry" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Production Order Settlement Journal Entry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: The above-mentioned features are related to Production Accounting (3F0) and are not the main goal of this blog. You can find more details in SAP help (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/s4_ce_prd_acc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/s4_ce_prd_acc)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now we can look at how the goods receipt and production variance of SG224-DEMO is captured in Material Price Analysis (CKM3N):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Goods receipt of 50 PC is evaluation as 341.00 EUR (50 PC multiplied by standard price 6.82 EUR) as shown in &lt;STRONG&gt;Preliminary Valuation &lt;/STRONG&gt;column.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The production variance of 407.08 EUR collected from order settlement is shown as &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Price Difference.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Order Settlement in CKM3N" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306689i1585C28D44AB4020/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="16-CKM3-orSett.png" alt="Order Settlement in CKM3N" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Order Settlement in CKM3N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-295910003"&gt;7. Create a Sales Order and Outbound Delivery&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following the completion of production of SG224-DEMO, we create a sales order (1516) to sell 20 PC of SG224-DEMO at the price 10 EUR/PC to a customer. Then we issue the goods to the customer with an outbound delivery document (80000286):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sales Order Created and Delivered" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306690i3839F62AC9A6783A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="17-deliverySO.png" alt="Sales Order Created and Delivered" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Sales Order Created and Delivered&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The goods issue is updated in Material Price Analysis (CKM3N) under &lt;STRONG&gt;Consumption as follows:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Goods Delivery of Sales Order in CKM3N" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306691i7707344E73FF64F4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="18-CKM3-delivery.png" alt="Goods Delivery of Sales Order in CKM3N" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Goods Delivery of Sales Order in CKM3N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before the actual costing settlement, the sales quantity of 20 PC is still evaluated using standard price 6.82 EUR (6.82 EUR * 20 PC = 136.40 EUR).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note that the profitability segment 106851 is derived from the sales order item. It combines all the relevant attributes of the sales order, including sales order ID, sales org, distribution channel, customer group, ship-to party, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Profitability Segment of Sales Order Item" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306692iFF6C8B4C49948FC9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="19-PA.png" alt="Profitability Segment of Sales Order Item" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Profitability Segment of Sales Order Item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-99396498"&gt;8. Settlement in Actual Costing&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;At the period-end close, we execute the Actual Costing run in &lt;STRONG&gt;CKMLCP (Edit Actual Costing Run)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, also known as &lt;EM&gt;costing cockpit&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Settlement Completed in Actual Costing Run" style="width: 704px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306433iB7742E4F32A088F8/image-dimensions/704x408/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="704" height="408" role="button" title="GraceZou_6-1756460359689.png" alt="Settlement Completed in Actual Costing Run" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Settlement Completed in Actual Costing Run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;FONT color="#808080"&gt;Note: Before the settlement in Actual Costing, make sure you’ve run the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;WIP Quantity Calculation &lt;/STRONG&gt;job in&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Schedule Inventory Accounting Jobs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for accurate WIP revaluation in Actual Costing. Also, remember to calculate actual activity cost rates in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Actual Cost Rate Calculation - Cost Centers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;app. These steps are not demonstrated in this example.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the settlement step, the system does the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;(1)&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Determine &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;any price and exchange rate variances of lower-level materials (RM124 in our example).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;In the &lt;STRONG&gt;Cumulative Inventory &lt;/STRONG&gt;line, &lt;STRONG&gt;Actual Value&lt;/STRONG&gt; (90.56 EUR) is a sum of preliminary valuation value, price difference and exchange rate difference. The actual price 0.45 EUR/PC of RM124 by dividing the actual value (90.56 EUR) by the cumulative quantity (200 PC).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Note that according to the ratio of consumption quantity/cumulative quantity (50 PC/200 PC), the production of SG224-DEMO only shares 1/4 of the total difference (5.39 EUR + 15.17 EUR = 20.56 EUR), that is 5.14 EUR (20.56 EUR/4).&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Raw Material Settled in CKM3N" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306693iD61C2C364D6E033F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="20-RMsett.png" alt="Raw Material Settled in CKM3N" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Raw Material Settled in CKM3N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;(2)&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Roll &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;the variances through to higher materials (SG224-DEMO) that used the lower-level materials.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;In Material&amp;nbsp; Price Analysis of finished goods SG224-DEMO, 5.14 EUR from lower material (RM124) is rolled up, divided into 1.35 EUR of price difference and 3.79 EUR of exchange rate difference.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Product Settled in CKM3N" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306694i1E78337C6273ACF5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="21-SG-sett.png" alt="Product Settled in CKM3N" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Product Settled in CKM3N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;(3)&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; Calculate &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;actual price (periodic unit price).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Actual price is calculated for each of the materials as shown above: 0.45 EUR/PC for RM124 and 15.06 EUR/PC for SG224-DEMO. These prices can reflect the actual cost more accurately, as all goods movements and cost fluctuations within the period are considered.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;(4) &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Allocate&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; the cumulated variance (and cumulative actual value) to consumption and ending inventory.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;As shown in screenshots of points 1 and 2, the cumulative differences are allocated to consumption and ending inventory in proportion to the quantity as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="89.37697511373067%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="14.699570815450643%"&gt;Material&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.502145922746784%"&gt;Cumulative Difference (EUR)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="21.566523605150213%"&gt;Consumption (EUR)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.609442060085833%"&gt;Ending Inventory (EUR)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="14.699570815450643%"&gt;RM124&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.502145922746784%"&gt;20.56 (= 5.39+15.17)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="21.566523605150213%"&gt;5.14 (=20.56*1/4)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.609442060085833%"&gt;15.42 (=20.56*3/4)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="14.699570815450643%"&gt;SG224-DEMO&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.502145922746784%"&gt;412.22 (=408.43+3.79)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="21.566523605150213%"&gt;164.89 (=412.22*2/5)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="26.609442060085833%"&gt;247.33 (=412.22*3/5)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;With that, consumption and ending inventory are revaluated as shown in &lt;STRONG&gt;Actual Value &lt;/STRONG&gt;column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--172348376"&gt;9. Post Closing Documents&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now that the cumulative differences are allocated and actual values of consumption and inventory are revaluated, we can post the closing entries to ACDOCA (Universal Journal) to adjust the consumption (e.g. COGS for SG224-DEMO) and ending inventory values, so that the relevant P&amp;amp;L accounts and B/S accounts are updated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To do that, select both &lt;STRONG&gt;Revaluate Material&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Revaluate Consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt; when executing &lt;STRONG&gt;Post Closing&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the costing cockpit (CKMLCP),&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Run Parameters of Post Closing Step" style="width: 396px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306514i7694D0B8F4023D8C/image-dimensions/396x466/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="396" height="466" role="button" title="GraceZou_0-1756461228225.png" alt="Run Parameters of Post Closing Step" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Run Parameters of Post Closing Step&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Post Closing&lt;/STRONG&gt; step is executed successfully.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Closing Journal Entries Posted" style="width: 604px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306513iD789F6CC32FF69F2/image-dimensions/604x350/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="604" height="350" role="button" title="GraceZou_1-1756461228230.png" alt="Closing Journal Entries Posted" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Closing Journal Entries Posted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Material Price Analysis, you don’t see much changes except the &lt;STRONG&gt;Period Status&lt;/STRONG&gt; is updated to &lt;STRONG&gt;Closing Entries Completed&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the price control of the materials is converted from&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;S (Standard Price)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;V (Periodic Unit Price)&lt;/STRONG&gt;, meaning the material stock has been revaluated at&amp;nbsp;the actual PUP price in the period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Closing Step Completed in CKM3N" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306698i5C1786C1C6D33235/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="22-SG-closing.png" alt="Closing Step Completed in CKM3N" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Closing Step Completed in CKM3N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Taking SG224-DEMO as an example, let’s look at what closing journal entries are posted by Actual Costing (you can jump to these journal entries by choosing &lt;STRONG&gt;Closing Document&lt;/STRONG&gt; on the screen). These journal entries are classified with the type &lt;STRONG&gt;ML (ML Settlement)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. ML stands for Material Ledger and Actual Costing is traditionally a part of it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the consumption (COGS) revaluation journal entry 4700000034, we can see that the adjustment value of 164.89 EUR together with the COGS splits by cost component. Notice the &lt;STRONG&gt;Account Assignment Type&lt;/STRONG&gt; is &lt;STRONG&gt;EO (Profitability Segment)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. With the profitability segment 106851, as we saw earlier in the consumption line, the sales order item-specific attributes, such as &lt;STRONG&gt;Product Sold&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Order&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Org&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Customer&lt;/STRONG&gt;, are also kept in the line items. Thanks to that, we can get a margin analysis report with the finest granularity to be shared later.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Consumption Revaluation Journal Entry" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306702iF99FCF6DDA648C6A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="23-COGSJE.png" alt="Consumption Revaluation Journal Entry" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Consumption Revaluation Journal Entry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the other journal entry 4700000034, by filtering product SG224-DEMO, we can see the following items sorted by transaction key:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;BSX (Inventory)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;Item 44 is a total difference (price and exchange rate differences) of 247.33 EUR is debited to the inventory account, indicating a value increase of the material stock.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GBB (COGS)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;Item 47 shows a total difference (price and exchange rate differences) of 164.89 EUR is debited to the COGS account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;KDM (Exchange Rate Differences)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;Items 11 is the exchange rate differences received from lower material RM124. Items 46 and 49 are those credited to the exchange rate difference accounts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;PRY (Price Difference)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-60px" style="padding-left : 60px;"&gt;Item 10 is the price difference received from lower material RM124. Items 45 and 48 are those credited to the difference accounts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Material Revaluation Journal Entry" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306703i0419AAD3E6E3B347/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="24-invJE.png" alt="Material Revaluation Journal Entry" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Material Revaluation Journal Entry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, the items 44, 46 and 45, representing inventory revaluation line in CKM3N, are automatically reversed in the subsequent period (009/2025) as shown below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Journal Entry Reversal in Subsequent Period" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306704i1CC77E206147965F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="25-revJE.png" alt="Journal Entry Reversal in Subsequent Period" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Journal Entry Reversal in Subsequent Period&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This brings the stock of period 009/2025 back to standard price. Meanwhile, the price differences and exchange rate differences assigned to ending inventory in period 008/2025 are carried over into the beginning inventory of period 009/2025.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="CKM3N for New Period" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306706i984246B4E6525376/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="26-newper.png" alt="CKM3N for New Period" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;CKM3N for New Period&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this way, the system ensures the actual cost of the beginning inventory of the new period equal that of the ending inventory of the previous period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: Price difference for the consumption of 164.87 EUR in period 008/2025 is not reversed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That concludes the example showing how Actual Costing collects differences of all goods movements along the period, calculates a more reliable actual price, and allocates the differences into consumption and material stock.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--368861881"&gt;10. View Produce Profitability&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Following the posting of consumption revaluation, you can view updated COGS in margin analysis report, such as &lt;STRONG&gt;Product Profitability Review Booklet&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Product Profitability Analysis (Production Variances Not Shown)" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306707i18F97E5B280974AF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="27-MA.png" alt="Product Profitability Analysis (Production Variances Not Shown)" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Product Profitability Analysis (Production Variances Not Shown)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here, for 20 PC of the product SG224-DEMO sold, the total COGS 301.29 EUR is a sum of preliminary valuation (136.40 EUR) and the consumption revaluation (163.37 EUR) by Actual Costing as you can see from the CKM3N screen in step 8.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By navigating to the line items, we can confirm that the closing journal entries posted by Actual Costing are considered in the COGS.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="COGS Journal Entry Line Items" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306708i2561AA5D18AC423C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="28-MAlines.png" alt="COGS Journal Entry Line Items" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;COGS Journal Entry Line Items&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--271972379"&gt;Additional Features&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This section briefly talks about the Actual Costing features that are not covered above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1055291898"&gt;Multiple Currencies and Valuations&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Actual Costing supports inventory valuation in multiple currency types (company code currency, group currency, and if configured, functional currency) and valuation views (legal valuation, group valuation) achieved by parallel ledgers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1251805403"&gt;Valuated Quantity Structure&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Valuated quantity structure shows the scaled receipt quantity of the actual input materials/activities in a hierarchical view.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The following screen shows the production structure of SG2024-DEMO from the above example, including raw materials and activity types valuated in both preliminary valuation and actual valuation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Valuated Quantity Structure" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306709i7D05E37D43BB732B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="29-vaQty.png" alt="Valuated Quantity Structure" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Valuated Quantity Structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The valuated quantity structure helps you analyze the differences roll-ups by showing all the price differences from the lower level to the top material level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note this view is dynamically generated without persisting in database, therefore the system performance might be slow in case of many hierarchy levels.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1448318908"&gt;Cost Component Split (CCS)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cost component split breaks down costs into cost components such as material, various production activities, and overheads. Actual Costing shares the same cost component structure as in product cost planning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can see in Material Price Analysis, the columns such as Direct Material, Material Overhead, Personnel Time, Machine Time, Set-up Time, and Production Overhead represent the cost components. Their values are determined based on the G/L accounts (cost elements) assigned to each component.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP is re-designing the cost component split feature with the concept of Universal Component Breakdown. We will explain this feature in detail when available in Actual Costing. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1644832413"&gt;Activity Consumption Analysis (CKM3A)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Actual Costing also revaluates activity types of each cost center by using the actual cost rates that are determined in &lt;STRONG&gt;Actual Cost Rate Calculation - Cost Centers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;app (KSII).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following screen of &lt;STRONG&gt;Activity Consumption Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;STRONG&gt;CKM3A&lt;/STRONG&gt;), we can tell that for in plant 1210 in period 008/2025, the cost center 12101301 consumes 1.25 hours of activity type 3 (Setup Production) for manufacturing SG224-DEMO with production order 1011288. In reality, there are more production orders and manufactured products.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Closing Completed in CKM3A" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306710i1C6342A81E0CF44E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="30-CKMA.png" alt="Closing Completed in CKM3A" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Closing Completed in CKM3A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Preliminary Valuation&lt;/STRONG&gt; column shows the activity valued with plan cost rates (378.88 EUR/hour) maintained in &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Cost Rates – Plan&lt;/STRONG&gt; or imported from SAP Analytics Cloud. The &lt;STRONG&gt;Actual Value &lt;/STRONG&gt;column shows the activity cost valuated at the actual cost rates (388.89 EUR/hour) calculated in KSII at period end.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the closing journal entries, the price difference is credited to the cost center (transaction key PRL Activity Price Difference) &amp;nbsp;and debited to the material price account.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Activity Revaluation Journal Entry" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306711i0B6C04BD1256256E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="31-activityJE.png" alt="Activity Revaluation Journal Entry" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Activity Revaluation Journal Entry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1841345918"&gt;Other Fiori Apps&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additional Fiori apps are available for multiple-material view, for example Display Actual Costing Result (F6073). See &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/7f47a6d9441c46ac86c96fd27f6015f0/4cc57871cfca4755a96d3929f16d9e38.html?version=latest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help&lt;/A&gt; for more info.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In addition, a new comprehensive analytical app is being developed with the aim to remove the current restrictions in F6073.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1451053409"&gt;Technical Implementation:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To use Actual Costing in SAP Cloud ERP, the scope item&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;33Q&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;must be activated.&amp;nbsp;With 33Q activation, the following are&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;active by default&amp;nbsp;for the relevant plants:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Actual&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;cost component split&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;WIP revaluation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;at actual costs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activity consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;update&amp;nbsp;in actual quantity structure is active and is taken into account upon price determination.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To access the relevant apps, users must be assigned with a role that contains the following&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;business catalogs&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_FIN_BC_IA_AC_PER_ACT_PC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Actual Costing - Periodic Activities) for apps such as Edit Actual Costing Run (CKMLCP).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_FIN_BC_IA_FACT_MPRC_PC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Inventory Accounting - Material Price Analysis) for&amp;nbsp;apps such as Material Price Analysis (CKM3N, aka CKM3)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_FIN_BC_IA_AC_REP_PC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Actual Costing - Reporting)&amp;nbsp;for apps such as Display Actual Costing Result (F6073).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_FIN_BC_IA_OM_REP_PC&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Actual Costing - Activity Reporting)&amp;nbsp;for apps such as Activity Consumption Analysis (CKM3A)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_FIN_BC_OH_PE_PAC_PC&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Overhead Cost Accounting - Actual Costing) for apps such as&amp;nbsp;Actual Cost Rate Calculation - Cost Centers (KSII)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These business catalogs are available in role template&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP_BR_INVENTORY_ACCOUNTANT or&amp;nbsp;SAP_BR_OVERHEAD_ACCOUNTANT.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1647566914"&gt;Master Data Preparation&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The materials subject to Actual Costing settlement are those with price control&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;S&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Standard price)and price determination&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;3&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Single/Multi-level) as below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Master Data of Materials Relevant to Actual Costing" style="width: 624px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306715iD8F6C1F118F63FBE/image-dimensions/624x615/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="624" height="615" role="button" title="32-SGMaster.png" alt="Master Data of Materials Relevant to Actual Costing" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Master Data of Materials Relevant to Actual Costing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: By default, price determination&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Transaction-Based) is used in material creation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1675896728"&gt;See Also&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more deep-dive topics in Actual Costing, for example, WIP Revaluation, Not Distributed, and Not Allocated values, see FAQ Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3617837" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://me.sap.com/notes/3617837&lt;/A&gt; (&lt;EM&gt;FAQ of Actual Costing in SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/EM&gt;) with concrete examples.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will continuously update the Note or publish blogs for other in-depth topics in Actual Costing, such as fallback logic for actual price calculation, account determination for closing journal entries, support of special production scenarios, and configuration activities. You are welcome to leave comments under the blog.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/actual-costing-in-sap-cloud-erp/ba-p/14199071"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T12:25:34.776000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/never-ever-remove-an-iam-app-from-a-business-catalog/ba-p/14200044</id>
    <title>Never ever remove an IAM app from a Business Catalog</title>
    <updated>2025-08-30T02:12:53.108000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Juwin</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/169790</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Never ever remove an IAM app from a Business Catalog!!!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As soon as such a Business Catalog change is published, as per SAP, "&lt;SPAN&gt;all roles need to be processed to ensure consistency since the data does not have a link anymore between the removed IAM apps and the affected catalogs."&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Yes, it processes&amp;nbsp;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;all roles in the system&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our case, it was &lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6000&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt; roles in the system. As you can see, the publishing/unpublishing jobs have been running for 7 days now and still continuing. We have been in touch with SAP Support. Their explanation of how publishing works: "&lt;SPAN&gt;In general, it works like this: if a publishing process A is triggered, it is processed right away. If during this process new publishing processes B and C are triggered, this is added to a queue until the publishing process A from before is done. Then B and C will be processed together. Now, if there are 10 or 20 of them queued up, they all will be processed together and depending on the objects, this can take longer. "&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There were 30-40 processes running in the system at the beginning. Now after 7 days, it has reduced to 11 processes. It locked up all the business roles for changes during the publishing process - Security team can't make any updates to roles for several days. Developers couldn't create new apps/communication scenarios/services etc. in the system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So, what is the workaround for this if someone really wants to remove an IAM app from a Business Catalog? The only way I could think of, is to create a brand-new Business Catalog and move whatever apps that are really needed into the new one. But, what if few months down the line, someone wants to remove another app from that 2nd Business Catalog? ... and so on...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Does this mean, to avoid all this trouble, developers should be allowed to have only one IAM app per Business Catalog? Are there any other possible ideas?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-08-29 19_48-000003.png" style="width: 883px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306861i8FE0472063A615F7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-08-29 19_48-000003.png" alt="2025-08-29 19_48-000003.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/never-ever-remove-an-iam-app-from-a-business-catalog/ba-p/14200044"/>
    <published>2025-08-30T02:12:53.108000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/functional-area-derivation-using-custom-logic-in-s-4hana-cloud-public/ba-p/14201753</id>
    <title>Functional area derivation using custom logic in S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-08-31T12:52:03.386000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>varunvenkat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83606</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Functional areas in SAP S/4HANA Cloud are organizational units used for classifying expenses by their nature rather than by operational or geographical divisions. They serve as a key component in cost-of-sales accounting and enable businesses to prepare segmental financial statements for compliance and decision-making purposes. The derivation of functional areas is determined based on the sequence as explained &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/e6175604fc874bfe84aa14d2f9ae1fbd/c26bf851a09a3f3ae10000000a441470.html?version=2408.500&amp;amp;q=deriving+functional+area" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;. In this short blog post, I would like to cover a practical example of how the functional area derivation works using a custom logic substitution rule, which is the last sequence step of the derivation logic. In this demo example, the use case is that the derivation should take place only for the company code 0800, and the default functional area will be substituted by a target functional area which is entered in a custom field of a professional services customer project. The prerequisite is creating and enabling the custom field&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;YY1_Functional_Area_WP_cpd&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp; in the business context "Work Package".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a custom logic implementation for the Extension Point &lt;STRONG&gt;FIN_CODING_BLOCK_SUBSTITUTION&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add the following code: in this example, if the Company Code 0800 is used&lt;EM&gt;, &lt;/EM&gt;the custom logic will substitute the default functional area with the functional area entered by the user into the custom field.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Note: please always copy the values from input to output first before

* any substitutions, otherwise, the initial values from the output will

* be used for substitutions!!

    MOVE-CORRESPONDING codingblockitem TO codingblockitemout.

 

DATA lv_project_target_fa type STRING.

*Only valid for customer projects, as the custom field is created in this context

IF codingblockitem-companycode = '0800'.

    SELECT YY1_Functional_Area_WP_cpd FROM I_WORKPACKAGE

    INTO _project_target_fa

    WHERE WORKPACKAGE = @codingblockitem-wbselementexternalid.

    ENDSELECT.

    "If the custom field value if empty, no substitution

    If  lv_project_target_fa IS INITIAL.

        EXIT.

    ELSE.

        codingblockitemout-functionalarea = lv_project_target_fa.

        substitutiondone = abap_true.

    ENDIF.

ENDIF.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next, create the substitution rule for this custom logic to be executed. In the “Manage Substitution/Validation Rules – Journal Entries” app, create a new rule for the business context Coding Block as follows:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_0-1756636740215.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307005i1C67466A75AEADD5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_0-1756636740215.png" alt="varunvenkat_0-1756636740215.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The precondition determines in which cases the substitution rule will be triggered – in our demo use case, we want the rule to trigger only when the source functional area is equal to 'YB25'. The substitution rule itself simply maps the target field value to the value of the source field functional area (which will be set to a new value during the runtime of the custom logic). So essentially, if the customer project custom field has a target functional area 'YB24' maintained, the default functional area YB25 will be replaced by 'YB24'.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once this is done, we can conduct a quick test to validate the result. The default functional area determined is YB25, and for our test project&amp;nbsp;XDT0031, the custom field has been maintained with YB24 as the target functional area. After completing a test time booking for the project, the derivation result can be successfully validated in the "Display Line Items in General Ledger" app:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_2-1756637397397.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307007iE10B8B9AE30ABA7D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_2-1756637397397.png" alt="varunvenkat_2-1756637397397.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/functional-area-derivation-using-custom-logic-in-s-4hana-cloud-public/ba-p/14201753"/>
    <published>2025-08-31T12:52:03.386000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/professional-services-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14202789</id>
    <title>Professional Services in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-01T11:12:03.356000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KatharinaStopf</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/234285</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Welcome to your one-stop shop to learn and share knowledge about SAP's ready-to-run public Cloud ERP software solution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition is part of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;that brings AI, data, and applications together into a fully integrated system. This community is open for anyone in the Cloud ERP ecosystem–customers, partners, and SAP experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;In this blog post I’d like to outline the innovations for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 in the area of Professional Services. These are the topics that are covered:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Resource Request Status (6JO)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configurable profit center and partner profit center derivation in new, resource-related intercompany billing (16T, 4AN)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deprecation of Old Resource-Related Intercompany Billing (16T, 4AN)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhance Launchpad for Professional Services Project Manager (J11)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional insight to project manager about purchase requisitions and work packages of professional services projects (J11)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UI Adaptation for Project Control-Professional Services (J11)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-assisted Note Corrections for Project Billing (4E9)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ability to Recognize Revenue based on a Current Foreign Currency Exchange Rate in Fixed-Price Customer Projects (1IL)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional Plan Sources in Revenue Recognition for Customer Projects (1IL)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check out my video to get a glimpse of the new features:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_ysgzv2tw" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Resource Request Status (6JO)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This functionality is part of the Resource Management functionality on the BTP which works hand in hand with the project management in SAP S/4HANA Cloud. In the&amp;nbsp;Staff Resource Requests&amp;nbsp;app, resource managers can now manually set the resource request status to&amp;nbsp;“fulfilled”&amp;nbsp;for bookkeeping purposes. This is helpful when resource requests are only partially staffed to mark these as fully staffed. Besides the automatic determined staffing status, they are able to re-set status from fully staffed manually back to open or to fully staffed. This will help to put focus on requests which really require attention. This status is also available in the request API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have a look at this demo to get a better understanding of the system:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Demo: New Resource Request Status (6JO)" href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_14fvctiu" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS_Resource.png" style="width: 869px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307250i1FFBF4C262FAC9D3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS_Resource.png" alt="SS_Resource.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For even more details, please have a look at the entry of this topic on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/PPRM_OD/afef0d26c811418aaebe8878e0a3cbaa/a3f9f4db6c94435f8c7e19ecca4ca07a.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configurable profit center and partner profit center derivation in new, resource-related intercompany billing (16T, 4AN)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can now also configure a profit center or partner profit center derivation logic in the new resource-related intercompany billing whereby the profit center derived during the new resource-related intercompany billing can be based on the profit center derived from the related intercompany sales order, in which case the partner profit center will be empty.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are several benefits that come hand in hand with this innovation, for one you have a detailed profit center reporting on billing documents and accounts payable and also your configuration can be adjusted to meet different reporting requirements, offering flexibility.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The profit center value is derived for every posting during the preparation of Billing Document Request (RICR). There is a new SSCUI to activate profit center derivation based on the Intercompany Sales Order Item (107061).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the configuration is unchecked, which is the case by default, the profit center derivation is based on the partner object of the posting.If the configuration is checked, the profit center derivation is based on the intercompany sales order item. The Partner Profit Center field will be empty in this case.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For even more details, please have a look at the entry of this topic on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/b12b53a60e364d83a631941af0f53c39.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Deprecation of Old Resource-Related Intercompany Billing (16T, 4AN)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The old version of the Resource-Related Intercompany Billing is deprecated. The new Resource Related Intercompany Billing is the successor providing greater flexibility and transparency. It is recommended to use the new Resource-Related Intercompany Billing. In case you have not yet moved from the old solution to the new solution, we recommend doing so. In case of any questions please feel free to reach out, we are happy to support you in this journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are multiple added values with the new solution, such as flexibility to configure the determination of material that influence the invoice structure, enhanced traceability of billing data with released CDS views, enablement of end-to-end extensibility, enablement of Brazil localization, and removal of restriction on using a single Intercompany Sales Order for a Sender and Receiver company code combination, during billing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is a easily switch to the new Resource-Related Intercompany Billing by activating the configuration setting &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/3728a3917cd748efa9caaac68ebbf875.html?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;New Resource Related Intercompany Billing activation (ID: 106897)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;. You can continue to use the same “Generate Intercompany Billing” application and scope items after transitioning from the old to the new Resource-Related Intercompany&amp;nbsp; to process the existing and new intercompany CO journal entries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For customer tenants with newly activated scope items for Resource-Related Intercompany Billing will have the new Resource-Related Intercompany Billing set as the default.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For even more details, please have a look at the entry of this topic on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/b12b53a60e364d83a631941af0f53c39.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhance Launchpad for Professional Services Project Manager (J11)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There is a new Space template that provides more efficient, user-friendly, and focused experience of SAP Fiori launchpad for professional services project managers. This enhanced role template now includes access to “Project Billing” application, financial reports such as project financial booklet, “Purchase Requisition” application and “Manage collaborative projects” application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The launchpad space has been split into the following pages for easier navigation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Overview&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Project Planning and Execution&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Project Billing and Financials&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Project Administration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The existing space template 'SAP_BR_PROJECT_MANAGER_PROF', assigned to the business role 'Project Manager - Professional Services (SAP_BR_PROJECT_MANAGER_PROF)', has been enhanced by adding new catalogs and organizing apps across multiple pages, such as Overview, Project Planning and Execution, Project Billing and Financials, and Project Administration, to reduce launchpad clutter.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ultimately this new structure leads to increased usability, productivity, and satisfaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For even more details, please have a look at the entry of this topic on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/8292f3b4b8ba40ec8464a38d13b5ac96.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional insight to project manager about purchase requisitions and work packages of professional services projects (J11)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You should already familiar with the “&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Project Control – Professional Services” application, as we have been mentioning innovations in this app in several of the previous releases and we are continuing to extend the functionality there.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With this release we &lt;/SPAN&gt;bring project managers direct insights into work packages and purchase requisition related to professional services projects. This has not been part of this app before and will allow key users to have access to even more information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Just some examples of the added insights are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Planned efforts, expenses, and costs and revenue&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Actual efforts, expenses, and costs&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cost and efforts estimated to completion &amp;amp; estimated at completion&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Purchase requisition and Purchase order related insights which are assigned to professional services project&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This brings us even closer to providing one single entry point for project managers that gives an overview of project-related information and access to related apps and actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have a look at this demo to get a better understanding of the system:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Demo: Additional insight to project manager (J11)" href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_rmvrc9rh" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS_Control.png" style="width: 968px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307253i3703B3874C15BF4F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS_Control.png" alt="SS_Control.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For even more details, please have a look at the entry of this topic on &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/db25b660143d4ffbad8e7f4825b9d83e.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UI Adaptation for Project Control-Professional Services (J11)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next innovation for the Project Control – Professional Services app is &lt;STRONG&gt;new UI adaptation functionality.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Enhancement allows you to create an app variant of the app using SAPUI5 flexibility features in a modification-free way. With an application variant, you can extend the original code to define changes that fulfil the specific business requirements of different business roles, user groups, organizational units, and countries. For example, you might want to create an application variant to simplify and streamline a specific process by hiding fields not required by casual users, visualizing data as a chart, or changing a responsive table to a grid table to make information easier to process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means that key users will now be able to customize applications for specific roles or departments, ensuring that each user group has access to the most relevant information and functionality specifically for them. This means for example to add new data sections or new visual elements. They can also change the outbound navigation within an app, for example defining navigation to custom price maintenance app or change the OData Service for UI adaptation project, this ensures that access to app from is consistent and secure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this demo you can see a very simple example of adding in a notes tab in one variant of the app, just to show you how this can look like. Please also make sure to have a look at the release blog from Katharina Stopf. There you will be able to find a more detailed video of the step-to-step process of generating this example.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have a look at this demo to get a better understanding of the system:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Demo: UI Adaptation for Project Control - Professional Services (J11)" href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_3vtaenpw" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS_UI_short.png" style="width: 964px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307254i620212F0364422BA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS_UI_short.png" alt="SS_UI_short.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Extended demo version:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Demo: UI Adaptation for Project Control -Professional Services (J11)" href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_53mrp8vv" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS_UI_long.png" style="width: 972px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307256i20777E7F808F5EBE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS_UI_long.png" alt="SS_UI_long.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For even more details, please have a look at this &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_5r7r5h0n" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;introduction video&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; and &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/group.sapui5-adaptation-projects.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;tutorial for key users&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI-assisted Note Corrections for Project Billing (4E9)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature in the Manage Project Billing app assists billing specialists by proposing grammatically correct smart suggestions for the notes of Time and Expenses items in Project Billing Request. This functionality will reduce the time spend manually reviewing numerous notes and accelerates the notes review process, which improves efficiency and accuracy in the billing process.&amp;nbsp;​It gives the option to either bulk review, which means to review up to 500 note corrections with a single click of the Smart Notes button or do a selective review, so choose up to 500 notes or specific Project Billing Request items for note proposals.​ The AI proposed notes which are saved are also available in the Invoice providing greater clarity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the demo you are able to see, that when a billing specialist enters the Manage Project Billing app, they select a billing element and click on the prepare billing button. In the next screen they are able to see the time and expense items including all their notes. When clicking on the&amp;nbsp; smart notes button you can find the proposed notes section. On the top it will always say that this was created with AI just to ensure the transparency to the users. After using this feature to simplify the review process, the billing specialist can submit and follow the next steps in the billing process as usual.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have a look at this demo to get a better understanding of the system:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Demo: AI-assisted Note Corrections for Project Billing (4E9)" href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_ld5px2qc" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SS_AI.png" style="width: 913px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307257iA658ECC473BC8AFC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SS_AI.png" alt="SS_AI.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For even more details, please have a look at the entry of this topic on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/29cf986299714386847f4d4c9bb86994/baaa95fc66a147689e80e6527f22c0f9.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Please remember that &lt;STRONG&gt;Andreas Hammerschmidt&lt;/STRONG&gt; updates his detailed blog &lt;STRONG&gt;“&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/project-billing-for-customer-projects-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/bc-p/13596157" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Project Billing for Customer Projects in SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;”&lt;/STRONG&gt; with every release, so you can find a comprehensive overview of the functionality there.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ability to Recognize Revenue based on a Current Foreign Currency Exchange Rate in Fixed-Price Customer Projects (1IL) &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;This is especially interesting for countries that tend to experience frequent changes in their currency rate, whereby the foreign exchange rate of the company code to the project currency consistently fluctuates. The revenue recognition key&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SPFCFX&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is internally linked to a new event-based revenue recognition currency handling method which uses the project or object currency as the principal currency. In order to leverage this functionality, you need to use the revenue recognition key SPFCFX for the integration with Customer Projects with fixed-price projects to provide revenue recognition data based on current foreign exchange rates for customer projects planned with a foreign currency.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s have a look at an example. We have a project in India, which means the company code currency is Indian rupee, but we bill in US dollars. Let's assume the exchange rate is changing, in period one it's 1 to 100 in period 5 it's 1 to 120.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The billing plan amount is 100000 US dollars.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In period one we take the current rate based on the project creation date. Let's assume there are some cost postings, and the percentage of completion is 10%. Then the revenue would be 10,000 US dollars.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But the realized revenue in the company code is 1 million Indian rupee.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's first look at how the system is handling it today with the with the SPFC standard key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The rate which is taken into consideration is still based on the project creation date. Let's assume there are additional postings which lead to a percentage of completion of 20% realized revenue, so 20,000 US dollars realized. But the realized revenue in the company code currency is still 1 million rupees.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new revenue recognition key is considering the first day of the period 5. So here it's 1 to 120.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Instead of realizing revenue and company code currency, Indian rupee of 1 million, we are realizing 1.2 million. The Work in progress overall still is 2.2 million.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To summarize the foreign currency valuation is currently taking reference from the frozen rate versus the end of the month rate. However, with the new revenue recognition key it will take first day of the period rate versus the end of the same month.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For even more details, please have a look at the entry of this topic on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/8e2dd56fbb60490d9bdb69eea86b122f.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional Plan Sources in Revenue Recognition for Customer Projects (1IL)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;With this release, you can now use additional plan sources in Event-Based Revenue Recognition for the revenue recognition keys for fixed price projects with the cost-based percentage of completion method (revenue recognition keys SPFC and SPFCTR).&amp;nbsp;This will help. This will empower your financial processes with expanded configuration options, enabling more tailored cost and revenue planning based on project-specific requirements​.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;It covers the following:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SPFC (fixed-price cost-based percentage of completion):​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;305: Confirmed estimate at completion (EAC) from the customer projects planning tools and revenues from the actual sales and distribution (SD) billing schedule​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;500: Cost and revenue planning of all objects from ACDOCP based on a configured plan category​&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SPFCTR (fixed-price cost-based percentage of completion and target revenue):​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;305: Confirmed estimate at completion (EAC) from the customer projects planning tools and revenues from the actual sales and distribution (SD) billing schedule​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For even more details, please have a look at the entry of this topic on &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/8e2dd56fbb60490d9bdb69eea86b122f.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1276484453" id="toc-hId-1888133734"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are interested in the latest and greatest blog posts on Professional Services, please have a look at my&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/professional-services-in-the-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-the/ba-p/13620466#M55586" target="_blank"&gt;collection blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and also take a look at the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud-professional-services" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Community page for Professional Services&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the Replays of Our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2502 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;  &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From July 21 to July 25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for Enterprise Portfolio and Project Management as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;– anywhere, anytime.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find All of Our Assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;  &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Cloud ERP Product Success Enablement" href="https://chart-bdmaicr0au.dispatcher.eu2.hana.ondemand.com/index.html?hc_reset" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="wheel.jpg" style="width: 788px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307261i6616F5C6AA38815D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="wheel.jpg" alt="wheel.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/professional-services-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14202789"/>
    <published>2025-09-01T11:12:03.356000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/public-sector-highlights-of-the-sap-cloud-erp-2508-release/ba-p/14191660</id>
    <title>Public Sector highlights of the SAP Cloud ERP 2508 release</title>
    <updated>2025-09-01T11:50:54.462000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MaryRamsrud</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/124885</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As planned, the Public Sector Management (PSM) Global scope bundle is now available for over 20 countries, including France, Italy, Spain, Ireland, Denmark, Norway, Sweden, Mexico, and Saudi Arabia.&amp;nbsp; With ever increasing demand, we continue the planned expansion to additional countries in 2602.&amp;nbsp; Check out the roadmap for details.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_0-1756146356537.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304786iC9DF4BE77C00CE6C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_0-1756146356537.png" alt="MaryRamsrud_0-1756146356537.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud ERP core enhancements&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As always, there’s a range of new core Cloud ERP feature-based innovations for S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition with the 2508 release. If you are interested in other areas of innovations for SAP’s Cloud ERP, please check out the Release Video from Bert Schulze:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_1-1756146356543.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304785iFF4BDBFCB3080943/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_1-1756146356543.png" alt="MaryRamsrud_1-1756146356543.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Screenshot + URL: Get the top highlights of the 2508 release&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;in this video by Bert Schulze&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New AI Features for Public Sector&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The AI-assisted easy filter in SAP Fiori elements-based applications allows users to define filter queries using natural language, making it easier to find specific entries without manually applying filters. Users can toggle between Classic mode and SAP Business AI-mode, view favorite and last used queries, and easily reset filters to display all entries. ​This feature has now been enabled within the SAP Fiori app, Manage Budget Documents, allowing budget users to use budget document attributes and natural language to easily find what they are looking for.​ AI-assisted filter criteria can be saved as a view and defined as a default view to help make it easier to find these same objects every time, including the ability to save a public or private view.​&lt;BR /&gt;​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;​Try typing “not posted” and automatically filter on all document statuses except posted.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_2-1756146356546.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304783i0B789996FBF7B906/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_2-1756146356546.jpeg" alt="MaryRamsrud_2-1756146356546.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Typing ‘sender over 1k usd created in last fortnight’ will automatically filter on large budget transfers in the last 2 weeks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_3-1756146356549.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304788i888794D759194702/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_3-1756146356549.jpeg" alt="MaryRamsrud_3-1756146356549.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the SAP Fiori Launchpad, you can use the AI-assisted enterprise search to access public sector management objects like fund and grant. Depending on your business role, you see a list of business objects in the​ SAP Fiori Launchpad search dropdown. This feature allows you to use natural language for searching public sector management business data. You can enter your search queries in natural language in the SAP Fiori Launchpad search bar to find the information you need.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enable natural language search on business objects by selecting the checkbox ’Enable AI Natural Language Search’ from the user profile settings. ​ On selecting the checkbox, you can view the list of business objects that are configured for natural language search.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Try searching “show me funds created recently” and get a list of newly created funds.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_4-1756146356552.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304787i86D243C0410E30F0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_4-1756146356552.jpeg" alt="MaryRamsrud_4-1756146356552.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;PSM Global&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release delivers a robust suite of Grants and Budget Management features tailored for public sector entities, including state and local governments, non-profits, cities, K-12 schools, and education &amp;amp; research institutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Building upon previous releases, the 2508 update introduces new capabilities designed to support public sector customers. Read on for an overview of the latest advancements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For more details on the global PSM scope bundle, visit the SAP Process Navigator to explore the complete list of available scope items.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_5-1756146356557.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304789iB848F945915B9AF2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_5-1756146356557.png" alt="MaryRamsrud_5-1756146356557.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Screenshot: Process Navigator focused on S/4HANA Public Cloud and the PSM industry capabilities.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow for earmarked funds from contract and lease management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Workflows for Earmarked Funds has been enhanced with enabling the workflows for earmarked funds from contract and lease management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;When a lease-in contract is created, earmarked funds are generated automatically, subject to approval settings. You can specify whether all changes, only initial changes, or no changes require approval. The workflow is managed through the "Manage Workflow for Earmarked Funds" step, where properties, conditions, and steps are defined. The default procedure from the Workflow for Earmarked Funds Document is used, ensuring that subsequent processing aligns with the initial setup. (source – Joule!)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;​Overview&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enablement of workflow for earmarked funds from contract and lease management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ability to determine approval procedure&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefits&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable effective budget control by providing the ability for the budget manager to approve or disapprove the commitment from contract and lease management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve efficiency by streamlining approval process&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Boost collaboration and compliance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;​&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_6-1756146356559.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304791iAD7481EC92A34156/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_6-1756146356559.png" alt="MaryRamsrud_6-1756146356559.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Screenshot: workflow for earmarked funds with Contract and Lease Management.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Budget Consumption Review Booklet&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Public Sector Management (PSM) now offers the&amp;nbsp;Budget Consumption Review Booklet&amp;nbsp;application to perform a detailed review of the PSM budget line items, commitment/actual lines items, and budget and commitment actual line items and other relevant details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;* &lt;EM&gt;available 2508.1 release, with incremental feature releases over the next few months&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Overview:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Combines the queries for the Budget Line Item Analyzer, the Commitment/Actual Line Item Analyzer, and the Budget and Commitment/Actual Line Item Analyzer&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Includes pages for each of the 3 reports, viewing each by revenue, expense, or combined&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Includes all the filters and key figures available in the earlier line item analyzer reports&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefits:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ability to enter and save comments at the field, page, or report level&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI Business Insights and Navigate To features planned for future incremental releases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_7-1756146356565.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304792i3F8237E32A6DB162/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_7-1756146356565.png" alt="MaryRamsrud_7-1756146356565.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Screenshot:&amp;nbsp;Budget Consumption Review Booklet&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Availability control (AVC) and budget address validations during the import of financial plan data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is possible to either import&amp;nbsp;PSM budget (via excel upload or via interface from SAC) or create budget documents. During these activities budget addresses and AVC control addresses are never allowed to be negative.&amp;nbsp;Through the “Import Financial Plan Data” app or SAC interface, this new feature checks to avoid budget overruns defined through the configuration of AVC and to avoid negative amounts on a complete budget address (combining of account assignments such as fund, budget account, grant, and budget type)​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Overview&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;During the budget upload through the “Import Financial Plan Data” app, new checks to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid budget overruns defined through the configuration of AVC&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Avoid negative amounts on a complete budget address (combining of account assignments such as fund, budget account, grant, and budget type)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;During budget upload and SAC imports the automatic validations are performed and will show possible overruns before the budget data is updated.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefits&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Improve budget consistency (for example, avoiding unwanted negative budgets)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This functionality also avoids an accidental deletion of budget data in case the&amp;nbsp;overwrite indicators are set incorrectly. It also avoids the possible deletion of budget documents with header information. ​&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_8-1756146356569.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304790i7BAE1D70E26AE77B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_8-1756146356569.jpeg" alt="MaryRamsrud_8-1756146356569.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Screenshot: error message in upload log&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Using statistical projects with public-sector management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can automatically derive PSM account assignments from statistical WBS elements when the cost center does not have a fixed assignment. For example, if you set a fixed PSM account assignment on a statistical WBS element and do not set one on the cost center, the system uses the assignment from the statistical WBS element.&amp;nbsp; This feature allows for better management of budget for statistical projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_9-1756146356573.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304793i573F0357C28EA759/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_9-1756146356573.png" alt="MaryRamsrud_9-1756146356573.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Screenshot: PSM account assignments on a statistical project&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Position budgeting with funds pre-commitments and budget availability check&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable financing of positions with their corresponding funding sources, such as funds, grants, or functional areas, and monitoring and control of budget consumption&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create earmarked fund precommitments in SAP Cloud ERP to reserve the position budget&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Finance vacant positions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Benefits&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enable accurate budget monitoring and control of personnel expenses by allowing the financing of positions in SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Features&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When a new employment gets created in SAP SuccessFactors, based on the employment costs, the necessary budget gets reserved in SAP Cloud ERP through an earmarked funds document of type commitment document. When an employee gets hired in SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central, based on the salary of the employee, the budget gets reserved in the SAP Cloud ERP system through an earmarked funds document, of type Commitment document. During every payroll run for the employee, the existing commitment document gets adjusted with the corresponding payroll actuals amount, and the corresponding actuals document is created and posted in the SAP Cloud ERP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can finance employees in SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central by using Position Budgeting Control for Cloud. The financing uses information from the funds commitment amount in SAP Cloud ERP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Position Budgeting Control for Cloud allows you to ensure that employees are sufficiently budgeted for a specified financial period.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_12-1756146677109.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304797iF9B1AE8AA0EBDF59/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_12-1756146677109.png" alt="MaryRamsrud_12-1756146677109.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Picture: Position Budgeting Control – Financing Details.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition latest 2508 release brings key enhancements, including AI-driven user experiences, embedded AI features, and improved Grants and Budget Management capabilities. &amp;nbsp;This release continues to drive efficiency, scalability, and sustainability in ERP operations for public sector organizations. Please join us in the Cloud ERP revolution and explore how these innovations can unlock your organization’s full potential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trial System&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Want to try out S/4HANA Cloud, Public Edition, for public sector?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Get a closer look at budget and grants management scenarios?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Access the public trial system.&amp;nbsp; Register for a free, two-week trial and take it for a spin.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/try-sap/s4hana-public-sector-trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, public sector Trial&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From July 21-25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. Don't miss this chance and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="Cloud ERP Product Success" href="https://chart-bdmaicr0au.dispatcher.eu2.hana.ondemand.com/index.html?hc_reset" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="MaryRamsrud_11-1756146356585.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304794i29613605B23D324C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="MaryRamsrud_11-1756146356585.png" alt="MaryRamsrud_11-1756146356585.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/public-sector-highlights-of-the-sap-cloud-erp-2508-release/ba-p/14191660"/>
    <published>2025-09-01T11:50:54.462000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/%E5%8D%B3%E5%88%BB%E5%85%8D%E8%B4%B9%E8%A7%A3%E9%94%81-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-%E5%9F%BA%E7%A1%80-ai-%E5%8C%85-base-ai-%E7%95%85%E4%BA%AB-joule-%E4%B8%8E%E5%86%85%E7%BD%AE-ai/ba-p/14204043</id>
    <title>即刻免费解锁：SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 基础 AI 包 (BASE AI)，畅享 Joule 与内置 AI 功能开通指南</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T09:26:31.868000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Helen_Han</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/131749</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;在 SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 中，SAP 提供了三类核心的&lt;STRONG&gt;基础AI (BASE AI)&lt;/STRONG&gt; 功能，旨在简化日常操作并提升用户体验。最重要的是——这些功能&lt;STRONG&gt;无需额外成本&lt;/STRONG&gt;。它们可通过 &lt;STRONG&gt;BASE AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;包免费开通&lt;/STRONG&gt;，或已包含在您的标准云订阅中，提供无限制访问，且无需购买额外的 AI 单元。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;本文将详细介绍这三种基础 AI 功能的范围，以及如何开通和获取相应的技术指导。&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;提示​​：&lt;/STRONG&gt;以下 AI 功能尚未在中国大陆地区上线，建议您咨询您的 SAP 客户经理以获取最新信息。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2017269178"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;基础&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;功能&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Joule Base AI Features)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule 是 SAP 的“一站式”AI 副驾驶，旨在通过提供直观、个性化和智能的用户体验来简化日常工作。Joule 拥有一系列覆盖 SAP 云应用程序的技能和能力，目标是支持 80% 最常用的任务和业务流程。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule 的基础 AI 功能主要通过以下三种交互模式提供能力：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;​&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;信息型&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Informational Capabilities)​&lt;/STRONG&gt;​：Joule 提供简明扼要的帮助内容摘要，以有效回答用户通过自然语言提出的问题。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;​&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;导航型&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Navigational Capabilities)​&lt;/STRONG&gt;​：Joule 推荐相关应用程序，并促进无缝导航，使用户能够执行其业务流程。SAP Cloud ERP 中有超过 500 个导航场景。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;​&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;事务型&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Transactional Capabilities)​&lt;/STRONG&gt;​：Joule 提供关于业务对象的深入信息，无需打开相应的应用程序。事务性交互使用户能够访问后端系统并管理业务任务，直接在对话中查看和操作业务对象。SAP Cloud ERP 中有超过 45 个事务场景。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1949838392"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;开通方式：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;您可以通过&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-base-entitlement.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Store&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;自助下单免费的&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SKU&lt;/STRONG&gt;或者&lt;STRONG&gt;联系您的销售代表为您下单。&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;请访问&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/artificial-intelligence/joule-base-entitlement.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Store&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;页面了解并开通&lt;/STRONG&gt;Joule 基础 AI 授权&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1753324887"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;技术设置官方文档&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;​：&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;初始设置&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap/initial-setup" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Initial Setup&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule 入门指南&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap/onboarding-joule" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Joule Onboarding Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;与 SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 的集成&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap/integration-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration &lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap/integration-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;with&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/integrating-joule-with-sap/integration-with-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt; SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;​&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP 也提供了基于&lt;STRONG&gt;Discovery Center Missions​&lt;/STRONG&gt;​的指导任务，帮助您一步步理解完成Joule 配置的必要步骤：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;创建Joule实例&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4538/4826/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Establish a Unified Joule Instance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;激活 Joule 与 SAP Cloud ERP &lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/missiondetail/4452/4738/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Activate Joule with SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1427728663"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;嵌入式基础&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;功能&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Embedded Base AI Features)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;这些 AI 功能直接嵌入在您的云 ERP 模块中，主要应用于用户体验等领域，通过自动化和简化任务来改善操作效率。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1360297877"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;功能范围：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;​&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;智能摘要&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Smart Summarization)​&lt;/STRONG&gt;​：对基于 Fiori Elements 的业务对象进行智能摘要。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;​&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;简易筛选&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Easy Filter)​&lt;/STRONG&gt;​：允许用户通过自然语言描述所需数据来筛选列表报告，适用于超过 1100 份报告。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;​&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;企业搜索&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Enterprise Search)​&lt;/STRONG&gt;​：支持用户使用自然语言进行企业搜索。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1163784372"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;开通方式：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;开通嵌入式基础 AI 功能的步骤如下：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;注册并接受&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapit-iex-prod-lizard.launchpad.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/9003c169-62d4-4285-b392-9e939ca5d535.workflowexternal.workflowexternal/preship/index.html#/create/1260" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI 条款​​&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;：由客户 S-User 或合作伙伴的 S-User 注册并接受 &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://sapit-iex-prod-lizard.launchpad.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/9003c169-62d4-4285-b392-9e939ca5d535.workflowexternal.workflowexternal/preship/index.html#/create/1260" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI 条款&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;。此操作只需执行一次，适用于 SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 的所有系统和租户。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;启动激活&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;​：在您接受条款后，SAP 将启动 AI 功能的激活并通知您。&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-967270867"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;系统配置：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;针对这些功能，SAP 提供了详细的配置指南和用户指南：&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;智能摘要：&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/4fc8d03390c342da8a60f8ee387bca1a/4a69b2cc611a40c4bf5afb42fa016e0e.html?version=2508.500" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;配置指南&lt;/A&gt; 和&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/4fc8d03390c342da8a60f8ee387bca1a/6c1bc21f01c840cba336404fb249cf95.html?version=2508.500" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;用户指南&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;简易筛选：&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/4fc8d03390c342da8a60f8ee387bca1a/e3410abd11404d87b319cb2d63a50a92.html?version=2508.500" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;配置指南&lt;/A&gt; 和&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/4fc8d03390c342da8a60f8ee387bca1a/804ed39a7dd34720912483ddfb847087.html?version=2508.500" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;用户指南&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;企业搜索：&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/f7765318841848a3941a3f4120d8cfd4.html?version=2508.00" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;配置指南&lt;/A&gt; 和&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a630d57fc5004c6383e7a81efee7a8bb/e69295d106654923be99d4ff4e22d751.html?version=2508.500" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;用户指南&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-641674643"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;机器学习基础&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; AI &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;场景&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; (Machine Learning Base AI Features)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;这些机器学习功能作为基础 AI 的一部分提供，旨在自动化和简化特定的业务流程，无需额外的许可证费用和申请。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;功能范围：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;​&lt;STRONG&gt;​&lt;/STRONG&gt;销售订单提取 (Sales Order Extraction, Scope Item 4X9)​​：&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;能够自动从 PDF 或图像格式的采购订单文件中创建销售订单（非结构化数据）。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;销售订单自动完成 (Sales Order Auto Completion, Scope Item 73P)​​：&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;为销售文档中缺失的数据提供建议，加快销售订单和客户退货订单的文档完成。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-574243857"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;开通方式：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;这些机器学习功能作为嵌入式基础 AI 功能的一部分，无需额外许可证即可使用。它们已包含在标准云订阅中，提供无限制访问。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-377730352"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;配置指导：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;销售订单提取&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/a376cd9ea00d476b96f18dea1247e6a5/2dcf49a616b842b096e0a3cad4dac458.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create Sales Orders - Automatic Extraction | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;销售订单自动完成&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/ee9ee0ca4c3942068ea584d2f929b5b1/4ee364ca1af446929d4e2c4fc2f709b9.html?version=2408.00" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Recommendation-Assisted Sales Order Completion | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Cloud ERP 的嵌入式基础 AI 功能、Joule 基础 AI 功能以及机器学习基础 AI 场景旨在通过提高最终用户满意度、改进生产力和节省时间来提升您的业务效率。由于它们包含在标准BASE AI订阅中且无需额外费用，我们鼓励您探索并激活这些功能，以充分利用 SAP 在人工智能方面的投资。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;更多信息及全面功能介绍请访问以下博客：&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-%E4%BA%AE%E7%82%B9%E5%89%8D%E7%9E%BB-%E4%BA%BA%E5%B7%A5%E6%99%BA%E8%83%BDartificial-intelligence/ba-p/14167515" target="_blank"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 亮点前瞻：人工智能Art... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/joule%E5%8A%9F%E8%83%BD%E5%85%A8%E6%99%AF%E4%BB%8B%E7%BB%8D-joule%E5%9C%A8sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition%E4%B8%AD%E7%9A%84%E6%A0%B8%E5%BF%83%E5%8A%9F%E8%83%BD%E4%B8%8E%E5%BA%94%E7%94%A8/ba-p/14164073" target="_blank"&gt;Joule功能全景介绍：Joule在SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/%E6%AC%A2%E8%BF%8E%E5%8A%A0%E5%85%A5-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508-%E6%9C%80%E6%96%B0-ai-%E8%BE%85%E5%8A%A9%E5%8A%9F%E8%83%BD%E7%9A%84-beta-%E6%B5%8B%E8%AF%95/ba-p/14170551" target="_blank"&gt;欢迎加入 SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 最新 AI 辅... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/%E5%8D%B3%E5%88%BB%E5%85%8D%E8%B4%B9%E8%A7%A3%E9%94%81-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-%E5%9F%BA%E7%A1%80-ai-%E5%8C%85-base-ai-%E7%95%85%E4%BA%AB-joule-%E4%B8%8E%E5%86%85%E7%BD%AE-ai/ba-p/14204043"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T09:26:31.868000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/environment-health-and-safety-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14204198</id>
    <title>Environment, Health and Safety in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T11:08:35.508000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ClaudiaRosbach</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1710699</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome to your one-stop shop to learn and share knowledge about SAP's ready-to-run public cloud ERP software solution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition is part of &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; that brings AI, data, and applications together into a fully integrated system. This community is open for anyone in the cloud ERP ecosystem–customers, partners, and SAP experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog post I’d like to outline the innovations for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 in the area of Environment, Health and Safety. These are the topics that are covered:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Management and applicability for compliance obligation registers (4C8)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conversational Incident (Safety Observations) with Joule (cloud) (4YX)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key performance indicators and safety insights for workplace safety (cloud) (4YX)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In case you do not need all the information below and briefly want to get an overview of the release highlights, please watch this video with the top three key innovations:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_96c3fk46" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Video#1:&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 for Environment, Health and Safety&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Management and applicability for compliance obligation registers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Background&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We delve into the evolution of compliance management with our newly introduced "Compliance Obligation Registers." This capability is designed to streamline the tracking and fulfillment of regulatory and internal compliance obligations, all within a centralized app. With the "Manage Compliance Register," EHS managers can seamlessly navigate through obligations tied to specific locations and subjects like air, waste, and water. The app’s structured interface illuminates each obligation’s applicability and fulfillment status through intuitive colour coding, allowing managers to quickly assess compliance health and pinpoint areas requiring attention. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Feature&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The integration of an enhanced operational compliance overview app provides stakeholders with analytical dashboards that track compliance performance. This empowers teams to maintain operational continuity by quickly identifying compliance lapses and facilitating swift corrective actions. By optimizing change logs to ensure audit trails and data traceability, businesses can now confidently navigate the complexities of compliance, bolstering both operational transparency and efficiency. Ultimately, this innovation not only promises seamless compliance management but also equips organizations with the insights needed to strategically plan and prioritize their compliance strategies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_om627r2l" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Video#2:&amp;nbsp;Management and applicability for compliance obligation registers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conversational Incident (Safety Observations) with Joule (cloud)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Background&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Moving on to employee safety reporting, our new AI-assisted "Safety Observation Recording Tool" underscores our commitment to enhancing workplace safety through technology. This tool empowers employees to report safety observations naturally and conversationally, minimizing the friction traditionally associated with incident reporting. By utilizing AI to parse and structure conversational inputs into formal reports, this tool accelerates incident logging, ensuring no detail is overlooked and every safety concern is addressed promptly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Feature&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The value proposition of this innovation lies in its ability to promote a proactive safety culture. By streamlining the reporting process, employees are encouraged to participate actively in safety programs, effectively turning every member of the workforce into a potential safety advocate. Moreover, the automatically structured data allows companies to rapidly identify and prioritize safety concerns, prompting timely interventions that mitigate risks before they escalate. This seamless interplay between technology and human initiative enhances safety standards and fosters a collaborative approach to workplace safety across all organizational levels.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_yb3721ss" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Video#3:&amp;nbsp;Conversational Incident (Safety Observations) with Joule (cloud)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key performance indicators and safety insights for workplace safety (cloud)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Background&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Finally, our "Workplace Safety Insights" application introduces a new paradigm in safety performance management. By leveraging real-time data, this tool provides managers with dynamic insight cards that enable continuous monitoring of safety metrics. From regulatory compliance KPIs to operational safety trends, these cards offer a multifaceted view that helps managers identify potential risk areas and address them through data-driven decisions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Feature&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;This innovation is key to establishing a sustainable safety environment by identifying potential issues before they become critical. The real-time analysis allows safety managers to implement preventive actions and corrective strategies, maintaining a high standard of safety operations. Through these strategic insights, companies can not only ensure compliance but also promote a culture of safety vigilance that permeates the entire organization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_k3r44186" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Video#4: Key performance indicators and safety insights for workplace safety (cloud)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for taking the time to read this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don’t hesitate to leave a comment and check out our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;community page&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to ask your questions and engage with the experts. Follow the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/PSCC_Enablement/tg-p/board-id/erp-blog-sap" target="_blank"&gt;PSCC_Enablement&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;tag to stay up to date with our latest blog posts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1649975545" id="toc-hId-1888187580"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you want to learn more in-depth, just a heads-up that from &lt;STRONG&gt;September 30th to October 2nd&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the v&lt;STRONG&gt;irtual EHS &amp;amp; Product Compliance Infodays&lt;/STRONG&gt; are taking place. You can register &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4942585&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=98DDEC90391042F1B0EC2C72608C443E&amp;amp;groupId=6107761&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; to see the agenda and join the event.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From July 21-25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for LoB/Industry/Topic as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ClaudiaRosbach_0-1756798246916.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307674i9A7F6D2A8F46BC11/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ClaudiaRosbach_0-1756798246916.png" alt="ClaudiaRosbach_0-1756798246916.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/environment-health-and-safety-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14204198"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T11:08:35.508000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/product-compliance-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14204257</id>
    <title>Product Compliance in SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T11:31:52.736000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ClaudiaRosbach</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1710699</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome to your one-stop shop to learn and share knowledge about SAP's ready-to-run public cloud ERP software solution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition is part of &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-suite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; that brings AI, data, and applications together into a fully integrated system. This community is open for anyone in the cloud ERP ecosystem–customers, partners, and SAP experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog post I’d like to outline the innovations for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 in the area of Product Compliance. These are the topics that are covered:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Classifying dangerous goods packaged in logistics packing instructions (3FC)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;EU safety data sheet generation for first scenarios and product groups (7DO)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support of branded products in the safety data sheet process (3VR)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In case you do not need all the information below and briefly want to get an overview of the release highlights, please watch this video with the top three key innovations:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_yadkxfvl" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Video#1:&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 for Product Compliance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Classifying dangerous goods packaged in logistics packing instructions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Background&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This feature revolutionizes compliance management by enabling users to manage and maintain compliance for products packaged through logistics instructions from handling unit management. By seamlessly integrating with our existing classification app for packaged products, this innovation allows businesses to comply with various dangerous goods regulations more efficiently. The integration not only enhances accuracy in classification but also simplifies the overarching regulatory processes, reducing the complexity traditionally associated with managing dangerous goods.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Feature&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This enhancement facilitates a systematic approach to compliance, leveraging the strengths of both classification apps to forge a cohesive, streamlined process. Companies can now ensure that compliance standards are met across the board by aligning logistic packing instructions with the regulatory demands of dangerous goods. This capability ultimately results in a more coherent compliance strategy that mitigates potential risks and fosters a safer operational environment.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_gquu85fu" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Video#2:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;Classifying dangerous goods packaged in logistics packing instructions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;EU safety data sheet generation for first scenarios and product groups&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Background&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our safety data sheet (SDS) generation feature has received significant enhancement to support first scenarios and product groups, particularly tailored for European Union compliance requirements. Leveraging integrated regulatory content for GHS specification, this feature ensures that your safety data sheets are comprehensive and meet the highest standards. One of the standout aspects is its incorporation of a starter template, allowing for customization to fit the unique needs of your business while maintaining compliance integrity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Feature&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A key complement to this is the new preview functionality, which offers the ability to verify end products before distribution, adding an essential layer of quality assurance in documentation. By ensuring the accuracy and compliance of each document before it reaches stakeholders, the enhancement minimizes the risk of non-compliance and potential disruptions. This innovative solution not only supports compliance practices but enhances them, offering a smooth path to achieving regulatory standards.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_9b56x81c" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Video#3:&amp;nbsp;EU safety data sheet generation for first scenarios and product groups&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Support of branded products in the safety data sheet process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Business Background&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our third key innovation is the support for branded products within the SDS process, which provides an entirely new dimension to product compliance management. This feature allows businesses to create and manage branded products distinctly from unpackaged or packaged ones, ensuring that they are accurately reflected in safety data sheets and other critical compliance documents. This added layer of flexibility allows organizations to represent their product portfolio authentically, while still adhering to rigorous compliance requirements.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Feature&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In addition, the branded products support means that businesses can optimize their regulatory processes for product differentiation, enabling them to stand out in the market while maintaining stringent compliance. By integrating branded names and specific product branding details into compliance documentation, companies are provided with the tools to navigate complex brand management issues with ease. This feature is especially useful for businesses with extensive product lines, permitting them to handle compliance needs across diverse product offerings seamlessly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_ljlwlsmg" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Video#4: Support of branded products in the safety data sheet process &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The value proposition we offer with Release 2508 is substantial. By integrating these innovations, we empower organizations to manage their product compliance with unprecedented ease and efficiency. You gain reliable compliance mechanisms that support global trade, mitigate risks, and protect your reputation. Our tools also help reduce administrative overhead and expedite the time-to-market by automating complex tasks and diminishing potential errors in compliance processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks for taking the time to read this blog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don’t hesitate to leave a comment and check out our&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/topics/s4hana-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;community page&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to ask your questions and engage with the experts. Follow the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/PSCC_Enablement/tg-p/board-id/erp-blog-sap" target="_blank"&gt;PSCC_Enablement&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;tag to stay up to date with our latest blog posts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you want to learn more in-depth, just a heads-up that from &lt;STRONG&gt;September 30th to October 2nd&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the v&lt;STRONG&gt;irtual EHS &amp;amp; Product Compliance Infodays&lt;/STRONG&gt; are taking place. You can register &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4942585&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=98DDEC90391042F1B0EC2C72608C443E&amp;amp;groupId=6107761&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; to see the agenda and join the event.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From July 21-25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for LoB/Industry/Topic as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ClaudiaRosbach_0-1756804360562.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307738iD66FBB491E7AE4FF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="ClaudiaRosbach_0-1756804360562.png" alt="ClaudiaRosbach_0-1756804360562.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/product-compliance-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14204257"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T11:31:52.736000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/retail-fashion-and-vertical-business-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14197250</id>
    <title>Retail, fashion and vertical business in SAP S/4HANA Cloud public edition 2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T17:05:12.941000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SiShores</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1755685</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Designed specifically for fashion and specialty businesses &lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, retail, fashion, and vertical business&lt;/SPAN&gt; natively support for enriched product management, advanced pricing, and promotional workflows—all integrated into core ERP processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It includes intuitive in-store apps that streamline procurement, inventory management, and omni-channel operations such as buy-online-pickup-in-store. Real-time data access helps store associates stay productive and customer-focused.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With comprehensive end-to-end process coverage, the solution ensures seamless operations across all roles and functions within a retail enterprise a&lt;/SPAN&gt;nd covers key domains including master data, merchandising, supply chain, store operations, and sales. Modular scope items, documented in SAP’s Process Navigator, enable fast activation and reduced implementation complexity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Retail E2E roles 2508.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308059i676A75DE45084BE9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Retail E2E roles 2508.png" alt="Retail E2E roles 2508.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The 2508 Release adds features across in-store sales, order management, and assortment operations, including hybrid orders, continuous scanning, support for weight-based articles, and mass assortment assignments. Here is a quick summary of some the key highlights in a short video:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_59oaj2ja" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s dive into three key highlights that will help you deliver impact at scale.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Monetize Your Offerings: Charging for Value-Added Services (VAS)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Retail operations often involve additional services—like custom labelling or packaging—that carry extra costs. To manage these effectively, we’ve introduced a feature that allows users to define and assign Value-Added Service (VAS) charge codes directly at the item level in both Purchase Orders and Sales Orders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These charge codes are centrally configured, making them easy to maintain and reusable across multiple service types. Once applied, they are automatically reflected in all relevant follow-on documents, ensuring consistency and transparency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This capability supports accurate pricing by including service-related costs in the item’s total value. It also helps businesses offer tailored, premium services while maintaining clear visibility into associated charges—enhancing both operational efficiency and customer perception.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mass assignment of products in assortments&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For category managers and assortment specialists, keeping assortments up-to-date—especially during seasonal changes or new product introductions—can be a time-consuming and click-intensive process. We heard your feedback and have delivered a major enhancement to streamline this critical task.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The Manage Assortment Modules app now allows for the efficient mass assignment of products, transforming a manual effort into a smart, automated workflow.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Recent updates to assortment module management deliver significant improvements in both scale and precision.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can now assign up to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;1,000 products&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to an assortment module in a single batch—five times the previous limit of 200. This increase is achieved without any impact on system performance, allowing for larger and more efficient planning cycles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To support more accurate product selection, we've introduced&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;attribute-based filtering&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Users can now filter by&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;generic article&lt;/STRONG&gt;, as well as specific characteristics like&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;color&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;size&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling precise and targeted assortment creation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The user experience has also been streamlined. The assignment process now begins directly at the product selection list, reducing unnecessary navigation. Once products are assigned to a module, they are automatically removed from the selection list, helping prevent duplicate entries and simplifying tracking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, these enhancements accelerate assortment planning, improve data accuracy, and allow retail teams to focus more on strategic, value-added activities.&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These enhancements dramatically accelerate your assortment planning cycles, improve accuracy through attribute-based filtering, and free up your specialists’ time to focus on more strategic, value-added work.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_96nqt8xo" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Revolutionize In-Store Operations with Hybrid Sales Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Imagine a customer in your store. They want to purchase a camera that’s in stock and take it home today. At the same time, they want to pre-order a new coffee maker that is currently unavailable. Previously, this would require two separate, cumbersome transactions. Not anymore.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The 2508 release introduces hybrid sales order functionality in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manage In-Store Sales Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fiori app, enabling store associates to process multiple fulfillment types within a single transaction.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This innovation addresses a common retail scenario: a customer wants to purchase an in-stock item for immediate pickup and simultaneously pre-order an unavailable product. Previously, this required two separate transactions. Now, both can be handled together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Store associates can create one sales order that includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immediate Pickup Items&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Entered using standard item categories, with support for GTIN/barcode scanning to speed up product selection.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scheduled Pickup Items&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Designated with different item categories and shipping points to indicate future fulfillment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The system intelligently separates fulfillment flows. When the associate selects “Generate Invoice,” only the immediate pickup items are processed. The system automatically creates the outbound delivery, posts goods issue, and generates the customer invoice. Items scheduled for later pickup remain open for future processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This enhancement simplifies operations, reduces transaction time, and allows associates to better serve customers with varied needs—all within a unified workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_uevztmw4" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;### Stay Connected&lt;BR /&gt;These are just a few of the highlights from the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. We are dedicated to continuously enhancing our retail solution to meet the dynamic needs of your business.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To explore these features in more detail, please check out the resources below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Official product page:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/erp/grow/industry/retail.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP website&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://partneredge.sap.com/en/solution/retail/about.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Partner portal&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;(log in needed)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Full retail solution processes:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/SolS/EARL_SolS-013/2408?region=DE&amp;amp;share=41081528-ba61-47c4-aa12-85f4d4a873e1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Process Navigator – SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learning journey:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/learning-journeys/exploring-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-for-retail" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Exploring SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, retail, fashion and vertical business&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;End-2-End Retail Demo:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://ivj-vx.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/journey/acafd523-e023-4279-a4bc-745b3da0b580/f8701bf8-3d4d-4f4d-9b80-835730cff37f" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Interactive Value Journey&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":film_projector:"&gt;📽&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Watch the replays of our SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 Early Release Series!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From July 21-25, we hosted a series of 21 compelling live sessions to highlight the exciting innovations shipped with the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508 release. Missed the live sessions? We've got you covered! Take advantage of the entire series or pick and choose the sessions most relevant to you. You will find the recording and presentation for LoB/Industry/Topic as well as 20 other topics of interest. Don't miss this chance and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/watch-the-replays-of-our-exclusive-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-2508/ba-p/14166300" target="_blank"&gt;watch them on demand&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;–anywhere, anytime.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find all our assets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We at Cloud ERP Product Success offer a service as versatile as our product itself. Check out the numerous offerings our team has created for you below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SiShores_0-1756396196884.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306052i86780D91EB39B68B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SiShores_0-1756396196884.png" alt="SiShores_0-1756396196884.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/retail-fashion-and-vertical-business-in-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14197250"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T17:05:12.941000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/product-update-batch-management-in-service-orders/ba-p/14206323</id>
    <title>Product Update: Batch Management in Service Orders</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T18:03:09.214000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>varunvenkat</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/83606</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In one of my previous &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/enhancing-the-standard-part-2-supporting-batch-management-in-the-service/ba-p/13576494" target="_blank"&gt;blog posts&lt;/A&gt; last year, I had covered a workaround approach on how to deal with using batch managed products in the service order process. Up till now, there was no integration which allowed the usage of batch managed products in the service order process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the release upgrade 2508, the usage of batch managed products is now supported in the service order process. In the service confirmation item for the batch-managed product, there is a field “Batch” now available, where the batch number of the product can be entered:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="varunvenkat_0-1756915318074.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308723iE30D4A2D5846621C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="varunvenkat_0-1756915318074.png" alt="varunvenkat_0-1756915318074.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/product-update-batch-management-in-service-orders/ba-p/14206323"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T18:03:09.214000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-key-user-in-app-custom-logic-extensibility-to-change-edocument/ba-p/14206358</id>
    <title>How to use key-user in-app Custom Logic extensibility to change eDocument currency in SAP Cloud ERP</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T18:50:33.202000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Glauber</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/19974</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-958441847" id="toc-hId-1759166241"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some countries (like Colombia) might required to have reports sent to fiscal authority on their local currency even if the transaction was executed in a different currency and is registered on the system in a foreign currency. On&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition/pd-p/08e2a51b-1ce5-4367-8b33-4ae7e8b702e0" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1199-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;this requirement might be delivered in some localizations via extensibility as a localization as a Self-service to be implemented during implementation project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below example, shows how a sale in USD would be reported without the extensibility (left) and with extensibility solution (right):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Reports with and without BAdI extension.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/308739i55726294279FE871/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Reports with and without BAdI extension.png" alt="Reports with and without BAdI extension.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-958441847" id="toc-hId-1562652736"&gt;Solution through Extensibility&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on a demand for Colombia invoice eDocument, we have developed the KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003648968" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3648968&lt;/A&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;On the KBA, we instruct how to find extension points (BAdIs) to change information in eDocument generated via &lt;STRONG&gt;eDocument Cockpit&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Electronic Documents&lt;/STRONG&gt; apps. We also highlight that for each localization, it should be consulted the SAP Help Portal documentation for that localization to check which extension points are available and which should be used.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We also provide a proof-of-concept sample code that shows how the change for a XML file created for an eDocument for Colombia can be changed. Note that each localization and eDocument likely will have different extension points and limitation as well as each implementation might have its own requirements that will result on complete different code. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;So each implementation should develop its own code and the KBA code is only an example and do not cover all scenarios nor is a final solution to be implemented.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--810179698" id="toc-hId-1366139231"&gt;Important Assets&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following documentation might be helpful to obtain more detailed information:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2805847/E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2805847 - eDocument Colombia Troubleshooting Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Topic B103)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003648968" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3648968&amp;nbsp;- Currency issues and Extensibility in Colombia eDocuments - SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP KBA&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0002974488" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2974488 - Calculation errors in CUFE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Help Portal:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/cb9131e59ba34741923bd19ef4cb1f90/f4eaec7288064c7aadfd4511011a7ad7.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Colombia App Extensibility&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help Portal:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/60a09f68f2444ceca31dcac2e7017945/546e6657290ba57ae10000000a4450e5.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Country/Region-Specific Functions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Help Portal:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD/0f69f8fb28ac4bf48d2b57b9637e81fa/228e93706169472abdb1665293378e8b.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Creating Implementations&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1246244860" id="toc-hId-1427791164"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;This content was brought to you by the SAP S/4HANA Cloud Customer Care Team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-use-key-user-in-app-custom-logic-extensibility-to-change-edocument/ba-p/14206358"/>
    <published>2025-09-03T18:50:33.202000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/preliminary-what-s-new-information-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14203312</id>
    <title>Preliminary What’s New Information for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.1</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T11:01:40.056000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>diana_vega</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/755777</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Preliminary version of What’s New information and of the Product Assistance are now available for customers and partners to get a preview on the upcoming new and changed features of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.1.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can find this preview on the current SAP Help Portal page&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_CLOUD?task=whats_new_task" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;(see What’s New section “Preview of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.1”). To access the Preliminary What’s New information, please use the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/4328a3353fb14ef6ba3345697ac9ecc3?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=1" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;or the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://release-assessment-v2.cfapps.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/cp.portal/site#Shell-home" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Release Assessment and Scope Dependency (RASD)&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;tool.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The RASD tool provides you with a personalized and tailored view on What’s New information based on the activated and used scope within your system. The preliminary information for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508.1 will be available in RASD within the next few days. We recommend using RASD to prepare for upgrades and updates of your system and to focus on the new and changed features that are relevant for you. A valid S-User ID is needed to use the RASD tool and to view all the preliminary content stated above.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For any feedback you may have, try the Commenting Feature for What's New documentation in this release.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blogs-by-sap/sap-s-4hana-cloud-2408-what-s-new-leave-us-your-feedback/ba-p/13737734" target="_self"&gt;See this blog&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;for more information.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/preliminary-what-s-new-information-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/14203312"/>
    <published>2025-09-04T11:01:40.056000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-continuous-influence-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-outcome-of/ba-p/14207312</id>
    <title>SAP Continuous Influence for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition – Outcome of the Q3/2025 Review</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T14:51:18.004000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DoreenBaseler</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/92695</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Blog_Banner.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/125701i4F79391A036D988D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog_Banner.png" alt="Blog_Banner.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dear Customers and Partners,&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;With the release of SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508, we are pleased to share an update on the progress made in response to your valuable input submitted via the Customer Influence portal. As part of our ongoing commitment, we continue to prioritize qualified requests while also considering those that did not meet the voting threshold—based on strategic alignment and available capacity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Highlights from the Q3/2025 Review&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We invite you to explore the latest outcomes and progress on customer requests addressed during the recent review cycle. For detailed spotlights, please refer to the individual blog posts from each&amp;nbsp;SAP Continuous Influence session&amp;nbsp;related to SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, published in case of major updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you for your continued engagement and collaboration!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="640px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Session&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Review Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP Central Business Configuration for SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3693" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Advanced Variant Configuration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3692/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Asset Management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1172/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, CDS View Extraction Enablement&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;See&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3024/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Data Management and Data Migration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3694" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Enterprise Portfolio and Project Management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3704" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Finance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1169/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition and Private Edition, Environment, Health and Safety&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3615/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition and Private Edition,&lt;BR /&gt;Group Reporting&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2283/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Localization&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3692" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Manufacturing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1171/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Master Data Maintenance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/1713/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Product Compliance&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/3334/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Professional Services Automation&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3703" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Sales&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3705" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Service&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3696" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Sourcing and Procurement&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3695" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="30px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, Supply Chain Logistics&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="30px"&gt;See &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/campaign/2897/ideas-all" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;request status list&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="453.219px" height="57px"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition, User Experience and Cross-Topics&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="185.781px" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/blog/3691" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Q3/2025&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-continuous-influence-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition-outcome-of/ba-p/14207312"/>
    <published>2025-09-04T14:51:18.004000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/print-form-adaptation-with-adobe-livecycle-designer-overview-onboarding/ba-p/14208960</id>
    <title>Print Form Adaptation with Adobe LiveCycle Designer Overview - Onboarding, Blogs and Live Sessions</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T18:00:07.827000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Felix_Wyskocil</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/142195</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1630148893"&gt;Intro&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog gives an overview of my print form resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Onboarding Video:&lt;/STRONG&gt; If you're new to Adobe LiveCycle Designer, I recommend watching the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Onboarding&amp;nbsp;Video&lt;/STRONG&gt; below.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blogs:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The Blogs provide guidance on some typical requirements and questions that you may come across while working on print forms.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Live Sessions:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Visit the &lt;STRONG&gt;Live Sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt; if you want to see some hands-on demonstrations or ask questions that you haven't found answers to so far.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1433635388"&gt;Live Sessions&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I deliver live sessions with a changing agenda on the topic of print form adaptation. If you are interested and would like to join, you can find the dates and the registration link on our learning platform&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/live-sessions/print-form-adaptation-with-adobe-livecycle-designer-for-sap-sales-and-service-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;learning.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Please note that you need a subscription in order to register for the live session!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The live sessions focus mainly on the work with the Adobe LiveCycle Designer itself, hence the major part is solution-independent. However, we usually look into at least one of the following SAP solutions in every session:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales/Service Cloud (former Cloud for Customer)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Sales/Service Cloud Version 2&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business ByDesign&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition (only general form maintenance)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1237121883"&gt;List of Print Form Blogs&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/03/24/how-to-get-xml-data-for-local-preview-of-print-forms-without-output-history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;How to get XML data for local preview of print forms without output history&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/print-form-adaptation-in-sales-service-2-get-xml-data-for-preview-in-adobe/ba-p/13742213" target="_self"&gt;Print Form Adaptation in Sales/Service 2: Get XML data for preview in Adobe LiveCycle Designer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/10/23/data-binding-basics-for-print-forms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Binding Basics for Print Forms&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/10/23/data-binding-with-repeating-items-and-simple-tables-in-print-forms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Binding with Repeating Items and Simple Tables in Print Forms&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/10/23/data-binding-with-repeating-items-and-complex-tables-in-print-forms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Binding with Repeating Items and Complex Tables in Print Forms&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/10/23/data-binding-with-repeating-items-and-complex-tables-in-print-forms/#ScriptingTables" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Building Tables with Scripts&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/dynamically-hiding-table-columns-in-print-forms-with-adobe-livecycle/ba-p/13872322" target="_self"&gt;Dynamically Hiding Table Columns in Print Forms with Adobe LiveCycle Designer and JavaScript&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1040608378"&gt;Onboarding Video&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The following video gives a very basic introduction to the Adobe LiveCycle Designer (ALD) itself and explains form maintenance in SAP Sales Cloud and SAP Service Cloud (version 1), as well as SAP Business ByDesign.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/source-Ids-list" target="1_j44dho57" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subscribe&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to this blog post if you want to get informed about new blogs of this series or and other print form related updates. Visit &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/142195" target="_self"&gt;my SAP Community profile&lt;/A&gt; to find more blogs on&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SAP Customer Experience Solutions – Integration and Extensibility&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;topics!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/print-form-adaptation-with-adobe-livecycle-designer-overview-onboarding/ba-p/14208960"/>
    <published>2025-09-05T18:00:07.827000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-for-joule-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-2508/ba-p/14209380</id>
    <title>What's New for Joule in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud-2508</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T07:55:59.978000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shubham1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/132064</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is a blog post of What's New features introduced in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud 2508 edition in the exciting world of &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New use cases now supported&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule&amp;nbsp;now enables you to view business data of many SAP objects like Process order , Solution order, Enterprise project , Inspection methods , Work Centers and many more...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update Delivery Date for Purchase Orders&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;enables you, as a purchaser, to update delivery dates for purchase orders.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For example, when suppliers or equivalent sources inform you of delays or changes, you can use Joule to update the delivery dates with the new information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Checking sales order fulfillment status&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule&amp;nbsp;allows you to check whether a sales order's fulfillment is on track and identify the issues that block its fulfillment. For each sales order,&amp;nbsp;Joule&amp;nbsp;can tell whether such issues exist in the order processing phase. If yes, you can display issue details, view possible causes and handling suggestions for each issue, and navigate to related apps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expiring Prices Handling&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule&amp;nbsp;now enables you to manage expiring prices (stored as condition records for pricing in sales) in&amp;nbsp;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition. With&amp;nbsp;Joule, you can fetch prices that will expire soon, extend their valid-to dates, and adjust their condition amounts or ratios as you need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Electronic Document Error Explanations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Manage Electronic Documents app now enables natural language interaction with&amp;nbsp;Joule, making it easier to understand electronic document exchange errors. You can ask&amp;nbsp;Joule&amp;nbsp;for error explanations and recommended resolution steps. By providing detailed insights, SAP Joule helps you understand the root cause of errors and offers guidance on corrective actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are many more features which can be explored by clicking on the What's New Viewer link&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/what-s-new-for-joule-capabilities" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/joule/capabilities-guide/what-s-new-for-joule-capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks!!!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore the SAP Business AI features with SAP Joule.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shubham&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Joule/pd-p/d0136351-8a9c-4881-aebc-bf414b785998" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1207-1"&gt;Joule&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+AI/pd-p/73554900100700002751" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1247-1"&gt;SAP Business AI&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition/pd-p/08e2a51b-1ce5-4367-8b33-4ae7e8b702e0" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1199-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-for-joule-in-sap-s-4hana-public-cloud-2508/ba-p/14209380"/>
    <published>2025-09-06T07:55:59.978000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
