<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Analytics-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-11-04T09:00:20.181107+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Analytics Cloud/pd-p/67838200100800006884" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Analytics Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-model-size-analysis-in-sac/ba-p/14238307</id>
    <title>SAP Business Data Cloud - Model Size Analysis in SAC</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T15:30:22.573000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_fery</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/259114</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2020161668"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Clearer View of Your Data: Introducing the New Model Size and Analysis Dashboard for SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;For administrators and system owners of SAP Analytics Cloud, maintaining a high-performing and stable environment is a top priority. As organizations expand their use of SAC, managing the underlying data volumes becomes increasingly important.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A technical consideration in this context are the database tables, which have a system limit of 2 billion records. Reaching this limit has a significant consequence: it blocks all data publishing for planning models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Until now, gaining proactive visibility into this data growth has been a challenge. Administrators often faced key questions without easy answers:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which of our hundreds of models are the largest and contributing most to our data footprint?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Is the growth coming from transaction data, or is the audit log expanding rapidly?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In our largest models, which specific versions (e.g., Forecast, Budget 2025) are consuming the most space?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today, we are pleased to introduce a solution designed to provide clear answers to these questions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to access:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Open the story in your tenant by going to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Side Menu &amp;gt; Performance &amp;gt; Model Size Statistics and Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_0-1759929912175.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324698i94B3E265E7AF6708/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="thomas_fery_0-1759929912175.png" alt="thomas_fery_0-1759929912175.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1823648163"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing the "Model Size Statistics and Analysis" Dashboard&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Available with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2025.QRC4 release&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we are delivering a new Story in SAC Content designed to give you the transparency and control you need to manage your SAC tenant's data footprint effectively. This Story serves as a central overview for monitoring, analyzing, and then to be able to take an informed action on data volumes before they become a critical issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_0-1759928975319.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324681iAB201907951E5049/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="thomas_fery_0-1759928975319.png" alt="thomas_fery_0-1759928975319.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Let's explore its key capabilities.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1627134658"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Capabilities: From Overview to Actionable Insight&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This new Story empowers you with a multi-layered analytical approach:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1559703872"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Instantly Identify Your Largest Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The dashboard presents a clear, ranked list of your&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Top 30 Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;by total record count. This immediately answers the fundamental question: "Where is my data?" This allows you to focus your attention where it's needed most, without guesswork or manual checks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1363190367"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Understand Data Composition with Category Breakdowns&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Once you select a model, the dashboard reveals a breakdown by&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Category&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. You can clearly see the ratio of Transaction Data, Audit Data, Master Data, and more. This is crucial for understanding the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;nature&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;of your model's size. Is it growing because of massive data loads, or is it the audit trail from frequent planning activities?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-1166676862"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Uncover Version-Level Insights (Even in Large Models)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;This is a significant enhancement. Previously, for models exceeding 100 million records, it was not possible to see the size of individual public versions within the Modeler. The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Model Size and Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;dashboard removes this limitation. You can now select a large model and see a clear chart showing which versions are the biggest contributors. This provides the information you need to target specific versions for cleanup or archiving&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_1-1759929036237.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324683i75008790B45AA47D/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="thomas_fery_1-1759929036237.png" alt="thomas_fery_1-1759929036237.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-970163357"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Correlate Growth with System Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The dashboard provides historical charts that track record growth over time. More importantly, it overlays this data with&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Import Jobs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Version Publish Events&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. You can now visually correlate a spike in data with a specific data load or a major publishing cycle, creating a clear cause-and-effect relationship. This helps you understand&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;why&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;when&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;your data is growing, enabling you to optimize your data management processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_2-1759929103872.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/324684iD4E1C8EAC4DB52DF/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="thomas_fery_2-1759929103872.png" alt="thomas_fery_2-1759929103872.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-644567133"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Business Value: More Than Just Numbers&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This dashboard delivers tangible business value by transforming how you manage your SAC environment:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ensure Business Continuity:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;By proactively monitoring the Audit and Fact table limits, you can prevent a system-wide pause on planning operations, safeguarding critical business processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable Proactive Housekeeping:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Move from a reactive to a proactive stance. Analyze data growth trends, identify old or unnecessary versions, and perform timely cleanup actions to keep your tenant lean and performant.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create Actionable Transparency:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The dashboard doesn't just provide data; it provides answers. You can now confidently explain data growth and justify housekeeping activities to business stakeholders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reduce Resource Consumption &amp;amp; Improve Performance:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;A well-maintained tenant with optimized data volumes naturally performs better. By cleaning up unnecessary data, you reduce the load on the system, leading to a better experience for all users.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get started today!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Once your tenant is updated to&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;2025.QRC4&lt;/STRONG&gt;, explore this new content and take command of your data. Empower yourself with the insight to ensure your SAP Analytics Cloud environment remains stable, performant, and ready for the future.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-448053628"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-122457404"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practical Tip: Keeping Your Audit Logs in Check&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A common question from administrators is, "How can I quickly find all models that have the audit function enabled?" This is a crucial housekeeping task because while audit logs can be essential for compliance, they are also sometimes activated by mistake and lead to uncontrolled data growth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The "Model Size and Analysis" dashboard helps you answer this question in seconds:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to do it:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Simply use the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Data Category" input control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;at the top of the page and filter the view to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Audit"&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_0-1760523402332.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327835i284A2DA8C4705C65/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="thomas_fery_0-1760523402332.png" alt="thomas_fery_0-1760523402332.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Result:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;The entire dashboard immediately focuses on the relevant information. The KPIs will show you the exact number of models with an active audit function, and the "Top 30" list will rank those models by the size of their audit table. This gives you a clear, prioritized list to start your review and take action where needed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;If the "Top 30" list doesn't cover all the models you want to review, you can simply switch to Edit mode and expand the chart's ranking (e.g., to a Top 50 or Top 100).&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-model-size-analysis-in-sac/ba-p/14238307"/>
    <published>2025-10-08T15:30:22.573000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864</id>
    <title>Unlocking the Next Chapter of Seamless Planning in SAP Business Data Cloud with Live Versions</title>
    <updated>2025-10-14T20:34:01.157000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Max_Gander</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14553</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762775784"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Seamless planning is generally available since Q1 2025. Since then, plan data resides directly in SAP Datasphere and with that, in the core of SAP Business Data Cloud. We are now thrilled to announce the release of live versions with QRC4 2025 (fast track wave 20.2025) that bring fact data into planning models without replication! Learn how this works, why it brings many planning use cases to a new level and how it benefits from the data product architecture of BDC.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I also want to highlight more features that we are introducing in this context:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seamless planning support for SAP Analytics Cloud compass incl. support for live versions (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-compass-support-of-seamless-planning-amp-live-version/ba-p/14245059?emcs_t=S2h8ZW1haWx8bWVudGlvbl9zdWJzY3JpcHRpb258TUdTOUlXNk5SRlBORUZ8MTQyNDUwNTl8QVRfTUVOVElPTlN8aEs" target="_blank"&gt;Check out this great blogpost &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46487"&gt;@ChenNee&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Detection of mismatches between fact and master data (postings on dimension members that are not part of your dimension tables)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Planning on live versions from other sources (e.g., Google BigQuery; not applicable for seamless planning; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/live-versions-from-an-sql-source-for-sap-analytics-cloud-planning/ba-p/14245675#M185464" target="_blank"&gt;check out this blogpost&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Watch out for more blogposts to come in the next weeks!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566262279"&gt;Use cases &amp;amp; benefits&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You cannot plan in a data vacuum. Plans rely on reference data and input. That can be actual data, other plan data, external influencer data etc. &amp;nbsp;Until now, you were required to physically bring this data into your planning models using import jobs, uploads or data actions. Hence, live versions represent an advanced paradigm to data management and offer benefits in core planning scenarios for different personas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accurate forecasts &amp;amp; plans&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Live versions pull actuals, and external drivers directly from SAP Datasphere into your planning models - without replication. This removes latency and reconciliation work, so forecasts are built on the latest, governed facts from a single source of truth. Rolling forecasts and variance analysis become immediate and more reliable, reducing forecast bias and improving plan quality. Live versions can even feed SAP Analytics Cloud predictive scenarios with live data!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Extended Planning and Analysis: &lt;/STRONG&gt;Cross-functional teams (finance, supply chain, sales, HR) consume the same governed facts directly from SAP Datasphere. Plans, assumptions and driver changes propagate instantly across domains, enabling end-to-end scenarios, consistent KPIs, and accelerating aligned decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operating a planning solution&lt;/STRONG&gt;: No more nightly imports, manual uploads, or complex data actions to keep models current. Live versions reduce data movement &amp;amp; data footprint, simplify model building &amp;amp; operations, and lower TCO. Furthermore, the graphical modeling interface in SAP Datasphere lets you define joins, mappings, transformations etc. to bring data into the exact shape that you need for your planning model.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud's data product architecture augments this opportunity.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use SAP-managed data products and base planning models directly on curated data from SAP applications.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use customer-managed data products from SAP BW PCE to support hybrid planning architectures while transitioning from BPC to planning in BDC.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Integrate results from SAP Databricks via SAP Datasphere&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1369748774"&gt;How does it work?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1302317988"&gt;Add data to an existing model&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your model details, you will find a new entry in the ‘Data’ section which is called ‘External Live Version Data Sources’&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Here, ‘Connect External Data Source’&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose an existing target version for the data source or create a blank version&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose your fact view from your model’s SAP Datasphere space&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Map the data source columns to your model’s columns&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Not all source columns need to be mapped&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Not all target columns need to be mapped&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Measures can be &lt;EM&gt;NULL&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dimensions can receive a default member&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Certain data type differences can be handled&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If we detect a mismatch between the live version and your master data, we will notify you and you can add missing dimension members directly (not shown in the video)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You’re done! You can add more sources to the model, if you want&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Adding a live version to a model" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327483i1D3D3E0DF1214EC6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ExtVersion_Blog.gif" alt="Adding a live version to a model" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Adding a live version to a model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105804483"&gt;Build a model from an SAP Datasphere view&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;‘Start with data’&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select SAP Datasphere as data storage location (=use seamless planning)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select a space. The view you want to use as basis for the planning model must be in the same space or shared with the space&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select SAP Datasphere as datasource&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select your view&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You now already see the live connection to the source view data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create dimension tables as needed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save the model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You’re done!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Creating a model from an SAP Datasphere view" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327484i51C5F095BEE2534E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ExtVersion_Blog2.gif" alt="Creating a model from an SAP Datasphere view" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Creating a model from an SAP Datasphere view&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-780208259"&gt;A usage example&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following example, we add headcount (full-time equivalent / FTE) data to the previously created sales planning model because we want to add a calculation of revenue generated per sales employee.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We have an FTE planning model which is deployed to our SAP Datasphere space. Note that the fact table is exposed in the data builder.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We create a view on the fact table with a filter on sales employees in SAP Datasphere&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We add the view to our sales planning model, do the mappings and add a calculation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the story, we see the live data from the FTE planning model and the calculation result&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When we change data in the FTE planning and publish it, the calculation in the sales model is refreshed in real-time&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Referring to data from another planning model" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327485iA68D040563AB2725/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="ExtVers_Blog_FTE.gif" alt="Referring to data from another planning model" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Referring to data from another planning model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-583694754"&gt;FAQ&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where can I use this feature?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature is available for SAP Analytics Cloud models that use SAP Datasphere as data storage location (=seamless planning models).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Can I use any fact table/view from SAP Datasphere?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can use fact views that are exposed for consumption. They must be available in the space that your model is deployed to. They can be shared with the space as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Can I also add data from other planning models?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can add data from other seamless planning models if they are deployed and exposed in the same space or if the exposed data has been shared from another space. You need to create a view on top of the tables which is exposed for consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What can I do with live versions? (And what can I not do?)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can display the live version data in the model data foundation and in tables, charts, etc. in stories.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can reference the live version data in model and story calculations as well as data actions (incl. advanced formulas).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You cannot write back into the referenced views (or rather their underlying tables). You can copy the live version data into planning versions via copy/paste in the table, data actions and version management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How do I see if data is live or not?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In models, a live version is highlighted in the data preview. In the version dimension, you see the data source per version. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In tables, live version data is locked for data entry and formatted accordingly. Reasons for unplannable data give accurate information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Is SAP Datasphere Data Access Control considered?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes, it is.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Do planners need to have certain roles in SAP Datasphere?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Only if a user has a consumer role for the underlying space, he will be able to see live version data. Otherwise, he can use the planning model but will not see live version data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Data access control applies as well.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What about live access to master data?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Live access to master data is future enhancement with high priority.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-387181249"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Live versions bring seamless planning to the next level and unlock a lot of value for planning in SAP Business Data Cloud. I am delighted to announce the general availability in Q4 2025.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864"/>
    <published>2025-10-14T20:34:01.157000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-seamless-planning-model-design-principles-compared-to-sap-bw/ba-p/14242687</id>
    <title>SAC seamless planning: Model design principles - compared to SAP BW</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T10:16:53.034000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tano_B</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1661359</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;After years of developing planning solutions with SAP BW Integrated Planning and BPC, I recently completed a SAC Planning project with seamless planning. Coming from a BW IP/BPC background, I initially tried to replicate familiar structures in SAC. But I quickly realized that SAC’s flexibility requires a different mindset, starting with model design and granularity.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In this first blog post, I’ll share model design decisions, and practical tips for BW developers moving to SAC Planning. This blog post shall also help developers without BW background by highlighting the restrictions of certain functionalities in SAC. Finally, I also want to show you the potential additional value of seamless planning for your planning project.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;1. SAC vs. SAP BW modelling: general background information&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;In SAC, the new model is a mixture of InfoCube-like and a direct-update planning ADSO in BW. All characteristics are keys (InfoCube-like), but there is only an active table (direct-update). Furthermore, measures in SAC models cannot be of a text/characteristic type. So,&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;there are no requests, no chance to roll back&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;no inherited delta mechanism&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;no characteristic as key figure.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;But SAC models come with a Standard data audit functionality, that works out of the box (except for import jobs). Because of the missing requests in SAC, planning functions should be kept simple.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Model Design: SAC is not BW&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;When designing planning solutions in SAC, I recommend you to break down planning requirements across multiple models. In SAP BW, developers were required to create composite providers and aggregation levels (and input enabled queries) on top of ADSOs to structure planning logic. SAC does not have those intermediate layers, which can accelerate development. But this simplicity also introduces challenges when trying to consolidate everything into a single model.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Here are a few examples:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Any data entry creates an edit version. If multiple planning scenarios share one model, SAC shows the “Publish Data” banner across all stories when you edit plan data in one story.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The SAC Excel Add-In allows end users to plan on ad-hoc created tables, which can be convenient for flexibility. However, this becomes significantly more critical when SAC models are large and complex. In such cases, ad-hoc planning can bypass frontend validations (for instance, javascript logic in stories), leading to inconsistencies and governance challenges (check comments here&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/296876/?section=sectionDetails" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Ability to disable planning option in SAC Cloud excel add-in centrally by admin&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Upload jobs in SAC cannot derive master data automatically. In huge models, this often leads to wide files with many columns.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Data validations are less robust than characteristic relationships in BW. They must be handled manually in Data Actions and carefully considered during story design, since SAC still allows "unassigned" values even when validations are defined.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Data point comments are more fragile. Because they depend on the full navigation state, they can be lost more easily in huge models.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;These limitations highlight the need to rethink model design. Instead of treating an SAC planning model like a BW ADSO, it’s more accurate to compare it to an aggregation level or even an input enabled query. It's a layer tailored to specific planning logic.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;3. How does seamless planning help?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;Seamless planning let's you expose your fact and dimension tables to Datasphere. Hence, you can bring together the data of your different models more easily for reporting purposes instead of having a lot of cross model copies in native SAC.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;You can also&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;add SQLscript logic,&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;enrich your plan data with&amp;nbsp;Datasphere tables for configuration/customizing (multiple keys and characteristics as non-key fields),&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;or leveraging public dimensions exposed from SAC (single key).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;The results can be consumed&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;via real-time reporting (Datasphere Analytic Models)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;or via import jobs to SAC models.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;4. What's next?&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="3" color="#000000"&gt;With the Q4/2025 update, seamless planning shall become bidirectional, meaning that the View data in Datasphere can be added to SAC models as read-only version. This update will make Datasphere data better accessible.&amp;nbsp;It&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;will support direct consumption of Datasphere fact data in planning models, which will let you have a single planning enabled table with real-time reference data from other planning models.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Model design matters&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Avoid putting all planning scenarios into one model. SAC lacks BW’s aggregation layer, so splitting models improves performance and governance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seamless Planning&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;currently focuses on exposing SAC fact and dimension tables to SAP Datasphere, enabling integrated reporting and SQLScript-based logic. It will help you implementing a federated planning landscape in SAC.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT color="#000000"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Always keep the Roadmap in mind&lt;/STRONG&gt;: By Q4/2025, SAC will support direct consumption of Datasphere fact data in planning models, reducing reliance on import jobs and enabling real-time integration in planning enabled crosstabs.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-seamless-planning-model-design-principles-compared-to-sap-bw/ba-p/14242687"/>
    <published>2025-10-15T10:16:53.034000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/efficient-migration-of-sac-classic-stories-focusing-on-the-essentials/ba-p/14244678</id>
    <title>Efficient Migration of SAC Classic Stories: Focusing on the Essentials</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T13:37:13.256000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomas_fery</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/259114</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;With the announcement that the creation of&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Classic Stories&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Analytic Applications&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;will be discontinued starting with the Q3 2025 release, planning the transition to the&amp;nbsp;Optimized Story Experience&amp;nbsp;is becoming a key focus for many SAP Analytics Cloud customers. The full deprecation of Classic assets is scheduled for the Q2 2026 release as stated in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="The Next Phase in the Deprecation of the Classic Experience in SAP Analytics Cloud" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-next-phase-in-the-deprecation-of-the-classic-experience-in-sap/bc-p/14197224/emcs_t/S2h8ZW1haWx8dG9waWNfc3Vic2NyaXB0aW9ufE1FVkc2TkdSM0tRTkk3fDE0MTk3MjI0fFNVQlNDUklQVElPTlN8aEs#M184102" target="_blank"&gt;The Next Phase in the Deprecation of the Classic Experience in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;A look into the file repository of an SAC tenant that has grown over several years can quickly lead to the assumption that a massive migration project is ahead. The sheer number of existing Stories and Applications can seem overwhelming and raise the question of where to even begin with the conversion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The good news&lt;/STRONG&gt; is: in most cases, the actual effort is significantly less than you might think. The key to a successful and resource-efficient migration is not to convert&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;all&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;assets, but to focus on those that are truly relevant to your business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2020969126"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Reality in the System: Total Count vs. Actual Usage&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;In practice, only a fraction of the Stories and Applications present in the system are used regularly. Many assets are the result of ad-hoc analyses, development prototypes, or have long been replaced by more current reports. A strategy that aims for a 1:1 migration of all assets would therefore be inefficient and would spend valuable resources on content that no longer provides business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A strategic approach&lt;/STRONG&gt;, instead, focuses on answering two central questions with data-driven insights:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which Classic Assets are actively used and must be prioritized for migration?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Which assets are outdated or unused and can be cleaned up as part of a housekeeping initiative?&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1824455621"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data-Driven Decisions with Built-in Tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud already provides the necessary tools to answer these questions. The foundation for this is the SAC_PERFORMANCE_E2E Model, which logs detailed information about content usage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For technical users who wish to access the model directly, it can be found by following this path:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where to Find the SAC_PERFORMANCE_E2E Model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the side menu, navigate to&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Files&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;folder.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Follow the path through the folder structure:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Common &amp;gt; SAC Content &amp;gt; SAC Content Performance &amp;gt; SAC Content Performance - Models&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In this folder, you will find the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAC_PERFORMANCE_E2E&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;model.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_0-1760527091589.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327870i22597904BDB01783/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="thomas_fery_0-1760527091589.png" alt="thomas_fery_0-1760527091589.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on this data, the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-system-overview/ba-p/13564442" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;already offers two crucial dashboards that you can use for your migration planning:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System Overview Feature Adoption:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/07/21/sap-analytics-cloud-feature-adoption-system-overview/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud - Feature Adoption&lt;/A&gt;, this dashboard helps you identify the most-used Classic Stories and applications. You get a clear overview of which content has a high usage frequency and a broad user base. This provides an ideal basis for a prioritized migration roadmap.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;System Overview Housekeeping:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;In parallel, the housekeeping function, as described in&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/efficient-data-maintenance-in-sap-analytics-cloud-system-overview/ba-p/14057374" target="_self"&gt;Efficient Data Maintenance in SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/A&gt;, allows for the identification of unused content. With the latest updates, this tool now even support the mass deletion of such objects. This is the perfect opportunity to clean up the tenant and improve both clarity and performance. Of course, caution is advised here to ensure that no rarely used but important reports (e.g., for quarterly or annual closing) are removed. Therefore, an analysis over a longer period is essential.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1627942116"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Look Ahead: Direct Transparency in the System Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;To make getting started with this analysis even easier, we are working on a direct integration of these key metrics into the System Overview. Soon, customers on Fast Track tenants with Wave 2025.21&amp;nbsp;and QRC Tenants with QRC4 2025 will see a new tile called&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;"Conversion Needed"&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_0-1760527826535.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327874i6C10996B91F72618/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="thomas_fery_0-1760527826535.png" alt="thomas_fery_0-1760527826535.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;This tile provides an at-a-glance overview of the number of opened stories, broken down by their version (Classic, Light Weight, Unified). It immediately quantifies the proportion of Classic usage and provides a direct starting point for a more detailed analysis. This makes the abstract volume of stories to be converted tangible and reduces it to the assets that are actually in use.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;Details reveal a list of Stories and Analytic Applications to be converted:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="thomas_fery_1-1760527968139.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327875iE282AB258287FA9B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="thomas_fery_1-1760527968139.png" alt="thomas_fery_1-1760527968139.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1431428611"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary and Next Steps&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;The transition to the Unified Story Experience is less of a technical hurdle and more of a strategic opportunity. Instead of being discouraged by the total number of Classic Assets, you should adopt a data-driven approach:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Identify&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;the actively used stories with built-in tools like the Feature Adoption dashboard.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prioritize&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;their migration to achieve the greatest benefit for your users.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Clean up&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;your system of unused content using the housekeeping features.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the new "Conversion Needed" overview, we are making the first step of quantifying the need even simpler.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;However, it is important to note that you do not need to wait for this tile to be released to start your planning.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;All the necessary data to identify your most-used Classic Assets is already accessible today through the "&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/07/21/sap-analytics-cloud-feature-adoption-system-overview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Feature Adoption&lt;/A&gt;" and "&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/efficient-data-maintenance-in-sap-analytics-cloud-system-overview/ba-p/14057374" target="_blank"&gt;Housekeeping&lt;/A&gt;" dashboards in the &lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/03/31/sap-analytics-cloud-system-overview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;System Overview&lt;/A&gt;. We encourage you to leverage these tools now to gain a strategic advantage and proactively shape your migration process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/efficient-migration-of-sac-classic-stories-focusing-on-the-essentials/ba-p/14244678"/>
    <published>2025-10-15T13:37:13.256000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-compass-support-of-seamless-planning-amp-live-version/ba-p/14245059</id>
    <title>SAP Analytics Cloud compass Support of Seamless Planning &amp; Live Version</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T19:25:07.612000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChenNee</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/46487</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;One of the most frequently received feedback since SAP Analytics Cloud compass' general release is the desire to simulate directly with data from SAP Datasphere. With the coming Q4 2025 release, this will become reality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The benefits are obvious: The support of seamless planning setup including live version connections will mean that users can do away with data redundancy and streamline data management workflow with the confidence that the compass simulations performed are always based on a single source of truth, the latest data, even if it is residing in SAP Datasphere, at any point in time. And as we all know: When it comes to simulations, this level of confidence is pivotal for the usefulness of the insights generated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more about seamless planning and the setting up of a live version connection, I highly recommend checking out&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14553"&gt;@Max_Gander&lt;/a&gt;'s blog post with use cases, benefits and FAQ:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864" target="_blank"&gt;Unlocking the Next Chapter of Seamless Planning in SAP Business Data Cloud with Live Versions.&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;Once that is all set up, compass users will be able to perform Monte Carlo Simulation directly on the live version. Below you can see an example of creating a simulation with the version "Plan00", a live version. You can see there is basically no difference between the handling of scenarios based on a live or native version, and there is free choice to base your scenarios on any of the available versions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="compass blog .gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328014i61144D34C5A51E4C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="compass blog .gif" alt="compass blog .gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;An important detail here: Users will also be notified upon data changes in live versions. In the below example you can see that a change is made to the original data, a CSV file, which is then uploaded into the local table in SAP Datasphere, upon which the view for the live version is generated. When this change is deployed, compass will be able to detect the difference in baseline value and reflect the change in the driver list.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="data update.gif" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328023i59345166CA99C385/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="data update.gif" alt="data update.gif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the support for seamless planning AND live version connection, compass is enabling more flexibility in setup and shortening the time-to-insight to a greater extent than before.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-analytics-cloud-compass-support-of-seamless-planning-amp-live-version/ba-p/14245059"/>
    <published>2025-10-15T19:25:07.612000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-planning-amp-reporting-the-version-dimension-and-its-limitations/ba-p/14244725</id>
    <title>SAC Planning &amp; Reporting: The Version Dimension and its Limitations</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T09:41:26.121000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tano_B</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1661359</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) Planning, the version&amp;nbsp;dimension is mandatory and unfortunately private. The private nature of the version dimension contradicts the recommendation I gave in an earlier blog post (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-seamless-planning-model-design-principles-compared-to-sap-bw/ba-p/14242687?emcs_t=S2h8ZW1haWx8a3Vkb3N8TUdSUVlTV1pRNTlLSlF8MTQyNDI2ODd8S1VET1N8aEs" target="_self"&gt;use of multiple models&lt;/A&gt;) but nontheless there are significant reasons to stay with the version dimension as designed.&amp;nbsp;This&amp;nbsp;requires version members&amp;nbsp;to be defined separately in each planning model. It makes early alignment on required versions essential in a SAC planning project. Furthermore, I want to highlight the version dimensions importance in context of the seamless planning roadmap and customer influence opportunities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;1. Why the Version Dimension Matters in SAC Planning&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While some recommendations suggest simplifying the model by using a single version member and managing versions via a custom public dimension, I would not recommend this approach. SAC offers several reasons to use the version dimension as intended:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Strong frontend support:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAC provides clear visual indicators for version editing by hitting the advanced button before publishing&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tano_B_0-1760523782238.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327838i39B52E28262D56AC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Tano_B_0-1760523782238.png" alt="Tano_B_0-1760523782238.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Private versions:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Using the native version dimension ensures consistent handling of version management capabilities in SAC, including the opportunity to create private versions on the fly to plan different scenarios.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Roadmap alignment:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP’s Seamless Planning roadmap shows continued investment in the version dimension, confirming its strategic importance in future planning capabilities. Building your planning landscape in SAC assuming there is only one version dimension member will create problems when trying to adopt the newest seamless planning features. Check the new blog post of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14553"&gt;@Max_Gander&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864" target="_blank"&gt;Unlocking the Next Chapter of Seamless Planning in... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;For these reasons, it’s advisable to define all necessary version members upfront and use the version dimension as designed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;2. Limitations of the Version Dimension in SAC Reporting&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Besides the private nature of the version dimension there are other limitations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For instance, when you try to use the data analyzer on top of a planning model, SAC forces you to either add the version to the drill or set a single member filter:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tano_B_1-1760525891819.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327846i513B56BB86520D7F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tano_B_1-1760525891819.png" alt="Tano_B_1-1760525891819.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The "New Table Building Experience" introduced flexibility regarding the version dimension and measures (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-new-table-building-experience-in-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/14159483" target="_blank"&gt;The New Table Building Experience in SAP Analytics... - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;) in Story Building. But the new experience still has certain restrictions (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/18850a0e13944f53aa8a8b7c094ea29e/05e2a824958c45eab7d791cf27496ed0.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=2025.20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Restrictions for the New Table Build Experience | SAP Help Portal&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The concept of a version dimension is not applied to analytic models in Datasphere. When you are using seamless planning you can bypass the restrictions in reporting regarding versions by defining an analytic model in Datasphere. But there are some widget features that only work with a version dimension, so this is also not a perfect solution.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;3. Limitations of the Version Dimension in SAC Planning&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you try to build input enabled layouts in SAC planning, you will be confronted with limitations regarding the version dimension. I will share one use case to show the problem in detail:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAC has this great "Forecast Layout" for planning. Unfortunately, the sum for the year value is not input enabled (see the green box). So, I tried to build a second input enabled table, that allows total values to be planned (see red box), beginning with the planning of the rest of the year:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Layout:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tano_B_2-1760527085296.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327869i923717518685AFFF/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tano_B_2-1760527085296.png" alt="Tano_B_2-1760527085296.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculation Editor "Rest of Year Forecast":&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tano_B_3-1760527291549.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327872i9DF9BFFF38F8EF69/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tano_B_3-1760527291549.png" alt="Tano_B_3-1760527291549.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you can see, the input on the "Rest of Year Forecast" measure works as expected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But the expectation is to plan the total year value including the YTD Actuals and here the limitation of the version dimension becomes problematic. Since I have to remove the filter in the table widget for the Version, everything becomes read-only:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Layout Forecast and Actuals:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tano_B_4-1760528165254.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327876i2E822EA0E6142CA2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tano_B_4-1760528165254.png" alt="Tano_B_4-1760528165254.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Calculation Editor Forecast with Actuals:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Tano_B_5-1760528451925.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327877iC12FA5A300CC4F61/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Tano_B_5-1760528451925.png" alt="Tano_B_5-1760528451925.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The use of the new experience, or the use of cross calculations does not help to solve the requirement to plan on a measure, that inherits two or more versions, although the inverse formula points to a specific version. I found a solution with constant selection (which I find problematic) and I just hope, that the flexibility with the version dimension will be enhanced in the future. Especially, with the new possibilities of seamless planning coming with the next release, this would be a great enhancement. Data federation in planning is only possible, when the input layouts can be designed in a flexible way. Otherwise, it will be required to copy/paste the data across the planning landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Although the version dimension comes with restrictions, I would advise you to use it as intended. To further support consistency across models, consider supporting the customer influence to &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/253621" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;enable Version as Public Dimension in SAC&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Restrictions in the data analyzer regarding versions will become more problematic with the new seamless planning release. Please comment, if you find a customer influence. I would definitely support it!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Restrictions in input enabled crosstabs regarding the version dimension are an obstacle when trying to build a federeated planning landscape. Consider supporting the customer influence to &lt;A href="https://influence.sap.com/sap/ino/#/idea/358351" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;allow inverse formulas on measures with different versions&lt;/A&gt;. If I missed a simple trick, please comment and I will update this blog post.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sac-planning-amp-reporting-the-version-dimension-and-its-limitations/ba-p/14244725"/>
    <published>2025-10-16T09:41:26.121000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/live-versions-from-an-sql-source-for-sap-analytics-cloud-planning/ba-p/14245675</id>
    <title>Live Versions from an SQL Source for SAP Analytics Cloud Planning</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T11:46:35.930000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Max_Gander</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14553</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1633750757"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Live data access for planning is a big theme of the QRC4 2025 release in SAP Analytics Cloud. We already shared how live versions now unlock a new chapter for seamless planning in SAP Business Data Cloud (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864" target="_blank"&gt;link&lt;/A&gt;). But the paradigm of live data access is coming for models that are not deployed to SAP Datasphere as well! In this case, live versions can link data from our available live SQL sources. So, this applies to our existing connection to Google BigQuery and shall apply to live SQL sources that we add going forward (&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#;INNO=000D3AAADBCE1FE094D1DE1E1D95EBFC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Microsoft Azure&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#;INNO=000D3AAC9DD21FD094D21E22066EB528" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Snowflake&lt;/A&gt;,…). Learn how to add a live version from Google BigQuery in this blogpost!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1437237252"&gt;How does it work?&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adding a live version to a model is easy. It is also easy to create a model from view in Google BigQuery. Here, I will show you how to add a live version to an existing model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your model details, you will find a new entry in the ‘Data’ section which is called ‘External Live Version Data Sources’&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Here, ‘Connect External Data Source’&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose an existing target version for the data source or create a blank version&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose Google BigQuery as source system (more to be added in the future)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose connection&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose your datasource from Google BigQuery&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Map the data source columns to your model’s columns&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Not all source columns need to be mapped&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Not all target columns need to be mapped&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Measures can be &lt;EM&gt;NULL&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Dimensions can receive a default member&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Certain data type differences can be handled&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If we detect a mismatch between the live version and your master data, we will notify you and you can add missing dimension members directly (not shown in the video)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;We also provide performance hints&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the data in calculations, data actions, stories etc.! In the video, you see the live data in action in a model calculation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You’re done! You can add more sources to the model, if you want&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Adding and using a live version from Google BigQuery" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328282i7D7E99ED99AA171A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-10_Blig_ExtVersions_SQLLive.gif" alt="Adding and using a live version from Google BigQuery" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Adding and using a live version from Google BigQuery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1240723747"&gt;FAQ&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where can I use this feature?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature is available for SAP Analytics Cloud models that are not deployed to SAP Datasphere (=not using seamless planning).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Can I use any source view?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Yes. However, not all data types are supported (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/2236676398d342619022bc21d76d922a.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;details&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What can I do with live versions? (And what can I not do?)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can display the live version data in the model data foundation and in tables, charts, etc. in stories.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can reference the live version data in model and story calculations as well as data actions (incl. advanced formulas).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You cannot write back to the source. You can copy the live version data into planning versions via copy/paste in the table, data actions and version management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How do I see if data is live or not?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In models, a live version is highlighted in the data preview. In the version dimension, you see the data source per version. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In tables, live version data is locked for data entry and formatted accordingly. Reasons for unplannable data give accurate information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1044210242"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Live data access in planning models represents a massive opportunity. SAP Analytics Cloud demonstrates openness and flexibility by offering live versions from live SQL sources.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/live-versions-from-an-sql-source-for-sap-analytics-cloud-planning/ba-p/14245675"/>
    <published>2025-10-16T11:46:35.930000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-%E3%82%AB%E3%82%B9%E3%82%BF%E3%83%A0%E3%83%87%E3%83%BC%E3%82%BF%E3%83%97%E3%83%AD%E3%83%80%E3%82%AF%E3%83%88%E3%81%AE%E4%BD%9C%E6%88%90/ba-p/14235138</id>
    <title>SAP Business Data Cloud: カスタムデータプロダクトの作成</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T07:32:47.646000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>akaney</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/852758</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761905029"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;はじめに&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;SPAN&gt;ではSAP&lt;SPAN&gt;のビジネスアプリケーション間のデータを共通のデータモデルとしてデータセットおよびセマンティック（項目名の用語や意味合い）を整え、SAP &lt;SPAN&gt;データプロダクトとして提供します。これによりSAPが管理の下でSAPのアプリケーションのデータは自動的にコピーされ、メタデータも併せてメンテナンスを行っていきます&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;が、&lt;SPAN&gt;S/4HANAのアドオンテーブルやカスタムCDS view、SAP以外のデータソースなどお客様独自の要件データソースに対してはカスタムデータプロダクトを作成することで、同様のフレームワークに組み込むことが可能です。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;これによってSAP&lt;SPAN&gt;アプリケーションのデータだけでなく、SAP&lt;SPAN&gt;以外のデータも整備しAI&lt;SPAN&gt;エージェントに必要なデータとして提供できるため、ダッシュボードでデータを可視化するだけではなく、Joule&lt;SPAN&gt;を使いながら対話形式でさらなるデータ分析の深堀やインサイトを得るなどデータ活用の幅を広げることができます。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565391524"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;概要&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;本ブログではS/4HANA on-premise&lt;SPAN&gt;から連携したCDS view&lt;SPAN&gt;をベースとするカスタムデータプロダクトの作成を想定し解説いたします。SAP&lt;SPAN&gt;以外のデータソースが対象となる場合でも同様の手順でカスタムデータプロダクトの作成が可能です。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;大まかなカスタムデータプロダクトの作成手順は以下の通りです。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="00_全体.png" style="width: 716px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327386i5DCDD6748F831188/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="00_全体.png" alt="00_全体.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;オブジェクトストアへのデータ連携&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;データ変換処理&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;カスタムデータプロダクトの定義&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368878019" id="toc-hId-1368878019"&gt;オブジェクトストアへのデータ連携&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;こちらでは以下の手順でオブジェクトストア内のローカルテーブルにソースシステムからデータ連携をします。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;複製フローの作成・実行&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;マージタスクの実行&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;SPAN&gt;オブジェクトストア内にデータを連携するため、データビルダより複製フローの作成を行います。複製フローは選択したソースシステムから選択したターゲットシステムへのデータ複製を行うことが出来る機能です。データビルダに統合されたユーザインタフェースを使用してシンプルな射影とフィルタを使用した1:1の複製を作成でき、&lt;/SPAN&gt;簡単な設定でソースシステムからターゲット システムへ大量データ複製を実現します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;オブジェクトストアの概要に関しては&amp;nbsp;こちらのブログ（&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/blogs/blogarticleprintpage/blog-id/technology-blog-sap/article-id/183048" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud: オブジェクトストア 入門編&lt;/A&gt;）&lt;SPAN&gt;をご確認ください。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;複製フローの概要に関してはこちらのブログ（&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/%E8%A4%87%E8%A3%BD%E3%83%95%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BCpart%EF%BC%91-%E8%A4%87%E8%A3%BD%E3%83%95%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81/ba-p/13575795" target="_blank"&gt;複製フローPart１: 複製フロー概要&lt;/A&gt;）&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;をご確認ください。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301447233" id="toc-hId-1301447233"&gt;複製フローの作成・実行&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;オブジェクトストアスペース内で「データビルダ」より「新規複製フロー」を選択します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="01.01_複製フロー選択.png" style="width: 856px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328941i6BCECF106D9AD43C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01.01_複製フロー選択.png" alt="01.01_複製フロー選択.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;データソースを選択します。本ブログではS/4HANA on-premise&lt;SPAN&gt;への作成済みの接続を介して複製フローを作成します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="01.02_複製フロー接続選択.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328942iF97F1D7012EAD165/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01.02_複製フロー接続選択.png" alt="01.02_複製フロー接続選択.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4HANAからの連携方法として、CDS viewを選択します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="01.03_cds view選択.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328943i44BA0C5122740DE6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01.03_cds view選択.png" alt="01.03_cds view選択.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;以下のように１つの複製フローではソースシステムからターゲットシステムに対して並列処理で複数のオブジェクトを複製することが可能です。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="01.04_cds view決める.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328944i52DF816FD8990771/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01.04_cds view決める.png" alt="01.04_cds view決める.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;今回はターゲットにオブジェクトストアのスペースを選択することで、ターゲットオブジェクトとして新規のローカルテーブルがオブジェクトストア内に作成されます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;また、複製フローでは&lt;SPAN&gt;シンプルな射影やフィルタの追加や、&lt;/SPAN&gt;初期ロードやデルタロードなどのロードタイプを選択することが可能です。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="01.0_複製フローンお作成.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328945i43CC94583A645F11/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01.0_複製フローンお作成.png" alt="01.0_複製フローンお作成.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;複製フローにビジネス名と技術名を付けて&lt;/SPAN&gt;デプロイ・実行することで、オブジェクトストア内にローカルテーブルが作成されます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="01.0_複製フローンデプロイ実行.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328946i8F338C4EBECD3E7D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01.0_複製フローンデプロイ実行.png" alt="01.0_複製フローンデプロイ実行.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104933728" id="toc-hId-1104933728"&gt;マージタスクの実行&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;その後「マージタスク」という処理を通じてテーブルにそのデータを反映させます。&lt;BR /&gt;複製フローの実行によりソースシステムからオブジェクトストア内に作成された受信バッファにデータが書き込まれますが、ここからマージタスクを実行することでオブジェクトストア内のデルタテーブル（ローカルテーブル）にデータが挿入されます。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;このマージタスクは、「データ統合モニタ」からそれぞれのテーブル毎に実行することもできますが、タスクチェーンの中に複数のテーブルに対するマージタスクを組み込むことで、複製フロー&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;変換フロー実行後にマージするなどのジョブ実行のスケジュールを組むことも可能です。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;本ブログではタスクチェーンを作成し、５つのローカルテーブルに対してマージタスクを並列実行させるように構成します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;タスクチェーンに関して詳細はこちらのSAP Helpページ（&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/c8a54ee704e94e15926551293243fd1d/d1afbc2b9ee84d44a00b0b777ac243e1.html?locale=ja-JP" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;タスクチェーンの作成&lt;/A&gt;）をご確認ください。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;「データビルダ」より「新規タスクチェーン」を選択します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="02_タスクチェーンの作成.png" style="width: 852px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328947i893443467CB07896/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="02_タスクチェーンの作成.png" alt="02_タスクチェーンの作成.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;左側のリポジトリより「オブジェクトストアへのデータ連携」で作成したローカルテーブルをドラッグ＆ドロップでタスクチェーンに追加します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="03_ソース選択.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328948iAA537C341B85CF26/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="03_ソース選択.png" alt="03_ソース選択.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;その他ローカルテーブルや複製フロー/変換フローなどのオブジェクトをタスクチェーンの中に新規タスクあるいは並列タスクとして追加することが可能です。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="04_新規タスク.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328949iF491617B45763741/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="04_新規タスク.png" alt="04_新規タスク.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;アクティビティに「マージ」が選択されていることを確認し、タスクチェーンの作成・実行をします。&lt;BR /&gt;また、タスクチェーンの実行後に電子メールによる通知を設定することもできます。&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="05_タスク.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328958i84AE24BE7E4964C0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="05_タスク.png" alt="05_タスク.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;タスクチェーンの実行状況はデータ統合モニタよりタスクチェーンの&lt;SPAN&gt;ステータスや進捗を確認することができ、タスクチェーンのプロパティから直接移動することが可能です。&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="06_保存.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328952iAD2D7EBD505733F9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="06_保存.png" alt="06_保存.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;詳細画面では実行に関するステータスやメトリクス、実行ログなどを確認できます。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="07_モニタ.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328953i3C22BC6B91342947/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="07_モニタ.png" alt="07_モニタ.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;また、「ローカルテーブル（ファイル）」メニュー画面よりローカルテーブルごとの詳細を確認することができ、受信バッファからそれぞれのローカルテーブルにデータが書き込まれレコードが挿入されたことが確認できます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="08_モニタ２.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328954iBC242E2A61D85F04/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="08_モニタ２.png" alt="08_モニタ２.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;「データビルダ」より複製フローで作成したターゲットテーブルを選択し、プレビューをするとデータが挿入されたことが確認できます。以上で、データソースからオブジェクトストア内にデータ連携が完了します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="01.05_プレビュー.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328956i900C169D26B9C9A6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="01.05_プレビュー.png" alt="01.05_プレビュー.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;このような形で複製フローを用いてデータ連携をすることで、オブジェクトストアを大量のデータを安価に保持するデータレイク領域として利用することができます。ローカルテーブルとして作成されたオブジェクトはスペースへと共有することで、ビューや分析モデルなど分析の用途のデータモデルとして活用することが出来ます。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-582823999" id="toc-hId-779337504"&gt;データ変換処理&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;複製フローでローデータをオブジェクトストアにデータ抽出をした後には、データ変換や集計、計算列の追加などの処理を変換フローにて実現することも可能です。変換フローの中ではSQLやSQLスクリプト、Pythonによるデータ変換などを組み込むことが出来ます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;変換フローの概要に関してはこちらのブログ（&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/%E8%A4%87%E8%A3%BD%E3%83%95%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BCpart2-%E3%83%87%E3%83%AB%E3%82%BF%E3%82%AD%E3%83%A3%E3%83%97%E3%83%81%E3%83%A3%E3%81%A8%E5%A4%89%E6%8F%9B%E3%83%95%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC/ba-p/13581517" target="_blank"&gt;複製フローPart2 : デルタキャプチャと変換フロー&lt;/A&gt;）&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;をご確認ください。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;「データビルダ」より「新規変換フロー」を選択します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="09_変換フロー.png" style="width: 888px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328957iDB310FCCF704A7D9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="09_変換フロー.png" alt="09_変換フロー.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;変換フローでは&lt;SPAN&gt;中間ビューとしてグラフィックビューあるいはSQLビューを作成し、ソースからデータをロードしデータを変換します。今回はグラフィックビューによるデータ変換をおこなうため、「グラフィックビュー変換」を選択します。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="10_ぐらふぃく.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328959i8CFF2303BD3D26CA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="10_ぐらふぃく.png" alt="10_ぐらふぃく.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;画面左側のリポジトリよりオブジェクトをドラッグ＆ドロップでグラフィックビューエディタに追加をします。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="11_テーブルの追加.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328960iE492C6CA3A710546/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="11_テーブルの追加.png" alt="11_テーブルの追加.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;結合などの&lt;/SPAN&gt;データ変換や集計、計算列の追加などを定義します。&lt;BR /&gt;グラフィックエディタから左上の「＞（戻る）」を選択することで変換フローエディタへ遷移することが出来ます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="12_変換処理.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328961iA0478FB7AC2ED3CC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="12_変換処理.png" alt="12_変換処理.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;変換処理がされたデータが書き込まれるターゲットテーブルを新規に作成するため、&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;「新規ターゲットテーブルの作成」を選択します。リポジトリより既存のテーブルをターゲットテーブルとして追加することも可能です。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="13_ターゲットテーブルの作成.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328962i199DA67AE1653620/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="13_ターゲットテーブルの作成.png" alt="13_ターゲットテーブルの作成.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;変換フローおよびターゲットテーブルにビジネス名と技術名を付けて&lt;/SPAN&gt;デプロイ・実行することで、変換処理されたデータがターゲットテーブルに挿入されます。&lt;SPAN&gt;変換フロー&lt;/SPAN&gt;の実行状況はデータ統合モニタよりタスクチェーンの&lt;SPAN&gt;ステータスや進捗を確認することができ、変換フローのプロパティから直接移動することが可能です。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="14_変換フロー実装.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328963i0AE266BDA077FD2F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="14_変換フロー実装.png" alt="14_変換フロー実装.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;このように複製フローを用いてオブジェクトストアを大量のデータを安価に保持するデータレイク領域としてデータ抽出・保持ができるだけでなく、&lt;/SPAN&gt;不要な列の削除や計算列の追加などクレンジングの変換処理を加え、分析用途で使える状態にした中間データもオブジェクトストアで保持することができます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;これらのデータソースから抽出したデータや、変換処理後のデータはメタデータと併せてカタログに情報が自動で登録され、管理されますが、カスタムデータプロダクトとしてカタログに公開することで対象のシステムに対してゼロコピーでデルタシェアによるデータの共有が可能です。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-582823999"&gt;カスタムデータプロダクトの定義&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;カスタムデータプロダクトの定義は「データ共有コックピット」を利用して行います。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;データ共有コックピットに関して詳細はこちらのSAP Helpページ（&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/e4059f908d16406492956e5dbcf142dc/b07e95d07a1e4569b87d9bb57b732bcf.html?locale=ja-JP" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;カスタムデルタ共有データプロダクトの作成&lt;/A&gt;）をご確認ください。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;「データ共有コックピット」＞「データプロバイダプロファイル」よりデータプロバイダーを作成します。この際に、「データプロバイダ/データプロダクトの表示/非表示」で「フォーメーション」を選択し、その他必要な情報を入力のうえ作成します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-386310494" id="toc-hId-386310494"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="16_プロファイルの作成.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328915iE77F9C4FC347C8C2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="16_プロファイルの作成.png" alt="16_プロファイルの作成.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-189796989"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="17_プロバイダーの家訓ん.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328934i17B625CF065A6D0A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="17_プロバイダーの家訓ん.png" alt="17_プロバイダーの家訓ん.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;データプロバイダの作成後、「データ共有コックピット」＞「データプロダクト」よりデータプロダクトの作成をおこないます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--6716516"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="18_データプロダクトの定義.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328914i7BFC9C990ED3DD26/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="18_データプロダクトの定義.png" alt="18_データプロダクトの定義.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;「アーティファクトスペース」を選択します。アーティファクトスペースでは通常のHANA Cloudスペースではなく、オブジェクトストアの領域より選択が可能です。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;その他ビジネス名や技術名などを入力します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-144024336"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="19_定位１.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328916i076B225B691D9765/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="19_定位１.png" alt="19_定位１.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;「プロダクトアーティファクト」よりソースとなるオブジェクトをオブジェクトストアより選択し「変更を保存」することで、カスタムデータプロダクトを作成することが出来ます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--52489169"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="20_オブジェクトの選択２.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328917iC546B598647F2C0E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="20_オブジェクトの選択２.png" alt="20_オブジェクトの選択２.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;カスタムデータプロダクトをカタログに公開するために、ライフサイクルステータスを「ドラフト」より「一覧表示済み」にステータスの切り替えを行います。これにより、作成したカスタムデータプロダクトがカタログ上に公開され、利用できるようになります。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--249002674"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="21_リスティング.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328918iF3C7B62761C4D729/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="21_リスティング.png" alt="21_リスティング.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="22_リスティング.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328919i44E46A6E0DDC14F5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="22_リスティング.png" alt="22_リスティング.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Cockpitの「カタログおよびマーケットプレイス」よりアクセスすると、先ほど作成したカスタムデータプロダクトを検索・利用することができることを確認できます。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="23_カタログ.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329348iAF35EDA2AC81BB1D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="23_カタログ.png" alt="23_カタログ.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;データ共有コックピットで定義したカタログ情報などが確認できますが、「共有」を開始することで、対象システムとデータプロダクトをゼロコピーで利用することが出来るようになります。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;対象システムへのデルタシェアに関してはこちらのSAP Helpページ（&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/business-data-cloud/governing-and-publishing-data-in-catalog/sharing-data-products-to-sap-databricks?locale=ja-JP" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;他の SAP システムへのデータ製品の共有&lt;/A&gt;）をご確認ください。&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="24_カタログ確認.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329349iF002739A93920E9A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="24_カタログ確認.png" alt="24_カタログ確認.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;今回はSAP Databircksを共有先のターゲットシステムとして選択し、共有名などを入力します。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="25_デルタシェア.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329350iAA121C1438C4F99A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="25_デルタシェア.png" alt="25_デルタシェア.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;共有が完了すると、カスタムデータプロダクトはSAP DatabircksのカタログであるUnity Catalogに登録され、ゼロコピーで利用することが出来るようになります。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="26_デルタシェエア.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328939i2D6BBDBAC6741C70/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="26_デルタシェエア.png" alt="26_デルタシェエア.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--445516179"&gt;さいごに&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;最後までご覧いただきありがとうございました！&lt;BR /&gt;本ブログではS/4HANA on-premiseのCDS viewをベースにオブジェクトストアへのデータ連携および変換、またカスタムデータプロダクトとして定義のうえカタログに公開することでSAP Databricksにおいて高度な機械学習シナリオで活用できるようになりました。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;その他関連する情報をまとめておりますので、併せてご確認ください。&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/c8a54ee704e94e15926551293243fd1d/2a6bc3f6d79b4c39a01b6d58d043fbaf.html?locale=ja-JP&amp;amp;version=DEV&amp;amp;state=DRAFT#loio2a6bc3f6d79b4c39a01b6d58d043fbaf__section_create_file_space" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;オブジェクトストアでのデータの取得および準備&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3538038" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3538038 - SAP Datasphere オブジェクトストアの重要な考慮事項&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" title="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap_datasphere/c8a54ee704e94e15926551293243fd1d/f7161e6c20204672ac4a6d90c81762e4.html?locale=ja-jp" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/c8a54ee704e94e15926551293243fd1d/f7161e6c20204672ac4a6d90c81762e4.html?locale=ja-JP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;変換フローの作成&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_DATASPHERE/e4059f908d16406492956e5dbcf142dc/b07e95d07a1e4569b87d9bb57b732bcf.html?locale=ja-JP" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;カスタムデルタ共有データプロダクトの作成&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/business-data-cloud/governing-and-publishing-data-in-catalog/sharing-data-products-to-sap-databricks?locale=ja-JP" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;他の SAP システムへのデータ製品の共有&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-%E3%82%AB%E3%82%B9%E3%82%BF%E3%83%A0%E3%83%87%E3%83%BC%E3%82%BF%E3%83%97%E3%83%AD%E3%83%80%E3%82%AF%E3%83%88%E3%81%AE%E4%BD%9C%E6%88%90/ba-p/14235138"/>
    <published>2025-10-17T07:32:47.646000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/implementing-sap-emarsys-loyalty-management-part-2-technical-deep-dive/ba-p/14247872</id>
    <title>Implementing SAP Emarsys Loyalty Management – Part 2 (Technical Deep Dive)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T06:02:50.534000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vijaysb15</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44279</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/implementing-sap-emarsys-loyalty-management-part-1/ba-p/14216345" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;, of this series, we explored how SAP Emarsys Loyalty Management addresses modern‐loyalty demands by going far beyond traditional point-schemes. We reviewed how loyalty programs are evolving into personalised, omnichannel experiences—and how Emarsys enables brands to design tiers, define actions and rewards, unify customer profiles across touchpoints, and engage members through highly relevant communications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With that foundational business and functional outlook established, this article now moves into the &lt;STRONG&gt;technical implementation journey&lt;/STRONG&gt;, explaining how the architecture, integrations and processes come together to make these business capabilities operational.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1891977696"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;To successfully implement SAP Emarsys Loyalty Management, ensure the following components and configurations are in place across the connected SAP landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1824546910"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; SAP Emarsys and Loyalty&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unique Identifier for contacts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Smart Insight setup&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automation program to create and assign &lt;STRONG&gt;Loyalty HashID&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Loyalty plan configuration (tiers, actions, and benefits)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Voucher setup (optional)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Loyalty Wallet (standard SDK-based or custom via Loyalty APIs)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Automation program to trigger &lt;STRONG&gt;Webhook&lt;/STRONG&gt; on loyalty point confirmation events&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1628033405"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sales data posting integration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GL accounts and controlling objects&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Settlement and clearing logic&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;REST APIs for financial posting for the accruals and redemption scenario&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1302437181"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105923676"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Architecture&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="vijaysb15_0-1760848383434.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329564i33B2C2C0C1AEFA2B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="vijaysb15_0-1760848383434.png" alt="vijaysb15_0-1760848383434.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-909410171"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-712896666"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Registration and Loyalty Onboarding&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Customer registration and loyalty onboarding begin when users join the program to enjoy rewards from their purchases and activities.&lt;BR /&gt;New customers can &lt;STRONG&gt;enrol during registration&lt;/STRONG&gt;, while existing customers can &lt;STRONG&gt;join the program anytime&lt;/STRONG&gt;. For both scenarios, a &lt;STRONG&gt;unique HashID&lt;/STRONG&gt; must be generated and assigned to their record before enrolment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The onboarding process can be initiated across &lt;STRONG&gt;mobile apps&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;websites&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or &lt;STRONG&gt;POS systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Typically, SAP Sales Cloud or SAP S/4HANA act as the primary sources of customer data, which are then replicated to SAP Emarsys via SAP CPI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When a new contact is registered, the record is first created in Sales Cloud or S/4HANA and then replicated to Emarsys. Once created, an automation program generates a HashID and stores it in a custom field at the contact level. Afterward, a Join API call is triggered to add the contact to the relevant Loyalty Plan.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For existing customers who join the loyalty program later, ensure that their &lt;STRONG&gt;HashID&lt;/STRONG&gt; is already generated before executing the Join API call.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="vijaysb15_0-1760848663195.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329566i871807C1277BABD8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="vijaysb15_0-1760848663195.png" alt="vijaysb15_0-1760848663195.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-516383161"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-319869656"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points Accrual&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;points accrual&lt;/STRONG&gt; process enables customers to earn loyalty points and benefits based on their purchases and other qualifying activities. For purchase-based accruals, sales data flows from SAP S/4HANA (or ERP) to Smart Insight and then to Emarsys Loyalty, where points and benefits are automatically calculated according to the customer’s plan and tier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once points are confirmed, they are sent back to SAP S/4HANA for financial posting, ensuring accounting accuracy.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4HANA periodically sends sales transaction data to Emarsys through a tenant-specific Sales Data Load URL found under &lt;STRONG&gt;Predict → Data Sources → Sales Data&lt;/STRONG&gt; in Emarsys. Once Emarsys receives the data, it calculates points based on the predefined logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="vijaysb15_1-1760848693559.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329567i6D2AD11617CE6ACB/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="vijaysb15_1-1760848693559.png" alt="vijaysb15_1-1760848693559.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;An automation program triggers a webhook on the &lt;STRONG&gt;loyalty_points_from_purchase_confirmed&lt;/STRONG&gt; event, which calls a CPI endpoint. This endpoint posts accrual entries in SAP S/4HANA, crediting customer accounts and updating liability GLs as per company-specific financial configurations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="vijaysb15_2-1760848747475.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329568i4CF873696D73DC08/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="vijaysb15_2-1760848747475.png" alt="vijaysb15_2-1760848747475.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-123356151"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points Redemption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;At checkout, customers can redeem their earned loyalty points either by paying directly with points or by using a voucher. Redemption can be initiated via mobile apps or websites during a purchase.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the customer chooses to pay directly with points, the &lt;STRONG&gt;Remove Points API&lt;/STRONG&gt; is called to deduct the required amount from their balance. A “Points Removed” activity is automatically recorded in their Emarsys profile.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alternatively, customers can claim a voucher using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Claim Voucher API&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Once the voucher code is generated, it can be applied at checkout. When a voucher is redeemed, the equivalent points are deducted, and a “Points Redeemed” activity is logged in Emarsys.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The financial postings for redemptions are handled by the respective sales channel (web, mobile, or POS) and then pushed to SAP S/4HANA via CPI to ensure accurate accounting entries.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="vijaysb15_0-1760848849628.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329569i7CDAD629F0C61303/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="vijaysb15_0-1760848849628.png" alt="vijaysb15_0-1760848849628.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--148388723"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Loyalty Segmentation, Personalization, and Campaigns&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Effective segmentation and personalization are key to increasing engagement and retention. SAP Emarsys enables marketers to create segments using &lt;STRONG&gt;relational data templates&lt;/STRONG&gt;, combining loyalty attributes (tier, points, activity type, or benefits) with contact and behavioral data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The relational data connection can be setup easily by referring the help link “ &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_EMARSYS/f8e2fafeea804018a954a8857d9dfff3/fdf13fc574c110148813e9861f7fecda.html?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Setting up Loyalty RDS connection&lt;/A&gt;” and templates can be setup as mentioned in the link&amp;nbsp; “ &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_EMARSYS/f8e2fafeea804018a954a8857d9dfff3/fdf146fe74c11014a46091ef8e59f041.html?q=Loyalty+Segement+templates&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=LATEST" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Setting up Loyalty segment templates&lt;/A&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These segments can be used across multiple campaign channels, including email, SMS, push, and web. Personalization tokens dynamically adapt campaign messages to show details such as the customer’s name, tier, available points, or next reward milestone.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="vijaysb15_4-1760849096026.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329573iDCD2D647A7F5AA56/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="vijaysb15_4-1760849096026.png" alt="vijaysb15_4-1760849096026.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--638305235"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; Personalization and Campaign Execution&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Once segments are built, they can be used across multiple channels — &lt;STRONG&gt;email, SMS, push notifications, or web campaigns&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp; Using &lt;STRONG&gt;personalization tokens&lt;/STRONG&gt;, each campaign message can dynamically adapt to display the customer’s &lt;STRONG&gt;name&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;tier&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;available points&lt;/STRONG&gt;, or &lt;STRONG&gt;next reward milestone&lt;/STRONG&gt;, delivering a truly personalized experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; SAP Emarsys offers prebuilt email template blocks designed for loyalty-related communications. Upon activation of a loyalty plan, the system automatically generates the relevant loyalty tokens. Furthermore, whenever a new Action or voucher is created, corresponding personalization tokens are generated by default.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; By blending loyalty data with Emarsys campaign automation, businesses can drive:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Higher engagement through relevant messaging&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Increased redemption and repeat purchase rates&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stronger customer retention and satisfaction&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="vijaysb15_3-1760849064233.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/329572iBA1DF9C01C9ED064/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="vijaysb15_3-1760849064233.png" alt="vijaysb15_3-1760849064233.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--541415733"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--737929238"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--934442743"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Loyalty Reports and Dashboards&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Analytics play a critical role in measuring loyalty program performance. SAP Emarsys publishes loyalty data to Google Cloud Platform through &lt;STRONG&gt;Open Data Views&lt;/STRONG&gt;. These can be connected to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/STRONG&gt; using the Remote Table option for near real-time data access.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Within SAP Datasphere, organizations can model data, define KPIs (such as Total Points Accrued vs. Redeemed or Active Members by Tier), and then visualize insights using &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; dashboards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This seamless data flow — from Emarsys to GCP, Datasphere, and SAC — provides real-time visibility into loyalty KPIs, helping businesses make data-driven decisions and optimize customer engagement strategies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1130956248"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;References:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_EMARSYS/8bf21e3e3ad3475bb9e25de1e0ac3d86/fdf6b8c874c11014ab07d03045e4962a.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;List of All Public API Endpoints&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_EMARSYS/f8e2fafeea804018a954a8857d9dfff3/fde868ae74c110148a62b53930abbd3a.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart Insight Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_EMARSYS/f8e2fafeea804018a954a8857d9dfff3/45d03e6a8c9d4e6fb48daff2d581b422.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Loyalty Implementation &amp;amp; Activation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_EMARSYS/f8e2fafeea804018a954a8857d9dfff3/57b315024f7a40ad9975fa1dab2cb36d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Loyalty Tactics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_EMARSYS/f8e2fafeea804018a954a8857d9dfff3/fdf6e2a274c11014a5528187e2f772da.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Relational Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_EMARSYS/f8e2fafeea804018a954a8857d9dfff3/52f427591f86482c9c5838a88ff7ebfe.html?q=segments" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Creating Segments&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_EMARSYS/f8e2fafeea804018a954a8857d9dfff3/275ffe318bcb411ebf2eb9eced0d6101.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Personalization&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_EMARSYS/f8e2fafeea804018a954a8857d9dfff3/8e7330ec1eb34779a3042304478a700e.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation Programs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1327469753"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In &lt;STRONG&gt;Part 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;, we explored the &lt;STRONG&gt;technical implementation journey&lt;/STRONG&gt; of SAP Emarsys Loyalty Management — covering end-to-end integration, automation flows, financial postings, customer service enablement, campaign personalization, and analytical insights through SAP Datasphere and SAP Analytics Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Stay tuned for &lt;STRONG&gt;Part 3&lt;/STRONG&gt;, where we will focus on &lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Service and Support Scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt; in greater detail.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Co-Authors:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/363791"&gt;@sandeepmkh&lt;/a&gt;(Sandeep Kulkarni) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/316584"&gt;@lokeshla&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;SPAN&gt;Lokesh Lakhondae)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/implementing-sap-emarsys-loyalty-management-part-2-technical-deep-dive/ba-p/14247872"/>
    <published>2025-10-20T06:02:50.534000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-horizon-themes-and-usability-enhancements-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14230129</id>
    <title>Introducing Horizon Themes and Usability Enhancements in SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T18:00:00.029000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnaBurkhardt</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4718</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A Fresh Look and a Smoother Experience for All Users&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are excited to announce the introduction of the Horizon themes in SAP Analytics Cloud a modern, cohesive visual language aligned across SAP’s product suite. You will have access to Morning and Evening Horizon, the light and dark themes as well as to the high contrast white and black themes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAC Home Page in Horizon Morning.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321160i2CA8FED2158D5072/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAC Home Page in Horizon Morning.png" alt="SAC Home Page in Horizon Morning.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This release also brings a series of improvements to the side navigation, user profile, user settings, and the search, making it easier than ever to find insights and personalize your application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1632673325"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1436159820"&gt;Horizon Themes: Modern, Accessible, and Unified&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The introduction of Horizon themes marks the next step in our user experience journey. These themes feature clean lines, contemporary color palettes, and improved contrasts, resulting in visually appealing UI that remain comfortable for extended work sessions. Accessibility is at the heart of Horizon, with thoughtful color selections and focus indicators for every user. The experience remains consistent as you move between SAP Analytics Cloud and other SAP solutions, offering a unified interface that supports productivity and ease of use. Personalize your experience by choosing from light, dark, and high contrast theme variants—simply head to your user settings to select your preferred look.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Theme Change in User Settings.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321188i1D3D6AA0FD2262C8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Theme Change in User Settings.png" alt="Theme Change in User Settings.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Belize theme will remain the default in Q4 and continue to be available for the next few quarters. Looking ahead, Horizon will become the standard theme in the first half of 2026. If you’d like to enable Horizon for your organization sooner, simply navigate to the administration section under default appearance to set Horizon as your tenant’s default theme.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1239646315"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1043132810"&gt;Improved User Profile and Settings&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The user profile and settings have been reimagined to put key information and settings at your fingertips. Instantly access your account details, profile image, and settings in one clear and organized dialog. Additionally, the “About” section is now conveniently located within your user profile making key information more accessible whenever you need it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="About Section in the User Profile.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321166iF39EB95D9E5B9969/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="About Section in the User Profile.png" alt="About Section in the User Profile.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-846619305"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-650105800"&gt;Simplified and Adaptive Side Navigation&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The redesigned side navigation bar logically organizes content and tools for easy access. Collapsible sections expand your workspace, and in collapsed view, hovering over each symbol shows module names to help you quickly find what you need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-453592295"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-257078790"&gt;More Convenient Search&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The search now features autocomplete, making it noticeably more convenient and user-friendly. As you begin typing, relevant suggestions appear instantly, streamlining the process of finding models, stories, and files. This enhancement helps you locate what you need more efficiently, even if you can’t recall exact names, ensuring a smoother search experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These updates are based on user feedback and extensive research, reflecting SAP’s commitment to delivering an analytics platform that is powerful, accessible, and a pleasure to use. The Horizon themes and experience enhancements aim to reduce friction, promote creativity, and empower you to shape insights in a visually appealing and highly functional space.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-60565285"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--135948220"&gt;What's Next&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can continue to style your SAP Analytics Cloud Stories independently, &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_ANALYTICS_CLOUD/00f68c2e08b941f081002fd3691d86a7/d385f41f9f6343eba6ed87eeeb50650b.html?q=theme" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;as the story theme mechanism will remain unchanged and won't follow the overall SAC theme.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the Q1 2026 release, we plan to update the preferences for new stories and make the Horizon Morning theme available in every story; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/horizon-theme-and-templates-for-stories-in-sap-analytics-cloud/ba-p/13657027" target="_blank"&gt;both Morning and Evening Horizon themes are currently available on GitHub.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The new Horizon themes and user experience improvements will be available mid-November in the Q4 2025 SAP Analytics Cloud release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you have feedback on the Horizon themes or the planned story theme updates, please reach out to me by message or in the comments.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-horizon-themes-and-usability-enhancements-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14230129"/>
    <published>2025-10-20T18:00:00.029000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-future-of-planning-in-excel-the-sap-analytics-cloud-add-in-as-a/ba-p/14245541</id>
    <title>The Future of Planning in Excel: The SAP Analytics Cloud Add-in as a Strategic Frontend – Part 2/3</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T09:24:21.145000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AlexanderZP</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2032280</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 2/3: Data Validation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-future-of-planning-in-excel-the-sap-analytics-cloud-add-in-as-a/bc-p/14234127" target="_self"&gt;first part of this series&lt;/A&gt;, we introduced the SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) add-in for Microsoft Office and positioned it as the strategic successor to Analysis for Office. We covered its modern architecture, seamless integration, and how to build a basic interactive planning sheet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now it’s time to move beyond simple data display and entry. In this second instalment, we’ll dive into one of the most powerful aspects of the add-in: how it works together with native Excel formulas. We’ll show how to use those formulas to create a practical, robust, and essential tool for any planner: a self-service data-validation sheet.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Use case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In most planning processes, a small group of “key users” monitors and oversees progress. They remind contributors to enter data, catch mistakes early, and help maintain overall planning quality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In later stages of a planning cycle, it becomes strategically important to know &lt;STRONG&gt;what changed compared to yesterday&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;why&lt;/STRONG&gt; it changed. To streamline this, the SAP Analytics Cloud add-in can be combined with standard Excel techniques to build a lightweight validation hub.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Create summary tables for the relevant dimensions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create one or more SAC-connected tables that summarise your planning data by the dimensions you care about.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Example:&lt;/EM&gt; in this post we use &lt;STRONG&gt;Country&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Material&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but in your scenario, it could be Cost Center, Product Group, Customer, etc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AlexanderZP_0-1760600785765.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328221i3CDC77865B1DB3FC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="AlexanderZP_0-1760600785765.png" alt="AlexanderZP_0-1760600785765.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Make sure each table is clearly labelled and, if helpful, filtered to the current planning year for quick scanning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Build a validation sheet with native Excel formulas&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On a separate worksheet (“Validation” or similar), use standard Excel functions to pull and compare values from the SAC-connected tables.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AlexanderZP_1-1760600832598.png" style="width: 679px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328222iEEA12B10EE14D1D0/image-dimensions/679x87?v=v2" width="679" height="87" role="button" title="AlexanderZP_1-1760600832598.png" alt="AlexanderZP_1-1760600832598.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This gives you a single list of values drawn from your summary tables, ready for checks and comparisons.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Tips for the validation sheet&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lookup &amp;amp; aggregation:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use XLOOKUP, INDEX/MATCH, SUMIFS, or AGGREGATE to retrieve totals for each combination (or whichever grain you need).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Change tracking:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Add a “Yesterday” (or “Baseline”) column populated from a prior snapshot (copy-pasted values, a versioned table, or a dated export). Then compute &lt;STRONG&gt;Delta&lt;/STRONG&gt; columns.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quality checks:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Use simple rules to flag issues like:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Missing values where entries are required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Negative or unusually large values.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Unexpected zeros for active entities.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conditional formatting:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Highlight deltas above a threshold, blanks, or outliers so key users can see problems immediately.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Filters &amp;amp; slices:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Add filters (e.g., by Region, Planner, Version) to narrow the validation view during review meetings.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Notes column:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Include a free-text column so reviewers can record the reason for changes (price update, volume re-forecast, currency effect, etc.).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AlexanderZP_2-1760600857031.png" style="width: 789px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/328223iB0D392D6EFF17D90/image-dimensions/789x147?v=v2" width="789" height="147" role="button" title="AlexanderZP_2-1760600857031.png" alt="AlexanderZP_2-1760600857031.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why this works&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Self-service:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Planners and key users can validate data in Excel without leaving the SAC context.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speed:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Native formulas keep it fast and flexible; no macros required.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Governance:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Clear flags and notes improve auditability and help explain variances.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s next (Part 3)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the final part of this series, we’ll show you how to transform your Excel sheet into a lightweight automation hub, enabling automatic data entry and streamlined updates to parameter values across your planning solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/the-future-of-planning-in-excel-the-sap-analytics-cloud-add-in-as-a/ba-p/14245541"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T09:24:21.145000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sneak-peek-in-to-sap-analytics-cloud-release-for-q4-2025/ba-p/14249322</id>
    <title>Sneak Peek in to SAP Analytics Cloud release for Q4 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T12:51:14.365000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Orla_C</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/654</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Sneak Peek Q4 2025.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330188i6A63D711CA776939/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Sneak Peek Q4 2025.png" alt="Sneak Peek Q4 2025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hard to believe we are at the final quarter of 2025 and what a year it has been. In this blog we give you a sneak peek into our Top 5 features in SAP Analytics Cloud for QRC4 2025. A full list of what is coming can be found on our&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q4%202025" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q4%202025" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Roadmap Explorer.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Let's dive in!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762949599"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Horizon Theme&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We are excited to announce the introduction of the Horizon themes in SAP Analytics Cloud a modern, cohesive visual language aligned across SAP’s product suite. You will have access to Morning and Evening Horizon, the light and dark themes as well as to the high contrast white and black themes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SAC Home Page in Horizon Morning.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330192i9C4338490C950C35/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAC Home Page in Horizon Morning.png" alt="SAC Home Page in Horizon Morning.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more about this and other usability enhancement check out this great &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-horizon-themes-and-usability-enhancements-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14230129" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/4718"&gt;@AnnaBurkhardt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566436094"&gt;My Metrics for KPIs Monitoring (formerly known as Watchlist)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A much anticipated new feature is the introduction of My Metrics (fka Watchlist).&amp;nbsp;My Metrics to create lists of metrics that you want to monitor, analyze, and share with other stakeholders. Add to a metrics list from a chart's context menu within a story. You can gain insights of the data changes and organize important metrics associated with your business in an intuitive way. With this new feature users can enjoy:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;New design that enables you to add and monitor your KPIs within SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ability to create, manage, and share your Metric Lists&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ability for viewers to add KPIs directly from stories&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Customized comparisons and previews&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="My Metrics.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330194iB78C223A2EF7DDF8/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="My Metrics.jpg" alt="My Metrics.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more check out this great &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-my-metrics-your-personalized-view-of-metrics-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14241430" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/719361"&gt;@marouferchichi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1369922589"&gt;Seamless Planning&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have two exciting additions to Seamless Planning this quarter,&amp;nbsp;SAP Datasphere fact view as a live version in a planning model and the ability to Scheduling a story based on a live SAP Datasphere solution connection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's start with the a&lt;SPAN&gt;bility to consume an existing SAP Datasphere fact view live using a separate version dimension element within a planning model:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Version element is available for consumption within stories (read-only in table)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Version element can be used as a source for planning operations, including copy and paste from an external version to a local version, or in batch operations, such as data actions, as a source or reference for copy and calculation operations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SeamlessPlanning_LiveVersions.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330198i5AC7E5B8231967E0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SeamlessPlanning_LiveVersions.jpg" alt="SeamlessPlanning_LiveVersions.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have also added the ability to schedule and deliver a story based on a live connection of SAP Datasphere to users over e-mail through SAP Analytics Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="DSP Scheduling.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330200i6A743A0FAC747D12/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DSP Scheduling.jpg" alt="DSP Scheduling.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;These are just 2 new features in the Seamless Planning story and there are many other in this great &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/unlocking-the-next-chapter-of-seamless-planning-in-sap-business-data-cloud/ba-p/14243864" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14553"&gt;@Max_Gander&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1173409084"&gt;Scheduling &amp;amp; Process Management: Factory Calendar&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Staying with planning we also introduce the ability to s&lt;SPAN&gt;chedule calendar tasks and publications based on working days. This includes the ability to:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Define a custom property representing workdays as an attribute in a model time dimension&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;View working days within the calendar and Gantt view&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set task recurrence based on working days&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="FactoryCalendar.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330205i54F30E7DD9713268/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FactoryCalendar.jpg" alt="FactoryCalendar.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-976895579"&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud Performance Content: Model and audit table sizes&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For administrators and system owners of SAP Analytics Cloud, maintaining a high-performing and stable environment is a top priority. As organizations expand their use of SAC, managing the underlying data volumes becomes increasingly important.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So in this release we are delivering a new Story in SAC Content designed to give you the transparency and control you need to manage your SAC tenant's data footprint effectively. This Story serves as a central overview for monitoring, analyzing, and then to be able to take an informed action on data volumes before they become a critical issue.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Model Sizes 2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330209i026912DC5B38F13D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Model Sizes 2.jpg" alt="Model Sizes 2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For further details check out this great &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-business-data-cloud-model-size-analysis-in-sac/ba-p/14238307" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt; by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/259114"&gt;@thomas_fery&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;There are plenty more exciting deliverables coming your way this quarter and we will be taking a deeper dive into these items in our What’s New video and blog series so stay tuned. For a full list of all features coming in QRC3 2025 for SAP Analytics Cloud check out the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Roadmap Explorer&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/42e4f84a0e5e458792b1047eaf81c31a" target="_self" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;What's New Viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Want to experience new and existing features for yourself? Take the leap and start your journey towards making data-driven decisions with confidence by signing up for a&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/cloud-analytics/trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;free trial&lt;/A&gt;, today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sneak-peek-in-to-sap-analytics-cloud-release-for-q4-2025/ba-p/14249322"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T12:51:14.365000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-on-the-sap-analytics-cloud-homepage-2025-q4-qrc-enhancements/ba-p/14234040</id>
    <title>What’s New on the SAP Analytics Cloud Homepage: 2025 Q4 QRC Enhancements!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T15:19:11+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marouferchichi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/719361</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The &lt;EM&gt;2025 Q4 QRC&lt;/EM&gt; release brings several welcome enhancements to the SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) Homepage that make personalization faster, admin controls more flexible, and metric monitoring easier. Whether you’re an end user customizing your view or a tenant admin managing resources, these updates streamline the experience and help you focus on what matters most.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s a quick tour of what’s new and why it matters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761874300"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Resizable Cards!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Users can now resize homepage cards vertically, horizontally, or both (depending on card type). You can better prioritize content visually to enlarge a critical story or metric card to occupy more space, shrink ancillary cards, and create a layout that mirrors your workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hover over a card until resize handles appear, then drag to resize. The responsive grid will rearrange other cards intelligently to preserve your layout.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 16.26.54.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325231i30BDE4B6953347A4/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 16.26.54.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 16.26.54.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Note:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;All cards are resizable, except the &lt;STRONG&gt;Quick Action card&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which can only be resized by removing its quick actions&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565360795"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Admin-Editable Resource Cards&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For tenant administrators, managing and sharing critical information just got a whole lot easier.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud tenant Admins can now edit the resource card by adding new custom resources.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;This means you can curate and provide direct links to essential internal documents, training materials, company portals, or any other relevant resources right from the homepage. Streamline access to vital information for your users and ensure everyone has what they need, exactly when they need it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the System Administration interface under Default Appearance, administrators will see a new Edit option on the resource card. Clicking the edit icon allows admins to add or remove links with a live preview of the card. Admins can also reset the resource card to its default appearance and restore the default links.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 16.49.50.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325233iC6A295412DCD7B4D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 16.49.50.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 16.49.50.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Note: The card must contain at least one resource (default or custom) to save changes.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368847290"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Unified Homepage and User Profile Settings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;To provide a more cohesive and efficient user experience,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud Homepage settings and User Profile Settings are now consolidated and unified in one intuitive interface.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;No more jumping between different menus to adjust your personal preferences and homepage layout. Everything you need to manage your personal workspace is now accessible from a single, convenient location, simplifying your personalization journey.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 17.23.38.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325250i56BEE92ED8818E71/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 17.23.38.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 17.23.38.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172333785"&gt;4. New "My Metrics" Card: Monitor Your Most Important Insights&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’re excited to introduce the brand-new&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;“My Metrics”&lt;/STRONG&gt; homepage card. This powerful new addition allows users to set up a personalized Metric List directly on their homepage. Monitor your most critical Metrics at a glance, ensuring you always have immediate visibility into your most important business drivers without needing to navigate away from your homepage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 17.08.03.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/325237i866776E7D69D493F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 17.08.03.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-09 at 17.08.03.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can select and load Metrics List owned by you or shared with you from the file reposotory in a very easy and simple way. By selecting a Metric from the card you will be redirected to My Metrics application where you will have a detailed overview of the selected Metrics. To learn more about &lt;STRONG&gt;My Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt; and its capabilities, please read this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-my-metrics-your-personalized-view-of-metrics-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14241430" target="_self"&gt;&lt;U&gt;blog &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;post.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975820280"&gt;5. A Fresh Look: The Horizon Theme is Here!&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Embrace a modern and vibrant aesthetic!&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Horizon theme is now enabled and can be easily set via your Homepage settings.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;This integration brings a fresh, contemporary design, aligning your SAC experience with the latest SAP Fiori guidelines. Enjoy a visually appealing and consistent interface that enhances readability and overall user satisfaction. To learn more about the new SAC themes, please read this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-horizon-themes-and-usability-enhancements-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14230129" target="_self"&gt;&lt;U&gt;blog &lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt;post.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-22 at 14.37.48.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/331001iF0B662E8F075A1CB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-22 at 14.37.48.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-22 at 14.37.48.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Features Not Supported on the New Homepage&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The redesigned SAP Analytics Cloud homepage brings many improvements for easier access to content and quicker insight into updates. However, a few &lt;STRONG&gt;Home&lt;/STRONG&gt; features are not available in the new experience:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Pin to Home&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Because Pin to Home depends on Classic Stories (&lt;U&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-next-phase-in-the-deprecation-of-the-classic-experience-in-sap/ba-p/14166173" target="_self"&gt;which will be deprecated in Q2 2026&lt;/A&gt;) &lt;/U&gt;and provides far fewer capabilities than My Metrics, we determined it is not a strategic feature and prioritized My Metrics to align&lt;STRONG&gt; with our &lt;/STRONG&gt;analytics roadmap.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recent Analytics Application, Recent Stories, and Recent Presentations&lt;/STRONG&gt;: have been consolidated into a single card called “&lt;STRONG&gt;Recent files&lt;/STRONG&gt;,” where you can view all your recent items and use filters to refine the card’s content.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Home Screen Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Note: the welcome message remains always enabled on the new homepage.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;System administration settings that are not supported on the new home screen include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Changing the background theme&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Changing or setting a custom logo&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;We recommend that you backup any of your pinned widgets and notes from your old homepage for your own records. Content within the deprecated home cards are intact in the new &lt;STRONG&gt;Home&lt;/STRONG&gt;, since you can filter the results of your recent files card to show your recent stories, recent presentations, and recent analytic applications. In addition, content within the favorites tab is intact in the favorites home card. The favorites card provides more control over how you can filter and search for your results.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These &lt;EM&gt;2025 Q4 QRC&lt;/EM&gt; release enhancements are all about putting more power, flexibility, and personalization into your hands, making your SAP Analytics Cloud experience more productive and enjoyable. We encourage you to explore these new features and tailor your homepage to truly reflect your unique workflow and priorities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779306775"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Next!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the upcoming SAC Homepage release, we’re rolling out &lt;STRONG&gt;Admin-focused&lt;/STRONG&gt; cards and enhancements for &lt;STRONG&gt;Admin Personas&lt;/STRONG&gt;: the new Admin Overview Console, Tenant Insights, Governance &amp;amp; Resources, and User Activity &amp;amp; Audit cards provide admins with fast access to management tools, tenant health metrics, and governance content. We encourage you to regularly consult our &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q4%202025" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;U&gt;roadmap&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/A&gt; for upcoming updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Log in to your SAP Analytics Cloud tenant today and experience the difference!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-on-the-sap-analytics-cloud-homepage-2025-q4-qrc-enhancements/ba-p/14234040"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T15:19:11+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-my-metrics-your-personalized-view-of-metrics-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14241430</id>
    <title>Introducing My Metrics: Your Personalized view of Metrics in SAP Analytics Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T18:12:20.374000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>marouferchichi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/719361</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In a world overflowing with data, the real challenge isn't just finding information, it's keeping a constant pulse on the numbers that truly matter. Business leaders, analysts, and decision-makers often find themselves navigating through multiple dashboards and reports just to track their most critical metrics. The process can be time-consuming and fragmented.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Today, we're thrilled to change that. We are excited to announce&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a powerful new innovation in SAP Analytics Cloud for the &lt;EM&gt;2025 Q4 QRC&lt;/EM&gt; release, designed to simplify how you &lt;STRONG&gt;monitor&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;analyze&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;share&lt;/STRONG&gt; your most important business metrics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1762712261"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is My Metrics?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;At its core,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;is your personalized, curated collection of metrics that matter most to you and your business. It’s a central "watchlist" where you can gather vital metrics from various stories and models into one intuitive, easy-to-access space.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine having a single screen where you can see your division's revenue, the conversion rate from your latest marketing campaign, and your team's customer satisfaction score, all updated in real-time, without having to open three different stories. That's the power of My Metrics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1566198756"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Started With My Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With My Metrics, you can build a personalized list to track the metrics that matter most to you. Arrange all your Metrics into categorized lists, making it easy to spot trends and understand your data at a glance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My Metrics is introduced as a new module within SAP Analytics Cloud, you can access it via the left panel from the New Side Menu. My Metrics is broken down into three simple areas:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your Metrics:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;A collection of all performance cards you have created or that have been shared with you. You may manage this collection by refreshing the list, modifying the variance display, sorting the cards, or deleting entries.&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;See below manage your list section. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Detailed Visualization:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;When you select a metric, a chart instantly visualizes its data. The type of chart can be set during the creation of the metric. You can also see exactly which filters are currently applied.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart Insights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Go beyond the chart with an automated analysis that reveals hidden patterns and important observations in your data.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-12 at 15.46.49.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326169i1AE1BDF23011E4AB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-12 at 15.46.49.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-12 at 15.46.49.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1369685251"&gt;Create and Edit Your Metrics List&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;There are several ways to create a new list. You can do so from the &lt;STRONG&gt;My Metrics &lt;/STRONG&gt;page or from the &lt;STRONG&gt;chart’s menu within a story&lt;/STRONG&gt; (optimized design experience). Let’s explore those options in details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1302254465"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create a List from the My Metrics Page:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;From the side navigation, select &lt;STRONG&gt;My Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt; and, from the list view drop-down, choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Create New Metrics List&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In the creation dialog, enter the list details, only the name is mandatory, though a description is recommended to clarify the types of metrics to be included. Optionally select a folder to organize the list, then choose Save to commit your changes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-21 at 17.32.12.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330334i1EF22B041F6BA0DC/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-21 at 17.32.12.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-21 at 17.32.12.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105740960"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create a List from Story:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open the story (&lt;STRONG&gt;optimized design experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;) that contains the chart data point you want to monitor, then choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Add to Metrics List&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the chart’s context menu. In the &lt;STRONG&gt;Add to Metrics List&lt;/STRONG&gt; dialog, set &lt;STRONG&gt;Add Metric to&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;STRONG&gt;Create New Metrics List&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and in the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create New Metrics List &lt;/STRONG&gt;dialog provide the list details, only the name is required, although a description is recommended to clarify the types of metrics to be saved. Optionally select a folder to organize the list, then choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt; to commit your changes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 15.45.53.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327365i7D19C48C654C1EE5/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 15.45.53.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 15.45.53.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-909227455"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rename a Metric in Your List:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once a list has been created, you have the option to rename metrics in a list when you have access to edit. From the side navigation, select &lt;STRONG&gt;My Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, open the relevant list, and select the metric you wish to rename. Then open the &lt;STRONG&gt;°°°&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;More &lt;/STRONG&gt;menu and choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Rename&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enter the new name, and select &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.00.55.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327174i6864FF03F8344D87/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.00.55.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.00.55.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-712713950"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Copy, Move, Add, or Jump to Original:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;At least one metric card must be present in the list to enable certain options in the More menu. You may edit a list by copying or moving metrics to other lists. If you have access to a shared metrics list or an individually shared metric, you can add those metrics to your own list as links. You may also navigate to the original story chart.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-516200445"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Delete a Metric from Your List:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;A metric may be deleted by its owner or by a user granted Full Control on an individually shared metric. Deleting a metric removes it from the list and permanently deletes its content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To delete a metric, select &lt;STRONG&gt;My Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the side navigation and open the list containing the metric. From the &lt;STRONG&gt;More&lt;/STRONG&gt; menu, choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Delete from Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt; List, then confirm by selecting &lt;STRONG&gt;Delete &lt;/STRONG&gt;in the warning dialog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-190604221"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Add to Your Metrics List&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We believe powerful features should be effortless to use. While analyzing data within a story built on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Optimized Design Experience&lt;/STRONG&gt;, you can now&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;right-click on the chart widget or on specific data points&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to add to your personal Metrics List instantly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 16.25.28.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327402i5E8A40D0F4A97A23/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 16.25.28.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 16.25.28.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="lia-unicode-emoji"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Note: Table and Geo Map widgets are not yet supported&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-123173435"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Add a Metric to Your List?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, open the menu on any supported chart by right‑clicking a data point or clicking the &lt;STRONG&gt;More Actions (°°°)&lt;/STRONG&gt; icon, then select &lt;STRONG&gt;Add to Metrics List&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In the pop‑up window, &lt;STRONG&gt;choose a Metrics List,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;pick a recent one, browse for an existing list, or create a new list, and enter a clear &lt;STRONG&gt;Metric Name&lt;/STRONG&gt; so you can easily recognize it later. You can click &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt; to add the Metric without needs for editing.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 15.59.48.png" style="width: 359px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327390i5390B5B5617AFE30/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 15.59.48.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 15.59.48.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--441974446"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure Your Metric:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Edit Metric Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;to review your filters, further customize the chart, or add a comparison. Review the data card details, see which filters are applied (for example, accounts, dimensions, or cross calculations).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the Comparison section, select &lt;STRONG&gt;Add Comparison&lt;/STRONG&gt; to configure how variance is calculated and displayed for the metric. The interface provides recommended comparisons, most commonly time-based (&lt;EM&gt;for example, week‑over‑week, month‑over‑month, or year‑over‑year&lt;/EM&gt;) or version‑based (&lt;EM&gt;for example,&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt; Actual vs Strategic Plan Budget&lt;/EM&gt;) which are suggested automatically based on the chart’s date fields, filters, and any version or release metadata. You can accept a recommended option or create a custom comparison from your choice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(Optional) Under the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Display Options&lt;/STRONG&gt;, add in your own footer label for the variance and modify other general display options of the metric card, such as inverting the color. For example, when your variance value has a higher expense than the predicted value. It makes sense to invert the color to red since an increase in value is not a positive sign.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 16.04.01.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327388i25BC10935EAAD478/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 16.04.01.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 16.04.01.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--638487951"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Configure Your Detailed Visualization:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click Next to review the &lt;STRONG&gt;Chart Visualization Details&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In this step you can select a chart type that best communicates your analysis: choose trend-oriented visuals such as line, area, or column charts for comparison analyses, and composition visuals such as stacked bars, 100% stacked bars, or pie charts to show how parts contribute to a whole. Some chart options will be locked because they would fundamentally change the original data points or aggregations you selected when adding the metric to the list (for example, altering the primary aggregation, dimension, or granularity).&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 16.00.39.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327385iBD8199602DCA5A38/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 16.00.39.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 16.00.39.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you're happy with it, click&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Your new Metric card will be added to your Metrics List.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--248195442"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Manage Your Metrics Lists&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can manage your Metrics Lists and metrics cards by:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Reloading Your List:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Refresh your list to display the latest updates to your cards. This option is usually found in the “More” settings.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 11.42.43.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327161i017083C292C9DE35/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 11.42.43.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 11.42.43.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Adjusting Variance Display:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Customize how card variance differences are shown. Through the “More” settings, you can choose to display these differences as a percentage or an absolute value.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Undoing or Redoing Changes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Easily revert or reapply your most recent actions within the list, such as renaming items, reordering cards, or changing variance display settings.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sorting Cards:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Organize your cards using several options:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Default (Custom):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Applies if you’ve set a specific custom order.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Recently Added:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;The standard sort order if no custom sort is active.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A-Z / Z-A:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Alphabetical sorting.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 11.40.11.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327159iB50A83CC0BDDA8DA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 11.40.11.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 11.40.11.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--444708947"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Share Your Lists and Individual Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can share your individual metrics or entire Metrics List with other stakeholders. When sharing, you have the ability to manage access levels, offering options such as view, edit, full control, or custom permissions. Additionally, you can send an email notification to users when you share with them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--934625459"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Share Individual Metric: &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shared metrics are automatically saved to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Individually Shared Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt; list, which is maintained by SAP. When sharing a metric, you may specify the level of access to grant each recipient.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.08.40.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327177iC07CDC2CE8EFF7BB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.08.40.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.08.40.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open the desired metrics list in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, open the metric card and choose &lt;STRONG&gt;°°°&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Share&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. In the Share Metric dialog, specify recipients by searching for users or by selecting Add users or teams, then choose the appropriate permissions from the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; drop-down: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;View&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Edit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, or &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Full control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, or select Custom to configure granular permissions (for example, permit sharing but disallow deletion). Optionally enable Email new recipients to notify users, and then select Share to apply the settings.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.42.15.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327198iE085915B9A5AD88B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.42.15.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.42.15.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1131138964"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Share Entire Metrics List:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Shared lists are automatically saved to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Shared with Me&lt;/STRONG&gt; section, which is administered by SAP. When sharing a list, you may specify the level of access granted to each recipient.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.46.15.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/327199i5D922049444C5078/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.46.15.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-14 at 12.46.15.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Open the desired metrics list in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Metrics&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and select &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;More&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Share&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. In the Share Metrics List dialog, specify recipients by searching for users or by choosing Add users or teams, then assign permissions from the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; drop-down &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;View&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Edit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, or &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Full Control&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, or select Custom to configure granular privileges (for example, allow sharing but restrict deletion). Optionally enable Email new recipients to notify them of the share, and select Share to apply the settings.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1327652469"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Modify Share Settings:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Modifying the share settings allows you to assign different access levels or revoke sharing permissions previously granted to teams or individual users.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To modify sharing settings, select the metric or list, choose &lt;STRONG&gt;More&lt;/STRONG&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Share&lt;/STRONG&gt;, then in the Share dialog select the users you wish to remove and click &lt;STRONG&gt;Unselect&lt;/STRONG&gt;; you may then make further adjustments or close the dialog to finalize the changes.&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1230762967"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A forthcoming My Metrics enhancement will enable users to &lt;STRONG&gt;subscribe&lt;/STRONG&gt; to scheduled &lt;STRONG&gt;metrics reports&lt;/STRONG&gt;, to keep tracking changes in your metrics list by defining the recurrence pattern.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please consult the official &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=67838200100800006884&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST#Q4%202025" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Analytics Roadmap&lt;/A&gt; for a comprehensive overview of forthcoming features.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-my-metrics-your-personalized-view-of-metrics-in-sap-analytics/ba-p/14241430"/>
    <published>2025-10-21T18:12:20.374000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-data-and-analytics-value-map-on-sap-community/ba-p/14249416</id>
    <title>Join the Data and Analytics Value Map on SAP Community</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T12:55:34.476000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Caroline-S</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/105086</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog Post Banner (4).png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330252i4A5E0C9B16BC5B38/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog Post Banner (4).png" alt="Blog Post Banner (4).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Value Maps have moved to SAP Community. &lt;STRONG&gt;Join us now in the SAP Community Groups&lt;/STRONG&gt; to stay up to date and informed on the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Support portfolio for Data and Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;, ranging from Expert-guided implementation (EGI) sessions, Continuous Quality Check (CQC) services, E-learnings, SAP Enterprise Support Advisory Council pilot programs and more.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Data and Analytics Value Map provides guidance for solutions including SAP Business Data Cloud, SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Datasphere, SAP Business Warehouse, SAP HANA Cloud, SAP Databricks, as well as SAP BusinessObjects. To see our new look in the SAP Community, watch the short SAP video (1 min, 30): &lt;A href="https://sapvideo.cfapps.eu10-004.hana.ondemand.com/?entry_id=1_n9gri9t0" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Value Maps on SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1892033252"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1695519747"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Access&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To access the SAP Enterprise Support Value Maps Group, you must login to SAP Community with an S-user ID or a Universal ID&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to us via the tab “Groups”, then “Customer Only Groups” or via our dedicated page: &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/resources/enterprise-support-value-maps" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Value Maps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SAPCommunityGroupsList.png" style="width: 784px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330261i1F3C3335E74B81F4/image-dimensions/784x490/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="784" height="490" role="button" title="SAPCommunityGroupsList.png" alt="SAPCommunityGroupsList.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Once in the SAP Enterprise Support Value Maps Group, select the Data and Analytics Value Map and click “Join Group”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Expand the “Options” button and click “Subscribe” to get email notifications of activity within the group&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Why join and subscribe? To set customization preferences, get notifications, participate in the group and have a better user experience&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="JoinGroup_Subscribe.png" style="width: 782px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330262i07D8EC551AE7E6EB/image-dimensions/782x643/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="782" height="643" role="button" title="JoinGroup_Subscribe.png" alt="JoinGroup_Subscribe.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499006242"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blog Posts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will continue to post blogs to let you know about availability of new and updated content in the SAP Enterprise Support portfolio, such as new E-Learnings, events taking place, best practices, and other relevant information for the Data and Analytics topic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1302492737"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1105979232"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Knowledge Base&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our Knowledge Base is a collection of documents, which provide both foundational information and in-depth guidance for SAP Data and Analytics topics including SAP Business Data Cloud. These focused documents organize the Expert-guided implementation (EGI) sessions, Continuous Quality Check (CQC) services, E-learnings, best practices, and more by topic. Making it easier for you to see in one place the SAP Enterprise Support offerings by topic and/or solution area. Here are three Knowledge Base directories to bookmark within the Data and Analytics Value Map:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-knowledge-base/sap-business-data-cloud-directory/ta-p/14220062" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Directory&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-knowledge-base/sap-data-warehousing-directory/ta-p/14220319" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Data Warehousing Directory&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-knowledge-base/sap-businessobjects-bi-2025-directory/ta-p/14205030" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BusinessObjects BI 2025 Directory&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-909465727"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-712952222"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use the Q&amp;amp;A section to ask us questions or find questions that have already been answered.&amp;nbsp;For example, maybe you need guidance on how to find best practices and make use of the SAP Enterprise Support offerings for your project such as a BW modernization in SAP Business Data Cloud. The following could be relevant for you:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;EGI for SAP BW Modernization with SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CQC for Private Cloud Go-Live&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CQC for Implementation&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CQC Technical Performance Optimization (TPO)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CQC Business Process Performance Optimization (BPPO)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CQC for Security Optimization&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;CQC for Data Volume Management&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Full details are in the Knowledge Base &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-knowledge-base/sap-bw-modernization-with-foundational-support/ta-p/14206374" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BW Modernization with Foundational Support&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-516438717"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-319925212"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Events&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;The monthly EGI schedule will be populated here giving details of the planned EGI topics, dates, time, regions and languages.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-123411707"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--148333167"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Request a Call&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Request a call with one of our topic experts to connect with the right content and resources.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--931652686"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--541360177"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;LIVE SESSIONS on SAP Enterprise Support value maps – Our Move to SAP Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Join this live session on&amp;nbsp;October 22, 2025, to learn more, where we will demo SAP Enterprise Support value maps on SAP Community.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/1nTUW1L8biA" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Link to join / Watch Replay&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1324679696"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId--1521193201"&gt;Enhance Your SAP Experience with Value Maps&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Enterprise Support offers additional resources to help you drive innovation. SAP Enterprise Support value maps provide expert-led resources, tailored recommendations, and advisory services - all included in your SAP cloud subscription. Get started today:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;One-time sign up for SAP Learning Hub, edition for SAP Enterprise Support, using a valid S-User ID (please allow up to 2 hours for processing)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access SAP Enterprise Support value maps for personalized guidance&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Request a call with our solution area experts for tailored advice&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Value Maps are part of SAP Enterprise Support commitment to your success. Visit the SAP Enterprise Support value maps&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/resources/enterprise-support-value-maps" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;landing page&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;to explore our range of topics and start engaging with us today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;About the author:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Caroline Sheridan&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a Topic Expert for SAP Enterprise Support value maps, specializing in SAP Data and Analytics. With a tenure of 12 years at SAP, Caroline’s expertise lies in assisting and guiding customers to succeed through SAP Enterprise Support offerings.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Have&amp;nbsp;questions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;on this content? Feel free to leave a comment below or submit them in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-value-map-q-a/qa-p/es-data-analyticsqanda-board" target="_blank"&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;section.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/join-the-data-and-analytics-value-map-on-sap-community/ba-p/14249416"/>
    <published>2025-10-22T12:55:34.476000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/is-it-possible-to-update-styling-rules-via-scripting-in-sac/ba-p/14250537</id>
    <title>Is it possible to update styling rules via scripting in SAC?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T13:03:04.216000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>azm_azm</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/811892</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here is the requirement. I want to define a custom styling rule within a table for two columns with different color. The table displays data at day granularity. The requirement is to highlight last two days of the previous month. For ex, if my planning cycle starts from Oct 2025, then 29 Sept and 30 Sept should be highlighted. If my planning cycle starts from Nov 2025, then 30 Oct and 31 Oct should be highlighted. I tried to follow the standard styling rule approach but the dynamic nature of requirement is causing an issue. I don't know if it is possible in SAC either via Scripting or by standard functionality.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="azm_azm_0-1761130886399.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/330924iD103A1743F8D570B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="azm_azm_0-1761130886399.png" alt="azm_azm_0-1761130886399.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Anyone who has faced this similar issue, or know the workaround in this scenario. Their comments would be deeply appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/is-it-possible-to-update-styling-rules-via-scripting-in-sac/ba-p/14250537"/>
    <published>2025-10-22T13:03:04.216000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/master-data-sync-in-public-dimension-using-hybrid-stories-and-scripting-in/ba-p/14242336</id>
    <title>Master Data Sync in Public Dimension using Hybrid Stories and Scripting in SAC</title>
    <updated>2025-10-23T06:32:23.021000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ajay105</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2102459</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1891823816"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maintaining data consistency across two dimensions' attributes depending on the ID or any other attribute is a common need in SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For instance, if one dimension (let's call it A Dimension) contains master data like product color, size, or type and another dimension (let's call it B Dimension) depends on it, then changes to a property in A Dimension must automatically be reflected in B Dimension.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Under these circumstances:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Dimension A = Dimension of the Product&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;B Dimension Equals Group Dimension&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The objective of this approach is to use a reference key (&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;Default_Product_ID,&lt;/FONT&gt; for instance) to synchronize the values of attributes (such &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;Color_Code&lt;/FONT&gt; and &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;Size_Label&lt;/FONT&gt;) between these two dimensions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Using SAC scripting, this blog demonstrates how to &lt;STRONG&gt;synchronize properties&lt;/STRONG&gt; between &lt;STRONG&gt;two dimensions in hybrid stories&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1695310311"&gt;Overview of the Use case&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Concept&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Model Used&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Product_G_Model&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dimensions Involved&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Product Dimension and Group Dimension&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="84px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Relationship&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="84px"&gt;Each Group member contains a property called Default_Product_ID that links it to a Product Dimension ID field&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="104px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Purpose&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="104px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Copy Color_Code and Size_Label from Product Dimension to Group Dimension for members flagged as “Y”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1498796806"&gt;Steps involved in implementation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1431366020"&gt;Step 1: Select the Planning Model&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose the Planning Model.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;Product_G_Model&lt;/FONT&gt;, the planning model that includes both public dimensions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1234852515"&gt;Step 2:&amp;nbsp; In the script, declare global variables.&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Under &lt;STRONG&gt;Script Variables&lt;/STRONG&gt;, create the following variables:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Variable Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Type&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mode&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Description&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;GroupMembers&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;PlanningModeMember&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Array&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Stores Group members&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;ProductMembers&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;PlanningModeMember&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Array&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Stores Product members&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="77px"&gt;&lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;Update_PRD_KPI&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="77px"&gt;Number&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="77px"&gt;Single&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="77px"&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tracks count of updated members&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;These variables make the script easier to read and reuse.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1038339010"&gt;Steps 3:&amp;nbsp;Write a Script Function&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a function under &lt;STRONG&gt;Script Objects&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Name: updateGroupFromProducts&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Return Type: PlanningModelMember[]&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Arguments:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;ProductMembers: PlanningModelMember[]&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GroupMembers: PlanningModelMember[]&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on Product data, this method will include the logic to change Group properties.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-841825505"&gt;Step 4:&amp;nbsp; Write the Script Logic&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;actual&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAC&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;script&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;that&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;does&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;synchronization&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;is&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;shown&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;below:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;var updatedMembers = ArrayUtils.create(Type.PlanningModelMember);
for (var j = 0; j &amp;lt; GroupMembers.length; j++) {
	var Member = GroupMembers[j];
	if (Member.properties.Flag === "Y") {
		for (var i = 0; i &amp;lt; ProductMembers.length; i++) {
			if (ProductMembers[i].id === Member.properties.Default_Product_ID) {
				Member.properties.Color_Code = ProductMembers[i].properties.Color_Code;
                Member.properties.Size_Label = ProductMembers[i].properties.Size_Label;
                updatedMembers.push(Member);
                break;
			}
		}
	}
}
return updatedMembers;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-645312000"&gt;Step 5: Execute on Initialization&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;The script used to get members, apply updates, and refresh the model during the app's initialization is shown below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;GroupMembers=Product_G_Model.getMembers("Group_Dimension_P1",{limit:2000});
ProductMembers=Product_G_Model.getMembers("PRD_DIM_2L",{limit:200000});
 var updList=ScriptObject_1.updateGroupFromProducts(ProductMembers,GroupMembers);
	Update_PRD_KPI=updList.length;
        if (updList.length &amp;gt; 0) {
            var success = Product_G_Model.updateMembers("Group_Dimension_P1", updList);
            if (success) {
                Application.refreshData();
            }
        }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-448798495"&gt;Sample Output&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;After execution, Group members flagged as "Y" will have their &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;Color_Code&lt;/FONT&gt; and &lt;FONT face="courier new,courier"&gt;Size_Label&lt;/FONT&gt; updated based on the linked Product member.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Sample output.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/326563i93C35658360DECB0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Sample output.jpeg" alt="Sample output.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-252284990"&gt;Benefits&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;By&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;automatically&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;synchronizing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;master&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;data,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;automation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;removes&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;need&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;manual&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;updates.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Consistently Keeps dependent dimensions conformed.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Reusability&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Function-based&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;design&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;allows&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;same&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;logic&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;be&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;applied&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;multiple&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;dimensions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;simplicity&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;deploy&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;features&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;methods&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;that&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;are&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;currently&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;included&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;in&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;SAC&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;scripting.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--441945610"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;This method ensures data synchronization between two related dimensions within a SAC Planning Model.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Changes to dimension properties are managed while maintaining data consistency.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/master-data-sync-in-public-dimension-using-hybrid-stories-and-scripting-in/ba-p/14242336"/>
    <published>2025-10-23T06:32:23.021000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/enabling-embedded-sap-analytics-cloud-sac-for-seamless-business-insights/ba-p/14254733</id>
    <title>Enabling Embedded SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) for Seamless Business Insights</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T06:56:02.287000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>shameek_sharma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/856453</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Embedded SAP Analytics Cloud (SAC) is a streamlined version of the full SAP Analytics Cloud platform, included at no extra cost with most SAP products. Once configured in SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud V2 or SAP Enterprise Service Management, this embedded solution allows users to access analytics directly within these applications, helping to drive better decision-making without the learning curve associated with custom/multiple in-built analytics solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While Embedded SAC is designed for ease of use, it does require a one-time configuration to integrate with your SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud V2 or SAP Enterprise Service Management solutions. Additionally, to enable a smooth login experience for your users, integration with an Identity Provider (IdP) is necessary.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integration with Identity Providers (IdP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For secure and streamlined access, you can choose from two supported Identity Providers:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Platform Identity Authentication Service (SAP IAS)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Entra ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These IdPs help ensure that users can easily log in to Embedded SAC with their existing credentials. Detailed configuration steps for for these can be found in our comprehensive documentation :&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES/ea5ff8b9460a43cb8765a3c07d3421fe/eceac5a75db64ddbb7afd524058a0a0c.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES/ea5ff8b9460a43cb8765a3c07d3421fe/eceac5a75db64ddbb7afd524058a0a0c.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For a step-by-step guide on how to enable Embedded SAC and configure it with SAP IAS, we’ve created an instructional video, which you can access here&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;div id="kaltura_player_1130551098" style="width:768px;height:432px;"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;script type="text/javascript" src="&lt;A href="https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/p/1921661/embedPlaykitJs/uiconf_id/54739572?autoembed=true&amp;amp;targetId=kaltura_player_1130551098&amp;amp;entry_id=1_3w0xwam0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/p/1921661/embedPlaykitJs/uiconf_id/54739572?autoembed=true&amp;amp;targetId=kaltura_player_1130551098&amp;amp;entry_id=1_3w0xwam0&lt;/A&gt;"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Troubleshooting &amp;amp; FAQs&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you encounter any issues during the setup process, our online help documentation provides a range of FAQs to assist you. We recommend reviewing these before reaching out for additional support :&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES/ea5ff8b9460a43cb8765a3c07d3421fe/319683f2e2b24f8a94eda0fbe9f74271.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/CX_NG_SALES/ea5ff8b9460a43cb8765a3c07d3421fe/319683f2e2b24f8a94eda0fbe9f74271.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By embedding SAP Analytics Cloud into your SAP Sales &amp;amp; Service Cloud V2 or SAP Enterprise Service Management environment, you unlock deeper, actionable insights, all while streamlining the user experience. Get started today by configuring Embedded SAC and integrating with your chosen Identity Provider.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/crm-and-cx-blog-posts-by-sap/enabling-embedded-sap-analytics-cloud-sac-for-seamless-business-insights/ba-p/14254733"/>
    <published>2025-10-28T06:56:02.287000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-monitor-consumption-for-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-and-its/ba-p/14257413</id>
    <title>How to monitor consumption for SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) and its components?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T18:37:48.747000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FernandaFroelich</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1410810</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Symptom&lt;/STRONG&gt;: You don't know how to check&amp;nbsp;SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) usage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Requirements&lt;/STRONG&gt;: You need to have an S-user and the role of Super Administrator assigned in SAP for Me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you don't have an S-User, please check&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/my-support/users/welcome.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;this page&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If you are unsure which role you have, please check&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/1282821" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;this note&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Resolution&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1) Open&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and log in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2) Navigate to the "&lt;EM&gt;Dashboards&lt;/EM&gt;" section and click "&lt;EM&gt;Finance &amp;amp; Legal&lt;/EM&gt;".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3) Select "&lt;EM&gt;Consumption&lt;/EM&gt;".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4) Filter for "&lt;EM&gt;Business Data Cloud&lt;/EM&gt;".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;5) Click on the measured number to open a card; it explains the consumption by each metric.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Image 01&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="FernandaFroelich_0-1761845531617.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334479iD0F371C3EF721D18/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FernandaFroelich_0-1761845531617.png" alt="FernandaFroelich_0-1761845531617.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Image 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="FernandaFroelich_0-1761848037864.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/334512i78FBDF2E31558FC7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="FernandaFroelich_0-1761848037864.png" alt="FernandaFroelich_0-1761848037864.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Important reminder:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;SAP Databricks and SAP Datasphere usage is based on actual consumption instead of what is in the quota assignment. For SAP Analytics Cloud, on the other hand, it is considered the number of users assigned for each SAC license according to the quota assignment. For more information on the components usage (SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Datasphere), please refer to this &lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/support/en_us/library/ssp/my-support/systems-installations/system-measurement/cloud-saas-application-usage/sap-business-data-cloud.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt;. If you want to know more about how the metric itself works, check this &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/about/trust-center/agreements/cloud/cloud-services.html?search=Business%20Data%20Cloud&amp;amp;sort=latest_desc&amp;amp;pdf-asset=aaa18b5a-267f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b&amp;amp;page=4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;pdf&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/how-to-monitor-consumption-for-sap-business-data-cloud-bdc-and-its/ba-p/14257413"/>
    <published>2025-10-30T18:37:48.747000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/automated-alerts-for-data-action-failures-in-sac/ba-p/14258641</id>
    <title>Automated Alerts for Data Action Failures  in SAC</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T05:24:24.214000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Swathi_Kottu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/174613</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1763846273"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a standard feature, SAP Analytics Cloud sends the alerts/ notification&amp;nbsp; for Data Management job failures whereas for the Data Actions&amp;nbsp; there is no such alert mechanism, and it requires manual monitoring to track the status of process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For Instance,&amp;nbsp; We need to go through the entire&amp;nbsp; " Data Action Monitor"&amp;nbsp; to check the Data Action status that we triggered as part of nightly runs. it would be complicated to check the status of each and every DA whether it is failed or successful.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To make this process easier ,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The solution involves creating an automated routine through SAC Analytic Apps by utilizing the system models containing the status of the Data Actions .&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Scheduling the routines at a regular interval so that it monitors the status of DA process and triggers an alert to Admins or the specified SAC users in case of any status other than “SUCCESS”&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1567332768"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Details of the objects used in Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Live System Model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; :&amp;nbsp; PLANNING_DATA_ACTIONS ( Path: Files| System/ Common/ SAC Content/ SAC Content Performance/ SAC Content Performance- Models )&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Table_1&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;:&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Acts as a source within&amp;nbsp; the application&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: 1.This model stores all the data action details in SAC tenant with default time zone &lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;:GMT&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;2. Assuming that we trigger this run this application for every 20 mins through a Calendar publication, so it will send an alert if it finds a failures within the interval&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;3. Drag all the quired columns to the table considering&amp;nbsp; " Final Status" as the first row&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;# OnInitialization
var curr_date = new Date(Date.now()); //Get the current Date
console.log(curr_date);

var l_date1 = new Date(Date.now());
var l_date2 = new Date(Date.now());
var min= l_date2.getMinutes();
var hr = l_date2.getHours();
var hr2= hr+4; // Converting the EST hours to GMT
var hr3= hr+4;
var min2 = min-20;// Setting up the mins as per the required interval
// Handling the exceptional case
if(min2&amp;lt;0){
	min2= min + 40;
	hr2= hr2-1;
	console.log(min2);
	console.log(hr2);

	if(hr2&amp;lt;0){
		hr2= 23;
	}
}



l_date2.setMinutes(min2);
l_date2.setHours(hr2);
l_date1.setHours(hr3);
// Setting up the range to filter out the source table
var range = TimeRange.create(TimeRangeGranularity.Minute,l_date2,l_date1);

Table_1.getDataSource().setDimensionFilter("DATETIME_EXECUTE", range);
console.log(range);

var count= 0;
var dims = Table_1.getDimensionsOnRows()[0]; //With assumption that the status column is in the first row
var selections = Table_1.getDataSource().getDataSelections();
var members = ArrayUtils.create(Type.string);
// Formatting the table to print in the alert email
var strTable = "--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; ";
    strTable = "&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Data Action Name    &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;  |&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;Model Name &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;  &amp;amp;nbsp;  |&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;Process Type      &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;  &amp;amp;nbsp;  |&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;Triggered From     &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;  &amp;amp;nbsp;   |&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;Execution Time     &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp; |&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;Status     &amp;amp;nbsp;  &amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;";
strTable = strTable + "--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; ";
for( var j=0;j&amp;lt;selections.length;j++){
	var member =Table_1.getDataSource().getResultMember(dims,selections[j]);
	{
		members.push(member.description);}}
//console.log(members);
for (var s=0; s&amp;lt;members.length;s++){
	if(members[s]!=="Success"){
		count++;
// Pushing the table details to the format table after filtering out the failed DA details			
	strTable = strTable + "&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;" + count.toString() + ".&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; &amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;"	 + selections[s]["PLANNING_PROCESS_NAME"] + "&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;      |&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;"+ selections[s]["MODEL_NAME"] +"       &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp; |&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;"+ selections[s]["PLANNING_PROCESS_TYPE"] +"       &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp; |&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;"+ selections[s]["TRIGGERED_FROM_NAME"] +"       &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp; |&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;" + selections[s]["DATETIME_EXECUTE"].substr(0,16) +"    &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp; |&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;" + selections[s]["STATUS_DESC"] +"&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;" ;
	strTable = strTable + "------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; ";
		
		
	}
}


console.log(count);
if(count&amp;gt;0){
Application.sendNotification({title: "ALERT: SAC Calendar Sequence Failure Notification", 
							  content:"This is a standard notification on your calendar tasks failure (Data Action or Multi-Action). Refer to the list below for the Tasks/Actions that have failed and take appropriate action to resolve the error.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;"+"Thanks,&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;"+"SAC Monitoring Process &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;"+ strTable + "&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;" ,
							  isSendMobileNotification:true,
							  isSendEmail:true,
							
							  receivers:["SAC User1","User2"]});
	
	
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Since this code is being written on OnInitialization runs through the Calendar publication and send alert emails&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image (1).jfif" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335099iE51475538459E933/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image (1).jfif" alt="image (1).jfif" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1499901982"&gt;Sample Email Alert:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="image (8).png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/335102i19E4DBE735EB0F23/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image (8).png" alt="image (8).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1174305758"&gt;Benefits&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business user to be benefitted by reduced lead time for Data action error remediation; automated email-failure notifications to Admins will result in immediate remediation effort&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reduced Manual monitoring effort through automation of alert notifications to SAC Admins on Daily/nightly loads.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-977792253"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This automation in SAC reduces manual monitoring, ensures timely intervention.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/automated-alerts-for-data-action-failures-in-sac/ba-p/14258641"/>
    <published>2025-11-04T05:24:24.214000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
