<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Community-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Community</title>
  <updated>2025-09-10T08:00:53.881201+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Community/pd-p/486157991894093153608181816584982" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Community blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/melbourne-blog-posts/wrap-up-sap-inside-track-melbourne-20th-aug-2025/ba-p/14191831</id>
    <title>Wrap up SAP Inside Track Melbourne - 20th Aug 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T02:51:51.169000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Saikrishna_Sriram</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/166729</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thank you to the SAP Community members who came out in force to support the SAP Inside Track even on 20th Aug 2025 for the third quarter of this year.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We had some awesome presentations on&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI assisted developments by Matthias and team&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Agentic AI by David Nye&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Both the topics were very engaging , inspiring and giving us a peak of what is possible with AI&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We would like to thank our friends at AWS for hosting us and providing the drinks and to SAP Press (@sappress) for their continued sponsorship.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Congratulations to Paras Arora and Michael Tanyusheng who were this quarters SAP Press book winners&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have some exciting sessions planned for the next event , so check this space for details to follow soon&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our next event is on 19th Nov at the same location&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/melbourne-events/sap-inside-track-melbourne-19th-nov-2025/ec-p/14092613#M13" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Inside Track Melbourne - 19th Nov 2025 - SAP Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saikrishna_Sriram_0-1756169299205.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304867i98616EF6F2C7DF5E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Saikrishna_Sriram_0-1756169299205.png" alt="Saikrishna_Sriram_0-1756169299205.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saikrishna_Sriram_1-1756169314190.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304868iB982145B1F79D8A4/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Saikrishna_Sriram_1-1756169314190.png" alt="Saikrishna_Sriram_1-1756169314190.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saikrishna_Sriram_2-1756169324833.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304869iD3D83E2976DDB8B8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Saikrishna_Sriram_2-1756169324833.png" alt="Saikrishna_Sriram_2-1756169324833.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Saikrishna_Sriram_3-1756169333678.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304870iC23B34FFF455EE1E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Saikrishna_Sriram_3-1756169333678.png" alt="Saikrishna_Sriram_3-1756169333678.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Melbourne Community&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/944" target="_blank"&gt;@pjcools&lt;/A&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/171482" target="_blank"&gt;@Machillanda&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/136196" target="_blank"&gt;@BenPatterson&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/166729" target="_blank"&gt;@Saikrishna_Sriram&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/143160" target="_blank"&gt;@davidnye&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/melbourne-blog-posts/wrap-up-sap-inside-track-melbourne-20th-aug-2025/ba-p/14191831"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T02:51:51.169000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/white-space-begone-new-pilot-removes-widgets-column-from-blog-posts/ba-p/14191534</id>
    <title>White Space, Begone! New Pilot Removes Widgets Column from Blog Posts</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T14:19:51.680000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jerryjanda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/23</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;For as long as I can remember, even going back to the previous SAP Community platform, members have asked us to reduce the amount of white space on post pages, arguing that the layout makes readability more difficult. It’s a complaint that continues today – and one that we’re taking steps to address.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The current platform includes a column for widgets (e.g., Top Kudoed Authors), but, depending on the length of a blog post, that column might be mostly blank. For that reason, members have &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-feedback-list/change-post-reading-view-to-one-column-layout/idi-p/14101534" target="_blank"&gt;requested its removal&lt;/A&gt;, and we’re now testing the favorability of that approach.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;To help illustrate the point, here’s a blog post with the widgets column:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jerryjanda_0-1756139473685.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304763i577F5F071F9027AE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jerryjanda_0-1756139473685.png" alt="jerryjanda_0-1756139473685.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Now here’s the very same post with the widgets column (and white space) removed:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jerryjanda_1-1756139473699.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/304764iA97EC8543DB4AA52/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jerryjanda_1-1756139473699.png" alt="jerryjanda_1-1756139473699.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;What do you think? Better? Worse? Don’t care one way or the other? We’re running a four-week pilot (starting today) so you can let us know!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;To experience a blog board free of the widgets column (and the white space that comes with), head on over to the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/bg-p/application-developmentblog-board" target="_blank"&gt;Application Development and Automation&lt;/A&gt; group. We’re currently testing that look and feel over there to give members the opportunity to view blog posts without the widgets.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;(Note: We are aware of issues with the formatting of some posts now that we've removed the widgets column. If this change affected the placement of images in your post, for example, you'll need to edit to correct. Per the "Blog Formatting Post-Migration" section of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/addressing-common-questions-and-complaints-about-the-new-platform/ba-p/13598606" target="_self"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt;, it's best to use the blog tool as intended, making sure to avoid complicated html and to clear formatting when copying over text.)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Compare the blog posts in the Application Development and Automation group to blog posts in other areas on the community. If you prefer the new widget-less layout, let us know in the comments below. Or, if you favor blog posts with widgets and the white space, make sure to share your opinions in the comments as well. We’ll review all feedback received between today (Tuesday, August 26) and Tuesday, September 23, then determine which layout members seem to favor.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If enough members choose the new approach (with the widgets and space gone), we can update all blog boards to match what you see in the Application Development and Automation group. Then again, if members tell us to leave the current layout alone, that’s what we’ll do (and we’ll switch the Application Development and Automation posts back to match the other boards).&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Will we change the status of this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-feedback-list/change-post-reading-view-to-one-column-layout/idi-p/14101534" target="_blank"&gt;feedback item&lt;/A&gt; to “Delivered”? Or “Declined”? You can help us decide!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;With this pilot, we’re inviting members to provide feedback that will help influence the design of our site – as it should be in a community that belongs to all of us.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We look forward to reading your input below!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/white-space-begone-new-pilot-removes-widgets-column-from-blog-posts/ba-p/14191534"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T14:19:51.680000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-translation-hub/ba-p/14192795</id>
    <title>SAP Translation Hub</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T14:54:04.281000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Хочете подолати мовні бар'єри та розкрити весь потенціал SAP рідною мовою?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Зареєструйтеся на пізнавальний вебінар, розроблений для революційних змін у вашому підході до перекладу документів та програмного забезпечення.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Приєднуйтесь до нашої панелі експертів, які розкриють трансформаційні можливості Translation Hub із захопливою демонстрацією практичного застосування в реальному часі, щоб проілюструвати його практичний вплив. Готуйтеся надихнутися!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":ukraine:"&gt;🇺🇦&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Цікавий факт:&lt;/STRONG&gt; українська мова підтримується в інтерфейсі рішень SAP уже майже 20 років, а досвід використання рішень SAP українськими компаніями — 30 років!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;За цей час сформовано потужну базу термінології та перекладацьких даних, що дозволяє максимально ефективно використовувати SAP Translation Hub і забезпечувати високу якість перекладу українською.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Радимо ознайомитися з можливостями сервісу та протестувати їх на власних матеріалах.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Розкрийте глобальні можливості з SAP Translation Hub!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Дата:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 29 серпня 2025 року&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":timer_clock:"&gt;⏲&lt;/span&gt;️ &lt;STRONG&gt;Час:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 12.30 за Києвом&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://url.sap/jlnhlj" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Зареєструйтеся зараз&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-translation-hub/ba-p/14192795"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T14:54:04.281000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/hyderabad-blog-posts/event-summary-sap-inside-track-hyderabad-2025-2nd-edition/ba-p/14192926</id>
    <title>Event Summary: SAP Inside Track Hyderabad 2025 (2nd Edition)</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T19:32:50.101000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MaheshCV</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1473048</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP Inside Track Hyderabad 2025 (2nd Edition) was a full-day event packed with technical sessions and strategic insights from various&amp;nbsp; speakers. The event's content provided a comprehensive look at the latest advancements in SAP, with a strong emphasis on the intersection of S/4HANA, AI, and Analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Event Highlights &amp;amp; Lowlights&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Highlights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;900 Registrations:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The event saw a massive number of registrations, indicating strong interest and engagement from the SAP community.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;10 Speakers:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A total of 10 speakers shared their knowledge and insights on various SAP related topics, providing a wide range of expertise.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MOURI Tech Stall:&lt;/STRONG&gt; MOURI Tech had a prominent stall at the event, which served as a key point for networking and interaction.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lowlights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;25% Turnaround:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Despite the high number of registrations, the event had a 25% turnaround, which indicates a significant number of registered attendees did not show up.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Event T-Shirt Arrived After the Event:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A notable logistical issue was that the event T-shirts were not available for attendees on the day of the event&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Event started with the panel discussion:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FROM TRANSACTIONAL TO PREDICTIVE: THE S/4HANA AND AI SYNERGY&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;DR. MAHESH KUMAR CV&lt;/STRONG&gt; Founding Member, Global Agentic AI Consortium&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GUPTA KANDULA&lt;/STRONG&gt; AVP, HCLTech&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RASHMI JOSHI&lt;/STRONG&gt; Technical Solution Architect, IBM&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SUNIL KUMAR NAVYA&lt;/STRONG&gt; Senior Director, MOURI Tech&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;This high-level panel, a key highlight of the event, delved into how S/4HANA's transactional data and AI/ML capabilities combine to deliver predictive analytics. The discussion emphasized the shift from merely reporting on past events to anticipating future outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Immanuel Kolagani (MOURI Tech): The Open Era of SAP Analytics - Datasphere and BDC :&lt;/STRONG&gt;Immanuel's session focused on SAP Datasphere and the Business Data Catalog (BDC). He explained how these tools represent SAP's commitment to an open data strategy, allowing for seamless integration and management of data from various sources to enable a unified analytics landscape.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Srinivas Reddy Edulakanti (Patil Group): SAP Transformation Journey Challenges :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;This talk provided a candid look at the real-world challenges organizations face during their SAP transformation projects. Srinivas shared insights on overcoming common hurdles, from technical complexities to change management issues, offering practical advice for a smoother journey.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dr. Mahesh Kumar CV (Al Bharath Consortium): How to Reskill in the age of S4HANA, Embedded Analytics, AI...SAP BDC :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Dr. Kumar's session was a crucial guide for professionals looking to stay relevant in the rapidly evolving SAP landscape. He outlined the key skills needed for the future, emphasizing the importance of expertise in S/4HANA, embedded analytics, AI, and SAP BTP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Naga Prathima Mummidisetti (MOURI Tech): Unifying the Cloud: Harnessing SAP BTP Integration Suite for a Connected Enterprise :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;This talk provided a deep dive into the SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), specifically focusing on its Integration Suite. Naga Prathima explained how organizations can use BTP to seamlessly connect disparate systems, both SAP and non-SAP, to create a cohesive and data-rich landscape essential for modern business operations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vidya Sagar Yedla (MOURI Tech): Building Modern Apps with RAP and CAP: A Developer's Journey &lt;/STRONG&gt;Aimed at developers, this session was a practical guide to building modern, cloud-native applications on SAP BTP. Vidya Sagar demonstrated the use of the ABAP RESTful Application Programming Model (RAP) and the Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP) to create flexible and scalable applications that extend the functionality of S/4HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hitendra Munjampally (MOURI Tech): Rise of ERP Copilots: AI Assistants Transforming Enterprise Productivity :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Hitendra's session explored the growing trend of AI copilots within ERP systems. He demonstrated how tools like SAP Joule can act as intelligent assistants, streamlining workflows, automating routine tasks, and providing users with actionable insights directly within their SAP interface.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Madhavi Arelli (SRIA Infotech): SAP AI in Transform Business with AI Agents, and Smarter Models :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Madhavi’s session provided a broad overview of how AI and intelligent models can fundamentally transform business processes. She presented various case studies demonstrating how AI agents can optimize operations, improve decision-making, and create new business models.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Vinod Kumar Reddy Komma (MOURI Tech): AI-Powered SAP: Where to Begin and What to Expec:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Vinod's talk served as a guide for organizations new to integrating AI with SAP. He outlined the starting points, necessary prerequisites, and a realistic roadmap for adopting AI, setting expectations for the benefits and challenges of the journey.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mrinalini KR (ToggleNow): From Reactive to Predictive: AI-Driven SAP Auditing :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Mrinalini's talk addressed the evolution of auditing within the SAP environment. She demonstrated how AI can move auditing from a reactive, post-event process to a predictive one, using machine learning to identify anomalies and potential fraud risks in real-time.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sudhakar Nagadevara (MOURI Tech): Beyond Development: Business AI + Joule Driving the Intelligent Enterprise:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;This session shifted the focus from technical development to the business impact of AI. Sudhakar explored how the combination of business AI applications and SAP's AI copilot, Joule, enables users at all levels to become more productive and contributes to the overall intelligent enterprise strategy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subbu Sravan Mulumudi (ToggleNow): Gen AI Agents for SAP GRC ;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A specialized topic, this session highlighted the use of Generative AI agents to enhance SAP Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC). Subbu Sravan showcased how these agents can assist in creating and managing compliance rules, simulating risk scenarios, and improving audit readiness.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Finally event ended with the group photo.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/hyderabad-blog-posts/event-summary-sap-inside-track-hyderabad-2025-2nd-edition/ba-p/14192926"/>
    <published>2025-08-26T19:32:50.101000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/thumbs-up-for-the-new-kudos-received-progression-badges/ba-p/14193157</id>
    <title>Thumbs Up for the New “Kudos Received” Progression Badges!</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T14:10:03.041000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jerryjanda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/23</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The members have spoken. The relaunch of our progression badge sets is a hit!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We started last week by rolling out four new badges that reward members for providing solutions to questions. Response to &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bringing-back-badges-to-reward-q-amp-a-experts/ba-p/14182870" target="_blank"&gt;my announcement in What’s New&lt;/A&gt; has been extremely positive.&amp;nbsp; “Bringing Back Badges to Reward Q&amp;amp;A Experts!” has thousands of views and dozens of kudos. Good thing for me, because the next progression set celebrates members for the number of kudos they received – so all those recent kudos sure will come in handy toward my progress!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Whether you call them a thumbs-up (as they appear in the site design), a like (as they were known in the previous SAP Community platform), or a &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/help/faqpage/title/kudos_whatis" target="_blank"&gt;kudo&lt;/A&gt; (as they’re called in our current platform), you know that your content has found an audience when members take the time to click that lovely little icon to show their appreciation for your contribution. And we know you’re the kind of member who deserves special gamification rewards!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;As with the “solutions” badge set, this new set will have five badges in total, although the first badge has been available since the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/let-the-gamification-begin/ba-p/311892" target="_blank"&gt;launch of our latest community platform&lt;/A&gt; last year. We’ve added four more badges to this set, and you progress based on the number of kudos received. Per the image below, the second badge requires 50 kudos, the third requires 100, the fourth requires 200, and the fifth requires 500.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jerryjanda_0-1756224874937.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305214iA63F9E5C0AC5EBBE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jerryjanda_0-1756224874937.png" alt="jerryjanda_0-1756224874937.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We’ll launch these badges at some point tomorrow, Thursday, August 28, one at a time over a period of a few hours. Depending on how many kudos you’ve received, don’t be surprised if you get multiple notifications as the badge assignment occurs during this period. (If you’re still waiting by Friday, August 29, try logging out and in again. Any new badges should show up then.)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Once again, we’ll award these badges retroactively. Any numbers migrated from the previous platform to this one count toward your progress, and kudos for any content type (e.g., blog post, comment) count as well. So if you’ve been contributing popular content for years, you may have done enough to earn all five badges.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Wondering if you’re already part of the “500+ kudos received” club? You can check for yourself in your “My content” area. In my last post, I provided instructions about how to find your content, but here’s a reminder for your convenience.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;First, make sure you’ve logged in. Click on the person icon in the upper right of any community page. Select “My content” from the dropdown.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jerryjanda_1-1756224874940.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305215i313C24F68C9305DE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jerryjanda_1-1756224874940.png" alt="jerryjanda_1-1756224874940.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;“Kudos received” appears in the gray box at the very top. To help illustrate, I’m once again relying on the anonymous member who appeared in last week’s post, by sharing a screenshot from his “My content” page. (He didn’t complain then, so I hope he doesn’t mind now. Or maybe he just hasn’t noticed yet.)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jerryjanda_2-1756224874943.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305216i25E316D96E62E4C1/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jerryjanda_2-1756224874943.png" alt="jerryjanda_2-1756224874943.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Looks like this community veteran has received thousands of kudos over the years – more than enough to rack up all four badges tomorrow.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;How about you? If you’re expecting all four of the new badges tomorrow, then kudos to you! (Pun intended.) Whether you receive one, five, or any number in between, we appreciate your involvement in SAP Community. More importantly, our members appreciate your activity – evidenced by all their kudos for you!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you don’t get a badge (or get one or some but want them all), you’ll have plenty of opportunity in future to complete the set. All you need to do is continue to contribute quality content to SAP Community. If members like what you’re sharing, you can eventually accrue enough kudos to work your way through this new progression set.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Not the kind of member who likes to publish content? That’s OK. We have more progression badge sets coming in the weeks ahead, and not all of them depend on posting to SAP Community. There are lots of things members can do to create a positive community, and we’ll be awarding badges for those, too.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Look for updates here in the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bg-p/whats-new" target="_blank"&gt;What’s New&lt;/A&gt; section to learn how you can receive gamification rewards as we introduce new progression sets. One thing is certain: The more you do in SAP Community, the more badges you can earn. My advice if you’re a badge hunter? Stay active. Stay engaged. In short, stay an important part of SAP Community. We look forward to recognizing all members who make our community a better place!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/thumbs-up-for-the-new-kudos-received-progression-badges/ba-p/14193157"/>
    <published>2025-08-27T14:10:03.041000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-august-28th-2025/ba-p/14197445</id>
    <title>SAP Developer News August 28th, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T21:10:00.031000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eberenwaobiora</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1937986</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FoTgQpkc0Xwg%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DoTgQpkc0Xwg&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FoTgQpkc0Xwg%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="400" height="225" scrolling="no" title="SAP BTP ABAP, Webinar on Gardener, Community Updates &amp;amp; ABAP Test Cockpit | SAP Developer News" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1867962216"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;PODCAST&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/sap-developers/2025/08/28/sap-developer-news-august-28th-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://podcast.opensap.info/sap-developers/2025/08/28/sap-developer-news-august-28th-2025/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP ABAP Environment, release 2508&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Blog Post: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2508/ba-p/14182635" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-abap-environment-release-2508/ba-p/14182635&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Open Source Webinar on Gardener&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Open Source Webinars &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/ospo-webinar-series/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://events.sap.com/ospo-webinar-series/en_us/home.html&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Webinar registration &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/neutral-governance-for-gardener-project/en_us/registration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://events.sap.com/neutral-governance-for-gardener-project/en_us/registration.html&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Gardener project &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/gardener/gardener" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://github.com/gardener/gardener&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Garden Update - SAP Community&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Blog Post: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/garden-update-the-raised-bed-went-wild/td-p/14194744" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/coffee-corner-discussions/garden-update-the-raised-bed-went-wild/td-p/14194744&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Community Updates&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What's New: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bg-p/whats-new" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bg-p/whats-new&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feedback List: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-feedback-list/idb-p/Coffee-Corneridea-board" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-feedback-list/idb-p/Coffee-Corneridea-board&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Pilot on Widget Removal Frame: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/white-space-begone-new-pilot-removes-widgets-column-from-blog-posts/ba-p/14191534" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/white-space-begone-new-pilot-removes-widgets-column-from-blog-posts/ba-p/14191534&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Badges for Kudos: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/thumbs-up-for-the-new-kudos-received-progression-badges/ba-p/14193157" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/thumbs-up-for-the-new-kudos-received-progression-badges/ba-p/14193157&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Badges for Q&amp;amp;A: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bringing-back-badges-to-reward-q-amp-a-experts/ba-p/14182870" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bringing-back-badges-to-reward-q-amp-a-experts/ba-p/14182870&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Event Filtering and Dark Mode: &amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-features-dark-mode-beta-and-events-listings/ba-p/14191070" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-features-dark-mode-beta-and-events-listings/ba-p/14191070&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP test cockpit (ATC) recommendations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP test cockpit (ATC) recommendations for governance of clean core ABAP development: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/ba-p/14186130" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-test-cockpit-atc-recommendations-for-governance-of-clean-core-abap/ba-p/14186130&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1671448711"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;CHAPTER TITLES&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0:00 Intro&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;0:10 SAP BTP ABAP Environment, release 2508&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1:38 SAP Open Source Webinar on Gardener&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2:34 Garden Update - SAP Community&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3:44 SAP Community Updates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7:07 ABAP test cockpit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1474935206"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;TRANSCRIPTION&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" size="3" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[Intro]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is the SAP Developer News for August the 28th, 2025. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" size="3" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[Rich]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hey friends, Rich Hallman here. I hope everyone is doing well. I'm now fully rusted from the Latin American Code Jam Roadshow. We had a great time and I'm really looking forward to seeing my new friends again soon. But for now, I want to take a minute and let you all know about the latest SAP BTP ABAP environment release, 2508, which just dropped last week. Nora Klemp from ABAP Product Management has posted a blog post outlining all of the new ABAP awesomeness for all of us to explore. ABAP Development Tools got a few updates, including behavior definitions for CDS table entities, a debugger comparison tool for internal tables, as well as other cool stuff. CDS got a new hierarchy generation wizard, which derives potential hierarchy nodes and guides you through the creation process. Fiori got some updates as well, including multi-dimensional reporting and multi-report applications. There are many more updates around business events, integration, reuse services, and much, much more. So check out Nora's blog post today for more information. Hope everyone is doing well, and I'll see you next time, friends. Bye for now. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" size="3" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[DJ]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We wanted to just let you know about an upcoming SAP open source webinar on Gartner. Now, Gardner is SAP's open source solution for managing Kubernetes clusters at scale. And the project is now governed under the Neo-Nephos Foundation, which is part of the Linux Foundation Europe. Now, this is a move that really strengthens its long-term sustainability and aligns it with the EU's important projects of common European interest in the cloud infrastructure and services area. that's ipceicis the webinar is on the 24th of september open to all and we'll cover gardeners features see some recent developments and there'll also be some live demos the link to the webinar registration is in the description &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" size="3" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[Tom]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;hi i'm coming to you here from my home garden building on the segment from DJ on Gardener. By home garden, though, I seem to have a problem. I can't get Kubernetes clusters to grow. But in all seriousness, bridging between the segment on Gardener, the open source project, and home gardening, I wanted to point you to a blog post on the SAP community by Marion Weiss sharing his home garden. Now, this isn't the normal SAP developer news segment where we talk about the latest in SAP tech trends. But it's still important because part of our efforts to reinvigorate the SAP community is bring more personality back to the community. So it's great to see Marion sharing his home garden. And we hope to do more initiatives like this and support them where we connect with one another, not just on technical topics, but other things of interest in our lives. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" size="3" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[Josh]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Hey, everybody. Mr. Bluebeard, Josh Bentley. I am here as a community advocate to tell you we've been doing a lot of stuff in the community. So as you go through and look at the What's New section of the community, you can see updates and read about them. Jerry Janda even has put out the newsletter recently that he used to publish that actually tries to collate and make you aware of these things. So make sure you subscribe to that newsletter or check out this section of what's new on the SAP community. To that end, I think there's several updates that have been put in place from the actual feedback board that we launched. So if you go to the feedback list and you get involved in that discussion, this is where some of the changes are coming from. So please request more things be added here, dialogue about the things that are on that list. And that's how some of these improvements come to be. and then they make it into the what's new section a recent update that we did that's going to be a pilot until september 23rd is taking away the frames from the side of a blog post where we have a widget and we're going to remove that widget in that side frame and give you a little less white space and more uh content area to read your blog post so check that out see if you like it better let us know and in the blog post in Jerry you can see the compare and contrast of the two pictures that show you what it looks like with it and without it so that's one update that want to make you aware of another is giving more people badges we know you like getting badges in the sap community if you submit an answer or a post that gets a lot of thumbs up those kudos thumbs up likes they're going to give you badges now based on how many kudos that you get for your post so Jerry even references do you want to find out if you're a member of the 500 kudo club well there's a way to check that in the instructions that he post here in this blog post and also you could have a one, a 50, 100, 200, 500 likes, depending on how many people click that they like your post. So great gamification badges that are being awarded for that. And also we really want you to be active and give us good answers in the SAP community. And if you get a lot of accepted answers, we're going to recognize that. And so you're going to see that you are going to get retroactive likes and retroactive accepted answer badges assigned to your profile. So if You've got a lot of accepted answers and a lot of likes. You're going to get those badges assigned to your profile. So another thing, there's so much great information coming out about the community, is that we've actually gone through and we said, hey, it's hard to filter lists for events, and let's try to improve that. So we're adding geographic filtering, and we're also adding the ability to filter lists based on SAP managed tags and a few other features that people have asked for to be able to sort the events that are happening and make sure they don't miss something that they want to attend. so check that out as well as the final note in here which is about dark mode for those who want to actually switch and flip back and forth between dark mode and light mode we are turning on dark mode to the SAP community so if you'd like to compare and contrast that no pun intended but if you'd like to look at the contrasting look of dark mode check that out and you know what people sometimes call me papa smurf and i say that papa smurf had a white beard and blue skin so i'm dark mode papa smurf or maybe i'm light load papa smurf i'm not sure anyway check out dark mode let us know what you think there's lots of information lots of blog posts from Jerry I thank him so much for all the great writing he's been doing and putting out these updates and i hope that you enjoy your sap community it's here for you and we're listening thank you &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" size="3" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[Mamikee]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT face="Arial" color="black"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;if you want to keep your systems clean and future ready it's all about using the ABAP test cockpit or ATC as a governance tool to support the Clean Core approach. The blog post by Olga shares how ATC can help enforce Clean Core principles, things like catching modifications that shouldn't be there, plugging non-release APIs, and making sure your extensions are safe when it comes time to upgrade. Now you can try out the new ATC checks for Clean Core to reduce the number of findings in your classic ABAP development and focus your adaption efforts on real technical depth. If you're building in the ABAP cloud world and want to stay ahead of the curve, this is definitely worth a read. Check the description below for the full blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/sap-developer-news-august-28th-2025/ba-p/14197445"/>
    <published>2025-08-28T21:10:00.031000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-site-improvements-new-badges-and-hot-content/ba-p/14197399</id>
    <title>SAP Community Voice: Site Improvements, New Badges, and Hot Content</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:04:54.073000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jerryjanda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/23</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;If you’re a What’s New regular, you know we’ve been busy since our last newsletter edition on August 15. We’ve launched new progression badge sets (with more coming in September), made several site improvements, and announced a redesign pilot for blog posts.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you missed those updates, we summarize them for your convenience below. We also highlight popular blog posts from SAP and non-SAP members, introduce new groups and topic pages, and cover upcoming events.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Read on to learn more!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1738878695"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Featured Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1800530628"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1604017123"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP Extensibility Guide – Clean Core for SAP S/4HANA Cloud &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;SAP’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6638"&gt;@OlgaDolinskaja&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;gives a breakdown of new clean-core extensibility guidance and explains how the ABAP extensibility guide has been updated with guidelines that align with and support the clean-core level concept for the classification of custom extensions. You won’t want to miss this post and its lively thread!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/abap-extensibility-guide-clean-core-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-august-2025/ba-p/14175399" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1407503618"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1210990113"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introducing the New AI Adapter for SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148179"&gt;@Punith_Oswal&lt;/a&gt;, one of our &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/sap-champions/ba-p/13988156" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Champions&lt;/A&gt;, has a question for you: Have you ever wished that your iFlow could talk to ChatGPT? If you answered yes, you’ll want to take some time out of your day to read this post. And if you answered no, I still feel pretty positive you’ll enjoy this contribution.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/sap-ci-just-started-talking-to-ai-introducing-the-new-ai-adapter-for-sap/ba-p/14170748" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1014476608"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-817963103"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Series: SAP UX Q3/2025 Updates&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;A new series from SAP’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/149639"&gt;@ThomasReiss&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;provides an overview of user experience innovations in the cloud from the last six months, covering the whole portfolio, such as AI and Joule, SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition 2508, and SAP SuccessFactors, as well as detailing innovations in SAP’s UI technologies for building great UX.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-ux-q3-2025-update-part-1-ai-joule-sap-build-work-zone-sap-mobile-start/ba-p/14161847" target="_blank"&gt;Start with the first post, which contains links to the entire series&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-621449598"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model with Local App Previews &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I’m happy to see our &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/sap-champions/ba-p/13988156" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Champions&lt;/A&gt; have been so active with their blogging this month!&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/789"&gt;@MioYasutake&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;has written a short blog post detailing experiences while trying out virtual endpoints with SAP Cloud Application Programming Model with Node.js. The post covers findings while testing local previews.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/cap-with-local-app-previews-tips-for-smooth-development/ba-p/14182208" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-166770655"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Community News&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-228422588"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badges, Badges, and More Badges!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Long-time SAP Community members may remember the days when they could earn sets of badges for ongoing positive contributions. Well, we’ve brought these progression badges back! This week, we rolled out four new badges based on the number of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/thumbs-up-for-the-new-kudos-received-progression-badges/ba-p/14193157" target="_blank"&gt;kudos received&lt;/A&gt;. Last week we assigned badges for providing &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bringing-back-badges-to-reward-q-amp-a-experts/ba-p/14182870" target="_blank"&gt;solutions to questions&lt;/A&gt;. And there are more badges coming in the weeks ahead. With these badges, we’re once again recognizing active members and encouraging everyone to make our community a better place by participating more frequently. Make sure to subscribe to &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bg-p/whats-new" target="_blank"&gt;What’s New&lt;/A&gt; so you won’t miss more badge announcements next month!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--465808012"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Features: Dark Mode (Beta) and Events Listings&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;A beta version of dark mode is available for SAP Community, and our events listings now include additional filtering options that make it easier for you to find activities of interest to you. You can learn more about these two new features in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-features-dark-mode-beta-and-events-listings/ba-p/14191070" target="_blank"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt;. Experiment with dark mode/light mode to see which presentation works best for you, and try out the various new event filters to find educational and social get-togethers in your area that appeal to you.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--662321517"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Your Feedback Wanted for New Design Pilot &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We’re currently running a pilot to test a new layout for blog posts that removes widgets and white space from the right column – based on a &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-feedback-list/change-post-reading-view-to-one-column-layout/idi-p/14101534" target="_blank"&gt;feature request&lt;/A&gt; from members who asked us to improve the readability of these pages. You can learn more about this pilot in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/white-space-begone-new-pilot-removes-widgets-column-from-blog-posts/ba-p/14191534" target="_blank"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt;, and we’re inviting members to share their opinions in the comments there. The pilot concludes on Tuesday, September 23, so please leave your input there before then.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--858835022"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;New Location Groups Now Available&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We’ve launched (or renamed) three location groups. Our Brazilian members continue to expand our groups in the Americas – with the recent addition of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/joinville/gh-p/joinville" target="_blank"&gt;Joinville&lt;/A&gt;. Over in the Europe section, the former ’s-Hertogenbosch group has switched its name to &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/the-netherlands/gh-p/the-netherlands" target="_blank"&gt;The Netherlands&lt;/A&gt; to accommodate more members in that country. Elsewhere in Europe, we’ve introduced the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/d%C3%BCsseldorf-k%C3%B6ln/gh-p/duesseldorfkoeln" target="_blank"&gt;Düsseldorf-Köln&lt;/A&gt; group to bring together members from those cities. If you’re from one of these areas, you’ll want to join the corresponding group so you can connect with members close to you.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--468542513"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Upcoming Events&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1251862032"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Meet SAP TechEd Community Speaker Marla Alschweiki&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/82"&gt;@TammyPowlas&lt;/a&gt;, part of &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community-leaders-finder/sap-mentors/ba-p/13988201" target="_self"&gt;our SAP Mentors program&lt;/A&gt;, has referred to the upcoming SAP TechEd event as a family reunion, and so it’s no surprise she’s showing familial-type support for another SAP Mentor,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7391"&gt;@Marla-Schwaiki&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(whom we mentioned in the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-popular-posts-blog-it-forward-site-updates-and-more/ba-p/14181784" target="_blank"&gt;last edition of SAP Community Voice&lt;/A&gt;). In &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/meet-sap-teched-community-speaker-marla-alschweiki/ba-p/14182264" target="_blank"&gt;this post&lt;/A&gt;, Tammy explains why you should attend Marla’s community talk in Berlin. We love seeing members supporting members, so if you’re planning to attend SAP TechEd, please make sure to include Marla’s session in your schedule.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1448375537"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Find Meetup Events in Your Region&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bg-p/whats-new/label-name/sap%20community%20voice" target="_self"&gt;last two SAP Community Voice newsletters&lt;/A&gt;, we’ve focused on &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam/eb-p/codejam-events" target="_blank"&gt;SAP CodeJam events&lt;/A&gt;, but as explained earlier in this edition, our events listings have been expanded to include filters for finding a variety of local activities. Therefore, I’d like to use this edition to draw attention to meetups (also known as SAP Stammtisch events in Germany) in September. Next month, you can socialize with members in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/wien-events/sap-stammtisch-wien-04-09-2025/ev-p/14192248" target="_blank"&gt;Wien&lt;/A&gt; (Austria), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/gurugram-events/sap-tech-night-in-gurgaon/ev-p/14185685" target="_blank"&gt;Gurugram&lt;/A&gt; (India), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-community/sap-community-meetup-casablanca/ev-p/14192768" target="_blank"&gt;Casablanca&lt;/A&gt; (Morocco), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/dortmund-events/sap-stammtisch-sap-community-meetup-dortmund-10-09-2025/ev-p/14180075" target="_blank"&gt;Dortmund&lt;/A&gt; (Germany), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/cyprus-events/sap-meetup-cyprus-networking-amp-insights/ev-p/14195156" target="_blank"&gt;Cyprus&lt;/A&gt; (Greece), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/brussels-events/sap-inside-track-belgium-september-20th-2025/ev-p/14093107" target="_blank"&gt;Brussels&lt;/A&gt; (Belgium), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/warsaw-events/sap-inside-track-warsaw-2025/ev-p/14177160" target="_blank"&gt;Warsaw&lt;/A&gt; (Poland), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/lingen-events/golf-member-amp-friendsturnier/ev-p/14182945" target="_blank"&gt;Lingen&lt;/A&gt; (Germany), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/bamberg-events/sap-stammtisch-bamberg-09-2025/ev-p/14145466" target="_blank"&gt;Bamberg&lt;/A&gt; (Germany), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/hamburg-events/sap-inside-track-hamburg-2025-registration-open/ev-p/14164575" target="_blank"&gt;Hamburg&lt;/A&gt; (Germany), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/porto-events/sap-inside-track-porto-2025/ev-p/13899698" target="_blank"&gt;Porto&lt;/A&gt; (Portugal), &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/rio-grande-do-sul-events/eb-p/rio-grande-do-suloccasion-board" target="_blank"&gt;Rio Grande do Sul&lt;/A&gt; (Brazil), and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/luzern-events/sap-stammtisch-plus-luzern-30-september-2025/ev-p/14142453" target="_blank"&gt;Luzern&lt;/A&gt; (Switzerland). You can find a full list of events &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/events/ct-p/events" target="_self"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;. Make sure to register for an event near you!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-site-improvements-new-badges-and-hot-content/ba-p/14197399"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:04:54.073000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/asunci%C3%B3n-blog-posts/sap-inside-track-londrina-2025-paraguay-sigue-expandiendo-fronteras/ba-p/14199993</id>
    <title>SAP Inside Track Londrina 2025: Paraguay sigue expandiendo fronteras</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T23:10:34.638000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Zamichiei</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163835</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;¡Una nueva aventura de aprendizaje llegó a su fin! El pasado fin de semana tuvimos el privilegio de participar en el &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Inside Track Londrina 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, confirmando una vez más que la comunidad SAP brasileña tiene mucho que enseñarnos y que Paraguay está cada vez más presente en estos espacios de conocimiento.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Una agenda de lujo&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;El evento nos sorprendió con una selección de temas súper actuales y relevantes para el mercado:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP Descomplicado&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Thiago Toma y Adriano Toma nos mostraron cómo posicionarse estratégicamente en el mercado actual&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP QM Quality Management en S/4 HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Valdevair Bezerra compartió las innovaciones más importantes para la industria&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4 Public Cloud: Implementación ágil y diferenciada&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Jean Baena y Clariana Narcizo demostraron las ventajas de esta modalidad&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplificando BTP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Danilo Oliveira nos ayudó a entender mejor esta poderosa herramienta&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;APIs Funcionales&lt;/STRONG&gt; - Kessia Salazar explicó su aplicación práctica&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Seguridad en Aplicaciones/Servicios en BTP en tiempos de IA: historia y evolución -&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Por José Sequeira&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/285608"&gt;@jose_sequeira&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SIT_LON2025.jpg" style="width: 577px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306852iC7FD0AE1E31DA42F/image-dimensions/577x318/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="577" height="318" role="button" title="SIT_LON2025.jpg" alt="SIT_LON2025.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gratitud especial&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Un reconocimiento muy especial para &lt;STRONG&gt;Jean Tiago Baena&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1639390"&gt;@Jean_Chess_IT&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;por recibirnos con tanta calidez y hacer que nos sintiéramos como en casa. Su hospitalidad y la de todo el equipo organizador fueron excepcionales.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3008.JPG" style="width: 575px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306853i682E97123B3A9D8B/image-dimensions/575x431/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="575" height="431" role="button" title="IMG_3008.JPG" alt="IMG_3008.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;El factor humano: lo que realmente importa&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Más allá de las presentaciones técnicas, lo que más valor aporta en estos eventos son las conversaciones durante los breaks, esos momentos de networking genuino donde se forjan relaciones que trascienden lo profesional. La comunidad SAP brasileña nos sigue demostrando su generosidad para compartir conocimiento.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3014.JPG" style="width: 574px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306854i0AC9AEB44E8B67FA/image-dimensions/574x431/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="574" height="431" role="button" title="IMG_3014.JPG" alt="IMG_3014.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Paraguay en el mapa SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Cada participación en estos eventos SIT nos da más experiencia y motivación para seguir construyendo nuestra propia comunidad. Estamos absorbiendo las mejores prácticas y adaptándolas a nuestra realidad paraguaya.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="sit_lon2.jpg" style="width: 576px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306856iB1B7597595A66969/image-dimensions/576x569/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="576" height="569" role="button" title="sit_lon2.jpg" alt="sit_lon2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Rumbo a SIT Paraguay 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Con cada evento que visitamos, se fortalece más nuestra visión de realizar el primer &lt;STRONG&gt;SIT Paraguay&lt;/STRONG&gt; en noviembre. Queremos que nuestros colegas locales tengan acceso a este mismo nivel de contenido y networking, sin necesidad de viajar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;¡Gracias Londrina por recibirnos tan bien! Nos vemos pronto en el próximo SIT, y esperamos que pronto sea en Paraguay.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Si eres profesional SAP en Paraguay, ¡únete a nuestra comunidad! Síguenos en LinkedIn para estar al tanto de nuestros próximos encuentros. &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Community/pd-p/486157991894093153608181816584982" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1161-1"&gt;SAP Community&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Inside+Track/pd-p/72472722867005232775920452375500" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="263-1"&gt;SAP Inside Track&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/asunci%C3%B3n-blog-posts/sap-inside-track-londrina-2025-paraguay-sigue-expandiendo-fronteras/ba-p/14199993"/>
    <published>2025-08-29T23:10:34.638000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/introducing-the-devtoberfest-scavenger-hunt-coming-soon/ba-p/14183972</id>
    <title>Introducing the Devtoberfest Scavenger Hunt 🔨🪙 ... COMING SOON</title>
    <updated>2025-09-01T08:09:22.994000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dan_Wroblewski</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/72</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Devtoberfest Scavenger Hunt&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a chase around important SAP developer-related tools/sites, a challenge to construct a secret phrase, and a chance to win 1000s of points toward the Devtoberfest &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-grand-prize-trip-faq/ba-p/13781581" target="_self"&gt;grand prize&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;The hunt officially starts &lt;STRONG&gt;Sept. 25&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with the release of the first clue during that day's &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Developer News&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and you have until the end of Devtoberfest, &lt;STRONG&gt;Oct. 24&lt;/STRONG&gt;, to complete it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="2" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;To get all the clues make sure to &lt;STRONG&gt;SUBSCRIBE TO THIS POST!!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756392968630.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/306022iE4681CFA8F3E546E/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756392968630.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756392968630.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more about the&amp;nbsp; entire Devtoberfest event in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423549"&gt;@KevinR&lt;/a&gt;'s post&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-welcome/ba-p/14182817" target="_self"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 Welcome!&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="frame0004-Photoroom" style="width: 222px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303712iDEFAB5049DFD4CE1/image-dimensions/222x145/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="222" height="145" role="button" title="frame0004-Photoroom" alt="frame0004-Photoroom" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1737841707"&gt;What you need to find&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have hidden a special phrase, which you need to figure out using the clues from several missions, described in the next section. Along your journey you will do the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visit about 10 different locations related to SAP developers, mostly web sites that are designed to help you in your daily SAP development.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;At each location, you will discover a set of hexadecimal digits.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Concatenate the digits together (in the order of the missions) to get one, 37-digit hexadecimal number.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Multiply that hexadecimal number by another secret number, for which we will give a clue.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Take the resulting 38-digit hexadecimal product, and convert it into the secret phrase, using each pair of digits as values for ASCII characters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enter the phrase, exactly (case-sensitive, no extra spaces), into the &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-scavenger-hunt.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Scavenger Hunt tutorial&lt;/A&gt;.‌&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not until the SAP Developer News of Oct. 16 will you have all the pieces to be able to complete the phrase.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1670410921"&gt;Example Hunt&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;As an example of what you will have to do, here's a short sample hunt (just a warm-up, no points will be earned). Each mission is independent of the other.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;Mission&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;No. Digits&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;SAP Web Property&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Instructions&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="289px"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="289px"&gt;7&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="289px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#7C484A"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Developers YouTube Channel&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="289px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to our &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/@sapdevs/videos" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Developer YouTube channel&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/156020"&gt;@Rekha_DR&lt;/a&gt;'s video "&lt;A href="https://youtu.be/1vElTfSxGWM?si=VO5Asnf6paocjKru" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build Process Automation (Part 1): Build your very first process&lt;/A&gt;". Watch it and find the secret 7-digit hexadecimal number in one of the info cards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756706383435.png" style="width: 580px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307154i7E73F36E50823BD8/image-dimensions/580x300/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="580" height="300" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756706383435.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756706383435.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can also see the hex digits in the description.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1757324129515.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/311023iACADC3BF745F6659/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1757324129515.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1757324129515.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#7C484A"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Community&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Inside this blog post, use the Developer Tools on your browser to inspect the words "SAP Community" in the cell immediately to the left (in this this very table) and find the 6-digit RGB ASCII code for the color of the text.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756706325713.png" style="width: 565px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307152i1D8D7FDEE95C1713/image-dimensions/565x202/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="565" height="202" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756706325713.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756706325713.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;None (directly)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;Concatenate the 2 sets of hexadecimal digits (13 in all), in order, and multiply the resulting hexadecimal number by the number of original SAP founders (you can easily find the number on the &lt;A href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SAP" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Wikipedia page&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Convert the resulting hexadecimal number into a phrase, converting each pair of digits into a character using ASCII codes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Post a comment/picture&amp;nbsp;about the phrase -- but NOT the phrase itself&amp;nbsp; (like your experiences with or opinion about the phrase, or a picture of something belonging to you that reminds you of the phrase) -- you won't get any points, but it will be fun and you will be ready for the real scavenger hunt. If you have any trouble with this example hunt, post in the comments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;REMINDER:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The above is just an example of how the real scavenger hunt will work. The real scavenger hunt instructions will be described in the rest of this blog post, as clues become available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1344814697"&gt;The (real) hunt&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below are the instructions for finding the hexadecimal digits for the actual scavenger hunt. We will release clues as follows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the SAP Developer News of &lt;STRONG&gt;Sept. 25&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Oct. 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Oct. 9&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Oct. 16&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In this blog &lt;STRONG&gt;each Monday during the first 3 weeks of Devtoberfest&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;To be notified when a new clue is released,&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;SUBSCRIBE TO THIS POST!!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rule.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295882i3E2967613A5D1256/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rule.png" alt="rule.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;‌ &lt;SPAN&gt;When you find the secret phase, just enter it into this &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-scavenger-hunt.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest tutorial&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756261779255.png" style="width: 1009px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305319iF03452ECEE94B400/image-dimensions/1009x185/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="1009" height="185" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756261779255.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_0-1756261779255.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To guide you, we have created a &lt;A href="http://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-scavenger-hunt-checking.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;second tutorial&lt;/A&gt; -- you do not have to use it, nor do you get any points from it. But you can enter the 1 to 6 digits from each mission to check if you received the correct digits for that mission.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756261827758.png" style="width: 984px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/305320i6D6063DA1D7F3A96/image-dimensions/984x185/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="984" height="185" role="button" title="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756261827758.png" alt="Dan_Wroblewski_1-1756261827758.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rule.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/295882i3E2967613A5D1256/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rule.png" alt="rule.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1406466630"&gt;Here are your missions&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;Mission&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;No. Digits&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;SAP Web Property&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Instructions&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Developer News&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6RpkC85SLQAVBSQXN9522_1jNvPavBgg" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Developer News&lt;/A&gt; comes out each Thursday with the latest about ABAP, CAP, BTP, SAP Build, UI5, Fiori, AI, and all your favorite SAP developer topics. All delivered by some of your favorite Developer Advocates, like DJ, Shilpa Shankar, Thomas Jung, Antonio Maradiaga, Nora von Thenen and the rest of the gang.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Most episodes about 5 minutes. Also available as a &lt;A href="https://podcast.opensap.info/sap-developers/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Podcast&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Watch the Developer News of Sept. 25&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Sept. 29&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;3&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Sept. 29&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Watch the Developer News of Oct. 2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;5&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;4&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Oct. 6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Oct. 6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;7&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Watch the Developer News of Oct. 9&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;8&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;6&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Oct. 13&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;9&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;To be released Oct. 13&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;10&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="10%" height="30px"&gt;None (directly)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="30%" height="30px"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="50%" height="30px"&gt;Watch the Developer News of Oct. 16&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Good luck!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":grinning_cat_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😸&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/introducing-the-devtoberfest-scavenger-hunt-coming-soon/ba-p/14183972"/>
    <published>2025-09-01T08:09:22.994000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kolkata-blog-posts/sap-inside-track-kolkata-2025-a-technical-consultant-s-journey-through/ba-p/14182125</id>
    <title>SAP Inside Track Kolkata 2025: A Technical Consultant's Journey Through Innovation, AI Use cases</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T07:52:14.350000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>VictorB</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1419033</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;As I sit down to consider the amazing experience of SAP Inside Track Kolkata 2025, which was conducted on August 2nd at the grand St. Xavier's University in New Town, I'm blessed to have such a huge sense of appreciation for the chance to have been included in such a motivating community event. Not only did I come as an avid SAP technical consultant but also as a coordinating volunteer for Track 2, and this provided me with an unrivalled insight into both the organizational expertise and technical expertise that made this event so exceptional.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Perfect Setting for Innovation&lt;BR /&gt;St. Xavier's University Kolkata offered the perfect setting for our community meet.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The commitment of the university to excellence was reflected in each and every aspect, from the state-of-the-art conference rooms to the stable network infrastructure underpinning our live demos and interactive sessions. Having been to many technical conferences, I can safely say that the venue contributed significantly to delivering the quality experience that SAP Inside Track Kolkata 2025 provided.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Track 2: Leading the Charge in Enterprise Transformation&lt;BR /&gt;Since I was the coordinating volunteer for Track 2, I had the privilege of collaborating very closely with some of the greatest minds in the SAP universe. Our track covered intelligent enterprise transformation and had the most innovative topics that are revolutionizing the way companies do business today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;RISE with SAP: Charting the Path to Intelligence&lt;BR /&gt;The day started with Debashis Majumder's engaging session on "RISE with SAP: Your Path to the Intelligent Enterprise". This session was all the more insightful because it highlighted how RISE with SAP is an end-to-end transformation package that brings together SAP S/4HANA Cloud, the SAP Business Technology Platform, and managed services to deliver an end-to-end digital transformation solution.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What I was most impressed by in this session was the way that RISE with SAP covers the entire range of enterprise requirements - from managed services and cloud infrastructure to business transformation as a service, as well as emerging technologies such as artificial intelligence, machine learning, and robotic process automation. As a technical consultant, I appreciated the conversation regarding the subscription model and the cost-effectiveness. This is especially important for the clients that I deal with who are looking at cloud migration strategies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule Studio: Democratization of AI Agent Development&lt;BR /&gt;Koushik Goon's "What is Joule Studio and how it works?" presentation was completely captivating. Joule Studio, under SAP Build, is a game-changer in how we work with AI-powered business automation. The ability to design and deploy custom Joule agents and skills with easy-to-use drag-and-drop simplicity presents huge opportunities for companies to make AI solutions customized to their requirements.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The showcase of how developers can create AI agents that solve goal-oriented, complex business situations using dynamic planning and reasoning was impressive. The SAP and third-party application integration ensures the AI agents integrate well across various technology landscapes, a key requirement in the heterogeneous environments most companies use today.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business AI and S/4HANA Integration&lt;BR /&gt;Sangeeta Majumder's presentation on "Business AI Use Cases with S/4HANA and SAP's AI Suite" offered real-world examples of how artificial intelligence is being integrated into central business processes. The session touched on real-world applications across business functions, from procurement optimization to financial reporting, illustrating quantifiable business value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;IBM's GenAI Assets and Platform Accelerators&lt;BR /&gt;The shared session between Aditi Chatterjee and Avijit Dhar on "Overview of IBM's Latest GenAI Assets and Process Accelerators on the IBM-SAP Platform" brought out the strategic significance of partner ecosystems in providing end-to-end AI solutions. Their observations about how IBM's generative AI assets are bundled with SAP platforms for speeding up business processes were especially insightful to understanding the wider AI picture beyond SAP's native capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Intelligent Invoicing Revolution&lt;BR /&gt;Arit Basu's talk on "Intelligent Invoicing using SAP Business Network" highlighted the real-world application of AI to daily business practices. The Intelligent Invoice Conversion functionality, leveraging Document Information Extraction (DOX) technology, to convert PDF and image-based invoice files into structured SAP Business Network invoices automatically, is a major step in accounts payable automation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I was amazed by the demonstration of how machine learning algorithms automatically extract and map invoice information, with an easy-to-use interface for suppliers to create annotation rules for complicated invoice data. This product solves a genuine pain point that most of my customers experience in their procure-to-pay processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next-Generation Field Mobility&lt;BR /&gt;The last Track 2 session, "Next-Gen Field Mobility: What's New in SAP Service and Asset Manager 2505" by Abhishek Chatterjee, discussed the transformation of mobile enterprise apps. The emphasis on growing field service functions with enhanced mobility solutions was a big hit with many of the participants who have asset-heavy businesses.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Networking: The Heart of Community Building&lt;BR /&gt;One of the greatest assets of SAP Inside Track Kolkata 2025 was the awesome networking opportunity it offered. As noted in numerous community forums, networking for SAP technical consultants is not merely a matter of swapping business cards - it's about creating enduring professional relationships that enable knowledge sharing, career growth, and access to out-of-the-way opportunities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Throughout the event, I engaged in substantive discussions with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other ABAP colleagues who exchanged innovative coding methods and debugging approaches&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;S/4HANA transformation project peers working on similar functional consulting projects&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Industry specialists who shared their vision on upcoming trends and best practices&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Community leaders leading different SAP user groups in India&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The afternoon fireside chat with community contributors was most informative, with participants from AWS User Group Kolkata, Kolkata WordPress Community, Databricks Community India, and SAP Community Kolkata. This inter-community collaboration session, led by Dipanwita Dutta, highlighted the need to bridge different technology communities to promote innovation and learning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Keynote Insights and Industry Perspectives&lt;BR /&gt;The keynote sessions on the first day of the event established a strong tone for the whole event. SAP Community Senior Director Josh "Bluebeard" Bentley's speech highlighted the importance of community-based learning and collaboration in the SAP community. His perspectives on how the international SAP community keeps adapting and evolving with emerging technologies were inspiring and thought-provoking.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Srini Gottimukkula's keynote provided valuable industry perspectives on the current state and future direction of SAP technologies. The emphasis on intelligent enterprises and the role of AI-driven transformation aligned perfectly with the themes explored throughout our track sessions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The welcome address by Reverend Dr. John Felix Raj, the Honourable Vice Chancellor of St. Xavier's University, beautifully captured the spirit of academic excellence and community collaboration that characterized the entire event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Panel Discussions: Multiple Insights on Digital Transformation&lt;BR /&gt;The two panel sessions offered multiple perspectives on hot issues impacting the SAP community:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Panel Session 1 included industry experts such as Pankaj Lal, Prasun Dutta, Debashis Majumdar, Sarmistha Shanyal, and Tilak Kumar Dhar, moderated by Monimoy Kundu. The topics discussed ranged from practical SAP implementation strategy tips to lessons learned from actual projects.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Panel Session 2 represented a coming together of academic and industry viewpoints with speakers consisting of Prof. Amlan Chakrabarti, Dr. Indranil Mitra, Manoj Mishra, Dr. Saptarsi Goswami, Sabyasachi Biswas, and Srini Gottimukkula, moderated by Amitava Nag. The session offered useful insights into the convergence of academic research and industry usage in the SAP space.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Technical Deep Dives Across Multiple Tracks&lt;BR /&gt;Though I was mainly busy coordinating Track 2, I got a chance to visit sessions on other tracks during the break times:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Track 1 had extensive sessions on supply chain transformation using AI-driven intelligence, next-gen warehouse operations, and cloud ALM roadshow presentations. The focus on real-world applications and live demos made these sessions very useful.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Track 3 explored in-depth generative AI embedding within business strategy, SAP BTP highlights from the view of a Basis consultant, and best practices for SAP S/4HANA transformation. The session on "Leveraging SAP Conversational &amp;amp; Generative AI: Bengali Code Bot" was also very innovative and highlighted how AI can be localized for local needs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Track 4 was data engineering and analytics, with sessions on Databricks, AWS and SAP integration, and foundation for Gen AI with SAP. These sessions gave a proper understanding of the overall ecosystem of technologies that go along with SAP solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Key Takeaways for Technical Consultants&lt;BR /&gt;Being a SAP technical consultant, some key learnings that will have a direct effect on my work are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. AI Integration is Accelerating&lt;BR /&gt;The prolonged emphasis on Joule, AI agents, and intelligent automation in several sessions undoubtedly demonstrates that the integration of AI is no longer a consideration for the future - it's an existing imperative. Technical consultants must acquire skills in AI-powered SAP solutions to stay relevant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Cloud-First Mindset is Mandatory&lt;BR /&gt;RISE with SAP and the other cloud-focused sessions validated that the sector has moved irrevocably towards cloud-first approaches. Cloud deployment models, migration approaches, and hybrid architectures are essential knowledge areas for technical consultants.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Low-Code/No-Code Platforms are Mainstream&lt;BR /&gt;The exhibition of Joule Studio's drag-and-drop feature and equivalent platforms in other sessions demonstrated that low-code development is going mainstream. Technical consultants must adopt these platforms alongside core development expertise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;4. Community Involvement Spur Learning&lt;BR /&gt;The networking and information exchange that were experienced during the event proved the tremendous benefit of an engaged community. Bi-weekly exposure to the SAP Community Network, local user communities, and events such as SAP Inside Track is crucial for career development.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Organizational Excellence Behind the Scenes&lt;BR /&gt;As a coordinating volunteer, I developed profound respect for the colossal effort that went into making this event happen. The SAP Inside Track Kolkata team showcased outstanding professionalism in handling:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multi-track coordination with smooth transitions among sessions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The success of the event is a testament to the tireless organizers and volunteers who spent hundreds of hours on planning and execution. The SAP Community Network principles of knowledge sharing, collaboration, and support were manifested in every step of the event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking Forward: The Future of SAP Community Events&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Inside Track Kolkata 2025 has established a new standard for community events in the region. The confluence of leading-edge technical content, industry expert views, hands-on demonstrations, and substantive networking opportunities provided an experience that will leave its mark on all participants.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The event proved that the Kolkata SAP community is not only consuming knowledge from the world but actively taking part in the worldwide SAP universe. The variety of speakers, the technical depth of conversations, and the quality of questions asked by participants reflected the maturity and professionalism of the local SAP community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Conclusion: A Day That Transformed Perspectives&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Inside Track Kolkata 2025 was not just a conference - it was a celebration of learning, innovation, and community. Having worked in the SAP ecosystem for a few years now, I departed from the event rejuvenated with the potential that awaits us.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The technical learnings from sessions on AI, cloud transition, and intelligent automation will impact my client work directly. The working relationships forged during the day are already starting to bear collaborative opportunities. Above all, the feeling of community and commonality that pervaded the event was the reminder of why I decided to work in the SAP ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To fellow SAP technical consultants who might be thinking of attending future SAP Inside Track events, I do not say enough good things about them. They offer a unique chance to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get up to date on the latest SAP technologies and industry trends&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Meet peers, experts, and potential collaborators&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Give back to the community through knowledge sharing and mentoring&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Boost your professional image and career opportunities&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get hands-on experience with innovative solutions and best practices&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The success of the SAP community is based on its collaborative nature and shared success. Examples such as SAP Inside Track Kolkata 2025 encapsulate these principles to perfection, generating environments where ideas are exchanged freely, bonds are forged, and innovation takes root.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I'm already counting down to SAP Inside Track Kolkata 2026 and the chance to extend this journey of discovery, sharing, and community building. Until that time, I invite all members of the SAP community to remain connected, keep up the learning, and keep adding to that shared knowledge that makes our ecosystem so rich and valuable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAPInsideTrack #SAPCommunity #KolkataSAP #DigitalTransformation #RISEwithSAP #JouleStudio #SAPTechnicalnsultant #AIInBusiness #CloudTransformation&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Heartfelt appreciation to the dream team who made every session, every connection, and every moment absolutely count!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/127440"&gt;@DataTherapist&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1407690"&gt;@Arka&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/748518"&gt;@SohamBhKoL&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2219300"&gt;@Pritam991&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2232648"&gt;@Kuntal_das&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2232709"&gt;@DEBADRITA_SAP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;@tunir_24&amp;nbsp;@titashshil&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1456324"&gt;@Sayontan_Das&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;@Udity1211&amp;nbsp;@Diya_Dasupta&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1460364"&gt;@Raya_16&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2232860"&gt;@ShreyanSAPO&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2065584"&gt;@adrijaMukherjee&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1434061"&gt;@SunnyMondal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/846198"&gt;@soumajit_paul&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1437544"&gt;@GDas&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;@Pritam_Paulm8&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2053553"&gt;@AmittDubey&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1418362"&gt;@Kamallica&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1422118"&gt;@Rahul_Agarwal1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;@Rajdeep_Dutta43&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2237884"&gt;@Anurag_Dey98&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;@chandika_sarkar&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you went to SAP Inside Track Kolkata 2025 or any other SAP community event, I'd be happy to know your thoughts and opinions in the comments section below. Let's keep the dialogue going and community spirit burning!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="SAP INSIDE TRACK KOLKATA 2025" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/victorbanik840_sapinsidetrackkolkata2025-sapcommunity-sitkol2025-activity-7357807737742745600-QLe3?utm_source=social_share_send&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop_web&amp;amp;rcm=ACoAACFdeaUBMVjOfTDGu1Yjp9KC4SLEylWhS0o" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Linkdin Post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1754238042934.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301624i40D0548127030B00/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="1754238042934.jpg" alt="1754238042934.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1754238042206.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301625iC83FFC9E0996BFD5/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="1754238042206.jpg" alt="1754238042206.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1754238063638.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301626iAF0219CEEAF0CE70/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="1754238063638.jpg" alt="1754238063638.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;  &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="1754238061213.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301627i9C7A8CEC5E6CAC5C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="1754238061213.jpg" alt="1754238061213.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-16 at 6.08.40 PM.jpeg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/301628iD869E1A596CB5E9F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-16 at 6.08.40 PM.jpeg" alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-16 at 6.08.40 PM.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kolkata-blog-posts/sap-inside-track-kolkata-2025-a-technical-consultant-s-journey-through/ba-p/14182125"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T07:52:14.350000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-roadshow-latam-2025-recap/ba-p/14204436</id>
    <title>SAP CodeJam Roadshow LATAM 2025 - recap</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T13:37:24.328000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ajmaradiaga</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/107</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;And that's a wrap..... Together with &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148"&gt;@josh_bentley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/97"&gt;@RichHeilman&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/139"&gt;@thomas_jung&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/43989"&gt;@SavioMarques&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39068"&gt;@jessicademarchi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1795547"&gt;@caiograbalos&lt;/a&gt;, we did a few SAP CodeJams in Latin America - four different cities (São Paulo &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":brazil:"&gt;🇧🇷&lt;/span&gt;, Lima &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":peru:"&gt;🇵🇪&lt;/span&gt;, Mexico City&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":mexico:"&gt;🇲🇽&lt;/span&gt; and Bogota &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":colombia:"&gt;🇨🇴&lt;/span&gt;), various meetups and even joined the SAP Inside Track in São Paulo. As part of the roadshow, we run the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-topics/ba-p/221407#codejam2" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Getting started with Generative AI Hub on SAP AI Core&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-topics/ba-p/221407#codejam8" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ABAP Cloud &amp;amp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;ABAP RESTful Application Programming Model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;CodeJams. It is always great to meet community members where they are and learn about the challenges they face in the different project and how SAP products enable them to tackle these.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="roadshow-lac-2025.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307787iD2C93AFE82AA95DA/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="roadshow-lac-2025.jpg" alt="roadshow-lac-2025.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the 2nd roadshow we've done in the region, and what a great experience it was. It was great to meet in person many SAP community members that I've interacted with online in the past. As well as seeing some familiar faces in the locations that we visited in the 1st LATAM roadshow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1888190275"&gt;São Paulo &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":brazil:"&gt;🇧🇷&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148"&gt;@josh_bentley&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;already share a recap of the events in Brazil and the first event in Peru.... so go ahead and check out all the photos he is sharing in the blog post -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/sap-codejam-roadshow-latam-2025-the-first-half-recap-being-present-is-about/td-p/14173987" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-discussions/sap-codejam-roadshow-latam-2025-the-first-half-recap-being-present-is-about/td-p/14173987&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1691676770"&gt;Lima &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":peru:"&gt;🇵🇪&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the first time we've done CodeJams in Lima, hosted at the SAP office. It was great to meet the local community and lovely to enjoy some of the local cuisine and coffee :-). Thanks to everyone who joined, even though there was a holiday right in the middle of the week #PeruEsClave.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5356.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307804i0BDB529A3DC6B503/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5356.jpg" alt="IMG_5356.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_5358.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307806i88B78C44C36C0861/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5358.jpg" alt="IMG_5358.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5372.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307807i61F8A56D66AE1003/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5372.jpg" alt="IMG_5372.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5368.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307809i538AC25E05E8A633/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5368.jpg" alt="IMG_5368.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="FullSizeRender.jpeg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307810i56064F53103CCC18/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="FullSizeRender.jpeg" alt="FullSizeRender.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5382.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307811iE75E6EFD6F4709D3/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5382.jpg" alt="IMG_5382.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1495163265"&gt;Mexico City &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":mexico:"&gt;🇲🇽&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Two amazing events hosted at the IBM offices in Mexico City. I got the opportunity to meet SAP Champions -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17466"&gt;@Sandra_Solis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/797"&gt;@MariettaLopez&lt;/a&gt;, whom I've interacted with in the past but never before met in person.&amp;nbsp;Also, Devtoberfest winners -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17466"&gt;@Sandra_Solis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135413"&gt;@eamarce23&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to IBM for hosting, looking forward to more events in Mexico :-). The day after the CodeJams we also had the opportunity to visit the &lt;A href="https://mna.inah.gob.mx/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Museo Nacional de Antropologia&lt;/A&gt; time and get some time to learn about the different Mexican indigenous cultures.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1298649760"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5392.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307813i6AFACA23A7C5563D/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5392.jpg" alt="IMG_5392.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1102136255"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5396.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307814i7A609B4977E19B50/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5396.jpg" alt="IMG_5396.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-905622750"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5404.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307815iA55A227C482762BD/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5404.jpg" alt="IMG_5404.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-709109245"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_2465.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307834iF171A9F0DA45FFAB/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_2465.jpg" alt="IMG_2465.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-512595740"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-316082235"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5418.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307835i465886421F11A737/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5418.jpg" alt="IMG_5418.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-119568730"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5421.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307836i304498586D33AC04/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5421.jpg" alt="IMG_5421.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--152176144"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5429.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307816iAF5D5F6A66821F9A/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5429.jpg" alt="IMG_5429.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--348689649"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5443.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307817i789D495B01A5807A/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5443.jpg" alt="IMG_5443.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5437.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307844i22755991B5C21CD9/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5437.jpg" alt="IMG_5437.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--545203154"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5483.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307818iA9131F8B0A0D5D97/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5483.jpg" alt="IMG_5483.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--741716659"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5481.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307819i1B956CF92B51607A/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5481.jpg" alt="IMG_5481.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--938230164"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5460.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307820iDBB6D50F37B75274/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5460.jpg" alt="IMG_5460.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1134743669"&gt;Bogota &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":colombia:"&gt;🇨🇴&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Last city part of the 2nd LATAM CodeJam roadshow. The day before the events, there was some time to explore the city a bit and visit the &lt;A href="https://www.banrepcultural.org/bogota/museo-botero/bienvenidos" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Museo Botero&lt;/A&gt;, as well as the &lt;A href="https://www.banrepcultural.org/bogota/casa-de-moneda" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Casa de Moneda&lt;/A&gt;. The events took place @ the SAP office in Bogota. It was great to catch up with various previous CodeJam attendees, as well as meet some more community members. Special mention to the large crew who joined the CodeJams from Globant (Bogota and Cali).... next time we will organise the event at the Globant office haha&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5511.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307823i77875131A6421C10/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5511.jpg" alt="IMG_5511.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5505.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307825i11DD6698E12141DB/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5505.jpg" alt="IMG_5505.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5490.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307827i80F2192015092FBE/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5490.jpg" alt="IMG_5490.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5537.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307828i821E4465370B0282/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5537.jpg" alt="IMG_5537.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5525.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307829i3141F9883C56EF57/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5525.jpg" alt="IMG_5525.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="33.333333333333336%"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5543.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307830i8DF0CA45E09141F2/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5543.jpg" alt="IMG_5543.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5539.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307832iE296CC7C5B4DFE97/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5539.jpg" alt="IMG_5539.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5518.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307838iE48A6E1344D7143C/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5518.jpg" alt="IMG_5518.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="IMG_5548.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307833i3318246CA1A51182/image-size/small/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="IMG_5548.jpg" alt="IMG_5548.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Personally, I always feel energised after connecting with the large Latin American SAP community and I know that it is also a great experience for the other advocates that have joined the roadshows. I'm already looking forward to next year and doing more CodeJams in the region.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-codejam-blog-posts/sap-codejam-roadshow-latam-2025-recap/ba-p/14204436"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T13:37:24.328000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/trends-in-b2b-commerce-webcast/ba-p/14204626</id>
    <title>Trends in B2B Commerce Webcast</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T15:18:34.050000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Привіт, Community!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Зовсім скоро відбудеться вебкаст про майбутнє B2B-комерції. Подія базується на свіжому дослідженні &lt;EM&gt;2025 State of B2B eCommerce Report&lt;/EM&gt; від Master B2B.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;У вівторок, &lt;STRONG&gt;9 вересня 2025 року о 13.00&lt;/STRONG&gt;, запрошуємо на онлайн-сесію &lt;STRONG&gt;«Тренди B2B-комерції 2025: як подолати бар’єри на шляху до розвитку»&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Її проведе Меганн Йорк, Global Head of Product Marketing в SAP Commerce Cloud, а спеціальним гостем стане наш клієнт — компанія &lt;STRONG&gt;Arauco&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Поговоримо про виклики, з якими стикається B2B-комерція сьогодні: організаційну складність, потребу в цифровому лідерстві та інші фактори, що часто гальмують трансформацію. Ми покажемо, як бізнеси успішно поєднують технології, таланти та партнерство, щоб рухатися вперед. Ви отримаєте конкретні ідеї та стратегії, які допоможуть керувати складними процесами й ефективно використовувати цифрові інструменти для досягнення цілей.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Реєструйтеся за &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=5038585&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=6E70FBACADF98CBDC33D84FA4C0873A6&amp;amp;groupId=6276799&amp;amp;partnerref=getsocial&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;посиланням.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/trends-in-b2b-commerce-webcast/ba-p/14204626"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T15:18:34.050000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/give-a-kudo-get-a-badge/ba-p/14204770</id>
    <title>Give a Kudo, Get a Badge</title>
    <updated>2025-09-02T16:11:21.685000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jerryjanda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/23</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Last week, we began to assign badges based on the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/thumbs-up-for-the-new-kudos-received-progression-badges/ba-p/14193157" target="_blank"&gt;number of kudos a member received&lt;/A&gt;. But what about the members who kindly grant kudos? Don’t they deserve some recognition, too?&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We think so, and that’s why, starting tomorrow (Wednesday, September 3), we’re launching our latest progression set – based on &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/help/faqpage/title/kudos_whatis" target="_blank"&gt;kudos&lt;/A&gt; given.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jerryjanda_0-1756820739616.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307996iFE90C6D10DF52B3D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jerryjanda_0-1756820739616.png" alt="jerryjanda_0-1756820739616.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;As with the other badges that we recently rolled out, this set contains five badges, the first of which has been &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/let-the-gamification-begin/ba-p/311892" target="_blank"&gt;available since the launch&lt;/A&gt; of our current platform last year. The rest are new. You make your way through the set as your activity meets the associated criteria. With these badges, you’ll acquire the second one after giving 30 kudos, the third after 75, the fourth after 200, and the fifth and final after 500.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;That’s a whole lot of kudos clicked!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Badges will start appearing in people’s “My content” area tomorrow – and we’ll require a few hours to assign them all. Since we’ll once again award them retroactively, you can already anticipate what you’ll attain (if anything) by looking at your accrued activity. How? Here’s a refresher.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;After logging in, select “My content” from the dropdown in the upper right.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jerryjanda_1-1756820739620.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307997iA2D1666DB7642F95/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jerryjanda_1-1756820739620.png" alt="jerryjanda_1-1756820739620.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Once you’ve navigated to your “My content” page, look for the gray box at the top. This area contains several stats, including “Kudos given.” As an example, I’m once again turning to my anonymous friend (who was the source of my screenshots for previous posts).&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jerryjanda_2-1756820739623.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/307998i22E7E31FC76C2CA1/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="jerryjanda_2-1756820739623.png" alt="jerryjanda_2-1756820739623.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;With more than 1,700 kudos given, he’ll complete the set during tomorrow’s rollout (having surpassed the threshold for all of the new badges…and then some!).&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;That’s some serious gold-medal kudo judo!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Now if you were so inclined, you could go give hundreds of kudos right now (although your finger might get sore from clicking all those thumbs), ensuring that you also complete the set tomorrow. But your kudos carry way more weight when you dole them out deservingly. Why give them away randomly when you can make another member’s day by delivering a kudo that sincerely indicates that you read and appreciated his or her content?&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;As someone who writes frequently for SAP Community, I can attest to the warm and fuzzy feeling that comes from a kudo. Clicking that thumb is such a simple act, yet its impact is undeniable for the recipient. It sends the message: “I like what you did. Thank you.” For that reason, I’m glad to see that our community’s cool kudo givers can earn rewards for their generosity.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you expect to gain one or more “kudos given” badges tomorrow, then let me give you a big thumbs up in advance. Also, as a reminder: If you don’t see your badges by Thursday, September 4, please log out and in again. And if you haven’t racked up the necessary numbers yet for the full set, don’t worry. You can always win the badges later by reading and reacting to contributions throughout the community. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In conclusion: Keep the thumbing coming for the content that you like, and make sure to check back next week. We plan to unveil more progression badge sets in September, and we’ll announce them weekly right here in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bg-p/whats-new" target="_blank"&gt;What’s New&lt;/A&gt;. In the meantime, remain an active, positive member, and you may find yourself surprised with even more badges this month.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/give-a-kudo-get-a-badge/ba-p/14204770"/>
    <published>2025-09-02T16:11:21.685000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/september-online-seminars/ba-p/14208772</id>
    <title>September Online Seminars</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T14:21:59.205000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759229723"&gt;Головне цього місяця&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;На вас чекає серія онлайн-подій від &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, присвячених трансформації бізнесу, ліцензуванню, впровадженню штучного інтелекту та інновацій у хмарних рішеннях.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1691798937"&gt;9 вересня 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/eep.transformation.en_us.0b4395ff-d31f-44d0-9d91-da3526056f04.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Вебкаст з трансформації: License Pathfinder for RISE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;15:00–16:00&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_gdk5OSNSSj-Abg5LlSFisQ#/registration" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Вебкаст з підтримки: SAP for Me Release Updates Q3 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;16:00–17:00&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1495285432"&gt;11 вересня 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/8bd5dfb7-f6b4-442e-a888-dc80692ca917@e554b651-513a-459c-a4ae-6402f49ad018" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Онлайн-сесія з ліцензій SAP: License Pathfinder for RISE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;11:00–11:45&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Подія RISE with SAP: Customer Onboarding &amp;amp; Launch Activities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;09:00–09:45&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7rhEUQRUdGY" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;ранкова сесія&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;та&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;15:00–15:45 &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HnxHcx7nf_w" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;денна сесія&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1298771927"&gt;16 вересня 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/eep.transformation.en_us.0b4395ff-d31f-44d0-9d91-da3526056f04.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Вебкаст з трансформації: Adoption Insights Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;15:00–16:00&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/F6n0rOo8IYc" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Вебкаст на SAP BTP: AI для трансформації бізнес-процесів&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;16:00–17:00&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1102258422"&gt;17 вересня 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RISE with SAP: Методологія трансформації&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;09:00–09:45&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/3BdjgiMof3k?list=PLpQebylHrdh7xvVEsvTROKRsrutDevcEu&amp;amp;index=4" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;ранкова сесія&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;та&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;15:00–15:45 &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/Lj68RmbfHCw?list=PLpQebylHrdh7xvVEsvTROKRsrutDevcEu&amp;amp;index=4" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;денна сесія&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_q4OQBJGuQ1C6ousoZYFnug" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Service &amp;amp; Support: Solution Search &amp;amp; Self Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;12:30–13:30&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-905744917"&gt;18 вересня 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/5030125/78B9CF3DBB5E84F268325833385AEDBA/6263433?partnerref=usergroups" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Вебкаст SAP Business AI: Модернізація ERP та даних для розкриття потенціалу AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;12:00–12:45&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-709231412"&gt;19 вересня 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/60266d33-513c-443d-93ab-27e71e12fafa@e554b651-513a-459c-a4ae-6402f49ad018" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Онлайн-сесія з ліцензій SAP: SAM4U&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;11:00–11:45&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-512717907"&gt;23 вересня 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/-JLjFXvCfGw" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Вебкаст на SAP BTP: Agentic AI у підтримці SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;16:00–17:00&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-316204402"&gt;25 вересня 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://go4.events.sap.com/sap-document-and-reporting-compliance-summit-2025/en_us/registration.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Віртуальний саміт: SAP Document and Reporting Compliance 2024&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;15:00–19:00&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://events.teams.microsoft.com/event/05c4952b-bccc-445f-a347-b2e58898808d@e554b651-513a-459c-a4ae-6402f49ad018" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Онлайн-сесія з ліцензій SAP: Adoption Insights Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;11:00–11:45&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-119690897"&gt;30 вересня 2025&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4942585&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=98DDEC90391042F1B0EC2C72608C443E&amp;amp;groupId=6107761&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Віртуальна подія: EHS &amp;amp; Product Compliance – стратегія у сфері сталого розвитку та ланцюга постачання&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;15:00–19:00&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;(3-денний віртуальний захід: 30.09 – 02.10)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/eep.transformation.en_us.0b4395ff-d31f-44d0-9d91-da3526056f04.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Вебкаст з трансформації: SAM4U Latest Features (Roadmap &amp;amp; How to Influence)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":alarm_clock:"&gt;⏰&lt;/span&gt;15:00–16:00&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":three_o_clock:"&gt;🕒&lt;/span&gt;Усі часи вказані за київським.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Реєструйтесь за посиланнями в назві вебінарів! &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;А опісля діліться своїми думками у коментарях.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/september-online-seminars/ba-p/14208772"/>
    <published>2025-09-05T14:21:59.205000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/asunci%C3%B3n-blog-posts/sap-labs-s%C3%A3o-leopoldo-desde-paraguay-visitamos-las-instalaciones-de-sap/ba-p/14209659</id>
    <title>SAP Labs São Leopoldo: Desde Paraguay Visitamos las instalaciones de SAP LABS</title>
    <updated>2025-09-07T01:34:06.090000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Zamichiei</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163835</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nuestra aventura épica en SAP Labs São Leopoldo&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Spoiler alert: Fue increíble y queremos contarte todo&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;Todo empezó con un plan (y mucha emoción)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagínate esto: un email llega a tu bandeja de entrada y Matheus Souza te invita a conocer SAP Labs en Brasil para aprender sobre Inteligencia Artificial. ¿Tu respuesta? ¡SÍ, por favor! 🙋‍&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":male_sign:"&gt;♂️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Así comenzó nuestra aventura. Meses de planificación, coordinación de agendas, documentos, rutas, hoteles... pero con una sonrisa en la cara porque sabíamos que esto iba a ser ÉPICO.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":racing_car:"&gt;🏎&lt;/span&gt;15 horas de carretera = 15 horas de aventuras&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;¿Conoces esa sensación cuando estás tan emocionado por algo que hasta un viaje de 15 horas se siente como una aventura? Pues eso nos pasó.&lt;BR /&gt;Desde &lt;STRONG&gt;Ciudad del Este, Paraguay&lt;/STRONG&gt; hasta São Leopoldo fueron &lt;STRONG&gt;15 horas en carretera&lt;/STRONG&gt; llenas de:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Conversaciones sobre IA (obvio)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Predicciones sobre lo que íbamos a aprender&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Chistes internos del equipo&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Muchas paradas para café &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hot_beverage:"&gt;☕&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 1.54.18 PM.jpeg" style="width: 562px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310409i5E4AD5252FEC3FEB/image-dimensions/562x421/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="562" height="421" role="button" title="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 1.54.18 PM.jpeg" alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 1.54.18 PM.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 9.55.24 AM.jpeg" style="width: 379px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310410i9EAB1A475A81FB5D/image-dimensions/379x674/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="379" height="674" role="button" title="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 9.55.24 AM.jpeg" alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 9.55.24 AM.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Algunos Manejan, otros Duermen!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="111111.jpeg" style="width: 610px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310411i7048C66D90830E35/image-dimensions/610x457/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="610" height="457" role="button" title="111111.jpeg" alt="111111.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Parada técnica en Porto Alegre: Cultura + Diversión&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Antes del entrenamiento intensivo, nos dimos una vuelta por &lt;STRONG&gt;Porto Alegre&lt;/STRONG&gt;. ¡Qué ciudad más linda!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Lo mejor de todo: conocer la cultura local, probar comida brasileña auténtica, y preparar nuestras mentes para absorber todo el conocimiento que venía.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3142.jpeg" style="width: 406px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310413i7B0FE476DB7180E4/image-dimensions/406x722/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="406" height="722" role="button" title="IMG_3142.jpeg" alt="IMG_3142.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Algunos se olvidaron los lentes de Sol&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":smiling_face_with_sunglasses:"&gt;😎&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3120.jpeg" style="width: 596px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310414i7379A4989C707028/image-dimensions/596x335/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="596" height="335" role="button" title="IMG_3120.jpeg" alt="IMG_3120.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3133.jpeg" style="width: 398px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310415iB4179CC5F66F96D3/image-dimensions/398x531/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="398" height="531" role="button" title="IMG_3133.jpeg" alt="IMG_3133.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3164.jpeg" style="width: 554px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310419i214EF770956ADB2A/image-dimensions/554x415/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="554" height="415" role="button" title="IMG_3164.jpeg" alt="IMG_3164.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3170.jpeg" style="width: 527px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310420i16657EC1E07B827C/image-dimensions/527x703/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="527" height="703" role="button" title="IMG_3170.jpeg" alt="IMG_3170.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Paseo Obligatorio en Sao Leopoldo&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3100.jpeg" style="width: 514px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310418i304DA21D30B1BAA6/image-dimensions/514x385/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="514" height="385" role="button" title="IMG_3100.jpeg" alt="IMG_3100.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3105.jpeg" style="width: 319px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310416iCE1E927C85355CE1/image-dimensions/319x567/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="319" height="567" role="button" title="IMG_3105.jpeg" alt="IMG_3105.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hasta participamos de Una maratón!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3109.jpeg" style="width: 453px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310417i453E3DB95150A0C7/image-dimensions/453x340/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="453" height="340" role="button" title="IMG_3109.jpeg" alt="IMG_3109.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Primera vista de SAP Labs: "¿Esto es real?"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Llegar a &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Labs&lt;/STRONG&gt; fue como entrar a una película de ciencia ficción. Edificios modernos, tecnología por todos lados, y esa sensación de "aquí es donde nace el futuro". Nos recibieron con la sonrisa más cálida del mundo y pensamos: "Esto va a estar buenísimo"&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3274.jpeg" style="width: 458px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310426iCAAA6E50924CB94E/image-dimensions/458x814/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="458" height="814" role="button" title="IMG_3274.jpeg" alt="IMG_3274.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3295.jpeg" style="width: 568px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310427i6219A5B8BD85A5D9/image-dimensions/568x758/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="568" height="758" role="button" title="IMG_3295.jpeg" alt="IMG_3295.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3275 (1).jpeg" style="width: 653px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310428iB53CE459E19C4E44/image-dimensions/653x367/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="653" height="367" role="button" title="IMG_3275 (1).jpeg" alt="IMG_3275 (1).jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-09-02 at 11.41.33 AM.jpeg" style="width: 502px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310429iD87788A7B920673A/image-dimensions/502x670/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="502" height="670" role="button" title="WhatsApp Image 2025-09-02 at 11.41.33 AM.jpeg" alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-09-02 at 11.41.33 AM.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lunes y Martes: Modo aprendizaje ACTIVADO&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Día 1: "¡Esto es el futuro!"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lunes por la mañana.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Café en mano. Energía al 100%. Ready para aprender.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lo que vimos (y nos voló la cabeza):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Introdução a metodologia AI Journey&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business AI SAP&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule for consultant&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joule for developers&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hands on: Joule on SAP build code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Día 2: "Ok, ahora sí que estamos en otra liga"&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Martes.&lt;/STRONG&gt; Más café. Más energía. Listos para el siguiente level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Round 2 de conocimiento:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discovery Center&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Business AI Use cases&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;AI no BTP&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Hands on: RAG with Hana&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3234.jpeg" style="width: 525px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310431iA13920936F66F219/image-dimensions/525x700/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="525" height="700" role="button" title="IMG_3234.jpeg" alt="IMG_3234.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3255.jpeg" style="width: 544px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310432iD86CFA00B18506CB/image-dimensions/544x726/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="544" height="726" role="button" title="IMG_3255.jpeg" alt="IMG_3255.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Kuaatec_sap3.jpg" style="width: 521px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310433i83576A06F9373FC0/image-dimensions/521x678/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="521" height="678" role="button" title="Kuaatec_sap3.jpg" alt="Kuaatec_sap3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3210 (1).jpeg" style="width: 619px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310434i4184BE6922F68BBF/image-dimensions/619x464/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="619" height="464" role="button" title="IMG_3210 (1).jpeg" alt="IMG_3210 (1).jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-09-02 at 11.34.46 AM.jpeg" style="width: 541px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310435iC2DD18F5580DA983/image-dimensions/541x722/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="541" height="722" role="button" title="WhatsApp Image 2025-09-02 at 11.34.46 AM.jpeg" alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-09-02 at 11.34.46 AM.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Me Toco rendir en el frente!&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":face_with_tears_of_joy:"&gt;😂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-09-01 at 4.54.24 PM (1).jpe" style="width: 494px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310436i7C8D2946B7AD19BC/image-dimensions/494x659/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="494" height="659" role="button" title="WhatsApp Image 2025-09-01 at 4.54.24 PM (1).jpe" alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-09-01 at 4.54.24 PM (1).jpe" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":night_with_stars:"&gt;🌃&lt;/span&gt;Las noches: Donde nacen las mejores conversaciones&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Si pensabas que todo era trabajo, te equivocaste. Las noches en São Leopoldo fueron LEGENDARIAS.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;El plan:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Salir a cenar, conocer la ciudad, probar comida local.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_3284.jpeg" style="width: 666px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310441i97D1AD19E4A75E58/image-dimensions/666x499/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="666" height="499" role="button" title="IMG_3284.jpeg" alt="IMG_3284.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 9.47.28 PM.jpeg" style="width: 523px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310439iDD9B716DC2B897DA/image-dimensions/523x698/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="523" height="698" role="button" title="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 9.47.28 PM.jpeg" alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 9.47.28 PM.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 10.22.35 PM.jpeg" style="width: 531px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310438iF09412F31405A8D3/image-dimensions/531x708/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="531" height="708" role="button" title="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 10.22.35 PM.jpeg" alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 10.22.35 PM.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 11.14.40 PM (1).jpeg" style="width: 457px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310437i5595F7C046234798/image-dimensions/457x812/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="457" height="812" role="button" title="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 11.14.40 PM (1).jpeg" alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 11.14.40 PM (1).jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 11.42.56 PM.jpeg" style="width: 470px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310440iB43349C827A49154/image-dimensions/470x835/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="470" height="835" role="button" title="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 11.42.56 PM.jpeg" alt="WhatsApp Image 2025-08-30 at 11.42.56 PM.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conocimiento nivel PRO:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ahora hablamos de IA como expertos (bueno, casi)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Inspiración desbloqueada:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Volvimos con mil ideas para implementar en Kuaatec&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Conexiones humanas:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Hicimos amigos que están a miles de kilómetros pero se sienten súper cerca&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Visión expandida:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Entendimos que el futuro no es "algún día", es AHORA&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;¡Los esperamos en Paraguay!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Crecer junto a las personas es el mayor resultado de todos&lt;/STRONG&gt; - y esto lo comprobamos en primera persona.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Brasil nos abrió sus puertas, nos enseñó, nos inspiró y nos hizo sentir como en casa. Ahora queremos devolver el favor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;¡Equipo SAP, los esperamos en Paraguay!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Las puertas de &lt;STRONG&gt;Kuaatec&lt;/STRONG&gt; siempre estarán abiertas para ustedes. ¡Vengan cuando quieran!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Gracias infinitas (en serio, INFINITAS)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/asunci%C3%B3n-blog-posts/sap-labs-s%C3%A3o-leopoldo-desde-paraguay-visitamos-las-instalaciones-de-sap/ba-p/14209659"/>
    <published>2025-09-07T01:34:06.090000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/pune-blog-posts/sap-inside-track-pune-2025-the-community-is-back-stronger-than-ever/ba-p/14210538</id>
    <title>📢 SAP Inside Track Pune 2025 – The Community is Back, Stronger than Ever!</title>
    <updated>2025-09-08T10:35:11.836000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Punith_Oswal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148179</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello SAP Community in Pune&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are thrilled to share that &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Inside Track (SIT) Pune&lt;/STRONG&gt; is returning for its &lt;STRONG&gt;second edition&lt;/STRONG&gt; on &lt;STRONG&gt;11th October 2025 at SAP Labs India, ITPP, Pune.&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the overwhelming response to the first edition, where we witnessed unmatched energy, knowledge sharing, and community bonding, we’re excited to bring the SAP ecosystem in Pune together once again – this time, with an even bigger focus and a more impactful agenda.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759912876"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":glowing_star:"&gt;🌟&lt;/span&gt;What is SAP Inside Track?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For those new to it, &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Inside Track (SIT)&lt;/STRONG&gt; is a &lt;STRONG&gt;community-driven event&lt;/STRONG&gt; where SAP professionals, experts, and enthusiasts come together to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Share knowledge and insights&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn about the latest innovations in the SAP ecosystem&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discuss real-world challenges and solutions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Connect and collaborate with like-minded professionals&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;It’s an event &lt;STRONG&gt;for the community, by the community&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and Pune has already shown how vibrant and powerful this community can be.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563399371"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1366885866"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;Spotlight Theme for 2025: &lt;STRONG&gt;Business AI in SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This year, we’re placing a strong spotlight on &lt;STRONG&gt;Business AI in SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; – exploring how AI is no longer just a buzzword but a powerful enabler across the SAP landscape.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will dive deep into how AI is transforming business processes and user experiences across:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ariba&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Concur&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1299455080"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":magnifying_glass_tilted_right:"&gt;🔎&lt;/span&gt;Key Topics You Can Expect:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;SAP AI Strategy &amp;amp; Roadmap&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;Embedded AI in SAP Solutions&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;Building with SAP AI Agents&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;Business AI Solutions (SAP)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✔️&lt;/span&gt;AI Innovations: Partners &amp;amp; Customers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973858856"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777345351"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":key:"&gt;🔑&lt;/span&gt;Why You Should Attend&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Attending &lt;STRONG&gt;SIT Pune 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt; means being part of something bigger:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Expert-Led Sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Hear directly from thought leaders and SAP experts.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":handshake:"&gt;🤝&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Networking Opportunities&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Build valuable connections with professionals, customers, and partners.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Real-World Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Learn from success stories, project experiences, and innovation journeys.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":direct_hit:"&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Community Spirit&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Experience the energy of Pune’s SAP community, where collaboration drives growth.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-580831846"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-384318341"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;Event Details&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Date:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 11th October 2025&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Venue:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP Labs India, ITPP, Pune&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Registration:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A href="https://konfhub.com/sit-pune-event2025" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Register here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":warning:"&gt;⚠️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Please note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Seats are limited – so make sure you secure your spot early.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-187804836"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--8708669"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":raising_hands:"&gt;🙌&lt;/span&gt;Be Part of the Movement&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Inside Track is not just an event – it’s a movement powered by the passion and collaboration of the SAP community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Whether you are a developer, architect, consultant, customer, partner, or simply an SAP enthusiast – this is your chance to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn something new&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Share your own experiences&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expand your network&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;And most importantly, &lt;STRONG&gt;celebrate the spirit of community&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;We can’t wait to welcome you to &lt;STRONG&gt;SIT Pune 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Let’s come together for an &lt;STRONG&gt;unforgettable day of Business AI, SAP learning, and community bonding!&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See you in Pune! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Community Pune - Core Team&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/pune-blog-posts/sap-inside-track-pune-2025-the-community-is-back-stronger-than-ever/ba-p/14210538"/>
    <published>2025-09-08T10:35:11.836000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/barcelona-blog-posts/call-for-speakers-sap-inside-track-barcelona-2025-nov-14th/ba-p/14210547</id>
    <title>Call for Speakers - SAP Inside Track Barcelona 2025 - Nov 14th</title>
    <updated>2025-09-08T11:28:14.684000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>saquibus</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/161573</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello &lt;STRONG&gt;SAPCommunity&lt;/STRONG&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As you already know 9th Edition of #SAPInsideTrack Barcelona 2025, will take place next November 14th.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Blog info&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://lnkd.in/dCQQkwQu" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://lnkd.in/dCQQkwQu&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now it is time to &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":loudspeaker:"&gt;📢&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Call for Speakers!! &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":right_arrow:"&gt;➡️&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://lnkd.in/d3B72Vu6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://lnkd.in/d3B72Vu6&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;About sessions suggested and agenda&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SITBarcelona will be on prem, next Friday November 14th 2025!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need you to build our &lt;STRONG&gt;agenda&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Opening&lt;/EM&gt; SITBarcelona&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SITBarcelona sessions (Block 1)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Would be nice listening from&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":play_button:"&gt;▶️&lt;/span&gt; SAP AI Strategy &amp;amp; Roadmap, Embedded AI in SAP Solutions, AI Agents, SAP Business AI Solutions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":play_button:"&gt;▶️&lt;/span&gt; SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":play_button:"&gt;▶️&lt;/span&gt; SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":play_button:"&gt;▶️&lt;/span&gt; AI Innovations: Partners &amp;amp; Customers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Break/beverages &amp;amp; snacks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;AUSIA-AUSAPE : SAP BTP Hackathon Final&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Lunch&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;SITBarcelona sessions (Block 2)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Closing SITBarcelona&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Inside Track Barcelona Team&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#SAP #SAPCommunity #SAPDevelopers&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;#SITBarcelona #SAPInsideTrack&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SITOrg:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/733"&gt;@Lluis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/182"&gt;@david_ruizb&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44"&gt;@enric101&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;@Imma&amp;nbsp;@Mireia&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/42293"&gt;@starverson&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/barcelona-blog-posts/call-for-speakers-sap-inside-track-barcelona-2025-nov-14th/ba-p/14210547"/>
    <published>2025-09-08T11:28:14.684000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/webinar-%D1%8F%D0%BA-%D1%85%D0%BC%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%BD%D0%B0-erp-%D1%82%D0%B0-ai-%D0%B7%D0%B0%D0%B1%D0%B5%D0%B7%D0%BF%D0%B5%D1%87%D1%83%D1%8E%D1%82%D1%8C-%D1%82%D0%BE%D1%87%D0%BD%D1%96%D1%81%D1%82%D1%8C-%D0%B1%D1%96%D0%B7%D0%BD%D0%B5%D1%81-%D1%80%D1%96%D1%88%D0%B5%D0%BD%D1%8C/ba-p/14211602</id>
    <title>Webinar: як хмарна ERP та AI забезпечують точність бізнес рішень.</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T09:56:06.681000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;Real-time дані для CFO!&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Фінансовий директор сьогодні - це не лише про контроль цифр. Це про швидкість ухвалення рішень, здатність передбачати ризики та вчасно бачити нові можливості для бізнесу.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Але як зберігати цю швидкість, якщо ринок змінюється щодня? Відповідь - у сучасних інструментах, які допомагають:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":ok_hand:"&gt;👌&lt;/span&gt;знімати з вас рутину;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":ok_hand:"&gt;👌&lt;/span&gt;забезпечувати єдину картину бізнесу в реальному часі;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":ok_hand:"&gt;👌&lt;/span&gt;скорочувати витрати та одночасно відкривати шлях до зростання.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Саме про це говоритимемо на практичному вебінарі. Ви дізнаєтесь:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;Як просто та ефективно керувати компанією за допомогою хмарних рішень.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;Як вбудований ШІ автоматизує рутину та допомагає швидше ухвалювати обґрунтовані рішення.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;Як ми скоротили час закриття місяця з 10 до 4 днів і зменшили витрати на інфраструктуру на 70 % завдяки хмарній ERP.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Приєднуйтеся 23 вересня о 16:00!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":mobile_phone_with_arrow:"&gt;📲&lt;/span&gt;Реєструйтеся тут:&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://lnkd.in/dRuKa_da" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://lnkd.in/dRuKa_da&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/webinar-%D1%8F%D0%BA-%D1%85%D0%BC%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%BD%D0%B0-erp-%D1%82%D0%B0-ai-%D0%B7%D0%B0%D0%B1%D0%B5%D0%B7%D0%BF%D0%B5%D1%87%D1%83%D1%8E%D1%82%D1%8C-%D1%82%D0%BE%D1%87%D0%BD%D1%96%D1%81%D1%82%D1%8C-%D0%B1%D1%96%D0%B7%D0%BD%D0%B5%D1%81-%D1%80%D1%96%D1%88%D0%B5%D0%BD%D1%8C/ba-p/14211602"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T09:56:06.681000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-team-spotlight-josh-bentley-september-2025-edition/ba-p/14180573</id>
    <title>SAP Community Team Spotlight: Josh Bentley - September 2025 Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T10:13:33.977000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>fatemehzarei_001</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2079550</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;You probably have already seen the past interviews of this series (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/author-spotlight-tim-koster-november-2024-edition/ba-p/13943136" target="_self"&gt;one&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/author-spotlight-daniel-mateo-december-2024-edition/ba-p/13959191" target="_self"&gt;two&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/author-spotlight-shaik-azmathulla-january-2025-edition/ba-p/13985327" target="_self"&gt;three&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/community-member-spotlight-roberta-fernandes-february-2025-edition/ba-p/14002811" target="_self"&gt;four&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/community-member-spotlight-manuel-robalinho-march-2025-edition/ba-p/14057231" target="_self"&gt;five&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/community-member-spotlight-marssel-vila%C3%A7a-april-2025-edition/ba-p/14090587" target="_self"&gt;six&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;/ &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-team-spotlight-anne-petteroe-may-2025-edition/ba-p/14112695" target="_self"&gt;seven&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-team-spotlight-laura-schmitz-july-2025-edition/ba-p/14138688" target="_self"&gt;eight&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;) which were done by my colleague Marco Santos. Today I am very excited to introduce you to another amazing person behind the SAP Community platform. Here we are with another SAP Community Spotlight, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/148"&gt;@josh_bentley&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Social Josh Bentley.jpg" style="width: 453px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/300791i1AF344BF81E85FF6/image-dimensions/453x453?v=v2" width="453" height="453" role="button" title="Social Josh Bentley.jpg" alt="Social Josh Bentley.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fatemeh Zarei (FZ):&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Hi Josh! Thank you so much for joining us today. To kick things off - would you like to tell us a little bit about your iconic blue beard? How did that all start?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Josh Bentley:&lt;/STRONG&gt; So, every superhero has their own origin story - mine's just a little less dramatic. I’ve been talking about technology for nearly 25 years, and in 2018, I joined the Developer Advocates team after leaving the Cloud Center of Excellence. At a conference - SAP TechEd - the women on our team had all these vibrant hair colors and teased us guys for being boring. I thought, “Why is it only the women showing personality?” But I don’t have hair - I’m bald! So, one of them said, “Well, you can dye your beard.” I didn’t take it seriously at first, but before SAP TechEd in 2019, I thought, "Why not?" I texted her for tips, used paper towels to mix colors until I got close to SAP blue, and I’ve kept it ever since. This October marks six years! What keeps me doing it is not just for my ego boost but for the smiles I get from others and the joy they truly show me when they see me.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FZ&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;STRONG&gt;That’s fantastic! Now, shifting gears a bit - how did you first get involved with the SAP Community?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Josh&lt;/STRONG&gt;: That goes back to my pre-sales days, around 2011 or 2012, when we had the “Blog It Forward” campaign that Moshe Naveh started. I was a solution engineer at the time and joined in by answering the campaign questions, then tagging others. That was my first real blog post and entry into the community. I wasn’t one of the founders or key players at the start - it was more of a resource to find answers or share thoughts. But that’s where it began for me.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FZ&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;STRONG&gt;What's your current role on the SAP Community team, and what does a typical day look like?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Josh&lt;/STRONG&gt;: These days, I focus on promoting community advocacy. I help highlight what’s working and where we can improve. My work is all about connecting with people - online and in person - and making sure their voices are heard. There’s no “typical” day, but it involves a mix of content creation, listening to feedback, and strategizing how to make the community better.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FZ: You’ve done so much! What’s one part of the SAP community experience that you’re particularly proud of?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Josh&lt;/STRONG&gt;: It’s hard to pick one, but I’ll mention three chapters in my SAP life. First, I was part of the team that transitioned SAP from BlackBerry to Apple devices, which was a major enterprise shift. We tackled security, analytics access, BYOD - it was a huge cross-functional effort. Then in pre-sales, I traveled extensively and gave technical demos to some of the biggest companies in the world. I got comfortable and confident in front of customers because I prepared so thoroughly - “sharpening the axe,” as they say. And in the Developer Advocate role, one big highlight was being trusted to go on stage for SAP TechEd, even during the COVID era when we broadcasted from Frankfurt. Being able to be myself and present on a global stage was unforgettable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FZ: Amazing. Do you have a favorite or most memorable moment in the community?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Josh&lt;/STRONG&gt;: One standout was my first SAP TechEd in Barcelona. Being in a role where I get to visit an amazing city like that is something else, but the real magic was seeing the show floor and the scale of how many SAP mentors and other legacy members made the trip. Some of my first SAP selfies with people I would work with for years were taken at that event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FZ: How do you stay in tune with the community’s needs and feedback?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Josh&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Three main ways. First, in-person events. That’s where people are really open. Online, they might not comment or engage as much, but in person they’ll say, “Hey, I saw your video!” Second, I post on YouTube and LinkedIn to keep communication flowing. Third, I look at outside platforms like Reddit or Stack Overflow to see what SAP techies are saying in the wild.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FZ: If you could wave a magic wand and change one thing in the community, what would it be?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Josh&lt;/STRONG&gt;: I’d love to see more people offering constructive feedback - with solutions in mind. Not just “this is broken,” but “here’s how it could be better.” I know we can’t always implement every suggestion - due to technology limitations or staffing - but the community is stronger when members help shape it. The community is bigger than just a website. It’s every conversation, every event. And we need our members to be co-owners in it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FZ: And one final question - do you have any advice for those new to SAP or the SAP Community, like me?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Josh&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Absolutely. Be your own advocate. No one else is going to push you harder than you will. Learn how your managers listen. In meetings - listen first. Figure out how you can add value. People ask how they can have a role like mine. I say, there are two ways: either start a company and create your own path - or gain experience over time. I didn’t go to school for SAP. I started wiring buildings, setting up IT systems, and just kept learning. Over time, I built a brand and a reputation for being honest, responsive, and knowledgeable. Have a point of view - or put in the work. There’s no shortcut. Just engage with kindness and curiosity, and the rest will come.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;FZ&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; What a wonderful way to wrap things up! Thank you so much, Josh, for joining me today and sharing your SAP journey with us. It’s been a real pleasure having you here.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Josh&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Thanks, Fatemeh. I really enjoyed our conversation.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-team-spotlight-josh-bentley-september-2025-edition/ba-p/14180573"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T10:13:33.977000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/nigeria-blog-posts/welcome-to-the-sap-community-group-nigeria/ba-p/14211916</id>
    <title>🌟 Welcome to the SAP Community Group Nigeria! 🌟</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T12:40:59.995000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>CharlesNwankwo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/127416</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hello SAP Nigeria Enthusiasts!&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’re super excited to kick off the SAP Community Group in Nigeria, a space created for collaboration, learning, and innovation within our local SAP ecosystem. Whether you’re a seasoned SAP professional, just starting out, or a business leader using SAP solutions to make an impact, this community is for you. Together, we’ll share ideas, learn from each other, and build strong connections that grow the SAP network across Nigeria.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our vision is to create a vibrant and dynamic community that thrives on collaboration and continuous learning. By sharing your knowledge, engaging in discussions, and supporting one another, we can build a strong SAP ecosystem that not only empowers professionals in Nigeria but also contributes to the global SAP family.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why join the SAP Community Nigeria Group?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Here’s what you can look forward to:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;Local Meetups &amp;amp; Events&lt;/STRONG&gt; – From informal gatherings to SAP-focused workshops and knowledge sessions, we’ll create opportunities to connect in person.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;Knowledge Sharing&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Publish blogs, ask questions, and share insights on SAP solutions and innovations. Your contributions form the backbone of this community.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;Networking &amp;amp; Growth&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Build relationships with SAP experts, professionals, and enthusiasts across Nigeria and beyond.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;Celebrate Success Stories&lt;/STRONG&gt; – Share how SAP is driving transformation in your career, business, or industry—we want to spotlight local heroes.&lt;BR /&gt;How you can get involved&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="Join the Group" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/nigeria/gh-p/nigeria" target="_self"&gt;Join the Group&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;A title="Post your Introduction" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/forums/postpage/board-id/nigeriaforum-board" target="_self"&gt;Post your Introduction&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp; (tell us about your SAP journey, location, and interests)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Stay tuned for events and discussions that bring learning and collaboration to life&lt;BR /&gt;Let’s Build the Future – Together&lt;BR /&gt;This community will only be as strong as the people in it. By sharing your knowledge, engaging in discussions, and supporting others, you’ll help us build a vibrant SAP ecosystem in Nigeria.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;Together, let’s make the SAP Community Nigeria a hub of innovation, collaboration, and growth!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;About the Initiator&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Charles Nwankwo&lt;/STRONG&gt; is an SAP PP/QM Consultant with over six years of professional experience. His career has spanned multiple industries, including manufacturing, consumer goods, beverages, pharmaceuticals, and chemicals. He has contributed to several end-to-end SAP projects, ranging from Greenfield and Brownfield S/4HANA implementations to public cloud deployments. Beyond technical expertise, these experiences have deepened his understanding of the challenges and opportunities that organizations face during SAP transformation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Driven by a passion for collaboration, he established this community to create a platform where SAP professionals in Nigeria can connect, exchange insights, and collectively drive innovation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/31"&gt;@lauraschmitz&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;#SAP#SAPCommunityNigeria&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/nigeria-blog-posts/welcome-to-the-sap-community-group-nigeria/ba-p/14211916"/>
    <published>2025-09-09T12:40:59.995000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
