<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Ariba-Buying-and-Invoicing-qa.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Ariba Buying and Invoicing</title>
  <updated>2025-07-25T11:12:47.691754+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Ariba Buying and Invoicing/pd-p/088a2ce1-412b-458b-becb-2311c968d328" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Ariba Buying and Invoicing Q&amp;A in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/multi-vat-on-single-invoice-line/qaq-p/14094683</id>
    <title>Multi VAT on single invoice line</title>
    <updated>2025-05-06T17:56:11.793000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AshishIncyte</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1562092</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We have suppliers who are posting invoice through Ariba Network for a simple service PO, these are PO with single line item for services. On Invoice posting , Suppliers are using multiple VAT components e.g. charging VAT 8.1 % and 2.6 %.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When we get these invoice in Ariba invoicing, there is no option to assign tax code on these split VAT lines. Instead, I just get an option to assign a VAT code on the total VAT, which is not accurate. Anyone else had this issue with Ariba invoicing? What can be done to assign appropriate VAT codes on individual split lines?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ashish&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/multi-vat-on-single-invoice-line/qaq-p/14094683"/>
    <published>2025-05-06T17:56:11.793000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/pr-integration-via-webservice-in-cig-configured-site/qaq-p/14096437</id>
    <title>PR Integration via WebService in CIG configured site</title>
    <updated>2025-05-08T14:59:42.933000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JakubC2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1867918</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I would like to know if we can use Web Service integration together with CIG integration method.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I need to use Web Service integration to load Requisition from third party system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For standard Ariba-ERP integration we use CIG now.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If that's not possible, would be great to know what are the options.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We would like to avoid replication of PR to S4 and then to Ariba.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#managedgateway #CIG #webservice&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/pr-integration-via-webservice-in-cig-configured-site/qaq-p/14096437"/>
    <published>2025-05-08T14:59:42.933000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-requisition-replication-to-s4/qaq-p/14096446</id>
    <title>Ariba Requisition Replication to S4</title>
    <updated>2025-05-08T15:07:32.148000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JakubC2</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1867918</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have requirement to create two separate processes in Ariba for the Purchase Requisition Creation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We use CIG as integration method at the moment and only first point is configured.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Standard PR replication with Budget Check interface then PR approval in Ariba and PO generated from Ariba.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. PR replication to S4 and further processing in S4 like approvals and PO.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any advise how to configure will be appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;#CIG #managedgateway&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-requisition-replication-to-s4/qaq-p/14096446"/>
    <published>2025-05-08T15:07:32.148000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/special-handling-line-item-ariba-network-invoice/qaq-p/14097621</id>
    <title>Special handling line item-Ariba Network invoice</title>
    <updated>2025-05-09T22:58:37.753000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AshishIncyte</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1562092</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are facing issue with commodity code default on Ariba Network invoice when we add Special handling charge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When I add a special handling line on network invoice- it loads in B&amp;amp;I with commodity 78, even though &lt;SPAN&gt;Application.Invoicing.SpecialHandlingCommodityCode&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;parameter&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;has been updated to pick commodity 78121603&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;But If I add a shipping line on network invoice – it loads in B&amp;amp;I correctly with commodity 7810, which matches with &lt;SPAN&gt;Application.Invoicing.ShippingCommodityCode&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;parameter value 7810.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both 7810 and 78121603 have same parent 78.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I asked Ariba support, why there is different behavior for Special handling vs shipping line, see below response.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Based on your initial request, we have updated the commodity code for handling 78121603. We did not make any changes to the Shipping aspect as it follows standard functionality. If we do not alter the commodity code in the parameter system, it will default to a four-digit code. Additionally, if we modify any other standard commodity code, it will attempt to align with the parapet commodity code specifically for the network invoice only.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does this make sense? Anyone else faced similar issue?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thanks&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Ashish&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/special-handling-line-item-ariba-network-invoice/qaq-p/14097621"/>
    <published>2025-05-09T22:58:37.753000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/why-is-so-difficult-for-sap-ariba-support-to-acknowledge-there-is-a-flaw-in/qaq-p/14102188</id>
    <title>Why is so difficult for SAP Ariba Support to Acknowledge there is a flaw in the system ?</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T10:29:19.573000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>yaccoulibaly</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/163691</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is a good tool because there are many possibilities and flexibility and the broad area it can cover, but one of the SAP weaknesses has been the support of customer, especially when it comes to SAP Ariba Support.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As implementation consultant, one of my activities, is to use the system intensively, and push the system to it limit, which some time I discover lot of issues or bug and usually after multiple check and possible workaround I will report the issue to SAP. In more than 90% of the case, the Ariba Support will mention nonsense reply, and set the case as "Solution proposed" which close your case automatically after few days.... &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP has released a solution that allows to send Storage Location to SAP Ariba using CIG [&lt;STRONG&gt;CP-8143: Inventory reservation for SAP ERP-integrated sites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;A title="https://help.sap.com/docs/ariba/sap-ariba-applications-2002-q1-2020-release-guide/cp-8143-changes-to-data-import-and-export" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/ariba/sap-ariba-applications-2002-q1-2020-release-guide/cp-8143-changes-to-data-import-and-export" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/ariba/sap-ariba-applications-2002-q1-2020-release-guide/cp-8143-changes-to-data-import-and-export&lt;/A&gt;)]. So, they developed a solution and release that solution, but we don't know how it was tested, but it was released, thus, customer will do the following: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;in S4 run ARBCIG_MASTER_DATA_EXPORT program&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;select Storage Location (StorageLocation.csv) maybe together with other Master Data object and execute the program.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the data is extracted and sent to SAP Ariba via CIG, but because of the missing of StorageLocation.csv missing in Ariba Batch Supported file, the transaction will always fail in CIG no matter if there are or not other data object.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I opened a case, saying this is an error and it should be added, but the support person is clearly refusing to do anything mentioning that there is an article which is saying:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The payload for Storage Location master data should contain the StorageLocation.csv file. However, this file isn't included in the 'Import Batch Data tasks' of the Ariba Procurement solution. This means that when this file is sent from ERP to Ariba procurement via CIG, the transaction is likely to fail. This issue is also discussed at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A title="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/KB0400688" href="https://support.ariba.com/item/view/KB0400688" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://support.ariba.com/item/view/KB0400688&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To import the Storage location master data into Ariba procurement, you may need to utilize the test run option. Following this, execute the report ARBCIG_MASTER_DATA_EXPORT for the Storage location master data, and obtain the StorageLocation.csv file locally.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finally, use this local file to manually upload it in the Ariba Procurement solution. You can do this by selecting the 'Import Storage Location Data' task under the 'Data Import/Export' option within the Site Manager in Ariba Procurement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Why do an article instead of fixing the issue, the article was for sure created because many customers faced this issue and opened a case. The purpose of the CIG is to automate import of data, but because SAP always work in silo, the team didn't probably consult any one and release the data without doing an end-to-end test.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;In this documentation (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/procurement-data-import-and-administration-guide/data-import-order-for-sap-erp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://help.sap.com/docs/buying-invoicing/procurement-data-import-and-administration-guide/data-import-order-for-sap-erp&lt;/A&gt;), it is cleearly mentionned that the storage location file should be at the position #69 of the Batch Sequence, but someone has to add it there, but again, instead of involving the correct team to do the right thing for customer, the Support Team, said the documentation is wrong and therefore he doesn't do anything.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Honestly speaking...how will you tacle this situation?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/why-is-so-difficult-for-sap-ariba-support-to-acknowledge-there-is-a-flaw-in/qaq-p/14102188"/>
    <published>2025-05-15T10:29:19.573000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-invoice-issue/qaq-p/14105060</id>
    <title>Ariba: Invoice issue</title>
    <updated>2025-05-19T09:41:27.112000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>dhinesh_thirugnanam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/219203</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi Team,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Need your suggestion on the below mentioned issue which we are facing in our test environment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The invoices for Indirect POs are failing in VIM because of "Invalid PO Item Number".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="VIM.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/262850i7DE688911C4E2018/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="VIM.png" alt="VIM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reason for this is in SBN, the Indirect PO item interval is 1,2,3,...&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Ariba - lineitem.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/262853iBAF657ADB046AA4F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Ariba - lineitem.jpg" alt="Ariba - lineitem.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;But the SAP ZARB PO item interval is 10,20,30,....&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="PO.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/262856i3272B9C34BA52F2D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PO.jpg" alt="PO.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When Supplier creates the Invoice in SBN, it adopts the item numbering from the SBN PO (1,2,3,...). &amp;nbsp;When that invoice makes it to SAP for processing, VIM is checking for that PO # and Line # in SAP and can't find a match since the SAP PO has different item numbering (10,20,30,...).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since this is a standard process do we need any customization?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do we require any of the option's to overcome this issue&amp;nbsp;(1) CIG mapping solution or (2) change ZARB line item interval config to 1,2,3.If so kindly suggest what needs to be done.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-invoice-issue/qaq-p/14105060"/>
    <published>2025-05-19T09:41:27.112000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/how-do-you-implement-automatic-surcharge-capture/qaq-p/14109365</id>
    <title>How do you implement automatic surcharge capture?</title>
    <updated>2025-05-22T15:08:18.265000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>-Nico-</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1429781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;You ever heard from this function? &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ChatGPT:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To implement automatic surcharge capture in SAP Ariba Buying, you need to define &lt;STRONG&gt;Pricing Conditions or Rules&lt;/STRONG&gt; within your catalog or through contracts. These rules specify how and when additional costs (e.g., shipping, customs) should apply. They can be configured in &lt;STRONG&gt;price sheets&lt;/STRONG&gt; as part of catalog uploads or set via conditional logic tied to item attributes, regions, or suppliers—this requires activation of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Total Landed Cost (TLC)&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature and possibly realm-level parameters.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;How do I set up the pricing rules?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ChatGPT:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Pricing rules are configured either through &lt;STRONG&gt;price sheets&lt;/STRONG&gt; in catalog uploads (CSV/CIF templates) or via &lt;STRONG&gt;contract pricing conditions&lt;/STRONG&gt;. In catalog uploads, you define rules using fields like additionalCostType, amount, currency, and application basis (e.g., per unit, percentage). For more advanced automation, use &lt;STRONG&gt;contract-based pricing&lt;/STRONG&gt; tied to specific supplier agreements, which can trigger conditions based on volume, product type, or region. All of this requires the &lt;STRONG&gt;Total Landed Cost&lt;/STRONG&gt; feature to be active in your realm.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Where do I find this: Click "Add Price Sheet" or edit an existing one — or do I need a parameter activated for that?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ChatGPT:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The “Add Price Sheet” option is not always visible by default. To access or upload price sheets:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your user role must have Catalog Admin permissions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;Total Landed Cost feature&lt;/STRONG&gt; must be enabled in your realm (via a parameter like Application.CustomCatalog.EnableLandedCost).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to: Catalogs → Catalog Manager, select or create a catalog, then go to “Import” and click “Download Template” or “Add Price Sheet”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this functionality is not visible, you likely need SAP Support or your system admin to activate the appropriate parameters for your realm.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;User:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;How do I find the Price Sheet layout in Ariba?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;ChatGPT:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To find the Price Sheet layout:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to Catalogs → Catalog Manager.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Choose an existing catalog or click “Create Catalog”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Under “Import”, click “Download Template” — this gives you the price sheet structure (CSV or Excel).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alternatively, find documentation on &lt;A target="_new" rel="noopener"&gt;SAP Help Portal – CIF Format&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR /&gt;If TLC fields like additionalCostType, additionalCost, etc., are missing, request the latest template from your SAP Ariba Support. These fields only appear if your realm has Total Landed Cost activated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example: Price Sheet (CSV) with TLC Surcharges&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;supplierPartID,description,unitPrice,currency,unitOfMeasure,additionalCost1Type,additionalCost1,additionalCost1Currency,additionalCost1Basis,region&lt;BR /&gt;1001,Standard Widget,50,EUR,EA,Shipping,5,EUR,Per Unit,DE&lt;BR /&gt;1002,Deluxe Widget,100,EUR,EA,Insurance,10,EUR,Percentage of Price,EU&lt;BR /&gt;1003,Heavy Machinery,1000,EUR,EA,Handling,100,EUR,Flat Rate,ALL&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1859709210"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Field Explanation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;Column Description &lt;TABLE&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;supplierPartID&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Supplier's internal item number&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;description&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Item description&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;unitPrice&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Base item price&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;currency&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Currency (e.g., EUR)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;unitOfMeasure&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Unit of measure (e.g., EA = Each)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;additionalCost1Type&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Type of surcharge (e.g., Shipping, Insurance, Handling, etc.)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;additionalCost1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Value of the surcharge (e.g., 5 EUR or 10%)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;additionalCost1Currency&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Currency of the surcharge (usually same as currency)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;additionalCost1Basis&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Basis for the surcharge: &lt;EM&gt;Per Unit&lt;/EM&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;Percentage of Price&lt;/EM&gt;, or &lt;EM&gt;Flat Rate&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;region&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Region where the surcharge applies (e.g., DE, EU, ALL)&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;We would kindly request your support for the following:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable Total Landed Cost (TLC) functionality&lt;/STRONG&gt; in our realm, if not already active – including the parameter (e.g., Application.CustomCatalog.EnableLandedCost or equivalent).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide access to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Price Sheet layout template&lt;/STRONG&gt; that supports TLC-related fields such as:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;additionalCostType, additionalCost, currency, basis (e.g. per unit or % of price)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Support for regional application (region, country)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Clarify where we can access the &lt;STRONG&gt;“Add Price Sheet”&lt;/STRONG&gt; option in the Catalog Manager UI – and confirm whether this depends on specific configuration or user role permissions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Optionally, share the &lt;STRONG&gt;latest official documentation&lt;/STRONG&gt; or specification for setting up TLC rules in catalog uploads (CIF or Excel), including sample templates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You mentioned: "If you want, I can create a sample CSV for a typical TLC Price Sheet upload." — Yes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Nico_0-1747919007703.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265100iD3D435EF044D89CD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Nico_0-1747919007703.png" alt="Nico_0-1747919007703.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/how-do-you-implement-automatic-surcharge-capture/qaq-p/14109365"/>
    <published>2025-05-22T15:08:18.265000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sap-ariba-buying-user-replication/qaq-p/14112214</id>
    <title>SAP Ariba Buying - user replication</title>
    <updated>2025-05-27T07:06:44.634000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Maxim</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/137030</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;on starting any app within SAP Ariba Buying we get the error “Your user has not been replicated yet. Please try again later.” Does anyone know what the reason is and how we can fix it?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you and best regards&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maxim&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/supply-chain-management-q-a/sap-ariba-buying-user-replication/qaq-p/14112214"/>
    <published>2025-05-27T07:06:44.634000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/re-assignment-of-a-pr/qaq-p/14115438</id>
    <title>Re- assignment of a PR</title>
    <updated>2025-05-30T14:57:32.736000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anthony_J</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1717602</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;we have configured Ariba to assign requisitions to a supervisor based on UNSPC segment who then assigns the PR to a Buyer.&amp;nbsp; The issue is that the PR is maintaining the Supervisors Delegation of Procurement Authority (DOPA) even when assigned to a Buyer (who has a lower DOPA).&amp;nbsp; Can we have the PR follow the most recent owner/assigned Buyer's DOPA?&amp;nbsp; What is the workflow or process or option for doing that?&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/re-assignment-of-a-pr/qaq-p/14115438"/>
    <published>2025-05-30T14:57:32.736000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-integrate-sap-ariba-with-third-party-applications-standard-apis/qaq-p/14122472</id>
    <title>How to Integrate SAP Ariba with Third-Party Applications – Standard APIs</title>
    <updated>2025-06-09T06:57:44.829000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SATHEESHKUMAR_1</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/804026</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have a requirement to integrate &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Ariba (Buyer module)&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;third-party applications&lt;/STRONG&gt; (non-SAP). I would like to know:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Are there any &lt;STRONG&gt;standard APIs&lt;/STRONG&gt; provided by SAP Ariba for such integrations?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If yes, could you please share the list of those APIs or relevant documentation?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Is there any recommended approach or best practice for integrating Ariba with external systems?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m particularly looking for &lt;STRONG&gt;direct integration options&lt;/STRONG&gt; (not via SAP S/4HANA or middleware) if available.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any guidance or reference to API documentation would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you in advance!&lt;BR /&gt;Best regards,&lt;BR /&gt;Satheesh Kumar.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/how-to-integrate-sap-ariba-with-third-party-applications-standard-apis/qaq-p/14122472"/>
    <published>2025-06-09T06:57:44.829000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/procurement-process-for-leasing-products/qaq-p/14124003</id>
    <title>procurement process for leasing products</title>
    <updated>2025-06-10T14:44:22.179000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>S_Agarwal</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/178871</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;I have a requirement of implementing the leasing process for some products . The customer wants to lease them instead of buying . Can Ariba buying be used to create PR for such leasing POs ? Is invoicing plan supported in Ariba ?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/procurement-process-for-leasing-products/qaq-p/14124003"/>
    <published>2025-06-10T14:44:22.179000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/migo-gr-not-transferring-into-ariba-buying/qaq-p/14127341</id>
    <title>MIGO GR not transferring into Ariba Buying</title>
    <updated>2025-06-13T17:45:47.724000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ProcurementExcellence</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1388685</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Anyone have a solution when posting GR in MIGO how to see the receipt in Ariba Buying and therefore, reducing the qty that needs to be received?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/migo-gr-not-transferring-into-ariba-buying/qaq-p/14127341"/>
    <published>2025-06-13T17:45:47.724000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/request-to-enable-requisitionimportpull-web-service-in-ariba/qaq-p/14136485</id>
    <title>Request to Enable RequisitionImportPull Web Service in Ariba</title>
    <updated>2025-06-25T11:28:56.922000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ravishankar2020</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/127620</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear Community,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We are planning to integrate with SAP Ariba to create requisitions via the RequisitionImportPull SOAP service. However, the Web Services option under Integration Manager is not visible in our realm.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Kindly help us with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Enabling the RequisitionImportPull web service&lt;BR /&gt;2. Granting access to Web Services Configuration&lt;BR /&gt;3. Confirming if this must be done in the parent realm&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/request-to-enable-requisitionimportpull-web-service-in-ariba/qaq-p/14136485"/>
    <published>2025-06-25T11:28:56.922000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/sap-ariba-supplier-accounts/qaq-p/14147905</id>
    <title>SAP Ariba supplier accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-07-09T08:03:44.034000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sabarish100</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2129461</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I have one query related to supplier accounts on SAP Business network, where supplier A have multiple contacts like X,Y,Z.... but supplier A already connected with customer ABC with supplier contact X, so that in SLP 360 for supplier A , only one contact X is showing public other contacts Y,Z are showing private.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here my question is, when a customer ABC invite a supplier A with contact Y for sourcing event, whether he needs to create another account to complete sourcing event or he use existing account to access event.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;what If he create another account, the ANID will be same or different?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I believe that one supplier have one ANID which connect all supplier contacts.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/sap-ariba-supplier-accounts/qaq-p/14147905"/>
    <published>2025-07-09T08:03:44.034000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/does-ariba-buying-allows-to-have-same-po-number-associated-with-different/qaq-p/14149352</id>
    <title>Does Ariba buying allows to have same PO number associated with different PRs of Ariba?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-10T12:22:52.083000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aranyak</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2130260</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;The Ariba Buying realm needs to be connected to two different ERPs system ids.&lt;STRONG&gt; The number ranges for PO are same for both system ids&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This will done through custom routing in CIG.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What happens when same PO number is generated from both the ERPs for different PRs that we create in Ariba?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Does Ariba buying allows to same PO number associated different PRs of Ariba?&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/does-ariba-buying-allows-to-have-same-po-number-associated-with-different/qaq-p/14149352"/>
    <published>2025-07-10T12:22:52.083000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/i-want-to-become-sap-mm-amp-ariba-consultant/qaq-p/14149613</id>
    <title>I want to become SAP MM &amp; Ariba consultant.</title>
    <updated>2025-07-10T15:51:08.041000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pratik_soni6</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2186680</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello All,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I want to become SAP MM &amp;amp; Ariba consultant.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;What is pathway to learn from scratch, please anyone guide for me&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;How can i grow in this field ? in this field have bright future &amp;amp; salary ?&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Is there any recommended video/ you tube channel for learning.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Currently i have basis experience&amp;nbsp; in SAP MM &amp;amp; Ariba.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;thank you for your answer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-q-a/i-want-to-become-sap-mm-amp-ariba-consultant/qaq-p/14149613"/>
    <published>2025-07-10T15:51:08.041000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/digital-certificate-authotication-for-sap-ariba/qaq-p/14149640</id>
    <title>Digital Certificate authotication for SAP Ariba</title>
    <updated>2025-07-10T16:14:40.875000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MOHAMMED_TAMBOLI</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1491646</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hallo Experts,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am looking to post cxml invoice from postman through digital certificate authentication for testing. But the challenge is as per Ariba, the certificate has to be procured from SAP Ariba trusted company. As I am looking for testing purpose, I would like know is there any possible to get digital certificate for testing so that I can test from Postman application and later conclude for procuring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/digital-certificate-authotication-for-sap-ariba/qaq-p/14149640"/>
    <published>2025-07-10T16:14:40.875000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/how-do-i-hide-unit-prices-in-guided-buying/qaq-p/14150104</id>
    <title>How do I hide unit prices in Guided Buying?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-11T09:13:51.372000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MarcinBogucki81</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/144647</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Colleagues,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am afraid I know the answer but "one who asks does not err" as they say ;+)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One of my customers asked a question on if it is possible to hide unit prices from Guided Buying users view. The motivation is simple and easy to understand - being a laboratory services provider, they want to secure their negotiated prices from being passed around by Guided Buying users. I am as well aware that it is easy to challenge - almost every user of any procurement related system on chosen step of buying process may have access to the prices giving invoices, reports, or S/4HANA access for finance as the first examples.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So my question - did any you guys ever met such customer requirement and if you ever heard of how to cover it?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Thank you ion advance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Marcin&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/how-do-i-hide-unit-prices-in-guided-buying/qaq-p/14150104"/>
    <published>2025-07-11T09:13:51.372000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/sap-a-ariba-integration-with-sap-business-one/qaq-p/14154382</id>
    <title>sap a]Ariba integration with Sap Business one</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T21:50:28.441000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Babatunde_Akinboye</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2155001</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Please expert, In an SAP Ariba integration with SAP Business one.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The procurement&amp;nbsp;process typically starts with an RFQ. Which system initiates this?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please can someone also assist with a simple architecture diagram of the integration&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/sap-a-ariba-integration-with-sap-business-one/qaq-p/14154382"/>
    <published>2025-07-16T21:50:28.441000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-cig-target-value-variable-mapping/qaq-p/14154668</id>
    <title>Ariba CIG Target Value Variable mapping</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T07:35:17.198000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>build</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2067061</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello,&lt;BR /&gt;I’m currently exploring &lt;STRONG&gt;CIG mappings&lt;/STRONG&gt; and testing various configurations to deepen my understanding. I need your help in understanding the difference between &lt;STRONG&gt;Target Position Variable&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Target Value Variable&lt;/STRONG&gt; in mapping.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m particularly confused about the purpose and usage of the &lt;STRONG&gt;Target Value Variable&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;what it actually does and how it should be used in mappings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Could you please explain this with a &lt;STRONG&gt;simple and easy-to-understand example&lt;/STRONG&gt;? Also, please let me know for which &lt;STRONG&gt;document types&lt;/STRONG&gt; this mapping is applicable so I can test it accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to your guidance.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/spend-management-q-a/ariba-cig-target-value-variable-mapping/qaq-p/14154668"/>
    <published>2025-07-17T07:35:17.198000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
