<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Business-Accelerator-Hub-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Business Accelerator Hub</title>
  <updated>2025-10-05T17:00:35.214690+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Business Accelerator Hub/pd-p/73555000100800001091" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Business Accelerator Hub blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/defining-business-architecture-a-guide-for-estimating-transformation/ba-p/13991401</id>
    <title>Defining Business Architecture: A Guide for Estimating Transformation Projects</title>
    <updated>2025-01-23T13:03:18.442000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rajen_Patel</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5988</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1080230150"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Problem Statement:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You are embarking on transforming your business by replacing/upgrading your 20-year-old Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) platform. You are in the Explore phase and looking for a realistic scope and budget for implementation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your goal is to implement effective and efficient processes on a new platform. However, in practice, processes are often inadequately documented. Significant uncertainty arises without a clear understanding of the degree of changes required to redesign and implement processes. This uncertainty complicates the estimation of scope and budget. A business architecture that provides a structured approach to understanding and estimating the transformation required at the process level must be created to reduce this uncertainty.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-883716645"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Why it’s essential to understand Business Processes&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Every organization (business, government, not-for-profit) follows business processes to create value by completing tasks in a given sequence. Using processes, business users exchange information, money and materials to create value (by completing a given task). The success of the business is dependent on the efficiencies and effectiveness of these processes. They may complete all steps using paper, phone calls, and fax or use 100+ well-connected systems. These processes may not be documented at all, partially documented, or not updated in years.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Small businesses don’t formalize or document business processes, as an individual task processor's memory can hold ‘how things are done here.’ Their record-keeping systems are simpler, and transaction volume is low. They rely on an individual’s capability to get the job done. It doesn’t mean they don’t have to deal with complexities during transformation, but due to the smaller scale of their operation, they can ‘manage’ transitions in technology and market conditions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;However, in large organizations, processes span various business units, departments and IT applications. Data/process steps overlap between systems, often managed through swivel chairs (duplicate entries) and barely linked interfaces. Many process variances arise due to individual preferences as they slightly twist/bend/adapt the system to accommodate their way of working. Often, this results in adding extra business rules/logic to the application. Over the years, as people change jobs and processes evolve, this extra logic becomes ‘illogical/redundant/burden’, aka Technical Debt. It's challenging to eliminate the technical debt because you don't know what skeletons you will find.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Typical reasons for not documenting business processes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;There is no clear ownership for documenting end-to-end processes. Business analysts often work in silos of their expertise and do not cross departmental boundaries. System analysts often focus on 'system steps' and interfaces, and ignore manual tasks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business users go through the daily motions of process execution based on ‘how things are done here,’ and they have a hard time describing end-to-end processes.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Users and analysts are so busy completing assigned tasks that they lack the time, energy, and motivation to stop and document the process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Documenting business processes seems enormous when you extrapolate 100s of processes across 10s of departments utilizing multiple systems (applications).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Defining business architecture iteratively early in the project will resolve the above issues.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-687203140"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How do you define a business architecture for your transformation project?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Two separate artifacts define business architecture&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;1. Business Capability Model (BCM) that describes the&amp;nbsp;complete set of capabilities&amp;nbsp;an organization requires to fulfill its mission.&amp;nbsp;It’s typically structured hierarchically in three levels and describes WHAT an organization needs to&amp;nbsp;deliver business value and succeed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Rajen_Patel_0-1737427146231.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/214617i3A2D805D7C53B432/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rajen_Patel_0-1737427146231.png" alt="Rajen_Patel_0-1737427146231.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 1 - SAP Reference Business Capability Model (BCM)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. A Business Process Model (BPM) describes&amp;nbsp;the business processes of an enterprise&amp;nbsp;based on a standardized set of value-creating activities. It’s typically structured hierarchically in levels and describes HOW these value-creating activities will be performed&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Rajen_Patel_1-1737427146242.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/214618iD2B930BE6A94DF4C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rajen_Patel_1-1737427146242.png" alt="Rajen_Patel_1-1737427146242.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 2 - SAP Reference Business Process Model (BPM)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Linkage between BCM and BPM:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The lower process levels will identify which set of capabilities a process needs to execute effectively and which processes a particular capability will serve.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can use hierarchical elements of BCM and BPM for various purposes. A few advantages of building hierarchies are:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Group higher levels into ‘Strategic,’ ‘Core,’ and ‘Supporting,’ per the organization's strategic objectives.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Performing heat mapping for capability maturity, risks, and investment requirements&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ease of scheduling workshops and assigning capability/process owners and subject matter experts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Estimate implementation and change management efforts at various levels of the hierarchy&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note: SAP Reference Business Architecture provides template/industry variants for BCM and BPM - &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.signavio.com/products/collaboration-hub/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Signavio Process Collaboration Hub.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The Business Roles catalog and Business Data catalog are two other business architecture artifacts created in the explore phase. They can be utilized as input to create business activity flowcharts. This blog does not cover business capabilities (L3) linking to Solution capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-490689635"&gt;&lt;I&gt;Why do you need to create a business process hierarchy?&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to the SAP Activate methodology, the business scope is defined in the Explore phase of the project. You will need the following to estimate the transformation scope/effort.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;List of business processes that are generally in scope (to be refined in Fit-to-Standard [F2S] workshop)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Scope of change at a process level, including a) effort to configure the system for to-be processes and b) change management efforts&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The above is achieved by &lt;A title="capturing delta requirements during fit-to-standard workshops." href="https://community.sap.com/t5/business-transformation-champions-blog-posts/capturing-delta-requirements-a-guide-to-fit-to-standard-workshops/ba-p/13994533" target="_self"&gt;capturing delta requirements during fit-to-standard workshops.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A business process hierarchy (BPH) can structure a list of business processes that are part of the project's overall scope (also called a business process catalog). This process is iterative and typically incomplete until all F2S workshops are complete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-294176130"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;How do you create a business process hierarchy?&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can utilize BCM or BPM to create BPH.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Option 1: Business Capability Model (BCM) based grouping:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Domain (L1), Business Area (L2), Business Capability (L3) + Business Activity (L4)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A functional view of the business &lt;EM&gt;[difficult to stitch together E2E process]&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Assing business process (L4) to one prime business capability (L3). Typically, there is more than one capability required to perform a given process, so assigning a prime will make it easy to visualize the hierarchy&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Easier to identify links between business capabilities and solution capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Option 2: Business Process Model (BPM) based grouping:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Business Process (L1), Business Process Module (L2), Business Process Segment (L3) + Business Activity (L4)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Process-centric &lt;EM&gt;[difficult to tackle duplicate capabilities within an organization]&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It is easier to accommodate process variances at higher levels in the hierarchy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It is difficult to assign a single end-to-end process owner as processes span multiple functions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The nested nature of BPM makes it challenging to visualize in a tabular list.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="2025-01-23_08-58-02 - BCM BPM.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/215919i94AF45982C6B70CE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-01-23_08-58-02 - BCM BPM.jpg" alt="2025-01-23_08-58-02 - BCM BPM.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 3 - Business Process Hierarchy example for "Manage Purchase Order"&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A Business Activity (L4) can be referenced in multiple higher-level processes/process variances. Business activities can be nested inside other business activities to break complex business activities with many steps into manageable activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Business Activity (Level 4):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A 'granular business process' creates value for internal or external stakeholders.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;will have consistent naming conventions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;further broken down into tasks (level 5) and steps (level 6)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;will have a unique process flow that is defined using a BPMN diagram&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Steps to perform in a given sequence with decision points&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Application/s &lt;EM&gt;[input from Application catalog]&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Data utilized/analyzed/updated/produced&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;[input from Business Data catalog]&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Roles/agents responsible for the activity &lt;EM&gt;[input from Business Role catalog]&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fit-to-standard workshops will evaluate business processes at this level. During these workshops, define 'to-be' Business Process, create flowcharts (in BPMN), and capture delta requirements (backlog). Use SAP Best Practices as a starting point (reference SAP Signavio Process Navigator).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Rajen_Patel_3-1737427146255.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/214620i524F989ED6DCFBC3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Rajen_Patel_3-1737427146255.png" alt="Rajen_Patel_3-1737427146255.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Figure 4 - Understanding links between BCM, BPM, Business Activity, Task and Steps&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Tips:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Start with the SAP reference content and tailor it to your industry/organization needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Defining the first three levels before diving into listing business activities (L4)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Involve the Business and IT user community&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Caution:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can start this exercise on a spreadsheet, but it’s not scalable and not great for collaboration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get the right tool to manage BCM (e.g. #SAP LeanIX), BPM and BPH (e.g. &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Signavio/pd-p/088166be-6441-4660-9e5b-1a046de322bf" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="36-1"&gt;SAP Signavio&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set up naming standards.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;You have now defined the Business Process Hierarchy and have the list of all required business activities (L4). You are ready to execute a fit-to-standard workshop to capture the backlog &amp;lt;&lt;A title="Capturing Delta Requirements: A Guide to Fit-to-Standard Workshops" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/business-transformation-champions-blog-posts/capturing-delta-requirements-a-guide-to-fit-to-standard-workshops/ba-p/13994533" target="_blank"&gt;blog - Conduct F2S&lt;/A&gt;&amp;gt;. You can summarize the backlog at various hierarchy levels to scope the estimated project cost and change management efforts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-97662625"&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Defining a business architecture is a crucial step in any transformation project. It provides a structured approach to understanding and improving the processes that drive your organization. By mapping out these processes, you can identify inefficiencies, streamline operations, and ultimately achieve your transformation goals. Remember, the success of your project depends on transforming business processes (they need to attend the party!). So, take the time to get it right; your efforts will pay off in the long run.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--98850880"&gt;Reference:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://pubs.opengroup.org/togaf-standard/business-architecture/value-streams.html#_Toc95288332" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;TOGAF Value Streams Guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP Signavio Process Explorer – Accessed Jan 20, 2025 &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Signavio/pd-p/088166be-6441-4660-9e5b-1a046de322bf" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="36-2"&gt;SAP Signavio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.signavio.com/downloads/white-papers/process-mapping-basics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Process Mapping Basics: Guiding Your Organization Toward Effective Process Mapping - SAP Signavio&lt;/A&gt; - Accessed Jan 20, 2025&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.signavio.com/post/top-5-mistakes-naming-business-processes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;The Top 5 Mistakes You Can Make When Naming Business Processes&lt;/A&gt; - Accessed Jan 20, 2025&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Book: Business Architecture: Collecting, Connecting, and Correcting the Dots, by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.amazon.ca/Roger-Burlton/e/B001IQZRC6/ref=dp_byline_cont_book_1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Roger Burlton&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;. Technics Publication&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/defining-business-architecture-a-guide-for-estimating-transformation/ba-p/13991401"/>
    <published>2025-01-23T13:03:18.442000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cpq-integration-with-sirion-contract-lifecycle-management-clm/ba-p/14011679</id>
    <title>SAP CPQ Integration with Sirion Contract Lifecycle Management (CLM)</title>
    <updated>2025-02-09T14:23:21.185000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="0_8ZQb4dtO6UJpSgvZ.png" style="width: 720px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/223814i07FCCCB8B785EE5D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="0_8ZQb4dtO6UJpSgvZ.png" alt="0_8ZQb4dtO6UJpSgvZ.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1831768170"&gt;Background&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;A href="https://www.sirion.ai/library/contracts/elements-of-a-contract/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sirion Contract Lifecycle Management (CLM)&lt;/A&gt; sell side adapter for SAP CPQ seamlessly integrates the contracting flow to the sell side process. New quotes created on SAP CPQ are automatically transitioned into a Contract Request on Sirion CLM enabling a sync between two systems for the entire sales and contracting flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The package contains:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Integration flows for:&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; a) Initiation of Contract Draft Requests based on SAP CPQ quotes including line items&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; b) Tracking the contract request status and enabling quick access to the Contract on Sirion CLM&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-02-09_14-09-29.png" style="width: 771px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/223815i0045FB67F31C6AE9/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-02-09_14-09-29.png" alt="2025-02-09_14-09-29.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Configuration guides for SAP CPQ, SAP Cloud Integration, Sirion CLM and Integration flow are available on the Documents tab.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-02-09_14-09-36.png" style="width: 775px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/223816i431D9313C79A8CCC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-02-09_14-09-36.png" alt="2025-02-09_14-09-36.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The adapter can be configured by defining integration points, mapping data fields between SAP CPQ and Sirion CLM, setting up Sirion API authentication on SAP Cloud Integration.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;Note : This will be partner based Integration packages offered and supports for SAP CPQ.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1635254665"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPCPQIntegrationwithSirionContractLifecycleManagementCLM/overview" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration Package - SAP API Business Hub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1438741160"&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SAPCPQIntegrationwithSirionContractLifecycleManagementCLM/documents" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP CPQ - CLM Integration Document&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-center video-embed"&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FqwuW68Chkvw%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DqwuW68Chkvw&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FqwuW68Chkvw%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="200" height="112" scrolling="no" title="Introducing Sirion CLM" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/financial-management-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cpq-integration-with-sirion-contract-lifecycle-management-clm/ba-p/14011679"/>
    <published>2025-02-09T14:23:21.185000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/sap-business-accelerator-hub-domains-take-centerstage/ba-p/14018368</id>
    <title>SAP Business Accelerator Hub domains take centerstage</title>
    <updated>2025-02-18T06:03:22.838000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>aadityanigam</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/6727</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Previous articles in this series&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="What are business accelerators?" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/what-are-business-accelerators/ba-p/13607794" target="_blank"&gt;What are business accelerators?&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="SAP API Business Hub renamed to SAP Business Accelerator Hub" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/sap-api-business-hub-is-now-sap-business-accelerator-hub/ba-p/13548604" target="_blank"&gt;SAP API Business Hub renamed to SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A title="Introducing SAP Business Accelerator Hub Domains" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/introducing-sap-business-accelerator-hub-domains/ba-p/13576728" target="_blank"&gt;Introducing SAP Business Accelerator Hub Domains&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1831973792"&gt;A brief recap&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub now hosts a variety of content catering to, sometimes diametrically opposite persona like pro-code developer or a no code user. To ensure all users have a great experience on the site we introduced the concept of domains.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We liked it so much we removed all our previous navigations and made it our top level navigation. That is what this blog covers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1635460287"&gt;Moving domains to centerstage&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="AcceleratorHubDomains.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/226377iC522D353C982DDF3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="AcceleratorHubDomains.jpg" alt="AcceleratorHubDomains.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;We started with&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/integrations/packages" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/build" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Build&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;domains, then we added &lt;A title="Analytics on the Business Accelerator Hub" href="https://hub.sap.com/analytics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Analytics&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;A title="Transformation domain on the Business Accelerator Hub" href="https://hub.sap.com/transformation" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Transformation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;We like this idea so much and believe in it that we moved this up to the top menu!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;So where did the other menu items go? Under the Explore menu item on the top right of the window!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;I really love this screen shot below, it shows &lt;STRONG&gt;90% of the valuable things you are able to do with the SAP Business Accelerator Hub.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Explore Acclerator Hub.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/226378i635653E4AFF13651/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Explore Acclerator Hub.png" alt="Explore Acclerator Hub.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;But this does not answer where did 'Discover Integrations' go?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It is the landing page of the Integration domain which fits, right?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Discover Integrations.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/226379i35550BBDE923783A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Discover Integrations.png" alt="Discover Integrations.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/sap-business-accelerator-hub-domains-take-centerstage/ba-p/14018368"/>
    <published>2025-02-18T06:03:22.838000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-process-innovation-with-enterprise-automation-sap-signavio-and/ba-p/14054685</id>
    <title>Accelerate Process Innovation with Enterprise Automation: SAP Signavio and SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-03-25T09:06:31.610000+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Palak</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/17091</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The ability to intelligently automate business processes is top of mind for many stakeholders involved in process management across organizations. According to a recent IDC study, annual spending on Intelligent Process Automation (IPA) technologies is projected to reach $102 billion by 2028. Of this, $19.9 billion will be allocated to AI-powered automation tools, with an impressive annual growth rate of 43.4%.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While there will be certainly no shortage in resources to spend for automation software, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the real challenge remains in the details: How can organizations implement a holistic approach for process excellence, which allows them to manage processes, identify bottlenecks, deliver scalable automations and integrate their process extension within a holistic process landscape. In another &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-builders-blog-posts/how-to-get-started-with-enterprise-automation/ba-p/13582512" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blogpost&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; by Manuel&lt;SPAN&gt;,we have already outlined in detail how SAP’s framework on Enterprise Automation delivers a solution to the problem statement mentioned above.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And this blogpost series will offer you a more detailed guidance on the interconnectivity of each service included in Enterprise Automation which are:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;and of course &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Signavio.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s explore the value you can unlock for your processes by combining SAP Signavio with SAP Integration Suite in this one in this one.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;You can refer the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/supercharge-efficiency-with-enterprise-automation-sap-build-and-sap/ba-p/14006724" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt; to understand SAP Build and SAP Integration Suite use case pattern. Also, refer the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/enhancing-business-agility-with-enterprise-automation-sap-build-and-sap/ba-p/14048503" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt; to understand SAP Signavio and SAP Build use case pattern.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is Enterprise Automation?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As outlined in previous &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-builders-blog-posts/how-to-get-started-with-enterprise-automation/ba-p/13582512" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blogpost&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Enterprise Automation with SAP: Enterprise automation with SAP software provides an integrated set of tools for process mining, automation, integration, monitoring, and optimization of your processes and workflows. It helps you quickly and intuitively gain insights into your business processes and identify the right automation tool for the right outcome. While each solution can be leveraged independently, Enterprise Automation offers native integration between SAP Build, SAP integration Suite and SAP Signavio – supplemented with best practices, guidance and pre-build content which can be implemented directly.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Palak_4-1742816896080.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/241760iBE0B0BD48AEF64BB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Palak_4-1742816896080.jpeg" alt="Palak_4-1742816896080.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Signavio&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; provides visibility into business processes and potential bottlenecks, root-cause analysis, and suggestions for improvement based on 200,000 industry benchmarks and best practices. This detailed understanding of inefficiencies across your organization enables you to optimize and automate processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is an integration platform as a service with thousands of prebuilt integrations, APIs, events and connectors to SAP and third-party software applications. The suite reduces complexity across on-premise and multi-cloud environments, helping you optimize comprehensive business processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; to create automations and applications using&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; drag-and-drop&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the low-code and no-code&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;design &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;tools. Including pre&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;-&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;built automations and connectors for SAP software and third-&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;party systems, the solutions let your business experts rapidly address process inefficiencies&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Here you can also see a visualization of the main components and its respective capabilities:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Palak_5-1742816896099.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/241762iCEBB03CEC193B114/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Palak_5-1742816896099.png" alt="Palak_5-1742816896099.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Leverage the combined power of SAP Signavio and SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Palak_6-1742816896112.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/241761iD5B12610BB8C32BD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Palak_6-1742816896112.png" alt="Palak_6-1742816896112.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;st&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; scenario: Mine Third Party Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;To identify inefficiencies and biggest automation potential in your processes, Signavio lets you consistently mine data within and across your IT software systems by leveraging the power of SAP Integration Suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can leverage the broad range of connectors and adapters offered by SAP Integration Suite to seamlessly integrate with any business application by designing your own iflows or by leveraging&amp;nbsp; pre-built content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Palak_7-1742816896121.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/241763iE1B92CEC79A7717C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Palak_7-1742816896121.png" alt="Palak_7-1742816896121.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/products/SAPSignavio/integrations/packages" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;, you’ll&amp;nbsp; find pre-built content connected to common third-party applications such as Salesforce, Coupa , Microsoft dynamics and many more to come.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each integration flow serves the purpose of replicating business objects and their associated events from third-party systems into SAP Signavio Process Intelligence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;The combined power of SAP Signavio and SAP Integration Suite helps you jump-start process mining initiatives and save time with ready-to-use content for multiple SAP and non SAP systems. You can now effectively prioritize your process mining efforts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Please refer the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/extract-salesforce-data-into-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-using-sap/ba-p/13804734" target="_blank"&gt;blogpost&lt;/A&gt; by Hoang on how to leverage pre-built content from non-SAP system like Salesforce.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you would like to develop your own connectivity logic using Cloud Integration capability ,please refer the &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/setup-upload-ci-signavio-pi.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;developer tutorial&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Palak_1-1742867479263.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/241954i0544FE73F53B0B7C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Palak_1-1742867479263.png" alt="Palak_1-1742867479263.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2nd &amp;nbsp;scenario: Connect mining to third party tools&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Another pattern to trigger processes without human intervention based on insights gained is using Cloud Integration capability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Some of the scenarios in which the pattern could be leveraged be:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Correction of Master Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;SAP Signavio Process Insights can identify issues such as incorrect or incomplete master data. Based on this insight, an integration flow in SAP Integration Suite could be triggered to automatically correct or enrich the master data in the relevant SAP or non SAP system&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic Customer Notifications&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;If SAP Signavio Process Insights detects delays in the order-to-cash process, SAP Integration Suite could trigger notifications to customers regarding potential shipping delays or other relevant updates.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automated Invoice Reconciliation&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Signavio Process Insights can identify discrepancies in invoice processing.This could trigger an integration flow in SAP Integration Suite to automatically reconcile invoices with corresponding purchase orders and goods receipts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Proactive Inventory Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When SAP Signavio Process Insights identifies potential stockouts or overstock situations, SAP Integration Suite could trigger an integration to adjust safety stock levels, initiate replenishment orders, or optimize warehouse operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please refer &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/signavio-process-intelligence/user-guide/setting-up-integration-with-sap-cloud-integration" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt; to understand how to configure cloud integration based actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Palak_0-1742871512021.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/241978i7E3E5F7F0340051C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Palak_0-1742871512021.png" alt="Palak_0-1742871512021.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3rd scenario: Event Driven Architectures&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;To be able to continuously improve processes in real time, Process analyst can configure actions in SAP Signavio based on insights gained using process data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using Event Mesh capability of SAP Integration suite, any SAP or non-SAP processes can be triggered for improvement. Thereby, allowing the system to proactively identify issues and initiate corrective actions based on real-time monitoring of process performance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Examples of event-based process improvements triggered by SIGNAL queries (&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/signavio-process-intelligence/signal-guide/intro" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Signavio Analytical Language&lt;/A&gt;) being run in SAP Signavio:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Alerting on order delays:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If a SIGNAL query detects that an order is taking significantly longer than usual to process, it could publish an event to trigger a workflow to the order management team to investigate and take corrective action in a non-SAP system&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Escalating customer support issues:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When a SIGNAL query identifies a high volume of customer support tickets related to a specific product, it can automatically trigger a workflow in a non-SAP system by publishing an event to escalate the issue to a higher tier support team.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic resource allocation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on real-time workload data from a SIGNAL query, an event can be published to trigger a non SAP process that could automatically reassign tasks to available team members to optimize capacity utilization.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please refer the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/signavio-process-intelligence/user-guide/setting-up-integration-with-sap-event-mesh" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;help documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; as to how the event-based actions are configured by a Process Analyst in SAP Signavio.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Palak_0-1742867428418.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/241953i36580A1CA0A1F61B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Palak_0-1742867428418.png" alt="Palak_0-1742867428418.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;I hope this blog post has helped you identify the key synergies between SAP Signavio and SAP Integration Suite and how they can enable seamless automation across your enterprise. Please remember that the use cases provided are just examples and can be tailored and refined to meet your specific needs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For further guidance, I’ve included links to additional blog posts and resources on the Help Portal that will assist you in implementing these use cases. If you're interested in exploring more scenarios related to Enterprise Automation, feel free to check out the following links:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/enterprise-automation.html?campaigncode=crm-ya22-int-1517065&amp;amp;source=ppc-de-googleads-search-71700000112010172-58700008741433987-btp_btp-x-x-x&amp;amp;dfa=1&amp;amp;campaigncode=crm-ya22-int-1517065&amp;amp;source=ppc-de-googleads-search-71700000112010172-58700008741433987-btp_btp-x-x-x&amp;amp;dfa=1&amp;amp;gad_source=1&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQiAhbi8BhDIARIsAJLOlucBTfD581QQmTOXJpIyBvCBQji33lBXlXVe-l_G84mlRbwbizdWbL8aAqJBEALw_wcB&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Official Enterprise Automation with SAP page&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to get started with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-builders-blog-posts/how-to-get-started-with-enterprise-automation/ba-p/13582512" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enterprise Automation Guide&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2024/07/b0a21f38-cc7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whitepaper: Transition to SAP S/4HANA with Enterprise Automation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/enterprise-automation/product-tour.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enterprise Automation with SAP Product Tour&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/enterprise-automation.html?video=72fb7c18-b57e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enterprise Automation with SAP webinar&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/accelerate-process-innovation-with-enterprise-automation-sap-signavio-and/ba-p/14054685"/>
    <published>2025-03-25T09:06:31.610000+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-partner-content-on-sap-business-accelerator-hub-q1-25/ba-p/14090098</id>
    <title>New Partner Content on SAP Business Accelerator Hub (Q1 ’25)</title>
    <updated>2025-04-30T14:31:04.795000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnanthNatarajan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/79594</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In continuation of our previous &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/new-partner-content-on-sap-business-accelerator-hub-q4-24/ba-p/13975842" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;, we are pleased to share further updates and maintain the momentum of delivering relevant insights to our community.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this installment of our blog series, discover the latest Integration packages published&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;by our partners during Q1 2025, along with a high-level summary of the year so far.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For complete details on each partner's content, refer to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/allpartners" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;partners listing&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;which is available on the home page of SAP Business Accelerator Hub.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1207588960" id="toc-hId-1839120842"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;KaTe GmbH&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId-1771690056"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Integration package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/KaTeRESTfulAdapter/overview" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KaTe RESTful Adapter&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The KaTe RESTful Adapter enables you to use Open APIs with SAP Integration Suite with a simplified development approach. It features the same set of capabilities as our existing RESTful adapter for SAP Process Orchestration and allows you to use SAP Cloud Integration as full featured Open API client or server.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1207588960" id="toc-hId-1446093832"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;NTT DATA Business Solutions AG&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId-1378663046"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Integration package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/SAPLeanIXIntegrationwithSAPBusinessTechnologyPlatform/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP LeanIX Integration with SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;This integration package is designed to synchronize the&amp;nbsp;SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) Account Structure (Global and Subaccounts) with SAP LeanIX, automatically creating Platform Factsheets in SAP LeanIX based on SAP BTP best practices for account structuring.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1207588960" id="toc-hId-1053066822"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Incture Technologies Private Limited&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId-985636036"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Integration package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/AnaplanIntegrationwithSAPAriba/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Anaplan Integration with SAP Ariba&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;Anaplan Integration with SAP Ariba package facilitates seamless data transfer between Anaplan and SAP Ariba to automate the creation of Purchase Requisitions. The integration enables Anaplan to send structured procurement data to SAP Ariba, ensuring efficient and accurate requisition processing.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are interested in&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partnering with SAP Business Accelerator Hub,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;please refer to this&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/partnerwithus" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;section&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for more details.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stay tuned for further updates and information by the end of the next quarter!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-partner-content-on-sap-business-accelerator-hub-q1-25/ba-p/14090098"/>
    <published>2025-04-30T14:31:04.795000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/extract-sap-ariba-data-into-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-using-sap/ba-p/14099400</id>
    <title>Extract SAP Ariba data into SAP Signavio Process Intelligence using SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-05-14T08:22:11.013000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>themmert</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/43082</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Overview&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To succeed with end-to-end digital procurement transformation, we at SAP Signavio aim to cover the whole process and IT landscape of our customers, comprising SAP, SAP Ariba as well as external systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I am happy to share the release of our out-of-the-box integration content for SAP Ariba connectivity to SAP Signavio Process Intelligence that you can use to perform process mining analysis on end-to-end procurement processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Challenge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Currently existing integration between SAP Signavio Process Intelligence and SAP Ariba is cumbersome and relies on a customized BTP app and consulting services for modifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Value proposition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Seamlessly connect to SAP Ariba using native 'Cloud Integration' from the SAP Integration Suite. This streamlined integration enables efficient data extraction from SAP Ariba into SAP Signavio Process Intelligence, unlocking powerful insights and process mining capabilities for procurement workflows.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Reuse integration capabilities and preconfigured integration packages for SAP Ariba in SAP Cloud Integration data services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;Provide insights into procurement process inefficiencies, enabling data-driven decision-making and continuous process improvement&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to get started?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s jointly explore where you can find the data extractor content and how to use it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, launch the SAP Business Accelerator Hub at &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/allproducts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;API.SAP.COM&lt;/A&gt;, and navigate to &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/products/SAPSignavio/overview?target=SAPAriba" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Signavio&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_28-1747076080438.png" style="width: 662px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260199i68C28B5463715095/image-dimensions/662x409?v=v2" width="662" height="409" role="button" title="themmert_28-1747076080438.png" alt="themmert_28-1747076080438.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then select the &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/products/SAPSignavio/overview?target=SAPAriba" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Ariba&lt;/A&gt; integration:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_29-1747076080443.png" style="width: 646px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260197i5F18E24566A22C8F/image-dimensions/646x340?v=v2" width="646" height="340" role="button" title="themmert_29-1747076080443.png" alt="themmert_29-1747076080443.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, select the SAP Ariba API Extractor for SAP Signavio Process Intelligence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A brief overview sketches the purpose of this data extractor. Once, navigated to the “Integration Flow” tab, the following view appears:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_30-1747076080449.png" style="width: 640px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260198i440DBAE175D5024C/image-dimensions/640x323?v=v2" width="640" height="323" role="button" title="themmert_30-1747076080449.png" alt="themmert_30-1747076080449.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For each of these integration flows, more information such as configuration file templates, user manuals and change logs are available for download. For illustration, the screenshot below shows the information flow of the Data Extractor.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_31-1747076080459.png" style="width: 636px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260200iA35FF9CC1F2479F8/image-dimensions/636x404?v=v2" width="636" height="404" role="button" title="themmert_31-1747076080459.png" alt="themmert_31-1747076080459.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Install Data Extractor in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this Data Extractor meets your goals, log into the SAP Integration and navigate to “Discover/Integration”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_32-1747076080466.png" style="width: 620px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260202i08142C23C9AED793/image-dimensions/620x310?v=v2" width="620" height="310" role="button" title="themmert_32-1747076080466.png" alt="themmert_32-1747076080466.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this search window, search for “Ariba API”, and the new Data Extractor will appear.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_33-1747076080477.png" style="width: 620px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260201i90BB02E2FD9C0D28/image-dimensions/620x310?v=v2" width="620" height="310" role="button" title="themmert_33-1747076080477.png" alt="themmert_33-1747076080477.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once you select the package “SAP Ariba API Extractor for Signavio Process Intelligence”, more information regarding the included objects is provided.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To install the package, just click on “Copy” to transfer the package in our design area for configuration and deployment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="themmert_34-1747076080487.png" style="width: 620px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/260203i9EA1943E63F64039/image-dimensions/620x310?v=v2" width="620" height="310" role="button" title="themmert_34-1747076080487.png" alt="themmert_34-1747076080487.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If this step is completed: Congratulations, the new package is installed. Finally, connect the pipelines in Process Intelligence with the Data Extractor and enjoy analysing your SAP Ariba processes in SAP Signavio Process Intelligence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To get you started, here some further links:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/products/SAPSignavio/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Signavio on SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/products/SAPSignavio/overview?target=SAPAriba" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Content: SAP Ariba Integration with SAP Signavio Process Intelligence&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you don't want to start from scratch, have a look at the following two Value Accelerators, which already use this Data Extractor:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/signavio-process-intelligence/accelerators/procure-to-pay-in-sap-ariba" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Procure to Pay in SAP Ariba&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/signavio-process-intelligence/accelerators/source-products-and-services-in-sap-ariba" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Source Product and Services in SAP Ariba&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/extract-sap-ariba-data-into-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-using-sap/ba-p/14099400"/>
    <published>2025-05-14T08:22:11.013000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/helpful-links-for-your-sap-transformation/ba-p/14101989</id>
    <title>Helpful links for your SAP transformation</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T06:41:47.799000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>jkmaeda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/154392</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The architecture chapter can use and recommend the tools and services below to guide and equip (and create principles and guardrails to) professionals and managers to support evidence-based decisions for your business and digital transformations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;The links below can help to provide visibility and clarity of your SAP ecosystem, especially to non-SAP professionals and leaders, so they can also make better questions when discovering and exploring the myriad of capabilities that SAP can offer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;You will need an SAP S-user (&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;me.sap.com&lt;/A&gt;) and an SAP account (&lt;A class="" href="http://sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;sap.com&lt;/A&gt;) to access the content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/processnavigator/HomePage" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Best Practices based on SAP Signavio Process Navigator&lt;/A&gt;, alternatively, &lt;A class="" href="https://www.signavio.com/products/process-explorer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Signavio Process Explorer&lt;/A&gt; is the gateway to get insights into SAP’s process portfolio and leverage related process implementation guidance and reference business and solution architectures. These include business-capability and solution maps, process models, metrics, industry best practices, and SAP best-practice and product recommendations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_0-1747283066894.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261344i545A3FC521671638/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_0-1747283066894.png" alt="jkmaeda711_0-1747283066894.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_1-1747283066895.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261342iF15ACE0C7D64064D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_1-1747283066895.png" alt="jkmaeda711_1-1747283066895.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://fioriappslibrary.hana.ondemand.com/sap/fix/externalViewer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Fiori Apps Reference Library&lt;/A&gt; to explore, plan and implement SAP Fiori, the latest user experience from SAP including all relevant content for the SAP Fiori launchpad.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_2-1747283066895.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261343i42C0706F280C57CE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_2-1747283066895.png" alt="jkmaeda711_2-1747283066895.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/A&gt; to explore and understand different architecture patterns which can be implemented using SAP BTP services.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_3-1747283066895.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261346i9214E50CBBC4C0CD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_3-1747283066895.png" alt="jkmaeda711_3-1747283066895.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/sap-btp-guidance-framework/guidance-framework/what-is-sap-btp-guidance-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/A&gt; for architects, developers, and administrators.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_4-1747283066895.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261347iA227CC743317BCB7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_4-1747283066895.png" alt="jkmaeda711_4-1747283066895.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://hub.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt; (or Intelligent Enterprise Reference Solution Architecture) to help discover, consume, and create integrations, extensions, and innovations.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_5-1747283066895.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261345i7CBCBA4BAD7906CB/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_5-1747283066895.jpeg" alt="jkmaeda711_5-1747283066895.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://go.support.sap.com/roadmapviewer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Activate&lt;/A&gt; provides a clear guided methodology to deploy, adopt and extend new capabilities with different approaches, e.g., agile or waterfall, cloud, hybrid or on-premise, implementation or upgrade.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_6-1747283066899.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261349i8713E59455C6A997/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_6-1747283066899.png" alt="jkmaeda711_6-1747283066899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Road Maps&lt;/A&gt; support the journey to SAP’s future product portfolio. Before customising, check for future enhancements.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_7-1747283066899.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261350i845ACB1C7D5CD6FD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_7-1747283066899.png" alt="jkmaeda711_7-1747283066899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://influence.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Customer Influence &lt;/A&gt;offers a range of programs that give customers the opportunity to influence SAP software development decisions, request specific enhancements or features, and adopt new innovations early on. Before customising, check (and vote) for opportunities and ideas to speed up SAP’s development and delivery of new requirements. Customers should engage the SAP account team to work internally with the development and product management teams.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_8-1747283066899.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261348i4762E5DEBDCDAA81/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_8-1747283066899.png" alt="jkmaeda711_8-1747283066899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://support.sap.com/content/dam/support/en_us/library/ssp/offerings-and-programs/support-services/sap-security-optimization-services-portfolio/SAP_Secure_Operations_Map.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Secure Operations Map&lt;/A&gt; ensures smooth operation of SAP solutions by taking action proactively, before severe security problems occur.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_9-1747283066899.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261351i32B0BD42EEE95E2C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_9-1747283066899.png" alt="jkmaeda711_9-1747283066899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Depending on use case, when the company is ready for transformational initiatives, use the tools and services available to customers:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://valuemanagement.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Value Lifecycle Manager&lt;/A&gt; for a value analysis, total costs of ownership calculation and more.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_10-1747283066899.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261352i5635781D5AA40E45/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_10-1747283066899.png" alt="jkmaeda711_10-1747283066899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/readinesscheck" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Readiness Check&lt;/A&gt; conducts a detailed analysis of our existing SAP system to help plan our digital transformation. For example, SAP S/4HANA Conversion, SAP S/4HANA Upgrade, SAP BW/4HANA Conversion, SAP ERP Usage and Data Profiling, SAP Customer Experience Solutions, SAP SuccessFactors Solutions, SAP Cloud ALM, SAP Datasphere, SAP BW Bridge.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_11-1747283066899.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261353i34728C4FB8A13BD5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_11-1747283066899.png" alt="jkmaeda711_11-1747283066899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/app/customcodeanalytics" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Custom Code Analytics&lt;/A&gt; uses aggregated Custom Code Management (CCM) data from your SAP Solution Manager. The application gives an overview about the custom code footprint of the ABAP systems and provides insights about code quality and usage.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_12-1747283066899.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261354iB32C17112B6DD917/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_12-1747283066899.png" alt="jkmaeda711_12-1747283066899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://support.sap.com/en/offerings-programs/enterprise-support/enterprise-support-academy/continuous-quality-check-improvement-services.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Continuous Quality Check &amp;amp; Improvement Services&lt;/A&gt; are included in the SAP Enterprise Support contract. After each service, you receive a service report with an executive summary, findings and a detailed action plan to mitigate risks or improve your situation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_13-1747283066899.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261355i49A57E72CD7EC133/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_13-1747283066899.png" alt="jkmaeda711_13-1747283066899.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://webinars.sap.com/customer-evolution-kit/en/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Customer Evolution Kit&lt;/A&gt; for cost-free engagement to accelerate digital transformation to the cloud.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_14-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261356i4F94D324849E0916/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_14-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_14-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://url.sap/discovery-edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Signavio, Process Insights, discovery edition&lt;/A&gt;, the successor of Process Discovery and Pathfinder on Spotlight, can get innovation recommendations based on the usage of the current system.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_15-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261359i8D4950588D68988B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_15-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_15-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://apphaus.sap.com/offering" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP AppHaus&lt;/A&gt; and its network partners offer different engagement types. From discovering innovation opportunities like rethinking business processes and user interfaces to delivering scalable solutions.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_16-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261358i4D69678808334542/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_16-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_16-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://cal.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Appliance Library&lt;/A&gt; offers a quick and easy way to create SAP workloads in our cloud infrastructure.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_17-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261357iE8B38D01C5A8FDC2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_17-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_17-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/registration/protected/background/digital-discover-assessment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Digital Discovery and Assessment&lt;/A&gt; is used to plan the scope of a planned SAP S/4HANA project (for SAP partners only).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/sic" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Simplification Item Catalogue&lt;/A&gt; helps better prepare for the transition to SAP S/4HANA and SAP BW/4HANA. It provides a description of all relevant changes that might have an impact when converting from SAP ERP to SAP S/4HANA or SAP BW to SAP BW/4HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_18-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261361i20C768D226F1453D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_18-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_18-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/extendS4" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Extensibility Explorer for SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt; covers a broad spectrum of topics that allow us to adapt standard business software to our business needs by leveraging the extensibility patterns and sample scenarios from SAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_19-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261360i2602D31DA67ACA30/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_19-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_19-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;When customising is required (&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2022/11/96974181-4f7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;Clean Core&lt;/A&gt;), refer to the following frameworks and additional resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/store.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Store&lt;/A&gt; is a digital marketplace with over 2000+ extensions where we can discover, try, and buy solutions from SAP partners.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_20-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261362iFD07539412AC72D8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_20-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_20-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/partners/find.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Partner Finder&lt;/A&gt; to find the best SAP partners to meet our needs.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_21-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261365iF330598191182D94/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_21-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_21-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model&lt;/A&gt; helps build cloud-native applications with maximised productivity at minimised costs, based on proven best practices served out of the box.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_22-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261363i9F5F3A4C465B09EA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_22-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_22-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAPUI5" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP UI Development Toolkit for HTML5&lt;/A&gt; is a platform for developing rich user interfaces for modern web business applications.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_23-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261364iC51AB1216C733D67/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_23-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_23-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learning.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Learning&lt;/A&gt; offers free online courses, tutorials, trials, and official SAP help documentation for anyone who wants to build in-demand SAP skills and prepare for SAP certifications.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_24-1747283066901.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261368i3DD38F73F6259443/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_24-1747283066901.png" alt="jkmaeda711_24-1747283066901.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/community.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP Community&lt;/A&gt; offers access to experts, knowledge sharing, the latest news, resources, and insights on SAP solutions and technologies.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_25-1747283066900.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261366iF395E00BB05D35E7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_25-1747283066900.png" alt="jkmaeda711_25-1747283066900.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc noreferrer"&gt;SAP for Me&lt;/A&gt; is the digital companion to interact with SAP and aggregates important alerts, metrics, and insights about the SAP product portfolio with a single access point.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_26-1747283066901.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261367iE4CB07810843F80A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_26-1747283066901.png" alt="jkmaeda711_26-1747283066901.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/architecture" target="_blank" rel="noopener ugc nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Microsoft Azure Architecture Centre&lt;/A&gt; on guidance for architecting solutions on Azure using established patterns and practices, including SAP on Azure (as Microsoft is our strategic partner).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="jkmaeda711_27-1747283066901.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261369iBFD56170C93BA0BA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jkmaeda711_27-1747283066901.png" alt="jkmaeda711_27-1747283066901.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;I hope it also helps guide and drive your project. It is a starting point to prepare your colleagues to support business and tech decisions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Surely I missed many helpful links here, so feel free to add yours in the comments too. Thanks!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Originally posted on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/helpful-links-your-sap-transformation-jacques-maeda-rawlc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/helpful-links-for-your-sap-transformation/ba-p/14101989"/>
    <published>2025-05-15T06:41:47.799000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-maxattention-blog-posts/explore-our-signature-offerings-access-essential-product-information/ba-p/14099794</id>
    <title>Explore Our Signature Offerings: Access Essential Product Information</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T18:03:27.228000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aletta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1927228</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1839395684"&gt;Explore Our Signature Offerings: Access Essential Product Information&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAPSapphireBanner2025.png" style="width: 802px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/261756i0777678CDB0E29F2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAPSapphireBanner2025.png" alt="SAPSapphireBanner2025.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Sapphire&lt;/A&gt; is the premier flagship event series to learn about SAP's strategic vision, new innovations, and industry-leading solutions in action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In Anja Schneider's (SVP, Global Head of Premium Engagement &amp;amp; Advisory, SAP SE) Spotlight Sessions in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire/flow/sap/so25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1742444751470001zNuk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Orlando&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/sapphire/flow/sap/sm25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1742830750977001mSZg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Madrid&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;you will discover how SAP MaxAttention and RISE with SAP turn strategy into action through cloud adoption, AI at scale, and continuous transformation. Anja will also illustrate how such offerings connect data, applications, and business AI to drive innovation — helping leading companies cut infrastructure costs, accelerate go-lives, and transform board-level decision-making.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog post will provide you with all the necessary links so you can take action right away.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1771964898"&gt;SAP MaxAttention&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find out more about SAP MaxAttention and benefit from a strategic long-term partnership for successful collaboration with SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/services-support/premium-support/maxattention.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Check out the services&lt;/A&gt; and directly request a meeting&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1575451393"&gt;AI assistance from SAP MaxAttention&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This &lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/asset/preview/59df0bf04a3f636119f4b56b5152b6c8c965d37a?query=AI+assistance+from+SAP+MaxAttention" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;introductory video&lt;/A&gt; including a demo dashboard will show you what AI assistance from SAP MaxAttention is about.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you are interested in updates on AI assistance from SAP MaxAttention, reach out to your SAP Account Executive or TQM.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1378937888"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unlocking the Power of your business data: This is our fully managed SaaS solution that unifies and governs all SAP data and seamlessly connects with third-party data&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get an overview and take the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;product tour&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Get a free &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/sap-migration-assessment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud Assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1182424383"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore our Business Transformation Content &amp;amp; Accelerators designed to support customers’ strategic objectives and industry specific needs alongside our SAP solutions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Central entry point&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-maxattention-blog-posts/explore-our-signature-offerings-access-essential-product-information/ba-p/14099794"/>
    <published>2025-05-15T18:03:27.228000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/data-products-in-sap-business-accelerator-hub/ba-p/14107310</id>
    <title>Data Products in SAP Business Accelerator Hub</title>
    <updated>2025-05-21T06:57:01.567000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>sruti_sagaram</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/396236</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="DataProducts_Comics.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/264036iC44A2BC969240B98/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="DataProducts_Comics.png" alt="DataProducts_Comics.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Find more information about &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/business-accelerator-hub/sap-business-accelerator-hub/data-products-3839648004cb44c1b20f92685c9d4cba" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Products&lt;/A&gt; on the SAP Business Accelerator Hub.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/data-products-in-sap-business-accelerator-hub/ba-p/14107310"/>
    <published>2025-05-21T06:57:01.567000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-implement-alert-notification-service-in-cloud-application/ba-p/14111080</id>
    <title>How To Implement Alert Notification Service in Cloud Application Programming Model (CAPM) Project</title>
    <updated>2025-05-27T09:30:42.241000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Aditya12</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1506379</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Go to Subaccount -&amp;gt; Go To Instance and Subscription -&amp;gt; Click Create Button&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265733i6C9275D7C0DECBA8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 1.png" alt="Page 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;: In Service Select Alert Notification and In the Instance Name Section Give Any Name, Leave Other Fields as It Is.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="page 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265734i966EBF5B4ED19503/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="page 2.png" alt="page 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If you did not create any space then you see create space option just below space filed. Just click on that give space name and choose roles and click Create&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="page 3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265735iC9F465BDA9C629FD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="page 3.png" alt="page 3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 4.png" style="width: 907px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265736iDFCD4A2E6957C8B5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 4.png" alt="Page 4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&lt;STRONG&gt; Access SAP Alert Notification Cockpit and Create a Subscription&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;After creating an instance, it will be listed under &lt;STRONG&gt;Instance and Subscription&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on the &lt;STRONG&gt;instance name&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the list.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;This will open the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Alert Notification Cockpit&lt;/STRONG&gt; in a new page.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the cockpit, navigate to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Subscription&lt;/STRONG&gt; section.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt; button to start creating a new subscription.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 7.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265744i1567FA947D603F75/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 7.png" alt="Page 7.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Create Subscription with Condition and Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create Subscription:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to the subscription creation section.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter a random name for the subscription.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt; to proceed to the next step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create Condition:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter a random name for the condition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;STRONG&gt;Condition&lt;/STRONG&gt; section, choose the criteria for triggering the email.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Example: Set eventType to &lt;STRONG&gt;Contains&lt;/STRONG&gt; → Warning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;If multiple conditions are created, you can select the relevant one in the next step.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Save and Next&lt;/STRONG&gt; to proceed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Create Action:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Email&lt;/STRONG&gt; as the action type.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Next&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Action Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Email Address&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the recipient.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Subject Template&lt;/STRONG&gt; (for email header)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Payload Template&lt;/STRONG&gt; (for email body)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;On the next page, select the appropriate action and click &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Notes:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note 1:&lt;/STRONG&gt; You can create &lt;STRONG&gt;Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Conditions&lt;/STRONG&gt; separately by navigating directly to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Action&lt;/STRONG&gt; or &lt;STRONG&gt;Condition&lt;/STRONG&gt; tabs from the left-side menu.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note 2:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The recipient email address will receive a confirmation email. They must &lt;STRONG&gt;accept&lt;/STRONG&gt; it to start receiving notifications.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note 3:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To send &lt;STRONG&gt;Email Subject&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Body&lt;/STRONG&gt; dynamically from your application payload, leave the &lt;STRONG&gt;Subject Template&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Payload Template&lt;/STRONG&gt; fields &lt;STRONG&gt;blank&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 8.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265750i351A7A6B76BB3B1B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 8.png" alt="Page 8.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 9.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265751i3359E9ED8D6A2740/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 9.png" alt="Page 9.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 10.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265752i62885F9D28872361/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 10.png" alt="Page 10.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 11.1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265754i826EFB2275910910/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 11.1.png" alt="Page 11.1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 12.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265755i393575A9607287BD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 12.png" alt="Page 12.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 13.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265756iB4D37BBBA96A3E7C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 13.png" alt="Page 13.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 5: Create a Service Key for the Alert Notification Instance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;After setting up the Alert Notification instance, locate it in the list.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on the &lt;STRONG&gt;arrow ( &amp;gt; )&lt;/STRONG&gt; next to the instance name.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A panel will open on the &lt;STRONG&gt;right side&lt;/STRONG&gt; of the screen.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the right panel, look for the &lt;STRONG&gt;Service Key&lt;/STRONG&gt; section.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt; button.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;A popup window will appear for creating a new service key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enter a &lt;STRONG&gt;name&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the service key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt; to generate the key.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 5.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265737i7F88A268CAC50106/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 5.png" alt="Page 5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 14.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265759i7A35E6E28DB09C22/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 14.png" alt="Page 14.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 6: Create Destination for Use in CAPM Application&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;After creating the &lt;STRONG&gt;service key&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the next step is to create a &lt;STRONG&gt;destination&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;This destination will be used in your &lt;STRONG&gt;CAPM application&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;To get the required details (URL, Client ID, Client Secret):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on the &lt;STRONG&gt;instance&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;View Credentials&lt;/STRONG&gt; to open the service key details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Copy the &lt;STRONG&gt;URL&lt;/STRONG&gt;, &lt;STRONG&gt;Client ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and &lt;STRONG&gt;Client Secret&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the credentials.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the left-side panel, go to &lt;STRONG&gt;Connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt; → &lt;STRONG&gt;Destinations&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click the &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Destination&lt;/STRONG&gt; button.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Fill in the destination details as shown in the reference screenshot:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;URL&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Authentication&lt;/STRONG&gt; method&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Client ID&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Client Secret&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Any other required fields&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt; to save the destination.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 15.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265762i70235718BAC9ED12/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 15.png" alt="Page 15.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="page 19.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265763i98E6640B8EDD43A3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="page 19.png" alt="page 19.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page  20.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265765i44E990DBDF9C8E45/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page  20.png" alt="Page  20.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 7: Integrate Alert Notification in a CAPM Application&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Open or create a &lt;STRONG&gt;CAPM application&lt;/STRONG&gt; where you want to integrate the alert notification.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the CAPM application, set up a connection to the &lt;STRONG&gt;destination&lt;/STRONG&gt; you created earlier.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;standard API endpoint&lt;/STRONG&gt; to trigger the notification:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/cf/producer/v1/resource-events&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;This endpoint allows your application to send events to the SAP Alert Notification service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;For full API details and supported parameters, refer to the &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/cf_producer_api/resource/postResourceEvent" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="page 21.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265766i9BF08BBE3FCE912F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="page 21.png" alt="page 21.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="page 22.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265767iD02A6832059A9991/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="page 22.png" alt="page 22.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Page 23.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265768iD5A02EB1C3EEE6DF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Page 23.png" alt="Page 23.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1860391577"&gt;Step 8: Test Using Postman&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Deploy your service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use the deployed service URL.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get the &lt;STRONG&gt;Client ID&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;Client Secret&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the environment variable under the &lt;STRONG&gt;xsuaa&lt;/STRONG&gt; section and use it in postman for authentication using &lt;STRONG&gt;oAuth 2.0&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="page 25.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265780iC93D30E6C70DAE2C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="page 25.png" alt="page 25.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="page 24.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/265781i9EA2DB3AC6424108/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="page 24.png" alt="page 24.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By following the above steps, we have successfully set up and integrated SAP Alert Notification with a CAPM application. Starting from creating the alert notification instance, setting up conditions and actions, generating a service key, creating a destination, and finally integrating and testing the service using Postman — the entire process ensures that your application can send real-time alerts based on defined events. This integration enhances monitoring and improves responsiveness to critical events in your system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/how-to-implement-alert-notification-service-in-cloud-application/ba-p/14111080"/>
    <published>2025-05-27T09:30:42.241000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-integration-content-for-coupa-to-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-now/ba-p/13939023</id>
    <title>New Integration Content for Coupa to SAP Signavio Process Intelligence Now Available</title>
    <updated>2025-05-28T14:19:56.416000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>hoangvu</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/315943</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We’re excited to announce that new integration content for Coupa to SAP Signavio Process Intelligence is now available, offering organizations an enhanced capability to analyze their end-to-end procurement processes. This valuable integration is accessible free of charge on the SAP Business Accelerator Hub, empowering businesses to make data-driven decisions with greater precision and efficiency.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1204006291"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Streamline Your Procurement Analysis&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Procurement processes are complex, involving numerous stakeholders and steps that can create inefficiencies and gaps if not closely monitored. By leveraging the new integration content for Coupa and SAP Signavio Process Intelligence, you can gain comprehensive insights into your procurement workflows. This integration helps you visualize, analyze, and optimize the entire procurement process from purchase requisition to payment, ensuring greater transparency and continuous improvement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1007492786"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;How to Access the Integration Content&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Accessing this powerful integration is straightforward. To get started:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Log in to the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hoangvu_0-1731665494722.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/191249iAFC3C04A6959D30E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hoangvu_0-1731665494722.png" alt="hoangvu_0-1731665494722.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Navigate to the “Explore” tab and search for “&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/products/SAPSignavio/integrations/packages" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Signavio&lt;/A&gt;”.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hoangvu_1-1731665544630.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/191251iEFC0366A42B49898/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hoangvu_1-1731665544630.png" alt="hoangvu_1-1731665544630.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Locate the new integration content for Coupa.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hoangvu_2-1731665610400.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/191252iAE2B987503F8976F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hoangvu_2-1731665610400.png" alt="hoangvu_2-1731665610400.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;View the integration package and dedicated integration flows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hoangvu_3-1731665690736.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/191253iC24328932ECD113A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hoangvu_3-1731665690736.png" alt="hoangvu_3-1731665690736.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The integration package includes dedicated integration flows that outline the relevant business objects and events extracted by default. This setup enables a quick start with the flexibility to adjust and extend the content to meet your specific business needs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-810979281"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Key Benefits of the Integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;End-to-End Visibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Gain a holistic view of your procurement operations, identifying bottlenecks and opportunities for optimization.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customizable Data Extraction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: The predefined business objects and events can be tailored to your organization’s unique requirements, offering adaptability for varied use cases.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enhanced Decision-Making&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: With seamless data extraction from Coupa and integration into SAP Signavio Process Intelligence, organizations can make informed decisions based on accurate process execution data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-614465776"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Share Your Feedback&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;We value your input and look forward to hearing your thoughts on this new integration package. Share your experiences and suggestions in the comments section below.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Start analyzing and optimizing your procurement processes today with the new Coupa to SAP Signavio Process Intelligence integration. Discover how this solution can transform your operations and drive better outcomes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In case you have not seen it yet, also check out the integration content we have recently released for &lt;STRONG&gt;Salesforce&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/extract-salesforce-data-into-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-using-sap/ba-p/13804734" target="_self"&gt;Blog post&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SalesforcetoSAPSignavio/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration content&lt;/A&gt;) and &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Dynamics CRM&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/extract-ms-dynamics-crm-data-into-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-with/ba-p/13923715" target="_self"&gt;Blog post&lt;/A&gt; / &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/MicrosoftDynamicsCRMIntegrationwithSAPSignavio/integrationflow" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration content&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-integration-content-for-coupa-to-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-now/ba-p/13939023"/>
    <published>2025-05-28T14:19:56.416000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/mastering-complex-sbpa-approvals-a-deep-dive-into-wait-steps-script-tasks/ba-p/13796837</id>
    <title>Mastering Complex SBPA Approvals : A Deep Dive into Wait Steps, Script Tasks, and API Integrations</title>
    <updated>2025-06-03T05:00:19.725000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mohit_bansal3</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40540</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;Welcome back to our new blog series,&amp;nbsp; our&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/architecting-complex-workflows-real-time-scenarios-with-sap-build-process/ba-p/13742643" target="_self"&gt; previous blog series&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt; delved into the intricacies of&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/architecting-complex-workflows-real-time-scenarios-with-sap-build-process/ba-p/13742643" target="_self"&gt; dynamic sequential approval&lt;/A&gt; workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this two-part series, my colleague&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476112"&gt;@Adwait_Fadnavis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; and I will explore some very critical business workflow&amp;nbsp; requirements&amp;nbsp; in detail using SAP Build Process Automation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Throughout this blog series, we will delve into the following critical business requirements:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Part 1 - Current Blog :Mastering Complex SBPA Approvals : A Deep Dive into Wait Steps, Script Tasks, and API Integrations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Part 2 : &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/mastering-sbpa-approvals-a-deep-dive-into-wait-steps-script-tasks-and-api/ba-p/14117204" target="_self"&gt;Demonstration with Complete end to end testing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will demonstrate how to use various SAP Build Process Automation tools to solve real-time challenges effectively.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This blog post addresses this complex requirement with detailed step-by-step instructions. You'll learn how to ensure workflows advance smoothly, even with&amp;nbsp; approval condition utilizing various innovative latest features&amp;nbsp;such as: Wait Step with API Triggering , Workflow Context update via API etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Context and Problem Statement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While working on multiple SAP Build Process Automation projects, we have faced situations where workflows only proceed if all departments or approvers approve them unanimously.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If any approver rejects the proposal, the entire workflow is rejected . This creates a need for a parallel approval process, &lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;adhering to an "all-or-nothing" requirement,&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt; which SAP's standard solutions do not support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In a below sample procurement workflow, the request is created and submitted. Both the Department Manager and Finance Department must approve it simultaneously. If either rejects, the workflow is terminated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If both approve, the request goes to the Executive for final approval. The Executive's decision determines whether the request is processed or terminated.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dynamic Number of Parallel Approval" style="width: 815px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266196i4A65416364DA5964/image-dimensions/815x719?v=v2" width="815" height="719" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748312890579.png" alt="Dynamic Number of Parallel Approval" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Dynamic Number of Parallel Approval&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Solutioning &amp;amp; Design&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this process, we will create&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; two workflows using SAP Build Process Automation’s Low Code/No Code&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; approach.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s refer to these as &lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow A (main workflow) and Workflow B&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748314489855.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266198i6E9C6DBD3B0EE57F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_1-1748314489855.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748314489855.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow A( Main Workflow):&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; This is the main workflow, triggered with all input parameters, responsible for the overall business process flow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;FONT color="#3366FF"&gt;Workflow B(Secondary Workflow)&lt;/FONT&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This workflow handles the approval task. It receives the Approval ID, total number of levels, and current level. If the final approval is granted, it triggers a wait step API&amp;nbsp; in Workflow A to proceed to the next level. If more approvals are needed, it sends the Approval ID to the next level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;U&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Technical Design Steps for Workflow A:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748320427762.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266266i9FB0AC9E0E80C6B6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748320427762.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748320427762.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trigger Workflow&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The workflow is initiated with input parameters.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Decision Creation&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A decision step is created to determine the number of approvals require.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748397456117.png" style="width: 636px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266720iC2121D9311DE6166/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_1-1748397456117.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748397456117.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Script Task&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This step determines the total number of approvals and the current approval level.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$.context.custom.doneapprovalcount = 0;
$.context.custom.currentcount = 0;
$.context.custom.subwfdefinationid = "Your Secondaray Workflow ID"; // replace with your secondary workflow id
$.context.custom.totalapprovalcount = $.context.decision_getAppprovers_1.Approvers.length;
$.context.custom.triggeredsubprocessids = [];
​&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Condition Check&lt;/STRONG&gt;: If the current level matches the total required approvals, A wait step will be created to wait for the completion. If not, Workflow B is triggered to initiate the approval task.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748402197865.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266735i80A9ECA693B65112/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748402197865.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748402197865.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trigger Workflow B&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Workflow B sends the work item to the respective user for approval.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Wait Step API&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This critical step waits for all parallel approvals to be completed. Once done, the dummy decision is triggered by Workflow B. This is very interesting and latest features&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a Wait Step with API as follows.&amp;nbsp;After Deployment it will event will create the API End Point which will used to trigger from secondary workflow B .&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_2-1748398144169.png" style="width: 752px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266724i8145CC97E159532D/image-dimensions/752x792?v=v2" width="752" height="792" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_2-1748398144169.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_2-1748398144169.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Execution ID is the Parent Workflow ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Upload the API specification and create the action for this&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;Also make sure to create the API key which will be used to trigger it from secondary workflow B.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748399148921.png" style="width: 771px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266726iE419DE671BFCE441/image-dimensions/771x370?v=v2" width="771" height="370" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748399148921.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748399148921.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1152207465"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;Technical Design Steps for Workflow B&amp;nbsp; (Triggered via Workflow A)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748326920552.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266301i039C188E9E0FCE69/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748326920552.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748326920552.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trigger from Workflow A :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Workflow B starts when Workflow A reaches a certain point to manage approval tasks separately and in parallel to the main workflow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Send Approval Task:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;The approval task is sent to the current level approver to obtain necessary approvals at each level before proceeding.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;On Approval:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;The system retrieves instance details and updates the approval count to keep track of completed approvals and update the workflow status.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748400024579.png" style="width: 703px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266728i491DDEE2C98375B9/image-dimensions/703x248?v=v2" width="703" height="248" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748400024579.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748400024579.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;sample code&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$.context.custom.approvedcount = $.context.action_get_getV1WorkflowInstancesWorkflowInstanceIdContext_6.result.custom.doneapprovalcount + 1;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Check Count: The&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;system checks if all required approvals are obtained:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If all approvals are done, the workflow proceeds to the next step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;If not all approvals are done This ensures the workflow only proceeds once all approvals are obtained&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748400188638.png" style="width: 716px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266729i99B6CAEA674396B3/image-dimensions/716x449?v=v2" width="716" height="449" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_1-1748400188638.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748400188638.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Update Parent Workflow A Approval Action &lt;/STRONG&gt;: increment the update count. created a custom action. If&amp;nbsp;all the approvals not done, then update the approval count via custom action. (refer our previous blog how to create action for workflow API)&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_2-1748400611380.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266730iA067AF57F0B4FB11/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_2-1748400611380.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_2-1748400611380.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Retrieve Task ID &amp;amp; Trigger Wait API&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;trigger wait step ( API) in Workflow A to signal that the approval process is complete / Reject&amp;nbsp; and it can proceed.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Now come to most crucial part of the Development: Trigger the wait step via API&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Created a custom action project&amp;nbsp; for the wait step api end point.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748401010931.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266731i5F77F9ECDF0ADE84/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748401010931.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748401010931.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Here is the Input mapping for the API call. Needs to provide the API Key and Parent ID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;It will trigger the wait step in workflow A to approve / move forward the workflow .&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748401110811.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/266732i6387F5788EFB7CDF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_1-1748401110811.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748401110811.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;In the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/mastering-sbpa-approvals-a-deep-dive-into-wait-steps-script-tasks-and-api/ba-p/14117204" target="_blank"&gt;upcoming blog post - Demonstration with complete end to end testing &lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476112" target="_blank"&gt;@Adwait_Fadnavis&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;will delve into the complete end to end testing for these which is very critical to understand the whole development flow.&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stay tuned for a comprehensive guide that will enhance your understanding and streamline your Development&amp;nbsp; process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohit-bansal-430a8218?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share_via&amp;amp;utm_content=profile&amp;amp;utm_medium=ios_app" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mohit Bansal&lt;/A&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Mentor. SAP BTP Solution Architect&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/mastering-complex-sbpa-approvals-a-deep-dive-into-wait-steps-script-tasks/ba-p/13796837"/>
    <published>2025-06-03T05:00:19.725000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/mastering-sbpa-approvals-a-deep-dive-into-wait-steps-script-tasks-and-api/ba-p/14117204</id>
    <title>Mastering SBPA Approvals : A Deep Dive into Wait Steps, Script Tasks, and API Integrations , Part 2</title>
    <updated>2025-06-03T17:49:45.591000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Adwait_Fadnavis</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1476112</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In our previous blog post, "Mastering Complex Approvals: A Deep Dive into Wait Steps, Script Tasks, and API Integrations," my colleague &amp;amp; SAP Mentor &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40540"&gt;@mohit_bansal3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;tackled a common but challenging business requirement: the "all-or-nothing" approval process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Part 1 - &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/mastering-complex-sbpa-approvals-a-deep-dive-into-wait-steps-script-tasks/ba-p/13796837" target="_self"&gt;Mastering Complex SBPA Approvals : A Deep Dive into Wait Steps, Script Tasks, and API Integrations&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Part 2 :&amp;nbsp;Current Blog :&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/mastering-sbpa-approvals-a-deep-dive-into-wait-steps-script-tasks-and-api/ba-p/14117204" target="_self"&gt;Demonstration with Complete end to end testing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We explored how SAP Build Process Automation, leveraging features like Wait Steps with API Triggering and workflow context updates via API, can handle scenarios where multiple approvals are needed simultaneously, and a single rejection stops the entire workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We walked through a procurement example where both Department Managers and the Finance Department had to unanimously approve a request before it could proceed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now, in this second blog, we will demonstrate the step-by-step testing process for the solution we developed. This will allow you to understand the entire development flow more deeply, from concept to validation. Let's dive into the testing for the previous blog's implementation!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Handling Approval Outcomes: Positive and Negative Scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The "All-or-Nothing" Positive Scenario :&amp;nbsp;Lets Start the complete Testing Process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let's first explore the "positive scenario," where every approver gives their stamp of approval. In this ideal outcome, once all required approvals are secured, the main workflow successfully completes its designated task. This seamless progression is the goal of our "All-or-Nothing" design, ensuring that every necessary check is performed before finalization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Approval Process Triggering&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;As you know from our previous blog, for demonstration purposes, we created a simple form within SAP Build Process Automation (SBPA).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748912453677.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268602i23CD1D692E4CFF57/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748912453677.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748912453677.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Main process upon submission of request: Context and log&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You'll notice two approvers listed, which will initiate two parallel workflows. We covered the specifics of these parallel workflows in a previous blog post. The determination of these approvers can come from a decision table or your own custom logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The &lt;STRONG&gt;key takeaway here is that we've dynamically fetched two approvers&lt;/STRONG&gt;, demonstrating the adaptable nature of this step.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;it can handle any number of approvers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_8-1748914750289.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268610i9D004191217D3173/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_8-1748914750289.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_8-1748914750289.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamically Triggering Secondary Workflows&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We're now kicking off&lt;STRONG&gt; secondary workflows dynamically&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and the number of these workflows depends entirely on the number of approvers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For our current scenario, since we have two approvers, this process will trigger two parallel secondary workflows.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Each of these workflows will then send an individual approval &lt;STRONG&gt;request directly to each approver's My Inbox.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Dynamically Secondary Workflow Triggered via API" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268605i3CF7D3B22A8CFFF6/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_3-1748914628770.png" alt="Dynamically Secondary Workflow Triggered via API" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Dynamically Secondary Workflow Triggered via API&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;My Inbox View&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Here's a quick look at My Inbox. For this demonstration, we've assigned the same approver.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That's why you see two work items in this approver's inbox. In a real-world scenario, these would be two separate workflow approval items, each in the respective approver's inbox.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Crucially, &lt;STRONG&gt;the main workflow won't complete&lt;/STRONG&gt; until both approvals are in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_5-1748914675429.png" style="width: 784px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268607i2FC8ABF321E4A539/image-dimensions/784x372?v=v2" width="784" height="372" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_5-1748914675429.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_5-1748914675429.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow Progress After First Approval&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The screenshot below shows the workflow log after the first approver has taken action. As you can see, the workflow isn't complete yet; it's waiting for the second secondary workflow to be actioned.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The main workflow will only move forward once both approvals are done.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But before we get ahead of ourselves, let's examine the workflow log immediately after that initial approvals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748916930228.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268618i58F7B17F756229CD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748916930228.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748916930228.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Updating the Main Workflow Context after each approval:&amp;nbsp; SBPA API used as action&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We'll be updating the main workflow's context after each approval and then comparing it against the total required count.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here's a quick glimpse of what happens to the workflow context once the first approval is complete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can see the "donecount" increasing, which we'll use to compare against the total number of approvals needed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We achieve this by updating the main workflow via its API, a process we've already covered in a previous blog post.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748917231647.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268621i20D0406D7DB780E8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_1-1748917231647.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748917231647.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Final Approval and Workflow Completion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Now, let's go a step deeper and understand the flow when the second, and final, approver takes action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once they approve, you'll see that the secondary workflow also completes, which then triggers the wait step in the main workflow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This &lt;STRONG&gt;wait step is triggered via an API&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a process we covered in detail in a previous blog post.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Understanding this particular use case of the wait step with an API is a critical aspect of this blog's core message.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748915031708.png" style="width: 743px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268612iFD4744828180676D/image-dimensions/743x379?v=v2" width="743" height="379" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748915031708.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748915031708.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Workflow Context After All Approvals&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Now, let's carefully examine how the workflow context gets updated once all approvals are complete.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is the crucial step that triggers the wait step and allows our main workflow to proceed.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this scenario, the "donecount" becomes equal to the total number of required approvals, which in turn triggers the wait step API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748915397729.png" style="width: 741px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268614i3F3D74115C0437E0/image-dimensions/741x671?v=v2" width="741" height="671" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_1-1748915397729.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_1-1748915397729.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Handling Approval Outcomes: Positive and Negative Scenarios&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;so far We've explored the "positive scenario," where all approvers green-light the requests, leading to the main workflow's successful completion.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But what happens when an approver rejects a request?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Imagine a scenario where just one approver rejects. In such a case, the entire workflow must be rejected. My colleague, Mohit Bansal, detailed the design considerations for this rejection scenario in a previous blog post, so from a testing perspective, the approach remains similar.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;However, in a rejection scenario, we need to take crucial additional steps:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-circle"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Call the workflow cancel API:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This immediately stops the main workflow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cancel any remaining open instances of secondary workflows&lt;/STRONG&gt;: This is critical for designing a robust, production-ready complex workflow. Without canceling these, you could have orphaned workflow instances consuming resources or causing confusion.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748918505116.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/268622i27E215A26961BCBC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="mohit_bansal3_0-1748918505116.png" alt="mohit_bansal3_0-1748918505116.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Here's a quick look at how the system responds when any approver rejects: the main workflow is canceled, and all remaining open secondary workflow instances are also terminated.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;We hope you enjoyed our blog series! We dove deep into complex workflow approval scenarios, exploring how to effectively leverage wait steps and workflow APIs to achieve robust "all-or-nothing" approval processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please feel free to leave comments and share your thoughts. A big thank you to my colleague&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/40540"&gt;@mohit_bansal3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; for his contributions, and stay tuned for more blogs on the latest innovations in this area!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Regards,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Adwait Fadnavis&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/mastering-sbpa-approvals-a-deep-dive-into-wait-steps-script-tasks-and-api/ba-p/14117204"/>
    <published>2025-06-03T17:49:45.591000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-sap-build-process-automation-content-for-side-by-side-extensions-with/ba-p/14121335</id>
    <title>New SAP Build Process Automation content for side-by-side extensions with flexible workflows</title>
    <updated>2025-06-30T12:39:16.202000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SBach</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/180248</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;My colleagues published a &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;action package "&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/eu10.storecontentdev.flexibleworkflowscenarionotifications/overview" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Flexible Workflow Scenario Notifications Action&lt;/A&gt;" on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; and in the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build&lt;/STRONG&gt; Store so that it becomes easier for Citizen Developer to discover and consume it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It oﬀers an action for an outcome driven extension workﬂow and makes it easier to combine ﬂexible workﬂows from &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt; capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From a use case perspective, you could think of including process participants from outside (like external project managers) into the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; Process. Or you include centrally managed services from &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt; like a Rules Service or Joule Skills into your &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; workﬂow project. Or you like to leverage ML services like the recommendation capability of &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/task-center/sap-task-center/working-with-intelligent-recommendations?version=Cloud" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Task Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;, which is only available for &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt; tasks? For the blog I took the use case with process participants from outside to explain the possibilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In line with side-by-side extensibility ﬂexible workﬂow oﬀers an activitytype "extension step" which can be implemented by flexible workflow scenarios to offer side-by-side extension. It is guideline for all scenario developers to enable it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2024-09-25_Workflow@sap_nd.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/280578i0E8664344C453C4A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2024-09-25_Workflow@sap_nd.jpg" alt="2024-09-25_Workflow@sap_nd.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I will give a short overview and add some points in addition to the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/btp/sap-business-technology-platform/model-action-project-to-notify-abap-environment-about-workflow-completion" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;oﬃcial documentation&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2023-09-07 SolutionDiagram-S4Extension SBPA.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/270832i65A921AF0AFC1700/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2023-09-07 SolutionDiagram-S4Extension SBPA.jpg" alt="2023-09-07 SolutionDiagram-S4Extension SBPA.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The solution architecture gives an overview on the connection between Sales Order Creation in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Over the ﬂexible workﬂow capability of &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Workﬂow&lt;/STRONG&gt; it is possible to start an extension process and get back the result / outcome from &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt; .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configuration in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; starts with definition of decision reasons for sales orders. In our use case we want to start a flexible workﬂow which is the internal approval solution. After setting an internal approval reason a BAdI checks after saving the Sales Order if an approval is necessary. If true a start event is thrown and checks if a workﬂow is deﬁned in the Manage Workﬂow Application for our scenario. If the scenario contains an extension step, the business process expert is able to configures an extension step with a process deﬁnition from &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt; from the connected BTP subaccount. During runtime when the flow comes to the extension, a &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt; workflow is started via api and a standardize payload.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For shared environments an API Trigger is needed. In the extension workﬂow of our use case we derive the complete sales order header data over an API call to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; and use this data for Agent Determination. After agent&amp;nbsp;determination via decision table a user decision is modelled with two outcomes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SBPA Extension Flow with script.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/275513i1F6ACC4ACB2422FC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SBPA Extension Flow with script.jpg" alt="SBPA Extension Flow with script.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the user decision took place we need to set the outcome via script and use it in the action content package. Go to &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build&lt;/STRONG&gt; Store. Search for "flexible".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Build Store.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/274743i61D3D27C3CF4EB7D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Build Store.png" alt="SAP Build Store.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on the action project for review the details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Build Store Action.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/274744iC71A8CBE9DC9E358/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SAP Build Store Action.png" alt="SAP Build Store Action.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add the action to your project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Action in SBPA.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/274745iE68EDD023AA244BE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Action in SBPA.png" alt="Action in SBPA.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To use the action and point to the correct ABAP-Backend-System:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;define a destination variable in the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt; project.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;define a destination in the BTP Cockpit to the&amp;nbsp;ABAP-Backend-System(s)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;map the destination to the destination variable during deployment of the project.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Define the workflowInstanceId in the context and fill it from the start payload. For the names of the outcomes you need to look up the flexible workflow scenario or check the documentation of the used scenario. If it is custom build in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;, private edition or &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; (like in this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/part-1-integrating-an-extension-workflow-on-sap-btp-into-a-flexible/ba-p/13510102" target="_self"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;) check your implementation of the extension step and fill the outcomes accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="flexWorkflowExtensionOutcome.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/274747iBECE6D41FCAC9D3D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="flexWorkflowExtensionOutcome.png" alt="flexWorkflowExtensionOutcome.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Please be aware that the development livecycle of the projects on &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP BTP&lt;/STRONG&gt; is independent. We work on further enhancements to simplify the integration via the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-extensibility-wizard-for-sap-s-4hana-cloud-public-edition/ba-p/13867427" target="_self"&gt;extensibility wizard&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and also on more features to enrich the possibilities. So stay tuned. A big thanks to all colleagues supporting the integration.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-sap-build-process-automation-content-for-side-by-side-extensions-with/ba-p/14121335"/>
    <published>2025-06-30T12:39:16.202000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/extract-workday-hcm-data-into-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-with-sap/ba-p/14137420</id>
    <title>Extract Workday® HCM data into SAP Signavio Process Intelligence with SAP Integration Suite</title>
    <updated>2025-07-04T16:24:11.673000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TamaraRemle</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1477711</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Once again, we are expanding our offering to analyze processes that touch non-SAP system – this time for Human Resources. We are happy to announce the release of our new integration package content for Workday® Human Capital Management which allows you to extract data from Workday® HCM into SAP Signavio Process Intelligence.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1862421023"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Improve Your Human Resource Process Analysis &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Improved and streamlined HR processes have a positive lasting impact on your business efficiency and benefits your workforce. The new integration content for Workday® HCM and SAP Signavio Process Intelligence is an essential starting point and enables you to visualize, analyze, and get fast insights into your Attract to Acquire process.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1665907518"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Access the Integration Content on Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Let’s dive into the topic and start with where you can find the integration content.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;Logon to&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and under "Explore"&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;search for "SAP Signavio"&lt;/STRONG&gt;: &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="jpeg.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282420iC7CD8A26C5FB2725/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="jpeg.jpg" alt="jpeg.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Scroll down until you see the “Discover Integrations” area and search for Workday®.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282424iDDD13285CEE1A54F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2.jpg" alt="2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click on the Workday® tile. There you can find the available Workday® integration package for SAP Signavio Process Intelligence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282425i5FE7201EABFBC50F/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3.png" alt="3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Click on the integration package.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You see a list of integration flows highlighting which business objects and events are being extracted.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This includes the business objects "Job Application", "Employee Contract", "Candidate", and many more.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="4.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282428iEBD92778BBAC053B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="4.png" alt="4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For further details on the underlying data extraction logic from Workday HCM, how it is transformed and pushed into SAP Signavio Process Intelligence – you can open the respective integration flows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Also check out the configuration guide attached to the integration package.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="5.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/282432i521453C50FFA766A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="5.png" alt="5.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The integration package includes dedicated integration flows that outline the relevant business objects and events extracted by default. This setup enables a quick start with the flexibility to adjust and extend the content to meet your specific business needs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1469394013"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Download content into SAP Integration Suite&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To use the content, log on to SAP Integration Suite and go to “Discover” and click on the "Integrations" section. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279523i38EA21C69AC888DD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="Picture1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use the search bar and search for "Workday", you will find all available content relating to Workday integration, including our new package for SAP Signavio Process Intelligence:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279519i471A5400E93CB53B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture1.jpg" alt="Picture1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;If you check out the package "Workday Integration with SAP Signavio Process Intelligence", you can find details on all available artifacts on the integration scenarios. To use the package, simply click on "copy" on the top right corner. This will automatically copy this integration package into your design area for further configuration and deployment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Picture1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/279157i66E30A1AA96EA95A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Picture1.png" alt="Picture1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1272880508"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1076367003"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits of the Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerated Connectivity Setup:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Speed up the integration between Workday HCM and SAP Signavio Process Intelligence with pre-identified objects and fields that simplify the initial setup.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Easily Adjustable Content:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;The delivered content can be adapted to your organization’s requirements, ensuring flexibility while reducing implementation effort.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Faster Insights:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;The streamlined setup allows you to analyze hiring operations more quickly, uncover inefficiencies, and support evidence-based decision-making.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-879853498"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Share Your Feedback&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;We are looking forward to hear your thoughts and feedback on the new integration package. Share your experiences and suggestions in the comments section below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;In case you missed it – check out the available integration content for &lt;STRONG&gt;Salesforce&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/extract-salesforce-data-into-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-using-sap/ba-p/13804734" target="_blank"&gt;Blog post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/SalesforcetoSAPSignavio/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration content&lt;/A&gt;),&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Dynamics CRM&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/extract-ms-dynamics-crm-data-into-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-with/ba-p/13923715" target="_blank"&gt;Blog post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/MicrosoftDynamicsCRMIntegrationwithSAPSignavio/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration content&lt;/A&gt;) and &lt;STRONG&gt;Coupa&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/new-integration-content-for-coupa-to-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-now/ba-p/13939023" target="_blank"&gt;Blog post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/CoupaIntegrationwithSAPSignavioProcessIntelligence/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integration content&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-left" style="text-align : left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/extract-workday-hcm-data-into-sap-signavio-process-intelligence-with-sap/ba-p/14137420"/>
    <published>2025-07-04T16:24:11.673000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-partner-content-on-sap-business-accelerator-hub-q2-25/ba-p/14154988</id>
    <title>New Partner Content on SAP Business Accelerator Hub (Q2 ’25)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T16:47:20.649000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnanthNatarajan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/79594</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In continuation of our previous&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-partner-content-on-sap-business-accelerator-hub-q1-25/ba-p/14090098" target="_blank"&gt;blog&lt;/A&gt;, we are excited to bring &lt;FONT face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif"&gt;you&lt;/FONT&gt; the latest updates and maintain the momentum of delivering valuable insights to our community.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this edition of our blog series, explore the newest content packages released on the &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; by our partners in Q2 2025, along with a high-level overview of the year’s progress so far.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For complete details on each partner's content, refer to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/allpartners" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;partners listing&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;which is available on the home page of SAP Business Accelerator Hub.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1207588960" id="toc-hId-1864183691"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Incture Technologies Private Limited&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId-1796752905"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Integration package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/OracleInventoryManagementSystemIntegrationwithSAPS4HANA/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Oracle Inventory Management System Integration with SAP S/4HANA &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Oracle Inventory Management System Integration with SAP S/4HANA package in SAP Cloud Integration facilitates seamless data exchange between Oracle Inventory Management System and SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1207588960" id="toc-hId-1471156681"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SirionLabs Pte Ltd&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId-1403725895"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Integration package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/SirionContractLifecycleManagementCLMIntegrationwithSAPAribaProcurement/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sirion Contract Lifecycle Management (CLM) Integration with SAP Ariba Procurement&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Sirion Contract Lifecycle Management (CLM) Buy-side adapter for SAP Ariba seamlessly integrates the contracting flow into the buy-side process. New Contract Draft Requests (CDR) created on Sirion CLM are automatically transitioned into a Purchase Requisition (PR) on SAP Ariba enabling a sync between two systems for the entire Buy-side and contracting flow.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/SirionContractLifecycleManagementCLMIntegrationwithSAPAribaSourcingAwards2/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Sirion Contract Lifecycle Management with SAP Ariba Sourcing Awards&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sirion Contract Lifecycle Management (CLM) Sourcing Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for SAP Ariba seamlessly integrates the contracting flow into the sourcing process. Sourcing Projects and Events initiated in SAP Ariba are automatically transitioned into Contract Requests (CDRs) and Contract Line Items (CLIs) in Sirion CLM, enabling synchronization between the two systems throughout the sourcing and contracting flow.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/SirionContractLifecycleManagementCLMIntegrationwithSAPAribaSourcingBids/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Sirion Contract Lifecycle Management with SAP Ariba Sourcing Bids&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sirion Contract Lifecycle Management (CLM) Sourcing Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;for SAP Ariba seamlessly integrates the contracting flow into the sourcing process. Sourcing Projects and Events initiated in SAP Ariba are automatically transitioned into Contract Draft Requests (CDRs) and Contract Line Items (CLIs) in Sirion CLM, enabling synchronization between the two systems throughout the sourcing and contracting flow.​&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1207588960" id="toc-hId-1078129671"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;LTIMindtree Limited&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId-1010698885"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Validated Partner Use Case package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/Intelligent_Master_Data_Curator/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Intelligent Master Data Curator&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Intelligent Master Data Curator transforms SAP Master Data Governance by harnessing the power of advanced Gen AI and Narrow AI technologies. By automating the validation of global attributes and accurately proposing local attributes, this solution ensures unparalleled data quality and integrity.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/Elevating_Supply_Chain_Performance_with_SmartATP/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Elevating Supply Chain Performance with SmartATP &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The implementation of Gen AI empowers organizations to anticipate potential delays from suppliers or vendors well in advance. This foresight enables the revision of production and sales plans, allowing for timely action to minimize disruptions. Gen AI can also trigger advanced notifications to planners and sales teams, ensuring proactive measures are taken to mitigate delays effectively.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1207588960" id="toc-hId-685102661"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ATOS INTERNATIONAL SAS&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId-617671875"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Validated Partner Use Case package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/QE_Assist_for_Digital_Assurance/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;QE Assist for Digital Assurance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI powered QE Assist - where Quality Assurance meets the power of intelligence, is the game changing solution that combines predictive AI and natural language capability driven by trained large language models (LLM) to offer a seamless, efficient, and impactful experience.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/AI_based_Maintenance_Assistant_in_SAP_EAM/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;AI based Maintenance Assistant in SAP EAM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;GenAI based knowledge assistant for maintenance and service technicians using large language Model via SAP BTP on SAP PM Objects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/Knowledge_Pilot_powered_by_GenAI/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Knowledge Pilot powered by GenAI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When the information is stored in multiple systems, multiple documents and multiple locations, search cost gets higher and efficiency reduces. Knowledge Pilot is an AI-powered knowledge search tool that provides precise, accurate, grounded information you need quickly and easily. The solution can be utilized for any situation and scenario which require high volume of documentation or huge knowledge repositories, but needs faster search capability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1207588960" id="toc-hId-292075651"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;BIGCube GmbH&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId-224644865"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Validated Partner Use Case package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/Streamlined_custom_table_maintenance/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Streamlined Custom Table Maintenance&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The application is based on an ABAP back end deployed in an SAP BW/4HANA system and offers odata services to connect to the front end. The app is a kind of framework that makes it possible to manage data in tables as desired. With granular privilege control (SAP Standard Authorization objects), users can only modify data they're authorized to, ensuring security and compliance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1207588960" id="toc-hId--176182728"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;KaTe GmbH&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId--666099240"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Integration package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/KaTeKafkaAdapter/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;KaTe Kafka Adapter&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;KaTe Kafka Adapter provides connectivity as publisher or subscriber of a Apache Kafka cluster with SAP Integration Suite or SAP Process Orchestration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1207588960" id="toc-hId--569209738"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Corevist Inc&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId--1059126250"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Integration package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/CorevistCloudCommerceIntegrationwithSAPS4HANA/integrationflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Corevist Cloud Commerce Integration with SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enable your customers to track orders and shipments; access invoices, quotes, and payment history; check account balance and available credit; and download business documents —directly from SAP ERP. Our customer portal streamlines operations, scales with your business, and fully aligns with the SAP Business Suite roadmap through direct SAP BTP integration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--962236748"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Prezien Solutions Ltd&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--431949866" id="toc-hId--1452153260"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Validated Partner Use Case package&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;EM&gt;published:&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/package/Editable_AI_Assisted_Document_Generation_in_Sales_and_Service/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Editable, AI Assisted Document Generation in Sales and Service&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Seamlessly generate, manage, and customise Word documents with AI assisted content for every sales, service, or HR interaction.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are interested in&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partnering with SAP Business Accelerator Hub,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;please refer to this&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://hub.sap.com/partnerwithus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;section&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;for more details.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stay tuned for further updates and information by the end of the next quarter!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-partner-content-on-sap-business-accelerator-hub-q2-25/ba-p/14154988"/>
    <published>2025-07-17T16:47:20.649000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/connect-to-public-cloud-api-in-node-js-via-authorisation-code/ba-p/14158313</id>
    <title>Connect to Public Cloud API in Node.js via Authorisation Code</title>
    <updated>2025-07-22T13:54:57.292000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Egan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1504852</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Connecting to a Public Cloud API (from &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;) via Node.js CAP application can be challenging. I hope this blog helps others attempting the same task.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1735214148"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Prerequisites&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;• SAP BTP subaccount (Cloud Foundry)&lt;BR /&gt;• Service key for the target Public Cloud API&lt;BR /&gt;• XSUAA instance bound to your CAP app&lt;BR /&gt;• SAP BTP Destination service instance&lt;BR /&gt;• Bruno installed for manual testing&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1538700643"&gt;1. Confirm the API's Auth Options&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, check which authentication methods are available for the API you plan to consume.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my example I connect to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Specification Management API&lt;/STRONG&gt;, but the steps apply to any Public Cloud API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If the &lt;EM&gt;OAuth 2.0 Access Code Flow&lt;/EM&gt; is listed under “Authentication Methods”, the API supports the authorization-code flow. That flow confirms a user context and usually grants wider authorisations, such as update and POST requests.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(&lt;EM&gt;OAuth 2.0 Application Flow&lt;/EM&gt; corresponds to the client-credentials flow.)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Auth-method screenshot" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289462iBE738F54BD94C2E9/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Egan_0-1753113819867.png" alt="Egan_0-1753113819867.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1342187138"&gt;2. Connect manually with Bruno (&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/data-export-api-getting-started-with-bruno/ba-p/14120240" target="_blank"&gt;Good blog on Bruno&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Because our API supports the auth-code flow, we first prove we can log in by calling it via Bruno.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a new collection and paste the base URI of your Public Cloud API instance (you’ll find it in the service key in your service instance of the saas application your connecting to).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Service key showing URI" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289463iD5B5C161AD23500A/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Egan_3-1753114108426.png" alt="Egan_3-1753114108426.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you send a test GET request you will probably receive an authorisation error. Configure OAuth 2.0 on the &lt;STRONG&gt;Auth&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select Grant type Authorisation Code&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then fill in the below fields using your service key from your service instance&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Bruno auth settings" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289461i1BABC87E61152C2F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Egan_1-1753113819868.png" alt="Egan_1-1753113819868.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Callback URL: &amp;lt;your Public Cloud API hostname&amp;gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Auth URL:** https://&amp;lt;subdomain&amp;gt;.authentication.&amp;lt;region&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/authorize&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Access-Token URL: https://&amp;lt;subdomain&amp;gt;.authentication.&amp;lt;region&amp;gt;.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/token&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Client ID / Secret: from the uaa section of the service key&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Request the token, pick your identity provider, and Bruno will return an access token. Inspect the scopes there to see what you can do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1145673633"&gt;3. Connect to the API from Node.js&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the manual check we can now automate the flow in a Node.js service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1078242847"&gt;3.1 Destination setup&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a destination that points to the same API endpoint and bind it to your app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Destination configuration" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/289460i1560E45388730B53/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Egan_2-1753113819869.png" alt="Egan_2-1753113819869.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The required scopes and the audience (aud) value are visible inside the Bruno access token.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;the Audience should start with the client id of your CAP application on BTP&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the destination is saved, ensure your application is bound to the Destination service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-881729342"&gt;3.2 xs-security.json&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add every scope your service needs so the approuter, it will forward it in the user’s JWT: in my example i needed this scope.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "name": "$XSAPPNAME.Spc_Write",
  "description": "Allow modification of specifications."
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Also reference the scope in authorities (and role templates, if used) and assign the resulting role collection to your user.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-685215837"&gt;3.3 Connect in code&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now time to connect to the API in the code itself.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First, obtain the user’s JWT. This helper below tries every possible source and falls back to LOCAL_USER_JWT in local development:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/** Try every source for a JWT and fall back to LOCAL_USER_JWT. */
function getJwt(capReq) {
  // CAP ≥ 7.3 keeps the raw token here
  if (capReq.user?.jwt) return capReq.user.jwt;

  // Plain HTTP / WebSocket headers
  const hdrs = capReq.http?.req?.headers || {};
  const token =
        hdrs['x-approuter-authorization'] ||   // CF WebSocket
        hdrs.authorization;                    // CF HTTP

  if (token) return token.replace(/^Bearer\s+/, '');
  // Last resort for local dev
  return process.env.LOCAL_USER_JWT;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-617785051"&gt;3.3.1 Testing locally&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;When testing locally we don't have access to the user JWT so we can add it manually to the environment file so we can still test locally, below is the process to get the JWT for user testing (each token lasts about 7 to 8 hours)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-550354265"&gt;Step 1 – Get an auth code&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://&amp;lt;instance&amp;gt;.eu10.authentication.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/authorize
?response_type=code
&amp;amp;client_id=&amp;lt;XSUAA client id of your deployed app&amp;gt;
&amp;amp;redirect_uri=http://localhost
&amp;amp;state=xyz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Paste your version into your browsers address bar, after login you will land on &lt;A href="http://localhost/?code=" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;http://localhost/?code=&lt;/A&gt;&amp;lt;AUTH_CODE&amp;gt;&amp;amp;state=xyz. Copy the value of AUTH_CODE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H5 id="toc-hId-353840760"&gt;Step 2 – Exchange the code for a JWT&lt;/H5&gt;&lt;P&gt;I made the Curl Request inside BAS itself. it will return a number of tokens, we only need the first and biggest one.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -v -X POST \
-u '&amp;lt;same client id&amp;gt;' \
--data-urlencode grant_type=authorization_code \
--data-urlencode code=&amp;lt;AUTH_CODE&amp;gt; \
--data-urlencode redirect_uri=http://localhost \
https://&amp;lt;instance&amp;gt;.eu10.authentication.eu10.hana.ondemand.com/oauth/token&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Save the token from the response into .env:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-markup"&gt;&lt;code&gt;LOCAL_USER_JWT=&amp;lt;paste JWT here&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--469472559"&gt;3.3.2 Call the destination with the JWT&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;const jwt = getJwt(req);
if (!jwt) req.reject(401, 'No user token found.');

const dest = await getDestination({
  destinationName: '&amp;lt;DestinationName&amp;gt;',
  jwt
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;await executeHttpRequest(dest, {
  method: 'POST',
  url: `/odata/v4/api/specification/v1/${EntityName}`,
  data: v
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you reach the destination but receive 401 Unauthorized, your JWT is missing the correct scope—ask the product team which one you need.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Other common pitfall is using the different XSUAA instances to get your JWT for the local run. use your applications XSUAA client since this is the same one your application will check the token against&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And that’s it! You should now be able to read from and write to the Public Cloud API. For read-only workloads the client-credentials flow is usually simpler.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If I missed anything or you’d like more details, please comment below—happy to help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;## Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;### What’s the difference between authorization-code and client-credentials flows?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The authorization-code flow runs in a user context, so it can carry user-level scopes (read, write, update). The client-credentials flow operates with a technical user—perfect for background jobs or read-only integrations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;### Why do I get “401 Unauthorized” after deployment?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Your user’s JWT is probably missing the required scope (e.g., `Spc_Write`). Make sure the scope is listed in &lt;STRONG&gt;xs-security.json&lt;/STRONG&gt;, mapped to a role template, and assigned via a role collection in the BTP cockpit.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;### Which audience value belongs in my destination?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;client ID&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;of your CAP application’s XSUAA instance&lt;/STRONG&gt;; it usually starts with `sb-&amp;lt;appName&amp;gt;!t&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;`.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Node.js/pd-p/723714486627645412834578565527550" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="322-1"&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Cloud+Identity+Services/pd-p/67837800100800007337" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="155-1"&gt;SAP Cloud Identity Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/API/pd-p/b31da0dd-f79a-4a1e-988c-af0755c2d184" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="123-1"&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Authenticator/pd-p/73554900100700000789" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="435-1"&gt;SAP Authenticator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Fiori+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800000375" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="20-1"&gt;SAP Fiori Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Cloud+Application+Programming+Model/pd-p/9f13aee1-834c-4105-8e43-ee442775e5ce" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="100-1"&gt;SAP Cloud Application Programming Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Application+Studio/pd-p/67837800100800007077" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="13-1"&gt;SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Technology+Platform/pd-p/73555000100700000172" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1215-1"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+S%25252F4HANA+Cloud+Public+Edition+Extensibility/pd-p/270c4f37-c335-46e1-bfad-a256637d5e26" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="37-1"&gt;SAP S/4HANA Cloud Public Edition Extensibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Accelerator+Hub/pd-p/73555000100800001091" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1214-1"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/JavaScript/pd-p/506421944534752500398156104608974" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="321-1"&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/API+Management/pd-p/67838200100800006828" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="358-1"&gt;API Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;!--    END BLOG FRAGMENT    --&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/connect-to-public-cloud-api-in-node-js-via-authorisation-code/ba-p/14158313"/>
    <published>2025-07-22T13:54:57.292000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/api-consumption-s-4-hana-cloud-public-edition-and-s-4-hana-cloud-private/ba-p/14162598</id>
    <title>API Consumption -  S/4 HANA Cloud,Public Edition and S/4 HANA Cloud,Private Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T14:23:04.065000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Arnab_G</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/151276</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;With the evolving SAP landscape and customers moving to S/4 HANA Cloud , our prime focus as a consultant is to follow a clean core approach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub(&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/&lt;/A&gt;) is one such platform which helps us in discovering standard APIs,Events, Extensibility options&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;which we can consume in our S/4 HANA landscape to achieve end-to-end business functionality. This blog focusses mainly on the API consumption from&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Business Accelerator HUB and how it differs between the two of the S/4 HANA Cloud offerings - S/4 HANA Cloud,Public Edition and S/4 HANA Cloud,Private Edition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will first go through some of the basic differences and then focus on technically how we can use or consume these APIs in each of the environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="513px"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="95.3935px" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="205.278px" height="77px"&gt;&lt;H6 id="toc-hId--2042675322"&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4 HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H6&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="211.586px" height="77px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4 HANA Cloud Private &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="95.3935px" height="371px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Where to find?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="205.278px" height="371px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Ready to use APIs available in Business Accelerator Hub(&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/&lt;/A&gt;) to be explored under the Tile -&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_5-1753445307318.png" style="width: 152px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291495i1181837D4CE9F7FE/image-dimensions/152x98?v=v2" width="152" height="98" role="button" title="Arnab_G_5-1753445307318.png" alt="Arnab_G_5-1753445307318.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="211.586px" height="371px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Ready to use APIs available in Business Accelerator Hub(&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/&lt;/A&gt;) to be explored under the Tile –&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_6-1753445307321.png" style="width: 144px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291496i91CAE9CBC3A7236D/image-dimensions/144x102?v=v2" width="144" height="102" role="button" title="Arnab_G_6-1753445307321.png" alt="Arnab_G_6-1753445307321.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="95.3935px" height="468px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Activation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="205.278px" height="468px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Communication management based API Activation. APIs are part of a standard communication scenario.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;Communication scenario can be found from SAP Business Accelerator HUB as below –&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_7-1753445307327.png" style="width: 189px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291497iAA9987D0F716B28A/image-dimensions/189x74?v=v2" width="189" height="74" role="button" title="Arnab_G_7-1753445307327.png" alt="Arnab_G_7-1753445307327.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="211.586px" height="468px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;SICF based API activation(&lt;STRONG&gt;OData V2&lt;/STRONG&gt;)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;For &lt;STRONG&gt;OData V4&lt;/STRONG&gt; no specific activation is needed but the Service Group needs to be published. Not associated to any communication scenario.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="95.3935px" height="489px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sandbox availability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="205.278px" height="489px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;“&lt;STRONG&gt;TryOut&lt;/STRONG&gt;” option available in SAP Business Accelerator HUB for OData APIs to execute the CRUD methods with Sandbox data. Also you can deploy your own system to do tryout with your actual data of your S/4 HANA Cloud,Public Edition system.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_8-1753445307330.png" style="width: 172px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291498iAAAFC26970B90C6D/image-dimensions/172x39?v=v2" width="172" height="39" role="button" title="Arnab_G_8-1753445307330.png" alt="Arnab_G_8-1753445307330.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="211.586px" height="489px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;No Tryout option available with any Sandbox. Also here the S/4 HANA system is in a private network and often there will be a Cloud Connector in between so TryOut options have been restricted for APIs for Private Edition&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_0-1753447612094.png" style="width: 179px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291540i3DAFA155943E598B/image-dimensions/179x49?v=v2" width="179" height="49" role="button" title="Arnab_G_0-1753447612094.png" alt="Arnab_G_0-1753447612094.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="95.3935px" height="262px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consumption&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="205.278px" height="262px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;API is consumed through a communication arrangement which is based on a standard communication scenario. Standard Fiori Application - &lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Communication Arrangements &lt;/STRONG&gt;to be used for consumption.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="211.586px" height="262px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;For OData V2 API is activated through transaction code - &lt;STRONG&gt;/n/IWFND/MAINT_SERVICE.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;For OData V4 API no separates activation is required but service group needs to be published through transaction code&lt;STRONG&gt; - /n/IWFND/V4_ADMIN&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Practice Guide&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We will be using &lt;STRONG&gt;OData V2 - API - API_PRODUCT_SRV&lt;/STRONG&gt; as an example to demonstrate the activation of the API in S/4 HANA Public Cloud and S/4 HANA Private Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;API Link for Public Edition – &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/API_PRODUCT_SRV/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/API_PRODUCT_SRV/overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;API Link for Private Edition - &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/OP_API_PRODUCT_SRV_0001/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/OP_API_PRODUCT_SRV_0001/overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Scenario 1# Activating API in Public Cloud –&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to the link &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/CE_PRODUCT_0002/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/CE_PRODUCT_0002/overview&lt;/A&gt; &amp;nbsp;for the API or you can search the API as below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/&lt;/A&gt; go to the tile &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4 HANA Cloud Public Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_10-1753445361003.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291501i1EEE9276A0669B57/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_10-1753445361003.png" alt="Arnab_G_10-1753445361003.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Under APIs go to ODATA V2 and search with “&lt;STRONG&gt;Product&lt;/STRONG&gt;” and open the one &lt;STRONG&gt;Product Master(A2X)&lt;/STRONG&gt; which say &lt;STRONG&gt;ODATA V2 API &lt;/STRONG&gt;and is&lt;STRONG&gt; “Active” &amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;for usage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_11-1753445361022.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291502i18D6AF5F6A1F651B/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_11-1753445361022.png" alt="Arnab_G_11-1753445361022.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;From SAP Business Accelerator HUB you will get the SAP standard communication scenario for the API –&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_12-1753445361029.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291500i0393CE6E9AA8792F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_12-1753445361029.png" alt="Arnab_G_12-1753445361029.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here we will be creating arrangement for communication scenario – &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_COM_009&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next create a communication user from the Fiori application “&lt;STRONG&gt;Create Communication User&lt;/STRONG&gt;”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_13-1753445361030.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291503iE27AFE8B09D2D4BA/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_13-1753445361030.png" alt="Arnab_G_13-1753445361030.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Give a Username and you can use the “Propose Password” option or you can add your own password.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_14-1753445361032.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291504iABC32D0F31D572C4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_14-1753445361032.png" alt="Arnab_G_14-1753445361032.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next step is to create a communication system from the Fiori application “&lt;STRONG&gt;Communication Systems&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_15-1753445361033.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291506iE2492A29D87F8F44/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_15-1753445361033.png" alt="Arnab_G_15-1753445361033.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on “New” and provide a System ID and System Name –&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_16-1753445361035.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291507i6FDCCE33C7E6F100/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_16-1753445361035.png" alt="Arnab_G_16-1753445361035.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Go to tab “&lt;STRONG&gt;Users for Inbound Communication&lt;/STRONG&gt;” and assign the user you just created in the previous step using “&lt;STRONG&gt;Create Communication Users&lt;/STRONG&gt;”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_17-1753445361037.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291508i8D38C3C456ACF352/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_17-1753445361037.png" alt="Arnab_G_17-1753445361037.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_18-1753445361038.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291510iA25BC4AA93ED5D33/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_18-1753445361038.png" alt="Arnab_G_18-1753445361038.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;For the ease of use you can check the checkbox “Inbound Only” which means you are not expecting any outbound communication&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; (&lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA -&amp;gt; External&lt;/STRONG&gt;) through this communication system and so you will not be asked to enter any user for Outbound communication user for this communication system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Save the communication system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next step is to create the communication arrangement. Go to application “&lt;STRONG&gt;Communication Arrangements&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_19-1753445361040.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291511iD9335181034254EA/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_19-1753445361040.png" alt="Arnab_G_19-1753445361040.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on “&lt;STRONG&gt;New&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following tab enter “&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP_COM_0009&lt;/STRONG&gt;” as the standard communication scenario for &lt;STRONG&gt;API_PRODUCT_SRV&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_20-1753445361042.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291512i9E01922DA2D7E020/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_20-1753445361042.png" alt="Arnab_G_20-1753445361042.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the ‘&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Communication System'(from value help)&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; which we have just created in the previous step. The assigned&amp;nbsp;Communication User will now automatically appear in User Name field.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_21-1753445361044.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291513iAEBFB889E9DBB0DC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_21-1753445361044.png" alt="Arnab_G_21-1753445361044.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;“Save”&lt;/STRONG&gt; and it will activate your communication arrangement.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can get your actual service URL for all Inbound Services associated, under the tab “&lt;STRONG&gt;Inbound Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;” under the column “&lt;STRONG&gt;Service URL/Service Interface&lt;/STRONG&gt;”.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Similarly all the Outbound services associated with this communication Scenario “SAP_COM_0009” will show under the tab “Outbound Services”.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Outbound services are generally either SOAP Outbound services or IDOCs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_22-1753445361045.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291515i830BB4A4A8A1AFAD/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_22-1753445361045.png" alt="Arnab_G_22-1753445361045.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;All the services that belong to the communication scenario “SAP_COM_0009” will be listed here under the tab “Inbound Service”.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get the URL where the Service says “&lt;STRONG&gt;Product Master(A2X)” / OData V2”&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_23-1753445361046.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291514iC186035CE2D57241/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_23-1753445361046.png" alt="Arnab_G_23-1753445361046.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The API link looks like this - &lt;STRONG&gt;https://&amp;lt;&lt;EM&gt;host&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;gt;/sap/opu/odata/sap/API_PRODUCT_SRV&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So this makes your API ready for consumption from the external system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Get the service URL and test it from POSTMAN using the communication user that you created in the first step. In POSTMAN you can use it for Basic Authentication under Authorization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can call this URL from &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt; using a &lt;STRONG&gt;OData V2 Adapter&lt;/STRONG&gt; with basic authentication with the user you created in &lt;STRONG&gt;“Communication User”&lt;/STRONG&gt; application.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt; – &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;For Public cloud the way of activating a OData V2 service and OData V4 service are same unlike Private Cloud where there is a difference.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So for OData V4 the API will be also activated by a communication arrangement only as shown above and the URL will look like this - &lt;STRONG&gt;https://&amp;lt;&lt;EM&gt;host&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;gt;/sap/opu/odata4/sap/api_product/srvd_a2x/sap/product/0002/&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Link to API Hub for the OData V4 API of Product Master - &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/CE_PRODUCT_0002/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/CE_PRODUCT_0002/overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Scenario 2# Activating API in Private Cloud –&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;First step same as Public cloud to find the API from &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/&lt;/A&gt; .&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to the link &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/api/OP_API_PRODUCT_SRV_0001/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/api/OP_API_PRODUCT_SRV_0001/overview&lt;/A&gt; for the API or you can search the API as below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/&lt;/A&gt; go to the tile &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4 HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_24-1753445361063.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291516i99958EE8FD8B1431/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_24-1753445361063.png" alt="Arnab_G_24-1753445361063.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Under APIs go to &lt;STRONG&gt;ODATA V2&lt;/STRONG&gt; and search with “&lt;STRONG&gt;Product master&lt;/STRONG&gt;” and open the one &lt;STRONG&gt;Product Master(A2X)&lt;/STRONG&gt; which say &lt;STRONG&gt;ODATA V2 API.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_25-1753445361074.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291519i8BBD5C6223E4C21D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_25-1753445361074.png" alt="Arnab_G_25-1753445361074.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next Run Transaction Code - &lt;STRONG&gt;/n/IWFND/MAINT_SERVICE&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Click on “&lt;STRONG&gt;Add Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Provide System Alias = “&lt;STRONG&gt;LOCAL&lt;/STRONG&gt;” and under Technical Service name – “&lt;STRONG&gt;API_PRODUCT_SRV&lt;/STRONG&gt;” and click on “&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_26-1753445361085.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291518iB597E74FBD128D19/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_26-1753445361085.png" alt="Arnab_G_26-1753445361085.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then select the service you want to activate and click on “&lt;STRONG&gt;Add Selected Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You can provide the package where you want to assign the service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_27-1753445361095.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291517i6DDFD736E874B38D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_27-1753445361095.png" alt="Arnab_G_27-1753445361095.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you want to use OAuth authentication you have to check the checkbox “&lt;STRONG&gt;Enable OAuth for Service&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next step is to activate the service as shown below. However it is recommended to go and activate the service from &lt;STRONG&gt;SICF transaction code&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_28-1753445361108.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291520i3FA188D969144132/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_28-1753445361108.png" alt="Arnab_G_28-1753445361108.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your OData V2 Activation is complete and you can test it from the Gateway. You can call this service now from SAP Integration Suite with a technical user who has the necessary roles.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Bonus Scenario #&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; Now we will see how we can activate a similar &lt;STRONG&gt;OData V4 &lt;/STRONG&gt;service of&lt;STRONG&gt; Product Master&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To find the OData V4 API go to &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://api.sap.com/&lt;/A&gt; and go to the node – “&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP S/4 HANA Cloud Private Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;:291522iD133E2FCB72EF160:&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Under APIs-&amp;gt;ODATA V4 -&amp;gt; Search Product&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_30-1753445361136.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291521i040A328EBDB86AD6/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_30-1753445361136.png" alt="Arnab_G_30-1753445361136.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Select the “Odata V4” one which is “&lt;STRONG&gt;Active”&lt;/STRONG&gt; and not “&lt;STRONG&gt;DEPRECATED&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_31-1753445361142.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291523i09A208A8D3AD7505/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_31-1753445361142.png" alt="Arnab_G_31-1753445361142.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Under API Resources -&amp;gt; Attributes you will find the &lt;STRONG&gt;Service Group Name&lt;/STRONG&gt; which you need to publish.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_32-1753445361146.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291524iC53AC33C2244891F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_32-1753445361146.png" alt="Arnab_G_32-1753445361146.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now Go to Transaction - &lt;STRONG&gt;/n/IWFND/V4_ADMIN &lt;/STRONG&gt;and click on “&lt;STRONG&gt;Publish Service Groups&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_33-1753445361162.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291525i92C14AB663901366/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_33-1753445361162.png" alt="Arnab_G_33-1753445361162.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next enter the &lt;STRONG&gt;Service Group Name&lt;/STRONG&gt; you got from Business accelerator Hub and click on “&lt;STRONG&gt;Get Service Groups&lt;/STRONG&gt;”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_34-1753445361168.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291527iA0DF1F40CACFC12D/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_34-1753445361168.png" alt="Arnab_G_34-1753445361168.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Arnab_G_35-1753445361174.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/291526iD8ECE4D8D37F8132/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Arnab_G_35-1753445361174.png" alt="Arnab_G_35-1753445361174.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now your OData V4 API will be ready for consumption from Integration Suite.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/api-consumption-s-4-hana-cloud-public-edition-and-s-4-hana-cloud-private/ba-p/14162598"/>
    <published>2025-07-25T14:23:04.065000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/connect-amp-go-integration-updates-for-2025-1/ba-p/14164407</id>
    <title>Connect &amp; Go: Integration Updates for 2025/1</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T13:50:24.638000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MaiaraEllwanger</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/58</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A seamlessly connected business is &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;more crucial than ever as organizations pursue agility and innovation. Just like the capabilities of SAP Integration Suite that enable you to connect everything in your business, the &lt;STRONG&gt;Connect &amp;amp; Go series&lt;/STRONG&gt; brings you a recap of the highlights for the product and how you can get started and integrate with confidence across SAP and non-SAP landscapes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the first half of 2025, SAP Integration Suite has delivered new features and enhancements, reaffirming its role as the AI-assisted IPaaS for seamless connectivity, automation, and data-driven decision making. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As you dive into this post, you will explore AI updates&lt;EM&gt;, expanded capabilities for migration to Integration Suite, latest additions to third-party connectivity and API-centric and event-driven integration. &lt;/EM&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1606936720"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1410423215"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":gem_stone:"&gt;💎&lt;/span&gt;AI Updates&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Integration Suite introduced a new user experience that empowers developers to use AI capabilities more effectively in their development, configuration, migration, testing, and workload monitoring tasks. This revamped interface aimed to enhance overall productivity and operational excellence, with a consolidated landing page offering a unified view and central activation control for all AI features.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1342992429"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-assisted API trends and predictions&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now organizations can leverage AI and machine learning to analyze historical API call volumes and forecast trends and provide insights into traffic patterns.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="API3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292610i5CAC3E435DEC0BCC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="API3.png" alt="API3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deviations from the normal usage or performance in API traffic often indicate security threats, system malfunctions, or other issues that might result in financial loss. This feature addresses this challenge through ML-based anomaly detection, which identifies unusual or abnormal behaviors by continuously monitoring the API traffic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Upon detection of anomalies in API Call Volume, API Error count, and API Response time, the system provides notifications and insights to support investigating the cause and analyzing the impact, as well as recommendations on probable remedial actions. Customers can customize options to select specific API proxies, choose the prediction duration, and set the frequency according to their preferences. With this feature they can proactively adjust their strategies, improving their resilience and competitive edge to maintain the security, reliability, and performance of their APIs. Read more:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/leveraging-api-traffic-predictions-in-sap-integration-suite/ba-p/14012084" target="_blank"&gt;Leveraging API Traffic Predictions in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1017396205"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-820882700"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":package:"&gt;📦&lt;/span&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub News&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;That the SAP Business Accelerator Hub is the&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;one-stop-shop for pre-built business accelerators you already know. But now, it includes Joule-based discovery and reuse of artifacts to help customers and partners find the right content faster and more intuitively. For an even smoother experience, the hub provides quick access to AI-specific APIs, events, and integrations in a dedicated space.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Joule in BAH.jpeg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292612i8E21985E3138C688/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Joule in BAH.jpeg" alt="Joule in BAH.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;And last but not least, the hub now includes a wide range of content for &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/dataproducts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Products&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Users can explore these products within SAP Business Data Cloud that are built to help businesses manage, analyze, and maximize the value of their data. Offerings include curated datasets, data integration tools, and analytics applications, all designed to support informed, data-driven decision-making.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-624369195"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-427855690"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Migration and Modernization&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-360424904"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support of Exactly-Once-In-Order scenario (EOIO)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;EOIO is essential in business scenarios where the receiving system requires messages to be received exactly once in the correct order, such as banking operations like deposits and withdrawals, where message order is critical. This functionality supports EOIO via exclusive queues in Cloud Integration and exclusive or partitioned queues using Advance Event Mesh. It ensures no duplicate messages or message loss, as well as the preservation of message sequence during processing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To learn more about EOIO and how to configure Java Message Service (JMS) adapter, check out &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-integration-flow-design-guidelines-covering-exactly-once-in-order/ba-p/14078696" target="_blank"&gt;New integration flow design guidelines covering Exactly Once In Order pattern&lt;/A&gt;, the &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/quality-of-service-exactly-once-in-order" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt;, and the &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/package/DesignGuidelinesPatterns/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;sample integration flows&lt;/A&gt; on SAP Business Accelerator Hub. For AEM, see &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/exactly-once-in-order-eoio-for-group-messages-using-advanced-event-mesh/qaq-p/14086945" target="_blank"&gt;Exactly once in order (EOIO) for Group messages using Advanced Event Mesh.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-163911399"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Clean Core Modernization Recommendations for IDOCs&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New modernization recommendations &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;now include evaluations of different IDOC types in integration scenarios&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. The respective SOAP/ODATA APIs and Business Events are recommended according to the content on SAP Business Accelerator Hub. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Customers can leverage these recommendations during migration to obtain risk and cost reduction when adopting a clean core approach. The additional information is reported in the full evaluation result spreadsheet, learn how to &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;extract the data with a &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/create-data-extraction-request?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Data Extraction Request&lt;/A&gt; or follow the &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/migration-assessment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;tutorial&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--161684825"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-411541753"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt;Third-party Connectivity&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this first half of 2025 we’ve expanded our ecosystem to help customers integrate across platforms effortlessly. A new set of integration adapters include: IBM MQ (REST, JMS), SAP LeanIX, Google Cloud Storage, Google Pub/Sub, Google BigQuery, Salesforce Pub/Sub, DocuSign,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MS 365 Teams, MS 365 OneDrive, Shopify, and &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/content-type/Adapters/adapters/packages" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;more&lt;/A&gt;. Additionally, the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/rfc-adapter-98a3c1900d0744e89d0e7dd29de6401b?locale=en-US&amp;amp;version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Remote Function Call (RFC) sender and receiver&amp;nbsp;adapter&lt;/A&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;was made available in &lt;/SPAN&gt;Edge Integration Cell to allow direct, on-premise communication with SAP and third-party systems without relying on the SAP Cloud Connector, allowing these systems to initiate RFC calls.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--78374759"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Space Integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Data Space Integration feature of SAP Integration Suite was made available in Q2 enabling participants within a data space, such as Catena-X, to exchange data with one another in a secure, reliable, and sovereign way. It provides straightforward integration between SAP and non-SAP applications and offers a unified, user-friendly approach to configuring and monitoring data exchanges within the data space, all using the SAP Integration Suite -&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/data-space-integration?locale=en-US" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;learn more&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-18514743"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--177998762"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;API-centric and event-driven integration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--667915274"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Single-source API and events catalog for developers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The API business hub enterprise &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;is now the&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/centralized-developer-hub-new-design?version=CLOUD&amp;amp;locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Developer Hub&lt;/A&gt;: a &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;centralized catalog designed for application developers to easily discover, search, and utilize APIs and business events published by their organizations. Customers can benefit from building an extensive company-wide repository of APIs and events, including thorough documentation and code examples, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;as well as new features like self-registration and analytics.&amp;nbsp;All &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;to empower developers to efficiently integrate various systems and applications. Start exploring: check out how you can &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-sap/discover-s-4hana-cloud-events-in-sap-developer-hub/ba-p/14097325" target="_blank"&gt;Discover S/4HANA Cloud Events in SAP Developer Hub&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/enable-sap-developer-hub-as-central-event-catalog/ba-p/14076495" target="_blank"&gt;Enable SAP Developer Hub as central Event Catalog&lt;/A&gt;; and read the documentation for &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/making-apis-available-in-catalog?version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;APIs&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/integration-suite/sap-integration-suite/make-events-available-on-developer-hub?version=CLOUD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Events&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--864428779"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP SuccessFactors &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;events &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;on SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/SPAN&gt;​&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore the new &lt;A href="https://api.sap.com/products/SAPSuccessFactors/events/events" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;events for SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt; published on SAP Business Accelerator Hub. Stay tuned for more events to come!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SSFF in BAH.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292613iBF156E8B536180D1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SSFF in BAH.jpg" alt="SSFF in BAH.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1060942284"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Event add-on for SAP ERP and SAP S/4HANA &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This add-on for SAP S/4HANA and SAP ECC allows the creation of custom events based on different trigger types. These events can be both notification and data events and allow for loosely coupled, highly scalable, real-time event-driven business architectures powered by SAP Integration Suite, advanced event mesh. Users can easily configure the add-on and create their custom extensible events with or without code, as well as leverage templates for selected events.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find all relevant details for this exciting update in the blog: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-e-in-event-driven-architecture-introducing-sap-s-new-event-add-for-erp/ba-p/14160285" target="_self"&gt;The E in Event-Driven Architecture: Introducing SAP’s new Event-Add for ERP&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/the-e-in-event-driven-architecture-introducing-sap-s-new-event-add-for-erp/ba-p/14160285" target="_self"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Karsten blog.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/292614iDA7F25C2A70C17E1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Karsten blog.png" alt="Karsten blog.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1550858796"&gt;The next edition of Connect &amp;amp; Go is scheduled for September/October 2025. Until then:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--2040775308"&gt;- Stay informed | Read the&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Related Updates:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blogs-by-sap/generative-ai-based-script-optimization/ba-p/13970403" target="_self"&gt;Generative AI-based script optimization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Q1 25&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/sap-business-accelerator-hub-domains-take-centerstage/ba-p/14018368" target="_self"&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub domains take centerstage&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Q1 25&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="http:/t5/integration-blog-posts/new-partner-content-on-sap-business-accelerator-hub-q2-25/ba-p/14154988" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;New Partner Content on SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Q2 25&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/integration-advisor-multi-payload-support-for-mig-creation/ba-p/14151474" target="_self"&gt;Integration Advisor – multi-payload support for MIG creation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Q3 25&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-integration-suite-update-version-of-an-integration-flow-component/ba-p/14158284" target="_self"&gt;Update Version of an Integration Flow Component&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Q3 25&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration-blog-posts/partner-directory-accelerator-tool-for-pipeline-concept/ba-p/14095019" target="_self"&gt;Partner Directory Accelerator Tool for Pipeline Concept&amp;nbsp;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Q3 25&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2057678483"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;- Stay in Touch:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join the &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-user-groups/en_us/ccoe.html#tabs-36f94c8943-item-1871f50d61-tab" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;monthly update webinars&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Interact in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration/gh-p/integration" target="_self"&gt;Integration group&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Subscribe to the &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/cmp/nl/sap-cloud-platform-integration-suite/index.html?sap-outbound-id=6287F912007644D6C49C53EAA9594EE1B4431938&amp;amp;smc_campaign_id=0000032983&amp;amp;source=email-smc" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Newsletter&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/connect-amp-go-integration-updates-for-2025-1/ba-p/14164407"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T13:50:24.638000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extending-sbpa-processes-with-apis-and-using-them-in-integrated-product/ba-p/14214260</id>
    <title>Extending SBPA Processes with APIs and Using Them in Integrated Product Development</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T08:32:57.494000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Alexandra_Rong</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/39057</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1630946523"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the &lt;A title="SBPA Guide" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/developing-processes-in-sap-build-process-automation-for-integrated-product/ba-p/14211078" target="_self"&gt;first blog post&lt;/A&gt;, we built and deployed a functional workflow in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation (SBPA) &lt;/STRONG&gt;and connected it to &lt;STRONG&gt;Integrated Product Development (IPD)&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Now, it’s time to take the next step: extending your process with API integrations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this article, we will explore how to set up and use APIs within SBPA processes to enrich your workflows with collaboration data and advanced functionality from IPD. You will learn how to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add and configure &lt;STRONG&gt;destinations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Set up and manage &lt;STRONG&gt;Actions in SBPA&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Include and execute &lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;API calls directly within your process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our specific goal in this post is to &lt;SPAN&gt;retrieve the Collaboration Name via an API call and make it visible inside a form within your workflow.&amp;nbsp;By the end of this post, you’ll know how to connect SBPA to IPD Collaboration APIs and enrich your workflow with live collaboration data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Prerequisite: You need a functional IPD workflow in SBPA. If you haven’t created one yet, you can follow my &lt;A title="SBPA Guide" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/developing-processes-in-sap-build-process-automation-for-integrated-product/ba-p/14211078" target="_blank"&gt;step-by-step guide&lt;/A&gt; to build a process in SBPA and integrate it into IPD.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1434433018"&gt;Guide&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367002232"&gt;Step 1: Register the EDP_Collaboration destination in SBPA&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;From the SAP Build (SBPA) Lobby, open &lt;STRONG&gt;Control Tower&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under &lt;STRONG&gt;Backend Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt;, click &lt;STRONG&gt;Destinations&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-01_11-22-20.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312810i8EDA86AF9A3E4623/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-01_11-22-20.png" alt="2025-09-01_11-22-20.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1170488727"&gt;Step 2: Select the EPD_Collaboration destination&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;To add a destination, click the &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt; button.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose the &lt;STRONG&gt;EPD_Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt; destination from the list.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Next&lt;/STRONG&gt; to proceed to Associate Environments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-11_16-25-48.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313175iA50720EB72A7DD59/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-11_16-25-48.png" alt="2025-09-11_16-25-48.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-973975222"&gt;Step 3: Associate the destination with environments&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the Associate Environments step, choose how the destination should be available:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;All Environments&lt;/STRONG&gt;: makes the destination usable in every SBPA environment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Specific Environments&lt;/STRONG&gt;: select only the environments where this destination should be active.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Add Destination&lt;/STRONG&gt; to save.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-01_11-24-57.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313166i43C3D49CBEDBE745/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-01_11-24-57.png" alt="2025-09-01_11-24-57.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777461717"&gt;Step 4: Create an Actions project&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the SBPA Lobby, go to &lt;STRONG&gt;Connectors → Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt; (top-right).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-01_11-27-11.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312816i7DDA1A3E472C5D22/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-01_11-27-11.png" alt="2025-09-01_11-27-11.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-580948212"&gt;Step 5: Import the IPD Collaboration API from the SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In your Actions project, click &lt;STRONG&gt;Choose an API Source&lt;/STRONG&gt; and select &lt;EM&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-01_11-29-43.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312820i261FF73711EF782B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-01_11-29-43.png" alt="2025-09-01_11-29-43.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the search bar, type &lt;EM&gt;Collaboration&lt;/EM&gt; and select &lt;STRONG&gt;Collaboration (ODATA)&lt;/STRONG&gt; under SAP Integrated Product Development (IPD).&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-11_11-06-42.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312822i31A947C7CC87A7D9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-11_11-06-42.png" alt="2025-09-11_11-06-42.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Import the API into your Actions project.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-11_11-07-20.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312823i65F00ABE307A5380/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-11_11-07-20.png" alt="2025-09-11_11-07-20.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-384434707"&gt;Step 6: Create the Action Project&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After selecting the Collaboration API, you will be prompted to create an Action project.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The Project Name and Description are prefilled with default values. You can keep them or adjust as needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Create&lt;/STRONG&gt; to finalize the Action project setup.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-11_11-07-56.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312824i641FC69D0A4E5957/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-11_11-07-56.png" alt="2025-09-11_11-07-56.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-187921202"&gt;Step 7: Add Available API Actions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A list of API actions from the SAP Business Accelerator Hub will appear.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the APIs you want to use for your collaboration scenario (for this guide:&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Retrieve a collaboration for the specified collaboration ID&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Confirm with &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;All chosen API actions will now be available in your Action Project.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-11_11-09-45.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312826iD91913C715E20007/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-11_11-09-45.png" alt="2025-09-11_11-09-45.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Tip: If you want to add an API later, open the Available Actions window using the &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt; button next to Actions.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-11_11-11-14.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312827i0308E25AB892A659/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-11_11-11-14.png" alt="2025-09-11_11-11-14.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--8592303"&gt;Step 8: Add missing "From" header for IPD APIs&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;For many IPD APIs, an additional &lt;STRONG&gt;From&lt;/STRONG&gt; header is required. This header is not automatically included and must be configured manually.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open &lt;STRONG&gt;Add&lt;/STRONG&gt; under the Parameters section.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure the parameter as follows:&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Key: From&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Mandatory: Yes&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Parameter: header&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Type: string&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add the parameter.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;To check whether an API requires the From header, refer to the &lt;A title="API Hub" href="https://api.sap.com/api/EPD_COLLABORATION/resource/Collaboration?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP API Business Hub – EPD Collaboration API&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-11_11-11-14.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312829i42684C61094C9FA6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-11_11-11-14.png" alt="2025-09-11_11-11-14.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_15-57-04.png" style="width: 838px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312830i7319592CCD8EE16D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_15-57-04.png" alt="2025-09-02_15-57-04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_15-57-25.png" style="width: 681px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312831iE369AE0B0501F1F2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_15-57-25.png" alt="2025-09-02_15-57-25.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-142148549"&gt;Step 9: Save, Release and Publish the Action Project&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_15-58-45.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312935iDA72DAA270DEF48F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_15-58-45.png" alt="2025-09-02_15-58-45.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Release&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_15-59-58.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312936iA16EA794616CD74A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_15-59-58.png" alt="2025-09-02_15-59-58.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-00-36.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312937i8D5C788F19A30B94/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-00-36.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-00-36.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Publish&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-01-04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312938iEA20D9EA9DD71F68/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-01-04.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-01-04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-01-29.png" style="width: 660px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312939i2A0645876FE87D1D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-01-29.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-01-29.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--54364956"&gt;Step 10: Move back into the process&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;After releasing and publishing the Action Project, return to your process model to continue the setup.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open your project in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Switch the project from &lt;EM&gt;Deployed&lt;/EM&gt; back to &lt;EM&gt;Editable&lt;/EM&gt; mode by selecting the dropdown and choosing &lt;STRONG&gt;Editable&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This allows you to make changes to the process again.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the project overview, click on your process (e.g., &lt;EM&gt;IPD Process&lt;/EM&gt;) to reopen it in the process editor.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-02-51.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312940iA396BA8D0AD9A555/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-02-51.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-02-51.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-03-40.png" style="width: 674px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312941i5D8EF7070229DAF3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-03-40.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-03-40.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-04-19.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312942iF21C0A8AB6ECC86A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-04-19.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-04-19.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--250878461"&gt;Step 11: Add the CollaborationID and TechnicalUser as custom variables&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under &lt;EM&gt;Process Details&lt;/EM&gt;, configure &lt;STRONG&gt;Custom Variables&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add CollaborationID and technicalUser as custom variables.&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can either set the &lt;EM&gt;technicalUser&lt;/EM&gt; directly as an initial variable or define it later in a Script Task.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-04-44.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312943i8543E4CF42958EB1/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-04-44.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-04-44.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_14-47-39.png" style="width: 769px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312944i52F512AB1B23E889/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_14-47-39.png" alt="2025-09-02_14-47-39.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-05-31.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312945i2165D58929EE8178/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-05-31.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-05-31.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--447391966"&gt;Step 12: Extract the Collaboration ID from the Business Key&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add a &lt;STRONG&gt;Script Task&lt;/STRONG&gt; to your process.&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-05-51.png" style="width: 940px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312946i868C54BC8F60BE0C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-05-51.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-05-51.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-01_11-47-08.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312947i812C6BCF1DF9363F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-01_11-47-08.png" alt="2025-09-01_11-47-08.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-06-14.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312949i2ABA0300106DD19F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-06-14.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-06-14.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the script editor, insert the following JavaScript logic:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;// get Business Key
var businessKey = $.context.startEvent.businessKey;

// delete "Collaboration"
var collaborationId = businessKey.replace("Collaboration", "");

// Write in Context
$.context.custom.collaborationid = collaborationId;
$.context.custom.technicalUser = "your@mail.com"; // enter the technical User Mail
      &lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-07-14.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312952iFE16D94D6F225D8B/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-07-14.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-07-14.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--643905471"&gt;Step 13: Add Collaboration Actions&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;After the Script Task, add a new element and select &lt;STRONG&gt;Action&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This connects the Collaboration API (configured earlier) directly to your process.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You can either reuse an existing action from your library or add a new one by selecting &lt;STRONG&gt;Browse All Actions&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the Action Library, search for and select the Collaboration API you want to use (In this guide the API:&amp;nbsp;&lt;EM&gt;Retrieves a collaboration for the specified collaboration ID&lt;/EM&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-08-45.png" style="width: 924px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312953iD20D965D5B826D93/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-08-45.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-08-45.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-09-12.png" style="width: 964px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312954i6AA291C5B2B153C3/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-09-12.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-09-12.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-09-56.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312955iC77AE7180F9EA956/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-09-56.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-09-56.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--840418976"&gt;Step 14: Configure Destination Variable&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Choose a &lt;STRONG&gt;Name&lt;/STRONG&gt; for the step.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Under &lt;EM&gt;Destination Variable&lt;/EM&gt;, create or select the variable that points to your Collaboration destination.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;When deploying the workflow, set this destination variable to &lt;STRONG&gt;EPD_Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-10-35.png" style="width: 682px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312956iDD1C10042C727DE9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-10-35.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-10-35.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-11-01.png" style="width: 938px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312957i8C368E7932EB26AB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-11-01.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-11-01.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-12-43.png" style="width: 960px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312958i8078EF0BD8DCFD71/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-12-43.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-12-43.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1036932481"&gt;Step 15: Configure API Inputs&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the workflow action settings, navigate to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Inputs&lt;/STRONG&gt; tab.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For the field &lt;EM&gt;From&lt;/EM&gt;, select the variable technicalUser.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;For the field &lt;EM&gt;ID&lt;/EM&gt;, select the variable CollaborationID.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This maps your process data to the API request. All responses from the API call are available as variables, which can be mapped and used in the input fields.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-01_13-45-11.png" style="width: 642px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/313168i0C886155C4276F98/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-01_13-45-11.png" alt="2025-09-01_13-45-11.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1233445986"&gt;Step 16: Add result from API to your Form&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the form.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Click &lt;STRONG&gt;Open Editor&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add a Text Field and name it &lt;EM&gt;Collaboration Name&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save the form.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Return to the Process and open the Input tab of the form.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add the &lt;EM&gt;Collaboration Name&lt;/EM&gt; into the field.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-13-24.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312961iB2FA8DB33B463A76/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-13-24.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-13-24.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-15-30.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312962iAAAD5769E86D3BC7/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-15-30.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-15-30.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-16-13.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312963iADDA7D0B52530232/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-16-13.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-16-13.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-16-47.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312964i48C2933DE8B7D0C2/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-16-47.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-16-47.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-17-38.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312972iF92B08712102A6D0/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-17-38.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-17-38.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1429959491"&gt;Step 17: Save, Release, and Deploy the Project&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Save your project after adding the API steps.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Release the project to make it ready for deployment.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;During deployment, set the Destination Variable to the &lt;STRONG&gt;EPD_Collaboration&lt;/STRONG&gt; destination.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-18-30.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312966i785C71E6FC0AC3CE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-18-30.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-18-30.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-18-53.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312967iCB39FAB044B4F297/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-18-53.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-18-53.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-19-20.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312968iE13A2021179D5E7A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-19-20.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-19-20.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-19-34.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312969iCFAFAEF43EA80FFD/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-19-34.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-19-34.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-19-56.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312971i8104C4126E990405/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-19-56.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-19-56.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1626472996"&gt;Step 18: Start the Workflow in SAP IPD&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the &lt;STRONG&gt;My Collaborations&lt;/STRONG&gt; app in SAP IPD.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select a collaboration where the workflow is already linked to the collaboration type (see how to do that: &lt;A title="SBPA Guide" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/developing-processes-in-sap-build-process-automation-for-integrated-product/ba-p/14211078" target="_blank"&gt;SBPA Guide&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Add the workflow to the collaboration.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Note:&lt;/EM&gt; This requires that you have completed all configuration steps from the &lt;A title="SBPA Guide" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/developing-processes-in-sap-build-process-automation-for-integrated-product/ba-p/14211078" target="_blank"&gt;SBPA guide&lt;/A&gt;, including setting up the Business Key, defining the Subject, and configuring the Workflow Properties and other prerequisites. Since the process was already configured, deploying it in SBPA only creates a new version of the workflow. When you start the workflow in IPD, the newly deployed version will be executed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-20-37.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312974i2A46F32615D69653/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-20-37.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-20-37.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-21-17.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312975i259E0035A43F939E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-21-17.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-21-17.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-21-35.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312977i57BDA6540DB33537/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-21-35.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-21-35.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-21-57.png" style="width: 589px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312978i27B910ADB3D33E7E/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-21-57.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-21-57.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1654802810"&gt;Step 20: Check the updated form in My Inbox&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the &lt;STRONG&gt;My Inbox&lt;/STRONG&gt; app in SAP IPD.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the task created by your workflow.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the form, locate the text field &lt;STRONG&gt;Collaboration Name&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The field now displays the Collaboration Name that was returned by the API.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-20-37.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312991i9C95EA19FA4D8DE6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-20-37.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-20-37.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-22-35.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312992i566FB2A5154C0F4D/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-22-35.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-22-35.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--2144719322"&gt;Optional: Monitor the Workflow&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the &lt;STRONG&gt;Monitor Workflow&lt;/STRONG&gt; app to track execution details.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In the monitoring view, verify that the API call is executed successfully and inspect the request and response data if needed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="2025-09-02_16-20-37.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312994i0264C4D34F3EC3E9/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="2025-09-02_16-20-37.png" alt="2025-09-02_16-20-37.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--1754426813"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conclusion&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Great work! You have successfully extended your workflow in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Build Process Automation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;by integrating APIs and connected it with &lt;STRONG&gt;Integrated Product Development&lt;/STRONG&gt;. With the Collaboration API in place, your process can now dynamically retrieve and display collaboration data, such as the Collaboration Name, directly inside your forms.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Beyond this example, you can use many other APIs from the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Accelerator Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt; to enrich your workflows with additional business data, collaboration features, or system integrations. This demonstrates how SBPA can go beyond simple workflow automation and become a powerful integration layer for IPD.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Alexandra Rong,&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Business Process Consultant for SAP IPD,&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;alexandra.rong@sap.com&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/product-lifecycle-management-blog-posts-by-sap/extending-sbpa-processes-with-apis-and-using-them-in-integrated-product/ba-p/14214260"/>
    <published>2025-09-12T08:32:57.494000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
