<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-Community-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP Community</title>
  <updated>2025-10-04T08:00:49.961623+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP Community/pd-p/486157991894093153608181816584982" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP Community blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/shanghai-blog-posts-%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2/sap-business-data-cloud%E4%B8%AD%E6%96%87%E5%85%A5%E9%97%A8%E5%90%AF%E5%8A%A8%E4%B9%8B%E6%97%85-%E8%A7%86%E9%A2%91%E8%AE%B2%E8%A7%A3/ba-p/14225129</id>
    <title>SAP Business Data Cloud中文入门启动之旅 视频讲解</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T08:04:50.990000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AlexDong</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/41983</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;请参阅&lt;A href="https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/CS2fhog?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1240090" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://dam.sap.com/mac/app/p/video/asset/preview/CS2fhog?ltr=a&amp;amp;rc=10&amp;amp;doi=SAP1240090&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/shanghai-blog-posts-%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2/sap-business-data-cloud%E4%B8%AD%E6%96%87%E5%85%A5%E9%97%A8%E5%90%AF%E5%8A%A8%E4%B9%8B%E6%97%85-%E8%A7%86%E9%A2%91%E8%AE%B2%E8%A7%A3/ba-p/14225129"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T08:04:50.990000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/introducing-a-new-badge-progression-set-just-for-bloggers/ba-p/14225884</id>
    <title>Introducing a New Badge Progression Set Just for Bloggers</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T16:06:27.363000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>caroleighdeneen</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/20</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In August, we launched three new badge progression sets that rewarded members for &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/bringing-back-badges-to-reward-q-amp-a-experts/ba-p/14182870" target="_blank"&gt;providing solutions to questions&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/thumbs-up-for-the-new-kudos-received-progression-badges/ba-p/14193157" target="_blank"&gt;earning kudos&lt;/A&gt;, and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/give-a-kudo-get-a-badge/ba-p/14204770" target="_blank"&gt;giving kudos&lt;/A&gt;. Now, after a brief badge hiatus, we’re back with a brand-new progression set exclusively for bloggers.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The previous sets built upon &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/let-the-gamification-begin/ba-p/311892" target="_blank"&gt;existing badges&lt;/A&gt; that have been available since we launched the new platform last year. To be specific: Before we rolled out those sets last month, members could earn a badge for their first kudo received, their first kudo given, and their first answer accepted as a solution. So we’ve long encouraged – and commended – those activities. With this new progression set, however, we are returning to recognizing members solely for their blogging.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;On our previous SAP Community platform, members could have earned five badges for publishing blog posts: Blogger, Avid Blogger, Skillful Blogger, Master Blogger, and Grand Master Blogger. You may even stumble across these retired badges when you click “View all badges” on the content page of a long-time member. For example:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="caroleighdeneen_0-1758635646148.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319044iF8F22CC536447C58/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="caroleighdeneen_0-1758635646148.png" alt="caroleighdeneen_0-1758635646148.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We haven’t had the equivalent of those blog badges on this platform, but that will change as of Wednesday, September 24 – the day when we bring back a progression set just for blogging.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="caroleighdeneen_1-1758635646158.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319043iFC83898AFD8DD566/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="caroleighdeneen_1-1758635646158.png" alt="caroleighdeneen_1-1758635646158.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;This blogging set, like the other sets made available in August, will contain five badges in total. We’ll award the first badge to members who published one blog post, the second to those who published two blog posts, the third to those who published five blog posts, the fourth to those who published ten blog posts, and the final badge to those who published thirty.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We plan to award the badges retroactively, so if you’re already an active blogger, you can expect one or more badges tomorrow. If you’d like to know exactly how many you’ll get (if any), you should check your “My content” page to confirm how many blog posts you’ve published. To do that, log in, then select “My content.”&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="caroleighdeneen_2-1758635646160.png" style="width: 385px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319045i317B9D2EF536B5EE/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="caroleighdeneen_2-1758635646160.png" alt="caroleighdeneen_2-1758635646160.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Once you’re on your content page, you’ll notice a gray box at the top. Please ignore it, as the numbers there aren’t related to the blogging badges. (The “Posts” number in this gray box does indeed include your blog posts, but it also includes your discussions, comments, and other content types that you’ve posted to the community. So it’s not the figure used for the blogging set.) Instead, scroll down to the “Private Stats” section and look for “Blog Articles Posted.” That’s the number which will determine how many blogging badges you receive. Here’s an example.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="caroleighdeneen_3-1758635646165.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319046i9588C85A5EAA2DF4/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="caroleighdeneen_3-1758635646165.png" alt="caroleighdeneen_3-1758635646165.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In this case, this member will earn all five badges tomorrow, as his 150 posts exceed all the necessary thresholds associated with this set.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We’ll assign the badges one at a time (from lowest to highest) over the course of a few hours tomorrow, and members will get notifications for each one received – so if you’re like the member in the example above, don’t be surprised when five notifications come your way.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you have your notifications turned off (but you’d still like to monitor your progress tomorrow), then refresh your “My content” page periodically throughout the day. Each time you get a badge, you’ll see it appear in the upper right, as well as on the page accessible from the “View all badges” link.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="caroleighdeneen_4-1758635646174.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319047i2C7647D460B35326/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="caroleighdeneen_4-1758635646174.png" alt="caroleighdeneen_4-1758635646174.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you’re still waiting for your badges to show up by Thursday, September 25, please log out of SAP Community and log back in. Your badge(s) should be visible then.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Blogging is one of the most important and time-consuming activities available to members, and we’re happy to recognize our dedicated bloggers once again. If you’d like to get involved with blogging, start by taking our &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/community-tour.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;community tutorial&lt;/A&gt; and familiarize yourself with our &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-knowledge-base/moderation-on-sap-community/ta-p/14220311" target="_blank"&gt;moderation policy for blogging&lt;/A&gt;. We want you to earn those blogging badges – and it might be tempting to try to push through thirty posts quickly to max out the set – but you should only submit one post at a time, per &lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/resources/rules-of-engagement#article-1:-participation-etiquette-and-general-rules-on-content-publication" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;article 1 of our rules of engagement&lt;/A&gt;. Pace yourself, do things right, and you’ll find success as a blogger (with the badges to show for it). &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;By sharing their knowledge (or perhaps a little about themselves), community bloggers deliver content that educates and engages our members. This set is just a small way of thanking them. And more thanks are coming. We’ll introduce additional badges soon, so even if you aren’t a blogger, you may find yourself earning other badges for additional content type contributions in the very near future. Stay active in all areas throughout the community and see what happens. And remember: Even the simple act of leaving a kudo on content that you enjoy can bring you one step closer to a badge. Any positive action in the community, no matter how big or small, makes a huge difference, and these badges demonstrate our appreciation for your quality contributions. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/introducing-a-new-badge-progression-set-just-for-bloggers/ba-p/14225884"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T16:06:27.363000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/casablanca-blog-posts/welcome-to-the-sap-community-casablanca-group/ba-p/14225919</id>
    <title>Welcome to the SAP Community Casablanca Group! 🎉</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T16:58:24.449000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Younes_Elmir</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2175219</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;BR /&gt;I’m thrilled to announce the launch of the &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Community Group in Casablanca&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- a dedicated space for SAP professionals and consultants to meet, connect, exchange knowledge, and grow together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Our vision is simple:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; Build a vibrant local SAP ecosystem where &lt;STRONG&gt;professionals can network, share experiences, and inspire each other.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; Give the SAP scene in Morocco the exposure it deserves through real, value-added events.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; Create a sustainable community led by professionals, for professionals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why join the SAP Community Casablanca Group?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Here’s what you can look forward to:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Local Meetups &amp;amp; Events&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- informal gatherings, SAP Inside Tracks, and knowledge sessions designed to bring people together.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Knowledge &amp;amp; Experience Sharing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- blogs, discussions, and posts where you can share insights, ask questions, and learn from peers.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Networking &amp;amp; Growth&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- meet SAP experts, professionals, and leaders from across Morocco and beyond.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How you can get involved&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Join the Group&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Post your Introduction (tell us about your SAP journey, location, and interests)&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt; Stay tuned for upcoming events and discussions&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This community will only be as strong as its members. By sharing your knowledge, engaging in discussions, and supporting others, you’ll help us build a &lt;STRONG&gt;solid and sustainable SAP ecosystem in Casablanca.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, we’re creating a place where &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP professionals can connect, exchange knowledge, and create new opportunities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;- while giving our local ecosystem the visibility and impact it deserves.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I’m Younes Elmir, SAP enthusiast student and Community Event Organizer for Casablanca. I launched this group because I believe we can make a real difference by coming together, learning from each other, and showcasing Morocco’s SAP talent to the world.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We’ve already held our &lt;STRONG&gt;first SAP Community Meetup in Casablanca&lt;/STRONG&gt;, and the energy was incredible - more than 20 participants, mostly consultants, all eager to collaborate and shape the future of this community.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now it’s your turn:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":speech_balloon:"&gt;💬&lt;/span&gt; Introduce yourself in the comments - where are you based, what’s your SAP area, what would you like to see in this community?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":loudspeaker:"&gt;📢&lt;/span&gt; Share your ideas for topics, events, and activities you’d like us to organize.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking forward to building this journey with you all!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Younes Elmir&lt;BR /&gt;SAP Community Event Organizer - Casablanca&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/casablanca-blog-posts/welcome-to-the-sap-community-casablanca-group/ba-p/14225919"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T16:58:24.449000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/my-expert-playlist-sap-teched-berlin/ba-p/14226668</id>
    <title>My expert playlist, SAP TechEd, Berlin</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T13:09:54.031000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>kostertim</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/130021</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="SAP Mentors TechEd 2025 Playlist 1.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319396i3EB42401F4682E1C/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="SAP Mentors TechEd 2025 Playlist 1.png" alt="SAP Mentors TechEd 2025 Playlist 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1755029810071001OPmt" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;PAR107 | SAP and Databricks: Real-time insights and AI without ETL&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Turn your trusted SAP data into AI-driven innovation - without the complexity of ETL. See how the SAP Business Data Cloud solution integrates with Databricks using Delta Sharing to provide more-secure, live access to SAP data for use with AI, data engineering, data warehousing, governance, and BI, and how global enterprises are accelerating value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749043723472001JyEA" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA160 | SAP Business Data Cloud from set up to streamline: A practical walk-through&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Gain practical expertise in the SAP Business Data Cloud solution. Explore the solution’s core components, learn how to activate and manage them, and practice strategies to streamline data integration, governance, and access. Find out how to use SAP Business Data Cloud to simplify complex data processes and deliver scalable, trusted data solutions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754081071909001LQxU" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA266 | Operationalizing AI with SAP Databricks in SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP Databricks capability, fully native in the SAP Business Data Cloud solution, brings scalable AI and ML to enterprise data. This session covers activating SAP Databricks, accessing and sharing governed data, building models, and running secure AI workflows—bridging data engineering and science without duplication.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753910209205001V1Vm" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA203 | SAP Business Data Cloud: The path forward for SAP Business Warehouse&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore best practices for modernizing your SAP Business Warehouse (SAP BW) application with the SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC) solution. Learn how to minimize migration risks, keep existing objects in SAP BW, and deliver the objects as managed data products and intelligent applications while using the latest data and AI capabilities in SAP BDC.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1754056240863001fO9w" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA264 | SAP Business Data Cloud: Explore the analytical components end to end&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Take a hands-on journey through the analytical components of the SAP Business Data Cloud solution. Use the SAP Datasphere and SAP Analytics Cloud solutions to design and build custom scenarios from beginning to end. This session is ideal for technical users seeking to transform data into meaningful business insights.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1753824733726001gxPw" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;DA205 | A deep dive into SAP as customer zero of SAP Business Data Cloud (SAP BDC)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Discover SAP’s journey of adopting SAP BDC and its pivotal role in SAP’s data democratization strategy with Product 360 as an internal frontrunner. Get practical tips from the integration with Databricks and SAP Business Technology Platform as the foundation for adapting, enhancing, and automating key business processes with SAP Business AI.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Not registered yet? Register now: &lt;A href="https://eur04.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sap.com%2Fevents%2Fteched.html&amp;amp;data=05%7C02%7Ctim.koster%40interdobs.nl%7C347cc5e53a0e4a37196508ddf132ba06%7Cfa1c8018ea334b9fbdf7e4ac514142d5%7C0%7C0%7C638931922427085628%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJFbXB0eU1hcGkiOnRydWUsIlYiOiIwLjAuMDAwMCIsIlAiOiJXaW4zMiIsIkFOIjoiTWFpbCIsIldUIjoyfQ%3D%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=2nDk8vgggf4KCy8kkitqeft3jnqhUyjw3UZqFsd%2FbaE%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.sap.com/events/teched.html&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/my-expert-playlist-sap-teched-berlin/ba-p/14226668"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T13:09:54.031000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/casablanca-blog-posts/the-importance-of-cross-module-knowledge-for-sap-consultants/ba-p/14227293</id>
    <title>The Importance of Cross-Module Knowledge for SAP Consultants</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T19:21:16.850000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>imanedr</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/865861</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631959513"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Importance of Cross-Module Knowledge for SAP Consultants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In today’s dynamic SAP landscape, being a consultant means much more than mastering your own module. As a functional consultant in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP MM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, I’ve learned over the years that success in real projects often depends on how well you understand the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;integration points&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; with other modules.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Why Cross-Module Knowledge Matters&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;End-to-End Processes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Business processes rarely stop at one module. A purchase order in MM eventually impacts FI through accounting entries, SD when linked to sales, and PP when it involves production. Without cross-module awareness, consultants risk missing critical dependencies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Better Communication with Teams&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Projects bring together FI, SD, PP, WM, and other consultants. Knowing their language and challenges helps avoid misunderstandings and ensures smoother collaboration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Problem-Solving&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Many issues reported by end users appear to be “MM problems,” but in reality, they stem from integration—such as GR/IR mismatches (MM–FI), stock discrepancies (MM–WM), or subcontracting issues (MM–PP). A consultant with cross-module knowledge can resolve issues faster.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Key Integration Areas for MM Consultants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MM–FI&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Inventory valuation, account determination, invoice verification.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MM–SD&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Third-party order processing, intercompany stock transfers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MM–PP&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Material requirements planning, subcontracting, and production orders.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MM–WM/EWM&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Goods receipt, stock placement, and picking processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;Benefits for Your Career&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stronger Profile&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Recruiters and clients look for consultants who can think beyond one module.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Added Value&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: You become a bridge between teams, often reducing delays in projects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Future-Readiness&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: In SAP S/4HANA, processes are even more integrated, making cross-module knowledge a must-have skill.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;How to Build Cross-Module Skills&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn from your colleagues on projects—ask questions, join design workshops.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore integration scenarios in a training or sandbox system.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Follow SAP documentation and blogs focused on cross-functional processes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Share knowledge within your teams and communities to reinforce your learning.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Final Thought&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Mastering your own module is essential, but expanding into cross-module knowledge transforms you from a “consultant” into a true &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;process expert&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. In the end, it’s not just about configuring SAP,it’s about understanding and optimizing business processes end to end.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/casablanca-blog-posts/the-importance-of-cross-module-knowledge-for-sap-consultants/ba-p/14227293"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T19:21:16.850000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-learning-hub-student-edition/ba-p/14229135</id>
    <title>SAP Learning Hub, Student Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T15:20:15.447000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Маємо чудову новину — &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Learning Hub, Student Edition&lt;/STRONG&gt; тепер доступний &lt;STRONG&gt;безкоштовно&lt;/STRONG&gt; для всіх студентів, які навчаються зараз, та викладачів!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;У підписці ви отримаєте:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;усі навчальні матеріали, доступні для клієнтів SAP Learning Hub,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2 безкоштовні спроби складання сертифікаційних іспитів&lt;/STRONG&gt;,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;доступ до &lt;STRONG&gt;живих сесій&lt;/STRONG&gt; із експертами,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;актуальний контент для підтримання сертифікації,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;доступ до &lt;STRONG&gt;хмарних навчальних систем&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Для реєстрації підготуйте свій університетський логін та студентський квиток.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/free-student-edition?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LH-studentedition" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Студенти можуть зареєструватися тут безкоштовно&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/lecturers?url_id=text-sapcommunity-prdteng-LH-studentedition" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Викладачі можуть зареєструватися тут безкоштовно&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890183388"&gt;Як розпочати навчання з SAP Learning Hub?&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1. Створіть свій SAP Universal ID&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Це універсальний акаунт, у якому відстежуватиметься ваш прогрес. Використовуйте університетську пошту. Якщо плануєте складати іспит, додайте ще одну (резервну) адресу.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2. Підтвердьте, що ви студент або викладач&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Система перевірить ваш статус навчання. Використовуйте університетську пошту або адресу, яку університет має у своїй базі. Знадобляться логін до порталу або студентський ID.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Старі поштові адреси з минулого навчання не підійдуть.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;3. Почніть навчання&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Поки чекаєте на підтвердження підписки, можна ознайомитися зі &lt;A href="https://learning.sap.com/students" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Student Zone&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; та стартувати навчання.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;4. Активуйте підписку&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Очікуйте листа з активаційним посиланням. Якщо його немає 3–4 дні, перевірте спам.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;5. Продовжуйте навчатися&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Обирайте свої &lt;STRONG&gt;learning journeys&lt;/STRONG&gt; у Student Zone та рухайтеся далі.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;6. Практикуйтеся на системах&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Робота з реальними системами — ключ до успішної сертифікації.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7. Реєструйтеся на живі сесії&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Спілкуйтеся з експертами та ставте запитання.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8. Заплануйте іспит&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Коли будете готові — переходьте до сертифікації.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693669883"&gt;FAQ&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":question_mark:"&gt;❓&lt;/span&gt;Я вже не студент, але маю стару університетську пошту. Чи можна?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":cross_mark:"&gt;❌&lt;/span&gt;Ні. Реєстрація доступна лише активним студентам.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":question_mark:"&gt;❓&lt;/span&gt;Скільки часу діє підписка?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;12 місяців. Можна продовжити, якщо ви ще навчаєтеся.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":question_mark:"&gt;❓&lt;/span&gt;Чи можна скласти два іспити з різних тем?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;Так! Якщо перший скласти з першої спроби, другий можна використати для іншого іспиту.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":question_mark:"&gt;❓&lt;/span&gt;З чого почати?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt;Якщо ще не визначилися з напрямком, спробуйте:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Discovering SAP for Students&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Positioning SAP Business Suite for Students&lt;/EM&gt; (доступно лише для студентів і викладачів після реєстрації).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":graduation_cap:"&gt;🎓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Бажаємо успіхів у навчанні та сертифікації!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-learning-hub-student-edition/ba-p/14229135"/>
    <published>2025-09-26T15:20:15.447000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/porto-blog-posts/the-strength-of-a-community-can-be-seen-in-events-like-sap-inside-track/ba-p/14229800</id>
    <title>The strength of a community can be seen in events like SAP Inside Track Porto 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-09-28T19:55:46.811000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MRobalinho</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/140615</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This past weekend I had the privilege of once again taking part in &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Inside Track Porto 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;, held at the inspiring &lt;STRONG&gt;Hotel Forte de Gaia&lt;/STRONG&gt;. It was a very special event, not only because of the unique atmosphere and the energy of the SAP community, but also because I had the honor of contributing in two ways: as an &lt;STRONG&gt;organizer&lt;/STRONG&gt; and as a &lt;STRONG&gt;speaker&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The SAP community in Portugal keeps surprising me with the quality of knowledge shared and the spirit of collaboration that grows stronger each year. This year’s agenda struck a great balance between highly technical topics — such as innovation with &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP and AI Agents&lt;/STRONG&gt; — and hands-on experiences in &lt;STRONG&gt;S/4HANA projects&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Cloud ERP&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Each session was an opportunity to learn something new and exchange insights with colleagues and friends who, like me, believe that the real strength of the community lies in sharing real-world experiences.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In my session, I spoke about &lt;STRONG&gt;bank connectivity in SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;, presenting a project we delivered in partnership with &lt;STRONG&gt;MAKEVALUE&lt;/STRONG&gt; and &lt;STRONG&gt;SIBS LABS&lt;/STRONG&gt;. I demonstrated how APIs and direct integrations can simplify critical financial processes: from payments and collections to bank statements, Open Finance, and instant payments. It was very rewarding to share the results and see the audience’s interest in exploring these scenarios, which are increasingly becoming part of companies’ daily operations.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The event closed on a memorable note with live music, reminding us that technology and culture can — and should — walk hand in hand.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I left this &lt;STRONG&gt;SIT Porto 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt; with a strong sense of accomplishment, but also with renewed inspiration to keep investing in this community that grows year after year. A special thank you to all the speakers, participants, and colleagues who made this gathering possible.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;And, as tradition, the positive balance of the event will be donated to a &lt;STRONG&gt;social support institution&lt;/STRONG&gt;, reinforcing the idea that the SAP community is not only about technology but also about making a positive impact on society.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;See you at the next SIT!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/porto-blog-posts/the-strength-of-a-community-can-be-seen-in-events-like-sap-inside-track/ba-p/14229800"/>
    <published>2025-09-28T19:55:46.811000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-hobbies-series-don-t-fly-blind-stress-to-strength-mindful/ba-p/14222767</id>
    <title>SAP Community Hobbies series: Don't fly blind (Stress to strength: Mindful living in work &amp; beyond)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T08:03:05.076000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>act45</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/14052</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Thanks to Moshe&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;First of all, a heartfelt thank you to&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/29"&gt;@moshenaveh&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, who initiated this wonderful blog series about hobbies in the SAP Community. His post “Mind your step” about walking and hiking not only inspired me, but also showed me how closely movement, nature, and inner peace are connected. Hiking and running have also been passions of mine for many years. But one special experience led me onto a new path: the path of yoga. Today I combine both movement in nature and on the yoga mat, combined with mindfulness, conscious breathing, and inner clarity.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Me on a mindful hike near Austria wearing a hat." style="width: 749px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317109i86F3435EB121DF84/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="P1070657.JPG" alt="Me on a mindful hike near Austria wearing a hat." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Me on a mindful hike near Austria wearing a hat.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631815274"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Who I am&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;My name is Achim Toeper, and I have been part of the SAP world for more than three decades. My professional journey has taken me deep into technology and leadership – but at the same time I discovered another passion: yoga and mindfulness. Since completing my yoga teacher training in 2018, these practices have become an integral part of my life. They give me energy, inspiration, and a new way of engaging with people in projects, teams, and communities. From this connection, personal projects where born, in which I combine movement, mindfulness, and leadership skills, like writing and talking about it.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;My path to yoga&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Some years ago, I found myself in an extremely intense professional period, marked by great responsibility and pressure. The stress kept growing – and I realized that I needed a counterbalance to avoid burning out. In this search, I came across yoga for the first time in a wellness hotel in the Allgäu – at exactly the moment when I needed it the most. This experience truly flashed me: I immediately felt that yoga is more than just movement. During those very days, I knew I wanted to dive deeper and one day become a yoga teacher myself. Step by step I learned how to regain strength through conscious breathing, movement, and meditation. Yoga gave me not only calm and balance, but also a new perspective on leadership, collaboration, and on myself.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Yoga class and ice bathing in the Ore Mountains 2014" style="width: 664px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317111iE5257BA1C4C9C656/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="PHOTO-2025-09-17-10-16-06.jpg" alt="Yoga class and ice bathing in the Ore Mountains 2014" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Yoga class and ice bathing in the Ore Mountains 2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693467207"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A special moment in Copenhagen&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since that first encounter, yoga has become a constant part of my life. In 2018 I had the opportunity to bring my passion into a very special setting at the SAP Community Event in Copenhagen. At the end of my talk, I sat down cross-legged on stage while the audience remained in their seats. Behind me, an animated GIF was running in my presentation, visualizing the rhythm of box breathing:&lt;BR /&gt;inhale for four seconds, hold for four seconds, exhale for four seconds, hold for four seconds.&lt;BR /&gt;Together we followed this rhythm – and for a moment the large conference room became completely silent. Everyone was connected through the same breathing pattern. This experience was surprising for many and deeply moving for me: a moment where technology, community, and mindfulness came together in a very powerful way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496953702"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A special honor for me on World Mental Health Day&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Another highlight was October 10th 2023, the international World Mental Health Day. On this day, I was invited to lead an international yoga session for my company. People from different countries and time zones came together virtually to breathe, move, and pause for a moment. For me it was a great honor and at the same time a confirmation that mindfulness and yoga go far beyond private practice – they can build bridges, create community, and have a tangible impact in a global professional environment.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1300440197"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What yoga means to me&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For me, yoga is far more than physical exercises. It is an attitude that shapes everyday life – both professionally and personally. It reminds me that behind every role and function there is always a human being. This perspective has changed my leadership style: away from pure control, towards more trust, calmness, and leading by example. In my company, some colleagues jokingly call me “Yoda” – a nice sign that mindfulness not only brings calm but also inspiration. For me, yoga is a compass that helps me stay clear, human, and connected even in challenging situations.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Practicing Vrksasana Yoga “Tree Pose” on a hike." style="width: 667px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317117i7BA71D4637A7435A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Yoga_Der Baum.jpeg" alt="Practicing Vrksasana Yoga “Tree Pose” on a hike." /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Practicing Vrksasana Yoga “Tree Pose” on a hike.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1103926692"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Running, swimming, and the strength of connecting with others&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Back in 2000, I joined a group mainly consisting of triathletes and hockey players. That was the moment I finally started running – something I had enjoyed before but never really practiced regularly.&lt;BR /&gt;My last major run was in 2014 in Vienna, a city that holds a special place in my heart.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Last year – as well as this year – I completed an Olympic triathlon. Swimming has always had a calming effect on me, running grounds me in the here and now, and the combination of all three disciplines teaches me perseverance, humility, and trust in my own body.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;I remember well the SAP Community Event in Copenhagen in May 2018 – that’s where I met&amp;nbsp;@smarchesini .&lt;BR /&gt;Sebastiano is not only someone who drives SAP topics forward, but also someone who shares his passion for running with others.&lt;BR /&gt;I am delighted that he will be next in this hobbies series – because running connects us, and I am sure his story will bring fresh inspiration.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Photo of me taken during a race at a multi-generational run" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317118i20C526BEDDE7E2FE/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="3 Lauf der Generationen 384.JPG" alt="Photo of me taken during a race at a multi-generational run" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Photo of me taken during a race at a multi-generational run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-907413187"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join the conversation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do you do Yoga or Meditation? Share the pictures and stories behind them in the comments section. Feel free to share other hobbies you have!&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If you're interested in joining the series, please reach out to Moshe Naveh via community@sap.com.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Let's get this journey going! I hope you all enjoy the great posts coming-up!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/community-corner-blog-posts/sap-community-hobbies-series-don-t-fly-blind-stress-to-strength-mindful/ba-p/14222767"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T08:03:05.076000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%B1%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B8-%D0%B6%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%82%D0%BD%D1%8F/ba-p/14230663</id>
    <title>Вебкасти Жовтня</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T16:21:52.704000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Вебкасти Жовтня 2025: Частина 1 &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":rocket:"&gt;🚀&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Перша половина жовтня насичена безкоштовними вебкастами від SAP - AI, трансформація, data та галузеві рішення!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt; Найближчі заходи:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1 жовтня, 15:00-19:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4942585&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=98DDEC90391042F1B0EC2C72608C443E&amp;amp;groupId=6107761&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Product Compliance Solution Update&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Demos &amp;amp; Customer Stories: стратегія, roadmap та панельні дискусії з EHS та Product Compliance&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;1 жовтня, 17:00-18:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NQrR9-P0KpI" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI in Asset Management&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Як AI трансформує управління активами: intelligent insights та автоматизоване прийняття рішень&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2 жовтня, 15:00-19:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=4942585&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=98DDEC90391042F1B0EC2C72608C443E&amp;amp;groupId=6107761&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Environmental Health &amp;amp; Safety Solutions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;What's New and What's Next у EHS та Product Compliance&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;2 жовтня, 17:00-18:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RK_2AZ-DSM8" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI in Service Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Революція в сервісному управлінні: AI-driven оптимізація та кращий клієнтський досвід&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;7 жовтня, 15:00-16:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/sap-user-groups/apps/251007_introduction_to_the_clean_core_strategy.ics" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Introduction to Clean Core Strategy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Модернізація ERP-ландшафту: як зменшити складність та підготуватися до трансформації&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;8 жовтня, 18:00-19:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=5049141&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=155E33D499506054AF6FD5A553C2BD38&amp;amp;groupId=6298861&amp;amp;mode=preview&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud: Module 3&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Create and Enrich Analytical Model with SAP Datasphere - hands-on workshop&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt; Modules 1-2 доступні on demand!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;9 жовтня, 17:00-18:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/2991608/084D5C4925C3BD9117CB0DD6C46000E7?partnerref=sapUG" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Transforming Shopping Journeys&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Персоналізація та AI у роздрібній торгівлі: від product recommendations до AI-powered пошуку&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;14 жовтня, 15:00-16:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/sap-user-groups/apps/251014_achieving_clean-core_extensibility_levels_kpis_and_governanc.ics" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Achieving Clean Core: Extensibility&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Clean Core Level концепція: KPI, governance та вибір правильних опцій розширюваності&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;14 жовтня, 16:00-17:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-btp-2025/en_us/registration.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Analytics Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Transforming SAP's End-to-End Planning Processes: досвід SAP IT у створенні інтегрованої платформи&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;14 жовтня, 17:00-18:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/2991608/084D5C4925C3BD9117CB0DD6C46000E7?partnerref=sapUG" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Service Cloud V2 - Q3/2025 Release&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Utilities та Enterprise Service Management: нові фічі та інтеграції&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;15 жовтня, 18:00-19:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sapinsider.org/webinars/sapj4c-em-sap-joule-for-consultants-expert-session/?hs-embed-af=t" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Joule for Consultants&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;AI-асистент для консультантів: як підвищити продуктивність та ефективність проєктів&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;*Всі години вказані за київським часом.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;U&gt;Якщо цей допис був корисним — ставте kudos!&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Реєструйтесь вже зараз, посилання в назві вебкасту&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%B1%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B8-%D0%B6%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%82%D0%BD%D1%8F/ba-p/14230663"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T16:21:52.704000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-developer-forums/ba-p/14230147</id>
    <title>New Developer Forums!</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T19:55:55.858000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnePetteroe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Since the platform migration last year so many of you have asked "Where is ABAP?" and "Where are the questions about ABAP?" - we heard you loud an clear. We are therefore thrilled to finally be able to answer your questions as we are launching new Developer forums today!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 20.32.24.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321354iE1158E0403BE1D10/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 20.32.24.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 20.32.24.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;This will be the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/developers/ct-p/developers" target="_self"&gt;new home&lt;/A&gt; for our developers and technical audience in the SAP Community, and we are starting with forums on the following topics:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-general-classic/gh-p/abap" target="_self"&gt;ABAP (classic)&lt;/A&gt;: Everything general around ABAP, the ABAP platform or classic ABAP development. (including DDIC, ABAP List Viewer (ALV), ABAP SQL, DYNP including PBO and PAI)&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-cloud/gh-p/abap-cloud" target="_self"&gt;ABAP Cloud&lt;/A&gt;: All ABAP Cloud related topics, including ABAP Core Data Services (CDS), ABAP RESTful Application Programming Model (RAP), and ABAP for cloud development.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/artificial-intelligence/gh-p/ai" target="_self"&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;: AI in general, SAP Business AI, Joule, Joule Agents, Joule for Consultants, Joule for Developers or AI Foundation.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-cap/gh-p/cap" target="_self"&gt;SAP CAP&lt;/A&gt;: Everything on SAP Cloud Application Programming Model.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics/gh-p/data-analytics" target="_self"&gt;Data and Analytics&lt;/A&gt;:
&lt;UL class="lia-list-style-type-square"&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud, including Databricks, Datasphere, Analytics Cloud and Business Warehouse.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA and SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;SAP Master Data Governance.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/frontend-ui5-sap-fiori/gh-p/frontend-ui5-fiori" target="_self"&gt;Frontend / UI5 / SAP Fiori&lt;/A&gt;: All frontend-related topics, including SAPUI5, OpenUI5 and SAP Fiori.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/integration/gh-p/integration" target="_self"&gt;Integration&lt;/A&gt;: For all SAP Integration related topics. (not limited to SAP Integration Suite)&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build/gh-p/tooling" target="_self"&gt;Tooling, including SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;: For all topics related to any SAP development tool, like SAP Build Code and ABAP Development Tools for Eclipse.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;But more than just launching a home for our developer/technical audience, we are also bringing back forums as a content type, including a more compact forum feed, threaded replies and not least a filter that many of you have requested for questions with no answers. We will get into the details of the new forums below &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;All developer forums consist of a hub with options both for asking questions (forum) and for publishing blog posts:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.07.21.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321056i0594C8D312E90D34/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.07.21.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.07.21.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;To be able to publish content in the forums, you first need to join the group/forum, therefore please make sure you hit the "Join Group" button:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.13.52.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321063i0B802DDE4D8B5D5F/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.13.52.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.13.52.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Joining the forum also automatically triggers a subscription to new content published in the group.&lt;BR /&gt;You can check or change your subscriptions and notifications in your account settings &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/myprofilepage/tab/user-subscriptions" target="_self"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890838823"&gt;Forums&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;As mentioned above, we are bringing back forums as a content type.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;This first iteration of the new forum feed does not contain any preview of content, thus making it easier/faster for everyone to scroll down the list to identify the questions they might have an answer to.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;The feed gives you an overview over who asked the question, when it was published, and you can also see who replied to it last (and when), if there are replies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;We also included a filter that many of you have requested, "No answers", which shows you all questions with no interaction. This is different to "No Solutions", as the no solutions filter will give you an overview over questions with an answer, but where the author has not yet accepted one of the answers as the right solution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Questions with a solution can easily be identified in the feed with the green checkmark to the left of the question. The second iteration of the forum feed will make it even easier to quickly identify questions with accepted solutions in the feed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;We also kept the icons for views, answers/replies and kudos/views in the feed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.02.59.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321131i86506C390B1462BF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.02.59.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.02.59.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Another change with forums, compared to the Q&amp;amp;As, is that we are bringing back threaded replies to questions. For forums there is no difference if it is a comment asking for clarification, or if you know the answer to the question.&amp;nbsp;The correct answer can be found anywhere in the threaded conversation, and the author has the option to accept any answer as the correct solution to the question.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;As you can see in the screenshot below, it is not possible to accept any reply, anywhere in the conversation as the solution:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 13.24.33.png" style="width: 950px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321136iF93065CFCD2A88BE/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 13.24.33.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 13.24.33.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;When a question has an accepted solution, it will behave the same way as the Q&amp;amp;As. The question will have an "Go to solution" marker on top, and the accepted answer will be displayed directly below the question with a green checkmark and a green box to identify as the correct solution:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 13.27.37.png" style="width: 872px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321137iC67E24FA397697D3/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 13.27.37.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 13.27.37.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Other than joining the group, no special permissions is needed to ask your question in the forums. Even if you are new to the SAP Community, and come here to find help, you can do so immediately after creating a new account.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;As everywhere else in the Community, please do not answer questions with AI-generated content. If you don't know the answer, please move on to the next question where you know the answer, instead of trying to build a reputation by publishing AI-generated answers that do not add any value, and in many cases also are misleading or false.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1694325318"&gt;Blog posts&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Blog posts in the developer forums will not have a separation between SAP employees and external community users.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Although the forums will not be curated,&amp;nbsp; we will keep a close eye on what gets published to ensure the quality of the content is according to our guidelines. Blog posts in the SAP Community should be used to share value and your personal knowledge and expertise.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;The permissions to publish blog posts will follow the rank ladder system, so if you are new to community, your blog posts will be subject to moderation review. Community users who already have permissions to publish blog posts in the "Product and Technology" categories, will be able to publish blog posts directly in the new forums, without moderation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;You can find more information on moderation in the SAP Community in &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-knowledge-base/moderation-on-sap-community/ta-p/14220311" target="_self"&gt;this article&lt;/A&gt; in our &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner/gh-p/welcome-corner" target="_self"&gt;Welcome Corner group&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The "Featured Topics" section is curated by the SAP Community team for now, and will focus on highlighting important product updates that should not be missed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497811813"&gt;Pilot-phase&lt;/H3&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The launch today is a pilot, as we want to first see how you all respond before we make a final decision on whether or not forums are here to stay. The pilot will run for 3 months, until the end of the year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;All forums start empty, with no published content.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;The exception is the three groups which we have moved over from the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/interest-groups/ct-p/interests" target="_self"&gt;Interest groups&lt;/A&gt;, namely "Artificial Intelligence", "Data and Analytics", and "Integration" - these three groups were moved to the new Developers area with their content.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We will over the next months continuously improve the user experience in the forums and forum feeds,&amp;nbsp;and are as always open to feedback and suggestions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;And one last thing. We have set the "Application Development and Automation" group to read only for now, to encourage everyone to participate here instead. We will decide what to do with the group and its content once this pilot has ended.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The SAP Developer News posts from the SAP Developer Advocate team will be published &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/developer-news/bg-p/developer-news" target="_self"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; in the meantime.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Happy foruming everyone!&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1430381027"&gt;Known bugs&lt;/H4&gt;
&lt;P&gt;On the main forum page, the button still says "Start a Discussion", this will be changed to "Ask a question" as soon as possible:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 16.11.00.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321213i0ADA93A4C539A8A7/image-size/small?v=v2&amp;amp;px=200" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 16.11.00.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 16.11.00.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In the mobile portrait view of the forum feed, the last filter tab may break to another line in some cases. We are aware of this, and it will be fixed in one of our upcoming releases:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="image.png" style="width: 391px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321147iA0E60B2CFC1C40B2/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="image.png" alt="image.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-developer-forums/ba-p/14230147"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T19:55:55.858000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-what-is-happening-week-1/ba-p/14230558</id>
    <title>Devtoberfest 2025 - What is happening Week 1</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T20:47:20.471000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KevinR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423549</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hurray! Devtoberfest 2025 just launched. Let me welcome you to a &lt;STRONG&gt;full month&lt;/STRONG&gt; of education, learning, networking and fun!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To give you a better overview on what is happening each week, I will release blog posts covering activities for each week.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;It can be that we will assign points and badges retroactively for this week as we are currently facing issues. No worries, all activities are being monitored!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890842699"&gt;Sessions for Week 1 (Sep 29 - Oct 3):&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;All sessions for Week 1 can be found in our Session Catalogue:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/eb-p/devtoberfest-events" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/eb-p/devtoberfest-events&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1823411913"&gt;🟢 ABAP (Monday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/clean-core-extensibility-strategy-powered-by-abap-cloud-and-generative-ai/ev-p/14183861" target="_self"&gt;Clean Core Extensibility Strategy Powered by ABAP Cloud and Generative AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/custom-code-development-and-transformation-for-clean-core-in-sap-s-4hana/ev-p/14205747" target="_self"&gt;Custom code development and transformation for Clean Core in SAP S/4HANA&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/boost-your-developer-satisfaction-with-sap-joule-for-developers-abap-ai/ev-p/14183120" target="_self"&gt;Boost Your Developer Satisfaction with SAP Joule for Developers, ABAP AI Capabilities&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1626898408"&gt;🟣 Tooling &amp;amp; Frontend (Tuesday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/code-along-build-a-joule-skill-from-scratch-with-joule-studio/ev-p/14197049" target="_self"&gt;Code-Along: Build a Joule Skill from Scratch with Joule Studio&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/building-agents-with-joule-studio/ev-p/14191307" target="_self"&gt;Building Agents with Joule Studio&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/unboxing-joule-studio-honest-insights-from-hack2build-champions/ev-p/14197584" target="_self"&gt;Unboxing Joule Studio: Honest Insights from Hack2Build Champions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/introducing-application-frontend-simplifying-ui-app-hosting/ev-p/14218995" target="_self"&gt;Introducing Application Frontend: Simplifying UI App Hosting&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/create-a-case-in-service-cloud-v2-by-uploading-images-using-ai-core-build/ev-p/14194984" target="_self"&gt;Create a Case in Service Cloud V2 by Uploading Images Using AI Core, Build Apps&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1430384903"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":red_circle:"&gt;🔴&lt;/span&gt;Integration (Wednesday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/accelerate-your-move-to-the-cloud-via-pipeline-for-cloud-integration/ev-p/14179023" target="_self"&gt;Accelerate your move to the cloud via Pipeline for Cloud Integration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/clean-core-event-driven-unlocking-sap-value-with-advanced-event-mesh/ev-p/14179025" target="_self"&gt;Clean Core, Event-Driven: Unlocking SAP Value with Advanced Event Mesh&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/designing-understandable-sap-btp-solution-diagrams-amp-contributing-to-the/ev-p/14217362" target="_self"&gt;Designing understandable SAP BTP Solution Diagrams &amp;amp; contributing to the SAP Architecture Center&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/open-resource-discovery-how-to-build-a-well-connected-metadata-catalog/ev-p/14179950" target="_self"&gt;Open Resource Discovery – How to build a well-connected metadata catalog across silos&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1233871398"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":blue_circle:"&gt;🔵&lt;/span&gt;Data &amp;amp; AI (Thursday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/leveraging-calculation-views-in-sap-bas-an-introduction/ev-p/14208844" target="_self"&gt;Leveraging Calculation Views in SAP BAS: an Introduction&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/enrich-data-products-with-sap-databricks/ev-p/14208928" target="_self"&gt;Enrich Data Products with SAP Databricks&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/behind-the-magic-how-cirque-du-soleil-reimagined-invoice-management-with/ev-p/14227799" target="_self"&gt;Behind the Magic: How Cirque du Soleil Reimagined Invoice Management with SAP Business AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1037357893"&gt;🟠 CAP (Friday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/building-enterprise-grade-cap-applications-using-btp-developer-s-guide/ev-p/14208567" target="_self"&gt;Building Enterprise Grade CAP applications using BTP Developer's guide&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/get-to-know-more-about-cap-s-documentation-offering/ev-p/14212557" target="_self"&gt;Get to know more about CAP’s documentation offering&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/integrating-s-4hana-public-cloud-apis-into-cap-made-simple/ev-p/14214711" target="_self"&gt;Integrating S/4HANA Public Cloud APIs into CAP Made Simple&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-840844388"&gt;🟡 Community (Friday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/the-new-developer-forums-in-the-community/ev-p/14198646" target="_self"&gt;The New Developer Forums in the Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-515248164"&gt;Fun Activities - The Devtoberfest Scavenger Hunt&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In week 1, we are launching the new and challenging Scavenger Hunt! Find clues, put them together and gain a lot of points towards the Grand Prize!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For all information about the Scavenger Hunt, follow Daniel's blog post:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/fun-for-week-1-the-devtoberfest-scavenger-hunt/ba-p/14183972" target="_self"&gt;🟡 Fun for Week 1: The Devtoberfest Scavenger Hunt &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer:"&gt;🔨&lt;/span&gt;🪙&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-318734659"&gt;Validation of your session participation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;At Devtoberfest, almost every activity earns you points against the Grand Prize in our competition. This is the case for your participation in the Devtoberfest sessions for each week. Every week we release validation tutorials for the different topic tracks&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP, Tooling &amp;amp; Frontend, Integration, Data &amp;amp; AI, CAP, and the Community sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The validation tutorials can be found in our &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorial-navigator.html?search=Devtoberfest" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Tutorial Navigator&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;It can be that we will assign points and badges retroactively for this week as we are currently facing issues. No worries, all activities are being monitored!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Head over to our tutorial page and complete the validation tutorials for earning your points!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-122221154"&gt;List of all point earning activities&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badge Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - ABAP, Week 1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-abap-week1-session-validation.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Week 1 - ABAP sessions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;1200&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Create an ABAP Cloud Project&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-environment-create-abap-cloud-project.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create an ABAP Cloud Project&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;500&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Create an ABAP Database Table and Relevant ABAP Dictionary Objects&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-dev-create-table.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create an ABAP Database Table and Relevant ABAP Dictionary Objects&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Create Your First ABAP Console Application&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-environment-console-application.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create Your First ABAP Console Application&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Create Business Configuration Maintenance Object&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-environment-deploy-cf-production.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create a SAP Fiori App and Deploy it to SAP BTP, ABAP Environment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Expose a Standard Core Data Service for ABAP Environment&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-environment-business-service-provisioning.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Expose a Standard Core Data Service for ABAP Environment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badge Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Tooling, Week 1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-tooling-week1-session-validation.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Tooling, Week 1&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1200&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Create an SAP Fiori App Using Business Application Studio&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/appstudio-fioriapps-create.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create an SAP Fiori App Using SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Set Up Prerequisites for SAP Build CodeJam&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/codejam-0-prerequisites.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Set Up Prerequisites for SAP Build CodeJam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Create the Product List Page&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/codejam-01-homepage.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;1 - Create the Product List Page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Configure the Product Details Page&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/codejam-02-product-detail-page.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2 - Configure the Product Details Page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Configure the Shopping Cart Page&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/codejam-03-cart-page.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3 - Configure the Shopping Cart Page&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;500&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badge Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Integration, Week 1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-integration-week1-integration-session-validatio.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Week 1 - Integration sessions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;1200&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Save, Filter and Get your needed data in your Integration Flow&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-integration-suite-integral-cpi-tasks.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Save, Filter and Get your needed data in your Integration Flow&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Consume a SAP Sales and Service Core API to create Sales Orders using SAP Cloud Integration&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-integration-suite-integral-sales-core.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Consume a SAP Sales and Service Core API to create Sales Orders using SAP Cloud Integration&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Send SMS using SAP Cloud Integration while consuming a Twilio API&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-integration-suite-integral-cpi-urlencoded.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Send SMS using SAP Cloud Integration while consuming a Twilio API&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Configure SAP API Management policies to avoid CORS issues and generate an API Key&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-integration-suite-integral-api-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Configure SAP API Management policies to avoid CORS issues and generate an API Key&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Integrate SAP Build Apps with SAP Integration Suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-integration-suite-integral-appgyver.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Integrate SAP Build Apps with SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&amp;nbsp;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badge Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Thursday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Data &amp;amp; AI, Week 1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-dataai-week1-session-validation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Week 1 - Data &amp;amp; AI sessions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;1200&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badge Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - CAP, Week 1&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-cap-week1-session-validation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Week 1 - CAP sessions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;1200&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Create a CAP Project with SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-cap-beginner-bas-wizard.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create a CAP Project with SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Learn About Selected CAP Conventions&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-cap-beginner-golden-path.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Learn About Selected CAP Conventions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Petoberfest&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Post your Petoberfest picture in the respective Blog Post.&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Will go live on Oct 3rd&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;1000&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;-&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-community-week1-session-validation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - The New Developer Forums in the Community&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enjoy your Devtoberfest Event 2025!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-what-is-happening-week-1/ba-p/14230558"/>
    <published>2025-09-29T20:47:20.471000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tri%C3%A2ngulo-mineiro-blog-posts/ajudem-estudantes-a-aprender-como-as-empresas-l%C3%ADderes-utilizam-a-tecnologia/ba-p/14232053</id>
    <title>Ajudem estudantes a aprender como as empresas líderes utilizam a tecnologia SAP em processos</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T21:55:17.653000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Renato_Baracca</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/527140</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;A &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP University Alliances&lt;/STRONG&gt; está oferecendo o curso &lt;STRONG&gt;Business Processes Open Lecture 2025/26&lt;/STRONG&gt;, uma oportunidade exclusiva para &lt;STRONG&gt;estudantes&lt;/STRONG&gt; conhecerem na prática como funcionam os principais processos empresariais com o suporte do SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":blue_book:"&gt;📘&lt;/span&gt; O curso tem &lt;STRONG&gt;60 horas&lt;/STRONG&gt; de duração e combina teoria e prática para oferecer uma visão completa dos processos de negócio em ação.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":white_heavy_check_mark:"&gt;✅&lt;/span&gt; E o melhor: ao final, você ainda terá a chance de realizar um &lt;STRONG&gt;exame oficial de certificação SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":spiral_calendar:"&gt;🗓&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Período:&lt;/STRONG&gt; 30 de outubro de 2025 a 31 de março de 2026&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Inscreva-se gratuitamente:&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;A target="_new" rel="noopener"&gt;https://imsap.co/6042Ag4Qn&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tri%C3%A2ngulo-mineiro-blog-posts/ajudem-estudantes-a-aprender-como-as-empresas-l%C3%ADderes-utilizam-a-tecnologia/ba-p/14232053"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T21:55:17.653000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/enhancements-to-sap-community-september-2025/ba-p/14231974</id>
    <title>Enhancements to SAP Community - September 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T08:54:05.368000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnePetteroe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;ul =""&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/enhancements-to-sap-community-september-2025/ba-p/14231974#toc-hId-1761793673"&gt;New Standards for Tags and Labels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/enhancements-to-sap-community-september-2025/ba-p/14231974#toc-hId-1565280168"&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt; tag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/enhancements-to-sap-community-september-2025/ba-p/14231974#toc-hId-1368766663"&gt;Table of Contents (TOC)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/enhancements-to-sap-community-september-2025/ba-p/14231974#toc-hId-1172253158"&gt;Dismissible global banner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/enhancements-to-sap-community-september-2025/ba-p/14231974#toc-hId-975739653"&gt;Glow/Dark Mode Fixes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:15px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/enhancements-to-sap-community-september-2025/ba-p/14231974#toc-hId-779226148"&gt;Creation Date Filter on Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We have been busy lately, and didn't only launch &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-developer-forums/ba-p/14230147" target="_self"&gt;new developer forums&lt;/A&gt; this week, but we also released a few other features.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761793673"&gt;&lt;SPAN class="TextRun MacChromeBold SCXW144030445 BCX0" data-contrast="auto"&gt;&lt;SPAN class="NormalTextRun SCXW144030445 BCX0"&gt;New Standards for Tags and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="NormalTextRun CommentStart CommentHighlightPipeRest CommentHighlightRest SCXW144030445 BCX0"&gt;Labels&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class="EOP CommentHighlightPipeRest SCXW144030445 BCX0" data-ccp-props="{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:240}"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;We are setting limitations for the number of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/help/faqpage/title/Associated_Products" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="none"&gt;SAP Managed Tags&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/help/faqpage/title/tagging" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="none"&gt;user tags&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/help/faqpage/title/labels" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="none"&gt;labels&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt; that members can add to blog posts, questions, discussions, and documents. With these new standards, members will only be able to add ten of each type – meaning a maximum of ten SAP Managed Tags, ten user tags, and ten labels per piece of content.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;By setting these limitations, we’ll make it easier for members to find relevant content that interests them – as excessive tagging and labeling causes confusion in feeds and may frustrate members who receive notifications for posts that don’t match their expectations. Too many tags can also make it difficult for members to identify what a question is actually about, or if a blog post contains information that appeals to them.&amp;nbsp;That’s why fewer tags are better – and why these new limitations have become necessary.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;Adding the right mix of SAP Managed Tags, user tags, and labels helps members locate what they want, so it’s important to understand what these selections represent – and equally important to be disciplined when picking them.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN data-ccp-props="{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:240}"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;SAP Managed Tags come from the official list of SAP offerings, as &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/all-sap-managed-tags/ct-p/managed-tags" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="none"&gt;shown here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;. Every blog post, question, discussion, and document require at least one SAP Managed Tag for publication. As a best practice, we recommend no more than three of these tags.&amp;nbsp;It is possible to subscribe to an SAP Managed Tag so that you will receive notifications of new content about that product.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;Complementing SAP Managed Tags are user tags. These tags are created by the users themselves. User tags aren’t tied to any official list, so members have flexibility when coming up with these additional tags.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;We’re setting a maximum of ten for labels as well. &amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Members can subscribe to a label to get notifications of new content associated with that label.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;While a minimum of one SAP Managed Tag is mandatory for most content types, user tags and labels are generally optional – although a single label may also be mandatory for certain groups/boards.&amp;nbsp;If you attempt to add more than ten, you’ll receive an error message when attempting to publish, and you’ll need to reduce the number before you can post the content.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN data-ccp-props="{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:240}"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;Note that these changes won’t impact existing content, so if you’ve been in the habit of adding dozens of tags and labels to content you’ve published in the past, you won’t need to go back and trim anything. But if you do try to make changes to this content (such as to correct a typo that you notice in an old blog post), you will need to make sure the post doesn’t exceed the maximum number of tags and/or labels. The system won’t let you update old content unless it meets the new standards for tagging and labeling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN data-ccp-props="{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:240}"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-contrast="auto"&gt;By applying SAP Managed Tags, user tags, and labels effectively (and judiciously), you’ll ensure that your content finds the right audience. Limiting the choices, to keep content more focused, will help your posts perform better, draw proper attention, and create a better experience for all.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN data-ccp-props="{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:240}"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="content.png" style="width: 551px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321867iC3445264A1A5148C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="content.png" alt="content.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565280168"&gt;&lt;SPAN data-ccp-props="{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:240}"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt; tag&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-ccp-props="{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:240}"&gt;We have added the ability to use the &amp;lt;code&amp;gt; tag for inline code elements.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;The &amp;lt;code&amp;gt; HTML element displays its contents styled in a colored monospaced font to indicate that the text is a short fragment of code in the body of a post.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;For longer pieces of code, please continue to use the "Insert/Edit code sample" functionality of the editor.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN data-ccp-props="{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:240}"&gt;To use the &amp;lt;code&amp;gt; tag, you need to open the HTML/Source code editor from the toolbar:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 18.52.16.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321758i54F7B6548959D4B1/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 18.52.16.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 18.52.16.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Next, you add the &amp;lt;code&amp;gt; tag around the inline code fragment you would like to share, or highlight in your post:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 18.51.53.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321759i8358858DE1780E39/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 18.51.53.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 18.51.53.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The published version of the post will look like this:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 18.54.22.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321760i926EC3C88AD4E583/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 18.54.22.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 18.54.22.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368766663"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Table of Contents (TOC)&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We have also added the ability to add a Table of Contents (TOC) to both blog posts and documents (Knowledge Base articles).&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;To use the Table of Contents functionality, you start by writing/adding your text in the editor after which you click the new "Table of Contents" button in the toolbar:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.15.53.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321799i88F4334512C10ED7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.15.53.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.15.53.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Clicking the button will open a "Manage Table of Contents" pop-up which will give you a preview of the TOCs, including an overview over the TOC options:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.30.27.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321800i6AA191F270077958/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.30.27.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.30.27.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;After clicking "Save", you will see a new "Table of Contents" menu at the top of the editor. Clicking this will open the "Manage Table of Contents" pop-up any time you need to access it:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.29.18.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321801i3622FA1CC8627D3B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.29.18.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.29.18.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The TOCs in the final published post will look like this:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.34.09.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321802i37D4962D244A6A46/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.34.09.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 19.34.09.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172253158"&gt;Dismissible global banner&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;You asked if we could make the global banners dismissible, which we did.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;Clicking the "x" in the banner will now remove the banner, until a new banner is added.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 22.50.32.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321803i093F829601161FBC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 22.50.32.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-30 at 22.50.32.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;There will still be some areas of the community where the banners cannot be removed, for instance in our &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/archived-content/ct-p/Archive" target="_self"&gt;"Archived Content" area&lt;/A&gt;, where we have permanent banners informing users that content there is set to read-only.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975739653"&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Glow/Dark Mode Fixes&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Various Glow (new design) and Dark mode fixes were released this month as well.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;For instance:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;the Label widget has been hidden in some boards&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;the word ‘Board’ has been removed from the top of feeds to allow for the content to be moved up&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Spacing around headers in posts have been fixed&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779226148"&gt;Creation Date Filter on Feeds&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;A ‘Creation Date’ sorting option has been added on the various feeds to allow for easier sorting of the various posts. This is the default sorting of all feeds:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-01 at 08.40.04.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321868iFE92AD5F9E0665B5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-01 at 08.40.04.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-01 at 08.40.04.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/enhancements-to-sap-community-september-2025/ba-p/14231974"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T08:54:05.368000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/fun-for-week-2-petoberfest/ba-p/14209744</id>
    <title>🟡 Fun for Week 2: Petoberfest 🐱🐶🐵🐷🐻🐸🐔🐴🦬🦎🐠🦜🐧🐌🐛</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T18:00:00.032000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dan_Wroblewski</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/72</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome to Petoberfest, a tradition of Devtoberfest when you get a chance to show off your beloved pet hamster, cat, iguana, dog or whatever your pet is.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Post a picture of your pet.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;Do not have a living, breathing pet? Upload a picture of your favorite neighbor's pet, or your favorite stuffed animal, or your favorite zoo animal, or any animal that tickles your fancy. Just participate!&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":backhand_index_pointing_right:"&gt;👉&lt;/span&gt;You can also upload a picture of you participating in any animal welfare activity (more on World Animal Day, below).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here's my dog, Pepper, begging for food and enjoying a day at the beach.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_9748.jpg" style="width: 314px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310509iEB8C3FB181B39141/image-dimensions/314x355/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="314" height="355" role="button" title="IMG_9748.jpg" alt="IMG_9748.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="IMG_7996.JPG" style="width: 476px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310513i7656235E42C14C9A/image-dimensions/476x357/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="476" height="357" role="button" title="IMG_7996.JPG" alt="IMG_7996.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1759259423"&gt;It wouldn't be anything without AI&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;And just to make it a little bit more interesting, upload a picture of your pet, then use the picture with any generative AI tool to create your pet doing something fun: like ....&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Doing your SAP programming work&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Flying to save the day&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Sipping a pina colada on the beach&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;... or whatever you think of.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Be creative, in what your pet is doing, as well as the style of the image.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here's Pepper expressing her love for SAP Build and helping me create my Devtoberfest Cryptic Crossword (she really does help me).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="ChatGPT Image Aug 17, 2025, 04_51_51 PM.png" style="width: 444px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/310512iFCD5DB85DAD2D7D6/image-dimensions/444x665/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="444" height="665" role="button" title="ChatGPT Image Aug 17, 2025, 04_51_51 PM.png" alt="ChatGPT Image Aug 17, 2025, 04_51_51 PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But I'm sure you can be much more creative.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1562745918"&gt;World Animal Day&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Petoberfest coincides with World Animal Day (Oct. 4),&amp;nbsp;which "&lt;SPAN&gt;exists to raise the status of animals and improve welfare standards around the globe".&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;According to the &lt;A href="https://www.worldanimalday.org.uk/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;World Animal Day group&lt;/A&gt; in Cheltenham, Gloucestershire::&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-indent-padding-left-30px" style="padding-left : 30px;"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;It’s a day for all animal lovers near and far.&amp;nbsp; Through organised events, big and small,&amp;nbsp; we raise awareness of how animals are treated globally.&amp;nbsp;We rally together organisations, children’s groups, schools,&amp;nbsp;clubs, companies, communities and individuals&amp;nbsp;to show we care deeply about animals.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One way you can show you care about animals is to post a picture of your pet, or a picture of any activity you participate in to help the welfare of animals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1366232413"&gt;Point, Points, Points&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Everyone who posts images of their pets will receive 1000 points toward the Devtoberfest grand prize.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;So post today, and comment and like the other community members' posts.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/fun-for-week-2-petoberfest/ba-p/14209744"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T18:00:00.032000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-new-enhancements-developers-forums-and-kick-off-event/ba-p/14233034</id>
    <title>SAP Community Voice: New Enhancements, Developers Forums and Kick-off Event for SAP TechEd!</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T23:00:13.620000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>GabrielaSoares</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2089515</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;The month of September is over, but let’s take time to give a shoutout for all the great things this month brought to our SAP Community! More than 10 new platform features and enhancements, fresh new Blog Badges, the comeback of Developer Forums, and insightful content from our members. We’ve also hit a new milestone with 50K YouTube subscribers, and we would like to show our gratitude to everyone who continues to contribute and grow with us.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;And to give you even more inspiration and reasons to connect with other members, we are celebrating and sharing all the information about the start of Devtoberfest and announcements for SAP TechEd on Tour (including the opportunity to become Community Talk Speaker for SAP TechEd on Tour in Bangalore!).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Read more below to find out what’s happening in and around SAP Community!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761844482"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Featured Content&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1823496415"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN class=""&gt;Simplified Journey with ALM and Integrated Toolchain Themes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Whether you are beginner or looking to reinforce your knowledge about SAP Cloud ALM, this step-by-step post by SAP´s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/578968" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@lealmeida&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, will for sure give you all the core features, background on integrated toolchain comprising powerful solutions and possible outcomes. Additionally, this content includes SAP Activate Methodology, to provide structured guidance for implementing SAP solutions effectively. Full of great resources, we highly encourage you to read, try and share your achievements in the comments!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-cloud-alm-amp-integrated-toolchain-your-ultimate-learning-path/ba-p/14205152" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1626982910"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Migrating from SAP PO to SAP Integration Suite (CPI)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The process of migrating from SAP Process Orchestration (PO) to SAP Integration Suite (CPI), sometimes can be very tricky. But, in this step-by-step guide written by&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1401210" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@Praveen_Kumar_Beera,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; you will learn how to connect SAP PO to SAP Cloud Connector, add it in SAP Integration Suite, and import message mappings along with dependent objects such as Imported Archives and Function Libraries. Beyond the technical shift, he made sure to explain how migrating is also an opportunity to modernize integration landscapes, adopt cloud-first patterns, and leverage the flexibility of SAP BTP. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/migrating-from-sap-po-to-sap-integration-suite-cpi-a-practical-guide/ba-p/14219938" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1430469405"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New feature in SAP BTP cockpit&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP´s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/404594" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@annikarossel&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, brought great news with the introduction of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Favorites and Recent&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; new feature for the SAP BTP cockpit. Providing faster and efficient access to important resources from everywhere in the cockpit, the main goal is to help you grow your productivity across various accounts, applications and services. Make sure to check the tutorial videos in the blog post, search where you can find these new buttons and give your feedback via the shell bar icon in the cockpit or join the user research survey.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-favorites-and-recent-in-sap-btp-cockpit-a-personalized/ba-p/14217622" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1233955900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd Expert Playlist&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;TechEd is right around the corner, and the best way to prepare is organizing yourself to attend the sessions with topics that you are most passionate about. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/7391" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@Marla-Schweiki&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, SAP community member since 2018 and that has recently joined SAP Mentors program, prepared her &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Expert Playlist &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;including all the themes and speakers in her favorites list. Be sure to check her selection and get some inspiration to make the most out of your time in Berlin!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/my-expert-playlist-sap-teched-berlin-2025-and-teched-virtual/ba-p/14219011" target="_blank"&gt;Read the blog post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779276957"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Community News&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-840928890"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New searching Beta&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you ever struggled on finding a specific topic, event or user on SAP Community platform, we think you probably will enjoy the new Searching Beta feature. Powered by Coveo, this option you can select on the search bar and offers enhanced filtering and federated results across multiple repositories, including &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP.com&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/store.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Store&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://support.sap.com/en/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Support Portal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; There are also new menus that let you filter by specific products and SAP Managed Tags. You can either search for available products and tags or select multiple options. Additionally, the members request has been heard and now it is also possible to filter questions by status (answered, solved, and open). Try the new beta search for yourself, explore around and give your feedback on the comments inside the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-intelligent-search-available-in-beta-phase/ba-p/14221475" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post here.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-644415385"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Update on Rules of Engagement&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Being an active member inside the SAP Community, also comes with the responsibility of following the rules and collaborating for a safe and enjoyable experience for everyone. In September the rules were updated to bring more clarification on participation etiquette, guidelines on publishing content and information on user profile. One of the most important is Article 3, that now has been revised to define what is “Unacceptable Content,” aligning with the EU’s Digital Services Act (DSA), and clarifies that job opportunities and postings are no longer permitted in the SAP Community. Please, we highly recommend reading the whole document &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pages.community.sap.com/resources/rules-of-engagement" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and putting effort into following the rules.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-447901880"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New blog badges&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In recognition of all our community bloggers, the full set of blogger badges is now live! If you are an active content creator, you have probably already seen this update and received a notification on your new badge. With milestones ranging from 1 to 30 content published, SAP´s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/204139" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@CaroleighDeneen&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; explained on her &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/introducing-a-new-badge-progression-set-just-for-bloggers/ba-p/14225884" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;latest blog post all the details on the progression set&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. If you’d like to get involved with blogging, start by taking our &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/community-tour.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;community tutorial&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and familiarize yourself with ours &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/welcome-corner-knowledge-base/moderation-on-sap-community/ta-p/14220311" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;moderation policy for blogging&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-251388375"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New developers Forums&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Many of the members have been looking forward to this and our SAP Community team is thrilled to announce the launch of Developer Forums. Covering topics like ABAP (classic and cloud), AI, SAP CAP, Data &amp;amp; Analytics, HANA, Fiori/UI5, Integration, and Tooling&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;this is the new home for our developers and technical audience. Perhaps, the forums include threaded replies, a more compact feed for faster browsing, and a filter that many of you have been waiting for: “No answers”. The Developer Forums will be running as a pilot for 3 months, SAP will refine the experience based on feedback, so now is the best time to join. So, make sure to read more details on &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36535" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@AnnePetteroe&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-developer-forums/ba-p/14230147" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;post about the new feature&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and use the comment section to tell us what you think!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--442842225"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;More Enhancements to SAP Community&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As you probably noticed by now, September was remarkable for the number of new enhancements in SAP Community. To make our members experience more smooth and complete, we are happy to launch:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New Standards for Tags and Labels -&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Enables only 10 SAP Managed Tags, user tags and ten labels per piece of content.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt; tag - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ability to inline &amp;lt;code&amp;gt; HTML element in the body of a post, which will be displayed its contents styled in a colored monospaced font.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Table of Contents (TOC) - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Functionality that allows to add the Table of Contents for blog posts and documents (Knowledge Base articles).&amp;nbsp; This button will open a “Managed Table of Contents” to give you a preview and options overview.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dismissible Global Banner - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The team heard our members request and now is possible to find the button “X” in the banner, which will be removed until a new banner is added. Perhaps, some areas in the platform the banner cannot be removed (e.g., &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/archived-content/ct-p/Archive" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;"Archived Content" area&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, where we have permanent banners informing users that content there is set to read-only).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Glow/Dark Mode Fixes – &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Both modes were fixed and now the Label widget has been hidden in some boards, the “Board” word has also been removed from the top of the feed (allowing the content to be moved up) and “spacing” around headers in post is fixed.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Date Filter on Feeds - &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Creation Date’ sorting option has been added to all feeds, making it easier to organize and view posts by when they were created.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/enhancements-to-sap-community-september-2025/ba-p/14231974" target="_blank"&gt;Check more details and images description of each one of these new features here!&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--639355730"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;YouTube channel reached 50K&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One of our main social channels has just reached a new milestone! The SAP Community YouTube channel now has more than 50k subscribers. We would like to say thank you to each one of our members who is active in our community and always engages with our videos. You are the reason we keep creating and doing our best to deliver great content. And if you’re not yet aware of our channel, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/@SAPCommunity" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;watch now here&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, explore our playlists, and subscribe to get notifications every time we upload another cool video!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--249063221"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Events&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1032382740"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Devtoberfest is here!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Built for developers by developers, the Devtoberfest by SAP TechEd has officially started! This first week is full of amazing sessions about ABAP, Tooling &amp;amp; Frontend, Integration, Data &amp;amp; AI, CAP and many fun activities &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/fun-for-week-1-the-devtoberfest-scavenger-hunt/ba-p/14183972" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;(For more information about the Scavenger Hunt, check Daniel´s post)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. If you are actively participating, don´t forget to earn your points for the Grand Prize competition, by taking the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorial-navigator.html?search=Devtoberfest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;validation tutorials here.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; Check the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-what-is-happening-week-1/ba-p/14230558" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;latest blog post&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; by &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423549" target="_self"&gt;@KevinR&lt;/A&gt; for more details on the list of all the points you can earn for each activity. Don´t miss this chance to participate!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1228896245"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reminder of TechEd Agenda Builder&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The end of the year for our SAP Community also means that we are getting closer to TechEd. Once again, we would like to remind everyone to take the time to build your agenda. Available for both onsite or online attendees, this tool allows you to mix and match the sessions with topics you are most looking forward to watching. Remember: you need a Full Conference Pass to book Hands-On Workshops and there is a maximum of 2 allowed per attendee. Act now because they fill up fast! &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/put-your-thinking-cap-on-it-s-time-to-make-some-tough-choices/ba-p/14211727%20i" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Read here more details on how to do it&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1425409750"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP TechEd on Tour is coming to Sydney!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Calling all our folks from Australia, because the SAP TechEd on Tour is coming to Sydney this year! From the 12 until 14 of November, the ICC Sydney will be hosting one of the biggest learning and networking events for our SAP community. Tracks covering the biggest trend topics, Developer Garage, the presence of SAP Mentors and Champions and much more. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/sap-teched-on-tour-is-coming-to-sydney/ba-p/14223499" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Look on this post for more details&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; And if you are part of the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sydney/gh-p/sydney" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sydney Location group&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; or are planning on visiting the city, make sure to take part!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1621923255"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Call for Community Talk Speakers for SAP TechEd on Tour in Bangalore&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Do you love exchanging insights and experience in SAP technologies with others? Then this is your opportunity to become a Community Talk speaker.&amp;nbsp; For our upcoming SAP TechEd on Tour in Bangalore, happening in November 25-25, we are offering slots for a 20-minute session to showcase your expertise. This is a great opportunity to collaborate and engage with developers, business leaders and expand your reach. The selected speakers get a “Lecture-Only” ticket to attend SAP TechEd (travel and expenses are not covered by SAP). October 10. Is the deadline to submit the application and the notification of acceptance will be sent out on October 17. The final presentation submission for review is on November 10. (but if you are not planning to give a presentation, that is completely fine as well). SAP´s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/25" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;@MynynaChau&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; gave some details on her &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/sap-teched-blog-posts/call-for-community-talk-speakers-step-into-the-spotlight-at-sap-teched-on/ba-p/14226945" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, make sure to read and find more details on the Topics to Consider and the guide on How to Apply.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId--1818436760"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Highlights of SAP Inside Tracks&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-justify" style="text-align : justify;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finally, we would like to recognize the amazing effort our SAP Community has put into the SAP Inside Track´s that happened in September. Congratulations to all event organizers and volunteers at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/newtown-square-events/sap-inside-track-philadelphia/ev-p/14206603" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Inside Track Philadelphia,&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/hamburg-events/sap-inside-track-hamburg-2025-registration-open/ev-p/14164575" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Inside Track Hamburg,&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/porto-events/sap-inside-track-porto-2025/ev-p/13899698" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Inside Track Porto,&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/rio-grande-do-sul-events/sap-sit-rs/ev-p/14139467" target="_blank"&gt;SAP SIT RS (Rio&lt;/A&gt; &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/rio-grande-do-sul-events/sap-sit-rs/ev-p/14139467" target="_blank"&gt;Grande do Sul, Brazil) &lt;/A&gt;. and many other meetups around the world.&amp;nbsp;Stay tuned to our&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/SAPCommunities" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;,&amp;nbsp;where we’ll soon be uploading exclusive content to give you a closer look and inspire you to attend upcoming events in your area!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/sap-community-voice-new-enhancements-developers-forums-and-kick-off-event/ba-p/14233034"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T23:00:13.620000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-what-is-happening-week-2/ba-p/14233248</id>
    <title>Devtoberfest 2025 - What is Happening Week 2</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T09:44:02.195000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>KevinR</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1423549</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Hi everybody, the first week of Devtoberfest is over and we are heading strong into Week 2. This blog post should give you a good overview on what is happening in our second week of Devtoberfest.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890929158"&gt;Sessions for Week 2 (Oct 6 - Oct 10):&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;All sessions for Week 2 can be found in our Session Catalogue:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/eb-p/devtoberfest-events" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/eb-p/devtoberfest-events&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1823498372"&gt;🟢 ABAP (Monday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/sap-btp-abap-environment-how-to-monitor-and-support-custom-cloud-apps/ev-p/14205860" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP BTP ABAP Environment – How to Monitor and Support Custom Cloud Apps&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/explore-the-latest-updates-in-abap-cds/ev-p/14192295" target="_self"&gt;Explore the Latest Updates in ABAP CDS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/updates-on-embedded-analytics-in-abap-cloud/ev-p/14183128" target="_blank"&gt;Updates on Embedded Analytics in ABAP Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1626984867"&gt;🟣 Tooling &amp;amp; Frontend (Tuesday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/wdi5-v3-faster-smoother-smarter/ev-p/14219010" target="_blank"&gt;wdi5 v3: Faster, Smoother, Smarter&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/best-practices-for-quickly-building-extensions-to-sap-successfactors/ev-p/14197069" target="_blank"&gt;Best Practices for Quickly Building Extensions to SAP SuccessFactors&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/leverage-joule-studio-to-implement-custom-skills-for-smart-customer/ev-p/14195048" target="_blank"&gt;Leverage Joule Studio to Implement Custom Skills for Smart Customer Advisory Companion&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/beyond-ui5-controls-with-the-rise-of-web-components/ev-p/14219001" target="_blank"&gt;Beyond UI5 Controls with the Rise of Web Components&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/build-mobile-solutions-with-advanced-scanning-using-sap-build/ev-p/14197082" target="_blank"&gt;Build Mobile Solutions with Advanced Scanning Using SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/multi-tenancy-support-within-sap-build-work-zone/ev-p/14197099" target="_blank"&gt;Multi-tenancy Support within SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1430471362"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":red_circle:"&gt;🔴&lt;/span&gt;Integration (Wednesday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/warp-speed-for-event-creation-overview-on-the-new-event-add-on-for-erp/ev-p/14179044" target="_self"&gt;Warp-Speed for Event Creation: Overview on the New Event Add-on for ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/hands-on-session-practical-demonstration-of-the-event-add-on-for-erp/ev-p/14179048" target="_blank"&gt;Hands-on Session: Practical Demonstration of the Event Add-on for ERP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/enterprise-in-motion-event-driven-architecture-use-cases-for-innovation-and/ev-p/14179041" target="_blank"&gt;Enterprise in Motion: Event-Driven Architecture Use Cases for Innovation and Agility&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/unleash-next-generation-hybrid-integration-with-edge-integration-cell/ev-p/14204292" target="_blank"&gt;Unleash Next-Generation Hybrid Integration with Edge Integration Cell&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1233957857"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":blue_circle:"&gt;🔵&lt;/span&gt;Data &amp;amp; AI (Thursday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/developing-ai-driven-sap-hana-cloud-applications-with-sap-business/ev-p/14220020" target="_blank"&gt;Developing AI-driven SAP HANA Cloud applications with SAP Business Application Studio and Joule&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/accelerate-ai-amp-generative-ai-innovation-in-sap-s-4hana-with-islm/ev-p/14215859" target="_blank"&gt;Accelerate AI &amp;amp; Generative AI Innovation in SAP S/4HANA with ISLM&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/prompt-create-and-innovate-with-ai-vibe-coding/ev-p/14215867" target="_blank"&gt;Prompt, Create and Innovate with AI Vibe Coding&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/building-multi-tool-research-agents-amazon-bedrock-generative-ai-hub-and/ev-p/14215889" target="_blank"&gt;Building Multi-Tool Research Agents: Amazon Bedrock Generative AI Hub and Strands SDK&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/demystifying-the-mcp-a2a-and-acp-protocols-to-build-custom-multi-agent/ev-p/14212321" target="_blank"&gt;Demystifying the MCP, A2A, and ACP Protocols to Build Custom Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/elevate-productivity-with-ai-in-mobile-apps-using-sap-build/ev-p/14224137" target="_blank"&gt;Elevate Productivity with AI in Mobile Apps using SAP Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1037444352"&gt;🟠 CAP (Friday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/less-code-same-logic-reduce-your-custom-handlers-by-using-new-cap-features/ev-p/14214416" target="_blank"&gt;Less code, same logic – reduce your custom handlers by using new CAP features&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/status-transition-flows/ev-p/14214699" target="_self"&gt;Status-Transition Flows&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/taking-ui5-server-side-rendering-to-the-next-level-with-ai/ev-p/14212554" target="_blank"&gt;Taking UI5 Server Side Rendering to the next level with AI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-840930847"&gt;🟡 Community (Friday)&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest/take-the-next-step-in-your-career-and-master-an-sap-certification/ev-p/14198681" target="_self"&gt;Take the Next Step in Your Career and Master an SAP Certification&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-515334623"&gt;Fun Activities - The SAP Puzzles&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;In week 2, we are launching the new and challenging SAP Puzzles! Head over to the Tutorial Navigator to solve the puzzles and earn points.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here are links to the Puzzles:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-sap-crossword.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;🟡 Devtoberfest 2025 - SAP Cryptic Crossword&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-sap-crossword-bonus.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;🟡 Devtoberfest 2025 - Bonus Points for SAP Cryptic Crossword&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-fun-scramble-codejam.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;🟡 Devtoberfest 2025 - Scramble Challenge - Event-Based Processes CodeJam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-fun-scramble-languages.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;🟡 Devtoberfest 2025 - Scramble Challenge - Programming Languages&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-318821118"&gt;Validation of your session participation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;At Devtoberfest, almost every activity earns you points against the Grand Prize in our competition. This is the case for your participation in the Devtoberfest sessions for each week. Every week we release validation tutorials for the different topic tracks&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;ABAP, Tooling &amp;amp; Frontend, Integration, Data &amp;amp; AI, CAP, and the Community sessions&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The validation tutorials can be found in our &lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorial-navigator.html?search=Devtoberfest" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Tutorial Navigator&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF9900"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Be advised that assignment of Badges and Points take some time as we are batch processing these in a given interval.&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Head over to our tutorial page and complete the validation tutorials for earning your points!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-122307613"&gt;List of all point earning activities&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badge Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - ABAP, Week 2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-abap-week2-session-validation.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Week 2 - ABAP sessions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;1200&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Create Database Table and Generate UI Service&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-environment-rap100-generate-ui-service.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create Database Table and Generate UI Service&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;&lt;P&gt;500&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Enhance the Business Object Data Model and Enable OData Streams&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-environment-rap100-enhance-data-model.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhance the Business Object Data Model and Enable OData Streams&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Enhance the Business Object Behavior With Instance Action&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-environment-rap100-instance-action.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhance the Business Object Behavior With Instance Action&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Enhance the Business Object Behavior With Factory Action&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-environment-rap100-factory-action.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhance the Business Object Behavior With Factory Action&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Enhance the Business Object Behavior With Dynamic Feature Control&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-environment-rap100-dynamic-feature-control.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enhance the Business Object Behavior With Dynamic Feature Control&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Monday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Write an ABAP Unit Test for the RAP Business Object&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/abap-environment-rap100-unit-testing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Write an ABAP Unit Test for the RAP Business Object&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badge Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Tooling, Week 2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-tooling-week2-session-validation.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Tooling, Week 2&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;1200&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="45"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Add Smart Controls to the User Interface&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/sapui5-fiori-cf-fiorify.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Add Smart Controls to the User Interface&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Create a Business Process Project&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/codejam-04-spa-empty-process.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;4 - Create a Business Process Project&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Add Approval Flow to Process&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/codejam-05-spa-approval-flow.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;5 - Add Approval Flow to Process&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Trigger Process from Your App&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/codejam-06-connect-app-process.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;6 - Trigger Process from Your App&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Build and Deploy App to BTP&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/codejam-07-build-deploy-app.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;7 - Build and Deploy App to BTP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;P&gt;500&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badge Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Integration, Week 2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-integration-week2-integration-session-validatio.html " target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Week 2 - Integration sessions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;1200&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Scenario overview&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-transport-management-cpi-01-use-case.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Scenario Overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Set Up the SAP Integration Suite Source Subaccount&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-transport-management-cpi-02-set-up-source-account.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Set Up the SAP Integration Suite Source Subaccount&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Set Up the SAP Integration Suite Target Subaccount&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-transport-management-cpi-03-set-up-target-account.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Set Up the SAP Integration Suite Target Subaccount&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Create a Transport Destination and Configure the SAP Integration Suite Transport Landscape&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-transport-management-cpi-04-connect-source-and-target.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Create a Transport Destination and Configure the SAP Integration Suite Transport Landscape&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Establish an Export Connection from SAP Content Agent Service in the Source Subaccount to SAP Cloud Transport Management Service&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-transport-management-cpi-05-create-ctms-destination.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Establish an Export Connection from SAP Content Agent Service in the Source Subaccount to SAP Cloud Transport Management Service&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&amp;nbsp;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Enable the Transport in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-transport-management-cpi-06-enable-the-transport.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Enable the Transport in SAP Integration Suite&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Run a Test Transport&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-transport-management-cpi-07-test-transport.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Run a Test Transport&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Wednesday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Use the SAP Content Agent Service UI to Start the Transport&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/btp-transport-management-cpi-08-cas-ui.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Use the SAP Content Agent Service UI to Start the Transport&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badge Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Thursday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Data &amp;amp; AI, Week 2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-dataai-week2-session-validation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Week 2 - Data &amp;amp; AI sessions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%"&gt;1200&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Day&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Badge Title&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Content&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Points&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - CAP, Week 2&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-cap-week2-session-validation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Week 2 - CAP sessions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="57px"&gt;1200&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Introduction to Application Development Using CAP&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/introduction.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Introduction to Application Development Using CAP&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="140px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Set Up SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/set-up-bas.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Set Up SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="25%" height="85px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Build a CAP Application&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/build-cap-app.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Build a CAP Application&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;-&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-community-week2-session-validation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Week 2 - Certification&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="57px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Techtoberfest&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-sap-crossword.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - SAP Cryptic Crossword&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;2000&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Techtoberfest&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-sap-crossword-bonus.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Bonus Points for SAP Cryptic Crossword&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Techtoberfest&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-fun-scramble-languages.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Scramble Challenge - Programming Languages&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Friday&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Techtoberfest&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://developers.sap.com/tutorials/devtoberfest2025-fun-scramble-codejam.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Devtoberfest 2025 - Scramble Challenge - Event-Based Processes CodeJam&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;500&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;P&gt;Enjoy your Devtoberfest Event 2025!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/devtoberfest-blog-posts/devtoberfest-2025-what-is-happening-week-2/ba-p/14233248"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T09:44:02.195000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/bengaluru-blog-posts/responsible-vibe-coding-tutorial-building-a-meeting-room-cap-app/ba-p/14233717</id>
    <title>Responsible Vibe Coding Tutorial: Building a Meeting Room CAP App</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T20:16:16.448000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ranjeetkumar07</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/44540</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":direct_hit:"&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is Vibe Coding?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Vibe coding means collaborating with AI assistants to build apps step by step, entirely through &lt;STRONG&gt;natural language prompts&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Instead of writing everything yourself, you “vibe” with AI to generate, refine, and optimize code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This tutorial shows how to build a &lt;STRONG&gt;Meeting Room Booking app&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;CAP + AI Core&lt;/STRONG&gt;, entirely through &lt;STRONG&gt;prompts&lt;/STRONG&gt; — from schema to service, business logic, AI integration, and a simple UI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Quick prerequisites&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;VS Code + Cline extension (or your Claude integration)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Node.js (v18+) and &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;/cds-dk (CAP CLI)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP BTP account with AI Core (for production); we include a dev fallback.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Git repo and .clinerules set up (recommended)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 0 — Plan first (Cline Plan mode)&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Always start with a short Plan prompt to the AI (Cline Plan mode). Example plan template:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Plan:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Goal: Add a MeetingRoom CAP service with Book/Cancel/Search and a recommendRoom AI action.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Acceptance criteria: CDS created + seed data; BookService exposing actions; recommendRoom returns top-3 rooms with reasons; endpoints testable via curl.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Assumptions: No auth (dev), timezone = UTC, single-tenant.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Edge cases: overlapping bookings, zero-capacity rooms, invalid room IDs.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;- Tests: curl examples for create/search/recommend and a UI smoke test.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 1: Setting Up the Environment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Set up a new CAP project for a meeting room booking system.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Happened:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The AI guided installation, created a new CAP project, and initialized dependencies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generated Commands:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;npm install -g &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1862993"&gt;@SAP&lt;/a&gt;/cds-dk&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;cds init meeting-vibe&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;cd meeting-vibe&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;npm install&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Always start with a clean project skeleton before vibing features.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 2: Creating the Data Model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a data model with Rooms and Bookings. Rooms have capacity, location, amenities, and availability. Bookings track user, room, start/end times, and status. Include seed data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Happened:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The AI generated the core CDS schema and sample CSV seed files.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":open_file_folder:"&gt;📂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generated Schema:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;namespace vibe.meetings;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;entity Rooms : cuid, managed {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; name&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; : String(111) not null;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; location&amp;nbsp; : String(111);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; capacity&amp;nbsp; : Integer;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; amenities : String;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; available : Boolean default true;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;entity Bookings : cuid, managed {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; room&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; : Association to Rooms;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; userId&amp;nbsp; : String(36);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; start&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; : Timestamp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; end&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; : Timestamp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; purpose : String(255);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; status&amp;nbsp; : String(20) default 'CONFIRMED';&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; A single domain-level prompt is enough to generate a correct schema with relationships.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 3: Adding the Service Layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Expose the Rooms and Bookings as a BookingService with actions: bookRoom, cancelBooking, searchAvailableRooms, and recommendRoom.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Happened:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The AI produced a full CDS service definition.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":open_file_folder:"&gt;📂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generated Service Definition:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;service BookingService {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; entity Rooms as projection on vibe.meetings.Rooms;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; entity Bookings as projection on vibe.meetings.Bookings;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; action bookRoom(roomId: UUID, userId: String, start: Timestamp, end: Timestamp, purpose: String) returns Bookings;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; action cancelBooking(bookingId: UUID) returns String;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; function searchAvailableRooms(start: Timestamp, end: Timestamp, minCapacity: Integer) returns array of Rooms;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; action recommendRoom(start: Timestamp, end: Timestamp, attendees: Integer, prefs: String) returns array of {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; roomId: UUID;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; score: Decimal(5,2);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; reason: String;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; };&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; The AI can infer the exact CRUD operations and business functions you need if you describe them clearly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 4: Business Logic Implementation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Implement handlers for bookRoom, cancelBooking, and searchAvailableRooms in JavaScript with validation and error handling.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Happened:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The AI generated a srv/book-service.js with full logic for booking, cancelling, and searching.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":open_file_folder:"&gt;📂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example Implementation:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;this.on('bookRoom', async (req) =&amp;gt; {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; const { roomId, userId, start, end, purpose } = req.data;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; if (new Date(start) &amp;gt;= new Date(end)) req.error(400, 'Invalid time range');&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; const overlap = await SELECT.one.from(Bookings).where`room=${roomId} AND start &amp;lt; ${end} AND end &amp;gt; ${start}`;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; if (overlap) req.error(409, 'Room already booked');&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; const booking = await INSERT.into(Bookings).entries({ room_ID: roomId, userId, start, end, purpose });&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; return booking;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;});&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; When you ask for &lt;EM&gt;validation + error handling&lt;/EM&gt;, the AI adds production-quality safeguards.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 5: AI-Powered Recommendations&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Add AI integration with SAP AI Core to suggest the best rooms. Include a fallback heuristic when AI Core is not configured.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Happened:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The AI created srv/ai-recommender.js, with both AI Core and fallback logic.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":open_file_folder:"&gt;📂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example Snippet:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;async recommendRooms({ start, end, attendees, prefs, rooms }) {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; if (!this.config.clientId) {&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; return rooms.map(r =&amp;gt; ({&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; roomId: r.ID,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; score: r.capacity &amp;gt;= attendees ? 80 : 50,&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; reason: `Capacity ${r.capacity} vs ${attendees}`&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; })).slice(0,3);&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; }&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; // AI Core integration here...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;}&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Always request a &lt;STRONG&gt;fallback path&lt;/STRONG&gt; — AI assistants can build graceful degradation into your app.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 6: Building a Simple UI&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a simple SAP UI5 page with fields for start/end time, attendees, preferences, and a button to call recommendRoom. Show results in a table.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Happened:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The AI created view/Main.view.xml with a table bound to the recommendation endpoint.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":open_file_folder:"&gt;📂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Example View Snippet:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;VBox&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;DateTimePicker id="start"/&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;DateTimePicker id="end"/&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;Input id="attendees" placeholder="Attendees"/&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;Input id="prefs" placeholder="Preferences"/&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;Button text="Recommend" press=".onRecommend"/&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;Table id="tblRooms"&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/Table&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;lt;/VBox&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Even complex UI scaffolding can be generated quickly when you specify layout + bindings.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Part 7: Documentation &amp;amp; Testing&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":microphone:"&gt;🎤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The Prompt:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create a TESTING_GUIDE.md with curl commands to test all service actions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":light_bulb:"&gt;💡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Happened:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;The AI wrote a full Markdown testing guide with:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;curl for bookRoom, cancelBooking, searchAvailableRooms, recommendRoom&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;expected responses&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;error case examples&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Learning:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Ask for &lt;STRONG&gt;docs and tests explicitly&lt;/STRONG&gt; — they are as important as code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":direct_hit:"&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Best Practices for Responsible Vibe Coding&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Engineer &amp;gt; AI&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Review, understand, and own every line.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Test Before You Trust&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Validate edge cases with curl or UI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Plan First&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Use Cline Plan mode before big prompts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Fallbacks Matter&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Always ask AI to build dev-safe fallbacks.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Docs Are Not Optional&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Generate and maintain documentation with prompts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":building_construction:"&gt;🏗&lt;/span&gt;️&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt; What We Built Together&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Through prompts alone, we created:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bar_chart:"&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Data Layer&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Rooms &amp;amp; Bookings entities with seed data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":wrench:"&gt;🔧&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Business Logic&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Booking, cancellation, search with validations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":robot_face:"&gt;🤖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Room recommendations with AI Core + fallback&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":artist_palette:"&gt;🎨&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;UI&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Simple SAP UI5 page for booking and recommendations&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":books:"&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Docs&lt;/STRONG&gt;: A testing guide for backend and UI&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":party_popper:"&gt;🎉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Congratulations!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;You’ve just built a &lt;STRONG&gt;Meeting Room Booking CAP app&lt;/STRONG&gt; by vibing with AI — responsibly. The secret: always combine &lt;STRONG&gt;AI’s speed&lt;/STRONG&gt; with &lt;STRONG&gt;your engineering judgment&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":open_book:"&gt;📖&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Learn More&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;SAP CAP Documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/AI_CORE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP AI Core Documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=saoudrizwan.claude-dev" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Cline Extension&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/bengaluru-blog-posts/responsible-vibe-coding-tutorial-building-a-meeting-room-cap-app/ba-p/14233717"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T20:16:16.448000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/testing-group/test-color-contrast-sap-manages-tags-and-co-authors/ba-p/14234295</id>
    <title>Test color contrast sap manages tags and co-authors</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T14:31:09.541000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>PC825</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2254442</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Test color contrast sap manages tags and co-authors&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/testing-group/test-color-contrast-sap-manages-tags-and-co-authors/ba-p/14234295"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T14:31:09.541000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%B1%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B8-%D0%B6%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%82%D0%BD%D1%8F-2025-%D1%87%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BD%D0%B0-2/ba-p/14234370</id>
    <title>SAP Вебкасти Жовтня 2025: Частина 2</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T16:29:05.825000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>SofiaKornuta</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2055172</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;FONT size="5"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Друга половина жовтня продовжує серію безкоштовних вебкастів - finance, supply chain, integration та ще більше AI!&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":calendar:"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt; Найближчі заходи:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;16 жовтня, 16:00-17:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-signavio-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Mastering Business Transformation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;SAP Signavio, SAP LeanIX та WalkMe + GenAI для культури постійних інновацій&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;16 жовтня, 17:00-18:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="http://gateway.on24.com/wcc/eh/2983783/lp/5059154/sap-sales-cloud-version-2-sales-and-foundation-topics-q32025-release-overview?partnerref=sapUG" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Sales Cloud V2 - Q3/2025 Release&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Sales та Foundation: покращення продуктивності та user experience&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;21 жовтня, 12:00-13:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/reimagining-operations-enabling-every-line-of-business-emea/en_us/registration.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Consumer &amp;amp; Retail: Top 3 AI-Enabled ERP Ways&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Як boost resilience та grow через connected data та embedded AI&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt; Три сесії для різних регіонів (12:00, 07:00, 18:00 EEST)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;21 жовтня, 15:00-16:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/sap-user-groups/apps/251021_achieving_clean_core_business_process_principle_overview.ics" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Achieving Clean Core: Business Process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Maturity assessment та adherence KPIs для оптимізації вашої трансформації&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;21-23 жовтня (платний)&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://almsummit.go10.events.sap.com/registrations/new" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP ALM Summit EMEA 2025&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;SAP Cloud ALM horizons, customer success stories, hands-on labs&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;22 жовтня, 12:00-13:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/unlocking-financial-innovation-learn-from-other-industry-europe/en_us/registration.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Unlocking Financial Innovation&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Як CFO оптимізують капітал та знижують ризики з SAP Business Suite&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt; Три сесії для різних регіонів (12:00, 07:00, 18:00 EEST)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;22 жовтня, 18:00-19:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;eventid=5049141&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=155E33D499506054AF6FD5A553C2BD38&amp;amp;groupId=6298861&amp;amp;mode=preview&amp;amp;sourcepage=register" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud: Module 4&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;From Ingredients to Impact: як Döhler побудував data fabric для даних та AI&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;22 жовтня, 18:00-19:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/1nTUW1L8biA" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Enterprise Support Value Maps&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Перехід до SAP Community: targeted guidance та best practices&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;23 жовтня, 12:00-13:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/supply-chain-disruption-2-0-emea/en_us/registration.html?source=scmsapcom" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Supply Chain Disruption 2.0&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Що змінилося та чого ми навчилися: симуляція сценаріїв та prediction&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt; Три сесії для різних регіонів (12:00, 07:00, 18:00 EEST)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;23 жовтня, 17:00-18:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/2991608/084D5C4925C3BD9117CB0DD6C46000E7?partnerref=sapUG" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Emarsys Release Recap Series&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;/A&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Q3 2025 SAP Commerce Cloud: highlights та інновації&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;23 жовтня, 17:00-18:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="http://youtube.com/live/aIpBMu6tm8s?feature=share" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Navigating Compliance in the Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Cybersecurity Month Special: Cloud Compliance framework та automation&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;28 жовтня, 15:00-16:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/sap-user-groups/apps/251028_sap_end_of_maintenance_what_customers_need_to_know.ics" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP End of Maintenance&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Що потрібно знати: трансформація від SAP ERP до Cloud, RISE journey та commercial offers&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;28 жовтня, 16:00-17:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="http://youtube.com/live/LhUA9S0X1xU?feature=share" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Signavio Process Mining&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Data-driven трансформація бізнесу: кейси з Customer Support та Cloud Operations&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;28 жовтня, 16:00-17:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/_0Cc5dMvp7I" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Fiori UX Guide - Part 1&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Hitchhiker's Guide 2025: SAP Fiori design system, SAP Build Work Zone, SAPUI5 та Fiori elements&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;28 жовтня, 17:00-18:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://assets.dm.ux.sap.com/sap-user-groups/apps/251028_sap_integration_suite_monthly_update.ics" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Integration Suite - Monthly Update&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Жовтневі оновлення iPaaS: дизайн, розробка та управління integration flows і APIs&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;29 жовтня, 12:00-13:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/harnessing-sap-business-suite-for-sustainable-procurement-europe/en_us/registration.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sustainable Procurement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;SAP Ariba Sourcing: збір Scope 3 emissions data та sustainability foundation&lt;/EM&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":pushpin:"&gt;📌&lt;/span&gt; Три сесії для різних регіонів (12:00, 07:00, 18:00 EEST)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;30 жовтня, 16:00-17:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/sap-signavio-2025/en_us/home.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Boost Data-Driven Transformation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;Останні інновації в SAP Signavio для генерації actionable insights&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;30 жовтня, 18:00-19:00&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":small_blue_diamond:"&gt;🔹&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/live/FU_mIbcYLpc" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Fiori UX Guide - Part 2&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt; &lt;EM&gt;SAP Build для AI-based розробки + ABAP development tools та extensibility сценарії&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;*Всі години вказані за київським часом (EEST)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Реєструйтесь вже зараз, посилання в назві вебкасту&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/kyiv-blog-posts/sap-%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%B1%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B8-%D0%B6%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%82%D0%BD%D1%8F-2025-%D1%87%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BD%D0%B0-2/ba-p/14234370"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T16:29:05.825000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/new-developer-and-sap-technology-forums-groups/ba-p/14234225</id>
    <title>New Developer- and SAP-Technology Forums/Groups</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T17:48:55.293000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AnnePetteroe</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/36</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Dear "Application Development and Automation" group members/subscribers,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In case you haven't seen the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-developer-forums/ba-p/14230147" target="_self"&gt;general announcement post&lt;/A&gt; that went out earlier this week, this blog post is to inform you that we launched a pilot of new &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/developers/ct-p/developers" target="_self"&gt;developer- and SAP-technology related forums/groups&lt;/A&gt; this week.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;For you, this means that while the pilot runs, the "Application Development and Automation" group is set to read-only. &lt;BR /&gt;We would like to encourage you to go to our new developer forums/groups, if you would like to ask or answer questions, or publish blog posts, on development/technology-related topics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;There are a number of different reasons why we would like to test these new forums/groups:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Since our platform migration last year, we have received feedback that you didn't know where to go to find topics like ABAP, Integration or UI5. With these new developer forums/groups, we hope we have made it easier for you to find the technology topics you are most interested in.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;We noticed that the discussion board in this group was used to ask development related-questions. Generally, everyone has been very helpful answering questions asked here. However, our &lt;A style="font-family: inherit;" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/interest-groups/ct-p/interests" target="_self"&gt;interest groups&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; are for having &lt;STRONG&gt;conversations&lt;/STRONG&gt; with, and connecting to, like-minded people around shared interests. This is why these groups have discussion boards (= for conversations) and blog posts, instead of Q&amp;amp;As/forums. Therefore, when someone asks a question in the "Application Development and Automation" discussion board, it is not possible for the author to accept the right answer as a solution. This again means, that if someone with the same problem comes to the community to get help later on, they will not be able to see what the solution to the problem was.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Which brings us to no. 3 below:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Because answers to questions in discussion (conversation) boards won't have accepted solutions, we are also not able to give credit to, or celebrate, the members who took the time to help answer questions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;With the new developer forums, authors can accept any answer as a correct solution, which means we will be able to bring back our topic expert leaderboards, and give proper credit to our members who answer questions.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;A new denser forum feed, with no preview of content, making it easier to scroll down the feed to look for the questions you can help answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.02.59.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322667iAEAB52470419ED1E/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.02.59.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-09-29 at 11.02.59.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;New filter for "Questions with no answers".&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;This long-requested filter has now been added to all new Developers forums, so that you can find all questions with. no answers on a specific topic with one click:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-10-03 at 17.25.13.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322665iA43F9097E5910031/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-10-03 at 17.25.13.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-10-03 at 17.25.13.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;We can now highlight important product announcements, or other valuable content, you shouldn't miss, around your favourite development topics by using the "Featured Topics" section for the individual topics.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Better subscription management. &lt;BR /&gt;You will now be able to subscribe to either all developer/SAP-technology related content, or drill down to and only subscribe to the specific parts that interest you the most:
&lt;OL class="lia-list-style-type-lower-alpha"&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Developers&amp;nbsp;&lt;A style="font-family: inherit;" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/developers/ct-p/developers" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/developers/ct-p/developers&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;- here you can subscribe to the whole category, this subscription sends you notifications on the platform and email notifications according to your&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A style="font-family: inherit;" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/myprofilepage/tab/user-subscriptions" target="_self"&gt;account settings&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;The individual groups, with both the Forums and Blog posts - here taking ABAP Cloud as an example:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A style="font-family: inherit;" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-cloud/gh-p/abap-cloud" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-cloud/gh-p/abap-cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;- here you have the same subscribe option as above. If you subscribe to content here,&amp;nbsp;it will send you notifications on the platform and email notifications according to your&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A style="font-family: inherit;" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/myprofilepage/tab/user-subscriptions" target="_self"&gt;account settings&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;The individual group boards, ABAP Cloud Forum:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A style="font-family: inherit;" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-cloud-forum/bd-p/abap-cloudforum-board" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-cloud-forum/bd-p/abap-cloudforum-board&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;- here you have both the option to Subscribe and Subscribe to RSS Feed. The Subscribe option is the same as the two options above, and the RSS Feed is the one you are looking for.&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;You will find the same options for the blog posts boards as well:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A style="font-family: inherit;" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-cloud-blog-posts/bg-p/abap-cloudblog-board" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/abap-cloud-blog-posts/bg-p/abap-cloudblog-board&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;
&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;If you missed the main announcement post, you can find more information in this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/what-s-new/new-developer-forums/ba-p/14230147" target="_self"&gt;What's New blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We hope you hop over to the new Developer groups to try them out &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;If you have any feedback to us on the forums, you can provide it in the comments section on the What's New post linked above.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/application-development-and-automation-blog-posts/new-developer-and-sap-technology-forums-groups/ba-p/14234225"/>
    <published>2025-10-03T17:48:55.293000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
