<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ajmaradiaga/feeds/main/scmt/topics/SAP-HANA-Cloud-blog-posts.xml</id>
  <title>SAP Community - SAP HANA Cloud</title>
  <updated>2025-10-07T05:01:04.933406+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP HANA Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800002881" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>SAP HANA Cloud blog posts in SAP Community</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/avoiding-data-loss-when-loading-initial-data-with-csv-files-in-cap/ba-p/14215172</id>
    <title>Avoiding Data Loss When Loading Initial Data with CSV Files in CAP</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T22:17:28.888000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MioYasutake</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/789</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760058105"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When you start learning CAP, running &lt;EM&gt;cds add tiny-sample&lt;/EM&gt; generates all the necessary sample artifacts, including a CSV file inside the &lt;STRONG&gt;db/data&lt;/STRONG&gt; folder. Once deployed, the data from this CSV file is loaded as initial data into SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This mechanism seems convenient for loading initial data into SAP HANA Cloud for productive applications, doesn’t it?&lt;BR /&gt;However, there’s a catch. &lt;STRONG&gt;If you change the CSV data or modify the schema, the data in SAP HANA Cloud will be reinitialized with the CSV content&lt;/STRONG&gt; — including the data entered by users! Let’s take a look at what the &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/guides/databases#using-csv-files" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt; says:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;On SAP HANA, only use CSV files for configuration data that can't be changed by application users. → See &lt;EM&gt;CSV data gets overridden&lt;/EM&gt; in the SAP HANA guide for details.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is exactly the point I want to highlight in this article. At the same time, I’ve also explored some alternative approaches and validated them.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1563544600"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367031095"&gt;Case1: New Development&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;When developing a new CAP application, you have the following options:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option A&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Do not use CSV files to register initial data for tables that will be maintained by the application users.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option B&lt;/STRONG&gt;:&amp;nbsp;If both initial data and user-generated data need to coexist, define filter conditions in the &lt;STRONG&gt;.hdbtabledata&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;file.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Option A is the simplest, if feasible. However, in some cases — such as for master data — the ability to quickly load initial data from CSV files is attractive. Below, let’s look at Option B&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;in more detail.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1299600309"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1103086804"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Option B:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;Define filter conditions in the &lt;STRONG&gt;.hdbtabledata&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Add a column called &lt;EM&gt;dataCategory&lt;/EM&gt; to the table to distinguish between different types of data. (This is just an example; you can use any column as an identifier.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;entity Books {
  key ID    : Integer;
      title : String;
      stock : Integer;
      dataCategory: String enum {
        system = 'S';
        user = 'U';
      }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;Run the command &lt;EM&gt;cds build --production&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;to generate an &lt;STRONG&gt;.hdbtabledata&lt;/STRONG&gt; file in the &lt;STRONG&gt;gen/db/src/data&lt;/STRONG&gt; folder. Copy this file to the &lt;STRONG&gt;db/src/static/csv&lt;/STRONG&gt; folder, and then add an &lt;STRONG&gt;include_filter&lt;/STRONG&gt; as shown below.&amp;nbsp; This ensures that the HDI container takes ownership only of the records specified by the filter. (Note:&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;The values must be strings, even if the column’s data type is numeric.)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "format_version": 1,
  "imports": [
    {
      ...,
      "import_settings": {
        "import_columns": [
          "ID",
          "TITLE",
          "STOCK",
          "DATACATEGORY"
        ],
        "include_filter": [
          { "DATACATEGORY" : "S" }
        ]
      },
      "column_mappings": {
        "ID": "ID",
        "TITLE": "title",
        "STOCK": "stock",
        "DATACATEGORY": "dataCategory"
      }
    }
  ]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;3. Move the CSV file into the &lt;STRONG&gt;db/src/static/csv&lt;/STRONG&gt; folder as well. Don't forget to set the dataCategory to "S".&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ID,title,stock,dataCategory
1,Wuthering Heights,100,S
2,Jane Eyre,500,S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;After the initial deployment, users update some of the records and insert one new entry, resulting in the following state (as shown in the result of a GET request):&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "@odata.context": "$metadata#Books",
  "value": [
    { "ID": 1, "dataCategory": "S", "stock": 100, "title": "Updated" },
    { "ID": 2, "dataCategory": "S", "stock": 500, "title": "Jane Eyre" },
    { "ID": 3, "dataCategory": "U", "stock": 10, "title": "New Book" }
  ]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;When schema changes or updates to the initial data are applied, records with dataCategory = "S" are overwritten, while records with dataCategory = "U" remain untouched. For example, after adding a new column newField:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "@odata.context": "$metadata#Books",
  "value": [
    { "ID": 1, "dataCategory": "S", "newField": null, "stock": 100, "title": "Wuthering Heights" },
    { "ID": 2, "dataCategory": "S", "newField": null, "stock": 500, "title": "Jane Eyre" },
    { "ID": 3, "dataCategory": "U", "newField": null, "stock": 10, "title": "New Book" }
  ]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-777490580"&gt;Case 2: Accidentally Mixed Data&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In some cases, custom data and pre-delivered data (from a CSV file) may accidentally end up in the same table governed by an HDI Table Data artifact (.hdbtabledata) without filter conditions to separate them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP Note &lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2922271/E" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2922271&lt;/A&gt; outlines how to handle this situation. Below, I’ll walk you through the steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The procedure described here applies to single-tenant applications. For multitenant scenarios, please refer to the &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/get-started/troubleshooting#hana-csv" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;documentation&lt;/A&gt;, as well as&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1517445"&gt;@Sekar_Somasundaram&lt;/a&gt;'s&amp;nbsp;&lt;/EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;detailed &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/handling-csv-data-deployment-in-cap-hdi-without-data-loss/ba-p/14118322" target="_self"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-710059794"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-513546289"&gt;Steps at a Glance&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Delete the CSV file.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Make the &lt;STRONG&gt;.hdbtabledata&lt;/STRONG&gt; artifact subject to undeploy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Ensure that existing data is preserved during undeploy.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-317032784"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-120519279"&gt;Current State of the Data&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;The CSV file initially contains the following data:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ID,title,stock
1,Wuthering Heights,100
2,Jane Eyre,500&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;After the initial deployment, users update some of the records and insert one new entry, resulting in the following state:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "@odata.context": "$metadata#Books",
  "value": [
    { "ID": 1, "stock": 100, "title": "Updated" },
    { "ID": 2, "stock": 500, "title": "Jane Eyre" },
    { "ID": 3, "stock": 10, "title": "New Book" }
  ]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--151225595"&gt;Step-by-Step: Deleting the CSV File After Initial Deployment&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. Delete the CSV file.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;2. Add "&lt;EM&gt;src/gen/**/*.hdbtabledata&lt;/EM&gt;" to &lt;STRONG&gt;db/undeploy.json &lt;/STRONG&gt;as shown below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[
  "src/gen/**/*.hdbview",
  "src/gen/**/*.hdbindex",
  "src/gen/**/*.hdbconstraint",
  "src/gen/**/*_drafts.hdbtable",
  "src/gen/**/*.hdbcalculationview",
  "src/gen/**/*.hdbtabledata"
]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;Copy &lt;STRONG&gt;gen/db/package.json&lt;/STRONG&gt; to the &lt;STRONG&gt;db&lt;/STRONG&gt; folder, and add the following parameters to the start script.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt; --undeploy src/&amp;lt;mytable&amp;gt;.hdbtabledata --path-parameter src/&amp;lt;mytable&amp;gt;.hdbtabledata:skip_data_deletion=true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In my example, the &lt;STRONG&gt;package.json&lt;/STRONG&gt; looks as follows:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "name": "deploy",
  "dependencies": {
    "hdb": "^0",
    "@sap/hdi-deploy": "^5"
  },
  "engines": {
    "node": "&amp;gt;=18"
  },
  "scripts": {
    "start": "node node_modules/@sap/hdi-deploy/deploy.js --use-hdb --parameter com.sap.hana.di.table/try_fast_table_migration=true --undeploy src/gen/data/my.bookshop-Books.hdbtabledata --path-parameter src/gen/data/my.bookshop-Books.hdbtabledata:skip_data_deletion=true"
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Deploy the project. In the db-deployer log, you will see a message indicating that the existing data was not deleted.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[APP/TASK/deploy/0] OUT The "skip_data_deletion" make parameter is set; no data will be deleted from the target table "MY_BOOKSHOP_BOOKS"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As a result, the updated user data remains intact.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  "@odata.context": "$metadata#Books",
  "value": [
    { "ID": 1, "stock": 100, "title": "Updated" },
    { "ID": 2, "stock": 500, "title": "Jane Eyre" },
    { "ID": 3, "stock": 10, "title": "New Book" }
  ]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;Before the next deployment, delete the &lt;STRONG&gt;db/package.json&lt;/STRONG&gt; file to restore the original state. From this point on, even if the schema changes, the data will no longer be overridden.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--54336093"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--250849598"&gt;Other Ways to Register Data&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Besides using CSV files during deployment, you can load data through the following approaches as well:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Insert data via HTTP requests&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Insert data after deployment using HTTP requests.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Upload CSV files through the Database Explorer&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Upload CSV files directly from the Database Explorer.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;For local testing&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Place CSV files in the &lt;STRONG&gt;test/data&lt;/STRONG&gt; folder instead of &lt;STRONG&gt;db/data&lt;/STRONG&gt; (see: &lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/guides/databases#location-of-csv-files" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Location of CSV Files | capire&lt;/A&gt;).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;* For CAP Java, configuration in application.yaml is required for loading CSV files from the &lt;STRONG&gt;test/data&lt;/STRONG&gt; folder. Please find my Q&amp;amp;A below:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cap-java-csv-data-in-the-test-data-folder-not-loaded-duirng-local-testing/qaa-p/14227290#M4927381" target="_blank"&gt;https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/cap-java-csv-data-in-the-test-data-folder-not-loaded-duirng-local-testing/qaa-p/14227290#M4927381&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--447363103"&gt;Closing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;A clear strategy on how to provide initial data must be defined upfront.&amp;nbsp;CSV files are convenient but must be used with caution, particularly in productive environments. Applying best practices such as separating system and user data, leveraging .hdbtabledata filters, or considering alternative loading options will help maintain data integrity and protect user input across deployments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--643876608"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--840390113"&gt;References&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/guides/databases-hana#csv-data-gets-overridden" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;CSV Data Gets Overridden (capire)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href="https://cap.cloud.sap/docs/get-started/troubleshooting#hana-csv" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;I removed sample data (.csv file) from my project. Still, the data is deployed and overwrites existing data. (capire)&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/avoiding-data-loss-when-loading-initial-data-with-csv-files-in-cap/ba-p/14215172"/>
    <published>2025-09-15T22:17:28.888000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-3-in-the-series/ba-p/14206253</id>
    <title>Top Reasons to Modernize with SAP HANA Cloud – Blog #3 in the Series</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T15:42:02.275000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomashammer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Welcome back to my &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/forums/searchpage/tab/message?advanced=false&amp;amp;allow_punctuation=false&amp;amp;filter=location&amp;amp;location=blog-board:technology-blog-sap&amp;amp;q=WhyHANACloud" target="_self"&gt;blog series&lt;/A&gt; on the value of migrating to SAP HANA Cloud. In the first two blogs, I discussed how features such as multi-model engines, infrastructure independence, and a next-generation application foundation all can help you build your business case for SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In fact, we’ve already seen powerful confirmation of the value of this database. For example, global consulting services provider &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2024/10/0a18d33e-d97e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;CONTAX Inc.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; migrated to SAP HANA Cloud to gain the elasticity and scalability it needed to handle huge demands on its database resources. This modernization helped CONTAX expand its database capacity while reducing its overall memory footprint and cost by 25%.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That’s impressive. So how can you best estimate the benefits of migrating to SAP HANA Cloud for your enterprise?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Many organizations want to migrate their database to the cloud because they want to build and deploy intelligent applications at scale. But that requires an advanced data landscape architecture—a database-as-a-service (DBaaS) for modernizing your applications. Let’s talk about two capabilities of SAP HANA Cloud that help you meet that need and deliver exceptional value: intelligent data tiering and multi-dimensional elastic scalability.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Intelligent data tiering&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The exploding growth of business data is both a cost issue and a management challenge for your business. How can you store the data users need and make it easily accessible without busting the budget?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Traditional database technology requires that you choose between database performance and costs. Should you pay more to over-provision storage space so data can be easily persisted in case of growing demands? Or should you archive data to save money but make data harder to access?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With SAP HANA Cloud, you can strike the right balance for your business.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog3-1.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315911i19C8581FD761EACC/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog3-1.jpg" alt="Blog3-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;Intelligent, multi-temperature data management features help you store data in tiers according to type, operational usefulness, access frequency, and scalability requirements. The database locates frequently accessed, business-critical “hot” data in high-performance, in-memory storage, which facilitates real-time processing. “Warm” data requiring moderate access uses disk storage. Infrequently accessed “cold” data can be stored in a lower-cost data lake optimized for long-term retention and compliance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By combining tiered storage with advanced virtualization capabilities, SAP HANA Cloud reduces cost and complexity while enabling optimum overall performance. Applications and users can query data at any tier without needing to know where the data is stored. Automatic optimization based on data location and access patterns eliminates complex, costly ETL processes—while supporting both operational efficiency and analytical depth. Data tiering also simplifies application development by offering one interface to multiple data tiers. Developers can use that interface to query data for applications without needing to know where the data is stored.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A recent &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IDC study&lt;/A&gt; [1] assessed database performance impacts for organizations that deployed SAP HANA Cloud. Query speed and response time improved by 31% and 29%, respectively. Backups executed 27% faster. Both data load time and recovery time were 24% faster.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;“Data is more accessible with SAP HANA Cloud,” said one study participant. “It is also available in real time and loads far quicker than our previous environment. Our data performance has enhanced.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Multi-dimensional elastic scalability&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another way SAP HANA Cloud helps you balance performance and cost is by enabling elastic scalability for data processing and storage across multiple dimensions. In today’s dynamic database environments, short-term processing peaks caused by issues such as period-end reporting surges, seasonal transactions, or heavy analytics workloads can create havoc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Elastic scalability lets you adjust compute and storage resources based on workload demands, in real time. The database ramps up resources during periods of high demand and then reduces them during low-usage times to conserve costs. Flexible resources include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Performance classes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with flexible CPUs and memory ratios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Elastic compute nodes&lt;/STRONG&gt;, on-demand resources provisioned in minutes for data-intensive OLAP workloads&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Dynamic scalability, &lt;/STRONG&gt;with individual storage tiers that allow the database to grow or shrink as needed&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud also includes elasticity features such as class-based dynamic workload routing, which automatically sends queries to the most appropriate compute resources. An ECN advisor analyzes historical workload patterns and creates optimal provisioning schedules. To prevent scaling events from disrupting application performance, SAP HANA Cloud offers built-in monitoring and workload routing capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These elastic scalability features help you respond rapidly to changing business needs, enabling optimal performance without over provisioning resources. These features make data more accessible to users while reducing infrastructure complexity. Together, they can help you drive operational agility and cost-effective resource management.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With these benefits in mind, IDC evaluated the infrastructure costs of surveyed companies that deployed SAP HANA Cloud. Using its business value methodology, IDC concluded that the infrastructure costs of an SAP HANA Cloud environment were 20% less than a comparable database environment over a three-year period.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;According to one study participant operating in the retail industry, “SAP HANA Cloud has given my organization the ability to scale and reduce redundancy, which are significant benefits.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore other SAP HANA Cloud features to build your business case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-4-in-the-series/ba-p/14206255" target="_self"&gt;next blog&lt;/A&gt; to learn how native AI capabilities, built-in data integration, and automation that streamlines database administrator duties can help you build your business case for SAP HANA Cloud while preparing for the future of modern, intelligent applications and processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional resources:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What’s the potential value of SAP HANA Cloud for your organization? Complete a short &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more about &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how moving to SAP HANA Cloud helps you create a &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana/cloud-migration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;foundation for modernization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore this guide on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-compelling-business-case-to-move-your-database-to-the-cloud/ba-p/14123254" target="_blank"&gt;building a compelling business case to move your database to the cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;[1]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;“&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Business Value of SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,” IDC, sponsored by SAP, April 2025.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-3-in-the-series/ba-p/14206253"/>
    <published>2025-09-17T15:42:02.275000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/gl-planning-in-s4-hana-fiori-launchpad/ba-p/14213228</id>
    <title>GL Planning in S4 Hana Fiori Launchpad:</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T11:42:23.680000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shah_Meer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/2223291</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;GL Planning in S4 Hana Fiori Launchpad:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In SAP S/4HANA, GL planning is performed through the Fiori Launchpad, offering a user-friendly and intuitive interface for financial planning activities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Steps:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Configuration that is required for GL planning in SAP S/4HANA. Plan Category needed to be created in the system through SPRO Customizing. The configuration path is shown in the attached screenshot.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_0-1757502860516.png" style="width: 588px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312291i849CBEF111B28C46/image-dimensions/588x103/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="588" height="103" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_0-1757502860516.png" alt="Shah_Meer_0-1757502860516.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Create the Plan Category exactly as shown in the configuration screenshot below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_1-1757502874793.png" style="width: 499px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312292iFD3DE44A6D892269/image-dimensions/499x273/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="499" height="273" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_1-1757502874793.png" alt="Shah_Meer_1-1757502874793.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, access the Fiori Launchpad by entering transaction code “&lt;STRONG&gt;/n/ui2/flp”&lt;/STRONG&gt; and proceed to log in.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Then, navigate to the &lt;STRONG&gt;'Import Financial Plan Data'&lt;/STRONG&gt; tile within the Fiori Launchpad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_2-1757502901674.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312294i07F2C62A009731BD/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_2-1757502901674.png" alt="Shah_Meer_2-1757502901674.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After selecting the tile, click on 'Download Templates' as shown in the screenshot, and download the template for 'P&amp;amp;L Statement Planning'.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_3-1757502911912.png" style="width: 683px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312295i561D1DAE6E31265F/image-dimensions/683x311/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="683" height="311" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_3-1757502911912.png" alt="Shah_Meer_3-1757502911912.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Below is the attached GL planning template that needs to be filled out. If required, you can also add additional fields such as Profit Center and Cost Center by identifying the relevant field names from the following SAP help page: &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/651d8af3ea974ad1a4d74449122c620e/41f88d19c3b64b1db1c2aa80165d9494.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Help – Financial Plan Data Fields&lt;/A&gt;."&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_4-1757502928780.png" style="width: 569px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312297i2641968905F0D4EC/image-dimensions/569x157/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="569" height="157" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_4-1757502928780.png" alt="Shah_Meer_4-1757502928780.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once the template is filled with the required planning data, upload it using the same 'Import Financial Plan Data' tile in the Fiori Launchpad.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_6-1757503007141.png" style="width: 612px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312300i1ECE037F3680F93F/image-dimensions/612x306/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="612" height="306" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_6-1757503007141.png" alt="Shah_Meer_6-1757503007141.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After uploading the file, navigate to the 'Display Financial Plan Data' tile to review the uploaded planning information.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_8-1757503052508.png" style="width: 380px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312302iF3971A3A7BAE54C5/image-dimensions/380x361/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="380" height="361" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_8-1757503052508.png" alt="Shah_Meer_8-1757503052508.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;After selecting the tile, enter the planning parameters as shown in the attached screenshot. Additionally, activate the navigation panel from the top left corner to include more parameter-based views, such as Profit Center, if it was included in your planning data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_9-1757503070784.png" style="width: 663px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312303i50C697CF5EBD5DA5/image-dimensions/663x338/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="663" height="338" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_9-1757503070784.png" alt="Shah_Meer_9-1757503070784.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_10-1757503083516.png" style="width: 750px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312304i377C0F053D5D1B5D/image-dimensions/750x243/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="750" height="243" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_10-1757503083516.png" alt="Shah_Meer_10-1757503083516.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To analyze Plan vs Actual data, you need to activate the 'P&amp;amp;L - Actual/Plan' tile in Fiori. This tile allows you to compare planned and actual figures at the Financial Statement Version (FSV) level, including its individual nodes, as shown in the screenshot below.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_11-1757503118483.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312306i477273670B910176/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_11-1757503118483.png" alt="Shah_Meer_11-1757503118483.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Shah_Meer_12-1757503129023.png" style="width: 911px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/312307iD69FE8DD1E9DE2D1/image-dimensions/911x203/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="911" height="203" role="button" title="Shah_Meer_12-1757503129023.png" alt="Shah_Meer_12-1757503129023.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary:&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;GL Planning in SAP S/4HANA, enabled through the Fiori Launchpad, provides a simple yet powerful approach for financial planners. From defining a plan category to importing data and analyzing plan vs. actual figures, the process is streamlined and user-friendly. With these capabilities, organizations can achieve better control and visibility over financial planning processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/gl-planning-in-s4-hana-fiori-launchpad/ba-p/14213228"/>
    <published>2025-09-18T11:42:23.680000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/email-notification-to-approvers-after-purchase-order-creation-in-sap-s/ba-p/14187663</id>
    <title>Email Notification to Approvers After Purchase Order Creation in SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud.</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T11:58:33.386000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Vinith</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/844872</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;In SAP S/4HANA Public Cloud, the Flexible Workflow framework is widely used to manage approval processes for business documents such as purchase requisitions, purchase orders, and supplier invoices. By default, approvers receive workflow notifications directly in their Fiori Launchpad inbox.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;While this works seamlessly within the system, many organizations also expect approvers to receive an email notification in addition to the in-app notification. This ensures that:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Approvers are alerted even when they are not logged in to SAP.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Important purchasing decisions are not delayed.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;The workflow process remains transparent and efficient.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To meet this requirement, SAP provides standard tools such as Workflow Scenario Management, Email Templates, and Email Transmission Monitoring. These enable businesses to configure and send customized email notifications for workflow tasks like purchase order approvals.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the following blog, I will walk through a simple scenario where an approver receives an email notification after the creation of a purchase order.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;U&gt;Applications Involved:&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Manage Workflow Scenarios&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Maintain Email Templates&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Monitor Email Transmission&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step-by-Step Process&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 1: Identify the Workflow Task&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Why&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; This app helps us find the workflow task ID linked to the purchase order approval process. Without identifying the correct task, we cannot map the notification to the right workflow step.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What you’ll do&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Open the workflow scenario for Purchase Orders and note the task ID to be used.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;how&lt;EM&gt; you’ll do&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open the Manage Workflow Scenarios app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the relevant workflow (in this case, Purchase Order Flexible Workflow).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Identify the Task ID that is triggered when a PO is sent for approval.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-center" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vinith_0-1755864338035.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303909i910DCB9258607168/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Vinith_0-1755864338035.png" alt="Vinith_0-1755864338035.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 2: Maintain the Email Template&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Why&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; SAP delivers standard templates, but they are generic. We often need to customize the subject and body of the email with business-specific content (e.g., PO number, company code, approver details).&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What you’ll do&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Copy the pre-delivered template SWF_CRT_NOTIFY_RECIPIENTS, rename it as per your scenario, and adjust the subject/body with standard fields.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;how&lt;EM&gt; you’ll do&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Go to the Maintain Email Templates app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Search for the pre-delivered template:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;nbsp;SWF_CRT_NOTIFY_RECIPIENTS&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vinith_3-1755864823826.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303914i9FAC5437AD6FC9FF/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Vinith_3-1755864823826.png" alt="Vinith_3-1755864823826.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Copy this template and create your own version.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Suggested naming convention: &amp;lt;ScenarioID&amp;gt;_CRT_ALL&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Vinith_2-1755864710043.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303912iF0D72FEA4F178721/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Vinith_2-1755864710043.png" alt="Vinith_2-1755864710043.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Modify the Subject and Body as per business requirements, using the available standard data fields.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 3: Trigger the Notification&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Why&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; To test the configuration, you need to trigger a purchase order approval workflow. This ensures the system sends both the in-app notification and the newly configured email notification.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What you’ll do&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Create a purchase order with a flexible workflow enabled and check whether the approver receives the email.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;how&lt;EM&gt; you’ll do&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a Purchase Order and ensure Workflow process is enabled and approver mail-id available.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;At every approval level, the approver will now receive:&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;A system notification in SAP Fiori, and&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;An email notification delivered to their inbox.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vinith_4-1755865148421.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303917i31F174F4F378C61B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Vinith_4-1755865148421.png" alt="Vinith_4-1755865148421.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Step 4: Monitor Email Transmission&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;Why&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Sometimes emails fail due to configuration issues or missing recipient details. This app helps track and troubleshoot all outbound email notifications triggered from SAP.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;EM&gt;What you’ll do&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Open the app to review email logs and confirm if the notification was successfully delivered to the approver.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;how&lt;EM&gt; you’ll do&lt;/EM&gt;:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use the Monitor Email Transmission app.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Here, you can check whether the email was successfully triggered and delivered.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;This app provides details of all outbound email activities, helping administrators track and troubleshoot.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Vinith_5-1755865246950.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/303920iDF436AFC250B4956/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Vinith_5-1755865246950.png" alt="Vinith_5-1755865246950.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1867040677"&gt;Summary&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;With just a few simple steps — identifying the workflow task, maintaining an email template, and monitoring the transmission — organizations can ensure that approvers are notified both inside SAP and via email. This enhancement improves workflow efficiency, reduces approval delays, and provides a better user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Useful SAP notes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A title="3395242" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/0003395242" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3395242 - Approval/Rejection notifications are not sent for Purchase Contract workflows&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Regards,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Vinith K&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-resource-planning-blog-posts-by-members/email-notification-to-approvers-after-purchase-order-creation-in-sap-s/ba-p/14187663"/>
    <published>2025-09-18T11:58:33.386000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/build-a-data-driven-enterprise-with-sap-s-data-amp-analytics-advisory/ba-p/14224035</id>
    <title>Build a Data-Driven Enterprise with SAP’s Data &amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T12:01:30.126000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>gauravdey</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183532</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="gauravdey_0-1758534693911.png" style="width: 711px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317823i94654445CE65DF7A/image-dimensions/711x222?v=v2" width="711" height="222" role="button" title="gauravdey_0-1758534693911.png" alt="gauravdey_0-1758534693911.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What is SAP BTP Guidance Framework: The Guidance Framework provides clear direction and a structured approach to adopting SAP technologies. With this guidance, you can develop intelligent applications using advanced analytics, equipping your organization with a robust foundation to support agile innovation. For more details read this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-guidance-framework-a-compass-for-architects-developers-and/ba-p/14138635" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In this blog post, we will look into how to build a Data-Driven Enterprise with SAP’s Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology under SAP BTP Guidance Framework. You can find this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/guidance-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; pillar under SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It’s imperative that in today’s economy, data is more than just numbers—it’s the foundation of innovation, strategy, and growth backed by AI. Yet many organizations still struggle to unlock the full potential of their data and give it purpose. SAP’s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; under SAP BTP Guidance Framework offers a structured, four-phase approach that helps enterprises transform raw data into actionable insights while building a strong data-driven culture.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="gauravdey_1-1758534693913.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317822i0ED9A8C45F754BDC/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="gauravdey_1-1758534693913.png" alt="gauravdey_1-1758534693913.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Four Phases of SAP’s Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Scoping &amp;amp; Baseline Analysis: In this phase you can&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;set the foundation by:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Defining the scope of investigation across business processes, organizational units, and data domains.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Assessing current data architecture and capabilities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Identifying gaps, pain points, and opportunities for improvement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Benefit of this phase is that your business will have a&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;clear baseline architecture, capability assessment, and prioritized opportunities.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. Business Outcomes &amp;amp; Solution Requirements: the focus in this phase shifts to aligning data with measurable business goals such as:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define specific, data-driven business outcomes.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Analyze use cases that trace how raw data transforms into business value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Identify required data products and map end-to-end integration flows.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This phase allows to clearly define business outcome definitions and solution context diagrams.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;3.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Capability Map &amp;amp; Solution Architecture: this phase transforms requirements into a target architecture by:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Developing a capability map using SAP BTP Maturity Assessment&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Explore architecture options through traditional capability mapping or solution diagrams from the SAP Discovery Center.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Validate the preferred architecture with proof-of-concepts.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With this phase the target solution architecture is validated through capability mapping and pilots.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;4.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data Governance &amp;amp; Roadmaps: this final phase ensures long-term sustainability:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Conduct a maturity assessment for data governance and organizational roles.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Define roles such as Chief Data Officer, Data Steward, and Governance Manager.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Build a roadmap with clear clusters (e.g., implementation, operations, security).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The key benefit of this phase is to define Data governance framework, organizational structure, and a roadmap for execution.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What makes SAP’s Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology stand out is that it’s not just about technology—it’s about data, people and processes. By integrating governance, roles, and organizational change management, it ensures that data initiatives aren’t just implemented but also adopted across the enterprise. For organizations aiming to thrive in a data-driven economy, SAP’s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; provides more than a roadmap—it delivers a proven framework for turning data into business value and give it purpose. By combining architecture best practices with governance and cultural adoption, it helps enterprises evolve from simply managing data to truly innovating with it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To read more about SAP’s &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics Advisory Methodology &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;check out &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://discovery-center.cloud.sap/guidance-framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;“Organizations that adopt this framework position themselves to lead in the AI-driven economy”&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Previous blogs in the series:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-ai-best-practices-your-ultimate-guide-for-building-ai-solutions/ba-p/14171864" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP AI Best Practices: Your Ultimate Guide for Building AI Solutions&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-discovery-center-expands-and-welcomes-the-sap-btp-guidance-framework/ba-p/14162329" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Discovery Center Expands and Welcomes the SAP BTP Guidance Framework&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-developer-s-guide-essential-best-practices-from-setup-to-scale/ba-p/14195253" target="_blank"&gt;SAP BTP Developer’s Guide: Essential Best Practices from Setup to Scale&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-sap-application-extension-methodology-version-2-4/ba-p/14174737" target="_blank"&gt;Introducing SAP Application Extension Methodology version 2.4&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Stay tuned for the next blog post in our ‘Exploring the SAP BTP Guidance Framework’ series!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Technology+Platform/pd-p/73555000100700000172" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1215-1"&gt;SAP Business Technology Platform&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Data+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100700003531" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1249-1"&gt;SAP Business Data Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/RISE+with+SAP/pd-p/1e76886f-86ac-4839-9833-8bf95f5eb775" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="29-1"&gt;RISE with SAP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+Business+Suite/pd-p/673127e5-8a50-46c5-8528-7ea141417160" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1250-1"&gt;SAP Business Suite&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/Data+Management/pd-p/b74f6ff6-7d1b-45cb-87ec-03c305c7ffc6" class="lia-product-mention" data-product="1283-1"&gt;Data Management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/build-a-data-driven-enterprise-with-sap-s-data-amp-analytics-advisory/ba-p/14224035"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T12:01:30.126000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-unmanaged-sap-hana-database-backup/ba-p/14223921</id>
    <title>Everyday issues: Unmanaged SAP HANA database backup.</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T12:42:59.562000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laszlo_Thoma</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/170406</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;ul =""&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:0px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-unmanaged-sap-hana-database-backup/ba-p/14223921#toc-hId-1631846857"&gt;Why was this blog post created?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:0px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-unmanaged-sap-hana-database-backup/ba-p/14223921#toc-hId-1435333352"&gt;How to check/detect if SAP HANA is having an unmanaged database backup issue?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:0px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-unmanaged-sap-hana-database-backup/ba-p/14223921#toc-hId-1238819847"&gt;What is the conclusion?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:0px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-unmanaged-sap-hana-database-backup/ba-p/14223921#toc-hId-1042306342"&gt;Everyday issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:0px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-unmanaged-sap-hana-database-backup/ba-p/14223921#toc-hId-845792837"&gt;Other article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:0px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-unmanaged-sap-hana-database-backup/ba-p/14223921#toc-hId-649279332"&gt;Useful bookmark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:0px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-unmanaged-sap-hana-database-backup/ba-p/14223921#toc-hId-452765827"&gt;Do you have further questions?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type:disc; margin-left:0px; margin-bottom:1px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-unmanaged-sap-hana-database-backup/ba-p/14223921#toc-hId-256252322"&gt;Contribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="banner_SAP_HANA.png" style="width: 800px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317799i03E5CD5550B88C05/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="banner_SAP_HANA.png" alt="banner_SAP_HANA.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class="lia-align-right" style="text-align : right;"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;last updated: 2025-09-30&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631846857"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Why was this blog post created?&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Unmanaged SAP HANA&amp;nbsp;database backup can affect &lt;FONT color="#FF0000"&gt;overall system performance&lt;/FONT&gt; (such as, general performance, memory area, CPU usage, and so on). Properly configuring SAP HANA database backup is an essential task. Missing this task can cause various issues (which are sometimes very difficult to identify precisely).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="backup.png" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323227i8FADC4B253730241/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="backup.png" alt="backup.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1435333352"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to check/detect if SAP HANA is having an unmanaged database backup issue?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;1. &lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3284834" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3284834&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;- SQL Statement Collection: "HANA_Configuration_Minichecks" report for SAP HANA&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;(SAP Community Article: &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/keeping-your-hana-system-healthy-with-mini-checks/ba-p/13140985" target="_blank"&gt;Keeping your HANA system healthy with Mini Checks&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The most general report will contain further information about the issue. The minicheck report contains a dedicated section belongs to backup area. With this report we can easily identify if there is issue with the backup. In the below example the&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Size of backup catalog (MB)&lt;/STRONG&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;STRONG&gt;Age of oldest backup in catalog (days)&lt;/STRONG&gt; values shows there are issue.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-sql"&gt;&lt;code&gt;195;**** ;BACKUP                                         ;        ;                                              ;              ; ;        
196;     ;                                               ;        ;                                              ;              ; ;        
197;  910;Age of last data backup (days)                 ;        ;0.37                                          ;&amp;lt;= 1.20       ; ; 1642148
198;  911;Age of last data backup error (days)           ;        ;2394.37                                       ;&amp;gt;= 1.20       ; ; 1642148
199;  915;Min. data backup throughput (GB/h, last week)  ;        ;3583.67                                       ;&amp;gt;= 200.00     ; ; 1999930
200;  916;Avg. data backup throughput (GB/h, last week)  ;        ;3810.26                                       ;&amp;gt;= 300.00     ; ; 1999930
201;  920;Age of last log backup (hours)                 ;        ;0.12                                          ;&amp;lt;= 1.00       ; ; 1642148
202;  921;Age of last log backup error (days)            ;        ;1657.16                                       ;&amp;gt;= 1.00       ; ; 1642148
203;  922;Maximum log backup duration (s, last day)      ;        ;140                                           ;&amp;lt;= 300        ; ; 2063454
204;  923;Log backup errors (last month)                 ;        ;0                                             ;&amp;lt;= 10         ; ; 1642148
205;  930;Automatic log backup                           ;        ;yes                                           ;yes           ; ; 1645183
206;  935;Database log mode                              ;        ;normal                                        ;normal        ; ; 1645183
207;  940;Size of backup catalog (MB)                    ;        ;463.63                                        ;&amp;lt;= 50.00      ;X; 2505218
208;  942;Catalog size share (last day, %)               ;        ;12.43                                         ;&amp;lt;= 3.00       ;X; 2505218
209;  945;Age of oldest backup in catalog (days)         ;        ;2532                                          ;&amp;lt;= 100        ;X; 2505218
210;  950;Log segments not free for reuse                ;        ;3                                             ;&amp;lt;= 100        ; ;        
211;  952;Log segments free for reuse                    ;        ;22                                            ;&amp;lt;= 250        ; ;        
212;  955;Max. number of log backups / service (last day);        ;650                                           ;&amp;lt;= 300        ;X;  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3411878" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3411878&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Backup related Housekeeping - LEAD SAP Note&lt;/SPAN&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3339034" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3339034&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;- SAP HANA multiple issue (Alert ID: 2, 36, 65) caused by large Log Backups due to large Backup Catalog size&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&amp;nbsp;SAP Knowledge Base Articles contains all relevant information to investigate further and the resolution steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1238819847"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What is the conclusion?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The best option to setup the proper backup right after the installation of SAP HANA. Retention period needs to choose correctly and the backup activity needs to review periodically. If initial actions missed, right after the backup related issue identified it needs to be solved, so the related issues will be eliminated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1042306342"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Everyday issues&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":writing_hand:"&gt;✍️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-there-is-no-miracle-or-magic-sap-hana-database-needs-memory/ba-p/14198560" target="_blank"&gt;Everyday issues: There is no miracle or magic. SAP HANA database needs memory.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":writing_hand:"&gt;✍️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-sap-hana-database-parameters-recommended-by-sap-not/ba-p/14230055" target="_blank"&gt;Everyday issues: SAP HANA database parameters (recommended by SAP) not configured properly.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-845792837"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Other article&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":writing_hand:"&gt;✍️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/03/29/where-can-i-find-knowledge-and-information-belongs-to-sap-hana/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Where can I find knowledge and information belongs to SAP HANA?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":writing_hand:"&gt;✍️&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://blogs.sap.com/2023/06/02/where-can-i-find-information-about-the-available-tools-for-sap-hana-all-types-of-use/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Where can I find information about the available tools for SAP HANA (all types of use)?&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-649279332"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Useful bookmark&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bookmark:"&gt;🔖&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://launchpad.support.sap.com/#/notes/2872774" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2872774&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Bookmark of Frequently Asked Questions for SAP HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bookmark:"&gt;🔖&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3311408" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;3311408&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– Bookmark of SQL Statement Collection reports for SAP HANA&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":bookmark:"&gt;🔖&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2658020" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;2658020&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;– List of SAP HANA SQL Error Codes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-452765827"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Do you have further questions?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Please do not hesitate to contact me if you have question or observation regarding the article.&lt;BR /&gt;Q&amp;amp;A link for SAP HANA: &lt;A href="https://answers.sap.com/tags/73554900100700000996" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://answers.sap.com/tags/73554900100700000996&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-256252322"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Contribution&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you find any missing information belongs to the topic, please let me know. I am happy to add the new content. My intention is to maintain the content continuously to keep the info up-to-date.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT color="#999999"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Release Information&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE width="100%" cellspacing="1"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="58px"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#999999"&gt;Release Date&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="58px"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#999999"&gt;Description&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#999999"&gt;2025.09.22&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD height="30px"&gt;&lt;FONT color="#999999"&gt;First/initial Release of the SAP Blog Post documentation (Technical Article).&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;FONT color="#999999"&gt;2025.09.30&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD&gt;&lt;FONT color="#999999"&gt;Table of Content&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/everyday-issues-unmanaged-sap-hana-database-backup/ba-p/14223921"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T12:42:59.562000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-integraci%C3%B3n-inteligente-control-financiero-y-sostenibilidad/ba-p/14224279</id>
    <title>🚀 SAP BTP: integración inteligente, control financiero y sostenibilidad</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T15:45:22.446000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>FedericoTokman</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/150724</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H3 id="ember4681" id="toc-hId-1890035522"&gt;Expansión de SAP BTP hacia los marketplaces de hyperscalers (AWS, Azure, Google Cloud)&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP ha anunciado que algunos servicios de SAP BTP estarán disponibles en los &lt;EM&gt;hyperscaler marketplaces&lt;/EM&gt; en la segunda mitad de 2025. Esto permite que clientes compren y consuman servicios de BTP directamente desde AWS Marketplace, Azure Marketplace, etc., lo que puede simplificar licenciamiento y despliegue. Mejora la flexibilidad en dónde ejecutar servicios, y posiblemente reduzca latencias si se usan infraestructuras cercanas. También implica que los equipos de finanzas deberán adaptarse a nuevos modelos de facturación. Los clientes podrán elegir entre usar BTP desde SAP directamente o vía Marketplace.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas&lt;/STRONG&gt;: más agilidad al aprovisionar servicios, posiblemente mejores acuerdos comerciales locales, menor fricción operativa, alineación con estrategias multicloud/híbridas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://aws.amazon.com/marketplace/pp/prodview-k5lexy6il2mfq" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mas&amp;nbsp;información &lt;/A&gt;/ &lt;A class="" href="https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/es-es/marketplace/apps/sapus.btp_us?tab=overview" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/es-es/marketplace/apps/sapus.btp_us?tab=overview&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Nuevas capacidades en SAP HANA Cloud: migración selectiva de objetos, gobernanza de costos y monitoreo granular&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Se han anunciado mejoras de HANA Cloud que permiten migrar objetos específicos de base de datos de un HANA on-premise o clásico hacia HANA Cloud de forma selectiva (no toda la base). También habrá mayor visibilidad del consumo, gobernanza financiera y monitoreo más granular del uso de recursos. Esto facilita planes de modernización (‘&lt;EM&gt;clean core&lt;/EM&gt;’) al permitir mover por piezas. Mejora del control de costos operacionales, menor riesgo de sobredimensionamiento. Ideal para empresas que quieren innovar poco a poco.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas&lt;/STRONG&gt;: menos riesgo al migrar; se puede hacer roll-out gradual; permite optimizar qué partes de datos o sistemas conviene mover al cloud; optimización del gasto.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/spain/products/data-cloud/hana/cloud-migration.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mas información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Customer Identity and Access Management (CIAM) disponible en SAP BTP bajo el Enterprise Agreement&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;CIAM (Customer Identity &amp;amp; Access Management) ahora está incluido como parte de SAP BTP bajo el contrato Enterprise Agreement. Esto aporta una solución multitenant, cloud-nativa para manejar identidades de clientes o socios, cumplimiento, privacidad y personalización. Reduce la necesidad de soluciones externas de identidad. Mejora la seguridad de datos de clientes y la experiencia de usuario. Puede alinearse con regulaciones europeas, latinoamericanas, etc., para gestión de consentimiento y protección de datos.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas&lt;/STRONG&gt;: menos componentes externos, integración más directa con otras herramientas de SAP, potencial reducción de coste de licenciamiento externo, mayor coherencia en políticas de identidad, visibilidad y auditoría centralizadas.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/spain/products/technology-platform/customer-identity.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mas información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember4693" id="toc-hId-1693522017"&gt;Extensibility Wizard” para SAP Build y extensiones guiadas desde SAP Business Suite / SAP S/4HANA&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP ha introducido un Extensibility Wizard&amp;nbsp;(asistente de extensibilidad) que guía el desarrollo de extensiones tanto para SAP Business Suite como para SAP S/4HANA Cloud. Esto ayuda a estandarizar la forma de extender aplicaciones, asegurando que las extensiones sean compatibles con futuras actualizaciones. Facilita que equipos menos experimentados con ABAP o con extension-points sigan buenas prácticas. Reduce el riesgo de “&lt;EM&gt;custom code spaghetti&lt;/EM&gt;”. Puede acelerar entregas menores/incrementales sin comprometer el core.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas&lt;/STRONG&gt;: menor tiempo de desarrollo, menos errores, mayor mantenibilidad, mejor preparación para upgrades, posibilidad de que las extensiones sean menos costosas de mantener.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-btp-q2-2025/ba-p/14145899" target="_self"&gt;Mas información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Integraciones nuevas-predefinidas / adapters adicionales en SAP Integration Suite&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP Integration Suite está incorporando nuevos adapters (conectores) para tecnologías como IBM MQ, Google Cloud Storage, Salesforce PubSub, Anaplan, Snowflake, etc. Esto amplía la capacidad out-of-the-box de conectar SAP con sistemas modernos de datos, aplicaciones SaaS, servicios de mensajería. Se suma la mejora de experiencia de usuario para descubrir contenido preconstruido, recomendaciones, etc. Facilita integraciones híbridas o entre SAP y no-SAP con menor customización.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas&lt;/STRONG&gt;: ahorro de tiempo, mayor estandarización, menor probabilidad de errores en adaptadores hechos a medida, mantenimiento más sencillo. También reduce la barrera para integrar nuevos partners o servicios externos.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/connect-amp-go-integration-updates-for-2025-1/ba-p/14164407" target="_self"&gt;Mas información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember4701" id="toc-hId-1497008512"&gt;Mejoras de visibilidad y gobernanza financiera / monitoreo de consumo en los servicios de BTP&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP está reforzando las herramientas de monitoreo del consumo, visibilidad de costos y gobernanza financiera en SAP BTP, especialmente para HANA Cloud, integración, servicios que consumen recursos. Esto permite a las empresas anticipar gastos (“forecast”) y evitar sorpresas en uso excesivo. Mejores dashboards, alertas, métricas más finas de uso, consumo por objeto o servicio, etc. También se alinea con políticas internas de presupuestos, auditorías y optimización de costos.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas&lt;/STRONG&gt;: mayor previsibilidad financiera, identificación temprana de cuellos de botella o servicios sub-utilizados, optimización del gasto, facilitar decisiones de cierre vs extensión del servicio.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/enhanced-finops-capabilities-for-sap-btp/ba-p/14113797" target="_self"&gt;Mas información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="ember4705" id="toc-hId-1300495007"&gt;Estrategia de sostenibilidad con SAP BTP: Control Tower, Footprint Management y Green Ledger&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;SAP está reforzando su portafolio de sostenibilidad, con herramientas como SAP Sustainability Control Tower, Sustainability Footprint Management&amp;nbsp;y SAP Green Ledger, integradas con SAP BTP y SAP S/4HANA Cloud. Estas soluciones permiten capturar datos ESG (ambientales, sociales y de gobierno), automatizar reportes, calcular huella de carbono por producto, y llevar métricas de sostenibilidad al mismo nivel que los reportes financieros. Para organizaciones con regulación creciente en estándares ESG, estas capacidades ayudan a cumplir normativas como CSRD y similares, además de mejorar reputación.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Ventajas:&lt;/STRONG&gt; visibilidad centralizada de datos ESG, capacidad de reacción ante exigencias regulatorias, posibilidad de incorporar responsabilidades ambientales en decisiones operativas, vínculo más claro entre sostenibilidad y estrategia de negocio, potencial ahorro a mediano plazo si se optimizan procesos, menos riesgos legales o reputacionales.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":link:"&gt;🔗&lt;/span&gt; &lt;A class="" href="https://www.sap.com/products/scm/sustainability-control-tower.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Mas información&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-btp-integraci%C3%B3n-inteligente-control-financiero-y-sostenibilidad/ba-p/14224279"/>
    <published>2025-09-22T15:45:22.446000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introduction-to-alert-rule-sets-in-sap-hana-cloud-central/ba-p/14223552</id>
    <title>Introduction to Alert Rule Sets in SAP HANA Cloud Central</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:57:50.208000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Hai</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160136</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud has advanced its monitoring and alerting capabilities by introducing Alert Rule Sets. Building on previous &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/mastering-alert-configuration-in-sap-hana-cloud-central-a-comprehensive/ba-p/14134933" target="_self"&gt;alert configuration methods&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/streamlining-alert-management-in-sap-hana-cloud-leveraging-rest-apis-for/ba-p/14081496" target="_self"&gt;REST API-based bulk management&lt;/A&gt;, Alert Rule Sets offer a graphical interface for bulk alert configuration accessible to all administrators without API expertise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890008545"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What Are Alert Rule Sets?&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Enable configuration of multiple alert rules at once and apply them across one or more HANA Cloud instances.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create reusable alert configurations usable across different environments such as development, testing, and production.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Each user can maintain up to 20 alert rule sets for better organization and flexibility.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1693495040"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Key Benefits&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operational Efficiency:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Bulk management reduces manual configuration effort.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Scalability:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Supports large enterprise deployments with complex environments.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simplified Maintenance:&lt;/STRONG&gt; Updating an alert rule set updates all associated instances.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1496981535"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How to Create and Manage Alert Rule Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1429550749"&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Requires SAP HANA Cloud administrator role for creating or updating alert rule sets.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SAP HANA Cloud viewer role suffices for read-only access.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alert rule sets cannot be created or modified for Data Lake instances, which only support read-only alert viewing&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1233037244"&gt;Configuration Steps&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;OL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Navigate to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Alert Rules Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt; page and choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Alert Rule Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt;. Then select &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Alert Rule Set&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="create rule set.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317600i6EE4A3B047B0EAD5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="create rule set.png" alt="create rule set.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Create a new alert rule set by naming it and providing a description. Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Next&lt;/STRONG&gt; to configure alert rules.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="step 1.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317601iACD9A1866DA6881A/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="step 1.png" alt="step 1.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Configure alert rules by selecting which alerts to include, adjusting thresholds, and setting their status. Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Next&lt;/STRONG&gt; to configure instance. Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Create Now&lt;/STRONG&gt; to save the set and jump to the review page without configuring instances that apply this alert rule set.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="step 2.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317610iB721A829D6538B71/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="step 2.png" alt="step 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select target HANA Cloud instances to apply the rule set. Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Review&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="step 3.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317603iB6BA60E59418F333/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="step 3.png" alt="step 3.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Review and apply the configuration to deploy.&amp;nbsp;Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Save and Apply&lt;/STRONG&gt; to create the set and apply it. If the process is successful, the time stamp of the application will be visible under the Last Applied field. Select &lt;STRONG&gt;Save&lt;/STRONG&gt; to create the set without applying it to one or more instances.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="step 4.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317604i38359073586C2235/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="step 4.png" alt="step 4.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1036523739"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;View Alert Rule Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Navigate to the &lt;STRONG&gt;Alert Rules Configuration&lt;/STRONG&gt; page, choose &lt;STRONG&gt;Alert Rule Sets&lt;/STRONG&gt; to see a list of your sets. Select a row to see more information about the set, including its name, description, status, and alert rules that are part of the set.&amp;nbsp;In the Instances section you can see if the set is Applied or Not Applied to the instances you chose. There are several reasons why an instance appears under the Not Applied section:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You have saved the set without applying it to the chosen instances.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;There has been an error during the application, for example, a server problem.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;You (or another user) have modified alert rules that are part of the set elsewhere, for example, in the basic configuration or in another set. For more information, see &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud/sap-hana-cloud-administration-guide/alerts" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Using Alerts in SAP HANA Cloud Central&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="rule set manage.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317605iF74A77326F788DE8/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="rule set manage.png" alt="rule set manage.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="manage set.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317606i514BF2A88CB43B6E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="manage set.png" alt="manage set.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-840010234"&gt;Modify Alert Rule Sets&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;You can edit, rename, and delete the set from the details page or from the list page, choosing &lt;STRONG&gt;... (More)&lt;/STRONG&gt; in the Actions column.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="edit set.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317608i805F23C85BB0A577/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="edit set.png" alt="edit set.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;After modifying alert rules in a set, reapply the set to your selected instances to incorporate the latest changes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="apply change.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/317609iF110B8B9B6162AB7/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="apply change.png" alt="apply change.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-514414010"&gt;Best Practices for Alert Rule Sets&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Use descriptive, consistent naming conventions (e.g., PROD-HighPerf-CriticalAlerts).&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Establish a review schedule to maintain relevance as infrastructure evolves.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Maintain comprehensive documentation for governance and clarity.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-317900505"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;The UI and API Bridge&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Alert Rule Sets represent a convergence of REST API automation and a user-friendly UI.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;API automation remains available for DevOps and infrastructure-as-code automation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Both approaches can be combined for hybrid workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-121387000"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Alert Rule Sets signify a critical advancement in SAP HANA Cloud’s alert management, enabling scalable, efficient, and consistent alert configuration across multiple instances. This feature supports enterprises as they grow their HANA Cloud deployments by simplifying alert management complexities and providing both powerful automation and ease of use.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With this tool, administrators gain enhanced operational efficiency and consistency, supporting hundreds of instances if needed, making monitoring more flexible and user-friendly.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introduction-to-alert-rule-sets-in-sap-hana-cloud-central/ba-p/14223552"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:57:50.208000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-sap-hana-cloud-on-sap-cloud-infrastructure/ba-p/14223782</id>
    <title>Introducing SAP HANA Cloud on SAP Cloud Infrastructure</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T09:03:08.889000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>isomesan</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1444439</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We are pleased to share that SAP HANA Cloud is now generally available on SAP BTP powered by SAP Cloud Infrastructure. This new deployment option complements our existing offerings on hyperscaler platforms, addressing the growing demand for technological independence, local compliance, and data control.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1760927841"&gt;About SAP Cloud Infrastructure&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Cloud Infrastructure (SCI) is SAP's own Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS) platform, operated from SAP data centers around the globe. Built on OpenStack APIs, it provides hyperscale-like capabilities including compute, storage, and networking. Originally designed to&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;run SAP cloud applications with high scalability, resilience, compliance, and security, SCI now also supports selected customer and partner workloads. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To explore the platform and its features, visit the&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_Cloud_Infrastructure?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=SHIP" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Cloud Infrastructure&amp;nbsp;Documentation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1564414336"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;How the new deployment fits into SAP's multi-cloud strategy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP gives customers the flexibility to run SAP HANA Cloud on the infrastructure that best meets their needs. Today, it's available on the leading hyperscalers—Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform, and Alibaba Cloud—leveraging our partners' global reach and modern infrastructure. See&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-data-centers/ba-p/13528822" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud data centers&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By adding SAP Cloud Infrastructure as a deployment option alongside the hyperscalers, we give customers even more choice and flexibility, while meeting requirements for technological autonomy, data residency, and access control in the public cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Figure2_2.png" style="width: 520px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319402i7D317206B59EA6BA/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Figure2_2.png" alt="Figure2_2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1367900831"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;First region and initial scope &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud is now live in the SAP BTP Europe (Frankfurt) region on SCI. This &lt;STRONG&gt;cloud-in-country deployment&lt;/STRONG&gt; keeps customer and backup data local, ensuring data residency and compliance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Operating in &lt;STRONG&gt;EU Access mode&lt;/STRONG&gt;, the SCI-based deployment restricts the processing of personally identifiable customer data to SAP delivery units located within the European Economic Area (EEA) and Switzerland, giving customers enhanced control and data protection.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;On SCI, SAP HANA Cloud delivers the same capabilities and benefits as on hyperscalers*, along with the same SLAs and pricing models, ensuring a consistent experience regardless of deployment choice.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1171387326"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What's next? &lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud is expanding alongside SAP BTP into new SCI regions. Additional SCI regions are planned for upcoming releases—check the latest SAP HANA Cloud data center availability in &lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73554900100800002881&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;q=data%20center" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Roadmap Explorer&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-974873821"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Summary&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With SAP HANA Cloud, customers can choose the infrastructure provider that best fits their business—either a partner hyperscaler or SAP itself. The first SAP BTP region on SAP Cloud Infrastructure is Europe (Frankfurt). With EU-Access, in-country hosting, and enterprise-grade SLAs, this region provides compliance, security, and reliability, serving the specific needs of German and European customers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="2"&gt;*Restrictions at GA: (1) SAP HANA Cloud, Data lake Relational Engine, (2) Joule in SAP HANA Cloud Central, (3) Customer-managed encryption keys (CMK), and (4) memory sizes larger than 7.5 TB.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-sap-hana-cloud-on-sap-cloud-infrastructure/ba-p/14223782"/>
    <published>2025-09-23T09:03:08.889000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-4-in-the-series/ba-p/14206255</id>
    <title>Top Reasons to Modernize with SAP HANA Cloud – Blog #4 in the Series</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T17:07:46.947000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomashammer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;We’ve been talking in this about how you can build your business case for modernizing to SAP HANA Cloud. However, many organizations still need help calculating the business value of migrating their database to the cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;A recent &lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;IDC study&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; confirmed the value of modernizing to SAP HANA Cloud. Using a detailed business value assessmt methodology, IDC calculated that each SAP HANA Cloud database delivered US$820,000 in average annual benefits, with a 10.3-month payback on investment. Numbers like that are sure to turn heads.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This blog reviews the three beneficial features that can help you make the case for SAP HANA Cloud: native AI capabilities, built-in data integration, and automation that streamlines the duties of database developers and administrators.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Native AI capabilities&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To gain value from huge volumes of business data, you need advanced AI capabilities that simplify the development and deployment of intelligent applications.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud is part of SAP Business Technology Platform, which offers powerful AI tools, frameworks, and services. These capabilities streamline the development and deployment of intelligent applications using machine learning and generative AI features. Extensive tools and resources, including prebuilt AI models, help you take advantage of business-ready AI.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multi-model engines process vast amounts of data and generate intelligent, in-context outputs. SAP HANA Cloud provides native storage, processing, and querying capabilities for AI data. A built-in vector engine handles embeddings as core data, so you can conduct similarity searches and rankings without creating separate vector databases. The database also supports retrieval-augmented generation, which helps large language models become more context-aware and integrate sensitive business context into data interactions.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog4-Pic.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319504iC21B2421C3C37FD4/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog4-Pic.jpg" alt="Blog4-Pic.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP HANA Cloud also includes built-in, AI-enabled analytics that support predictive modeling, graph and similarity search, and time-series analysis. A predictive analysis library supports powerful features such as clustering, recommender systems, and outlier detection.&amp;nbsp; In addition, a library of 100+ business and scientific algorithms for key ML scenarios is embedded natively into the database. The IDC report suggests organizations can use these capabilities to automate insights and optimize decision-making by processing multiple data types. Study participants realized a 25% productivity increase, which translates into a value of $271,184 per enterprise.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Global cosmetics leader &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/asset/dynamic/2025/01/a68bf3d4-ef7e-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Natura &amp;amp;Co&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; used the AI capabilities of SAP HANA Cloud with SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP) to create a similarity search. The vector engine feature of SAP HANA Cloud allows users to extract information from large volumes of documents using natural language. The company also plans to use the generative AI capability to streamline business processes and support faster decision-making in its implementation of SAP S/4HANA.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Built-in data integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Your IT landscape is complex—with data flowing to and from multiple systems, cloud platforms, and on-premises environments. Bringing this data together has always required complex ETL processes, synchronization mechanisms, and data duplication efforts. How can you simplify the integration of this business data? Realistically, every business uses data sources provided by various vendors. To bring this data together requires smooth data integration.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud offers native connectivity with almost any data source. You can access data from SAP and third-party applications, including ERP systems, IoT devices, and external data services. The database can gain live access to sources without data replication. This integration unifies disparate data streams and creates one holistic view of your enterprise data, allowing developers to build intelligent data applications that deliver accurate, current information in real time. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Built-in data integration capabilities include:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart data access&lt;/STRONG&gt;, offering virtual data access from source systems without physical data movement&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Simple switching between virtual data access and data replication&lt;/STRONG&gt;, balancing cost and performance effectively&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Smart data integration&lt;/STRONG&gt;, enabling real-time or batch data replication with transformation capabilities&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Hybrid connectivity&lt;/STRONG&gt;, with unified connection to on-premises SAP HANA systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Multi-model capabilities combine federated relational data with other data types, including vector embedding, spatial information, graph relationships, and JSON documents. By eliminating traditional barriers between data sources and locations, SAP HANA Cloud helps you simplify data management while creating a connected enterprise data ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the IDC report, respondents said the ability to gain access to real-time data from a single source helped their analytics teams accelerate data reporting. One executive working in the retail industry said, “The data is far more accessible and quicker to get with SAP HANA Cloud.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Automation to streamline DBA duties&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The workload of database developers and administrators seems to grow endlessly, as data architectures become more complex. Whether they are diagnosing and resolving issues, tuning database performance, or writing queries, these workers face a long list of highly manual tasks.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Using integrated, AI-powered tooling available with SAP HANA Cloud helps administrators work more efficiently and productively. Conversational AI features help them generate SQL statements from plain text queries, create intelligent explanations of database behaviors or issues, and automatically summarize alerts and system messages into actionable insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud also automates routine database maintenance issues. The database continuously monitors system usage and offers proactive recommendations for optimization. It can identify performance bottlenecks, guide resource tuning, and suggest areas ripe for elastic scaling. Administrators can get the job done with no deep technical intervention required.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The benefits of automation are notable. In the IDC study, companies reported a 30% efficiency boost for their database administrator (DBA) teams, resulting in an average annual business value of $336,089 per organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One technology organization appreciated this value. “SAP HANA Cloud provides our DBA team with more tools to help identify issues and resolve them,” said the participant. “It has increased their productivity as a result.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another company in the agriculture industry concurred. “The fact that SAP HANA Cloud has centralized database administration and provided flexibility to add a data lake within its data source connections has positively impacted the productivity of our DBA team,” the executive added.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore other SAP HANA Cloud features to build your business case&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Read the final blog to learn how comprehensive security and a complete development system can help you build your business case for SAP HANA Cloud while preparing for the future of modern, intelligent applications and processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additional resources:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;What’s the potential value of SAP HANA Cloud for your organization? Complete a short &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Learn more about &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Discover how moving to SAP HANA Cloud helps you create a &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana/cloud-migration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;foundation for modernization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Explore this guide on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-compelling-business-case-to-move-your-database-to-the-cloud/ba-p/14123254" target="_blank"&gt;building a compelling business case to move your database to the cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; “&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Business Value of SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;,” IDC, sponsored by SAP, April 2025.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-4-in-the-series/ba-p/14206255"/>
    <published>2025-09-25T17:07:46.947000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/hello-python-my-first-script-in-sap-bas-connecting-to-hana-cloud/ba-p/14228993</id>
    <title>Hello Python: My First Script in SAP BAS Connecting to HANA Cloud</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T13:05:26.454000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sharathmg</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/174516</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;Credit:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/183"&gt;@Vitaliy-R&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Your startup blogs kindled my interest to explore working with Python in SAP ecosystem.&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/using-python-in-sap-business-application-studio-my-notes/ba-p/14155516" target="_self"&gt;Python in BAS&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/using-jupyter-in-sap-business-application-studio-my-notes/ba-p/14167294" target="_self"&gt;Jupyter in BAS&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I first started exploring SAP Business Application Studio (BAS), I was curious about how Python could fit into the SAP landscape. I’ve mostly associated BAS with HANA artefacts(SQLScript, hdbcalculationview, hdbreptask etc.) and CAP artefacts, so writing a Python script inside BAS felt like venturing into new territory. My goal was simple: write a basic script and connect it to SAP HANA Cloud. What I discovered along the way is that Python not only works smoothly in BAS but also makes it easy to interact with HANA Cloud, opening up opportunities for data exploration, automation, and integration in a way that feels both modern and approachable.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Before jumping into the Python script, I had to get my environment ready in SAP Business Application Studio (BAS). Here’s what I set up:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;A BAS dev space with a full-stack cloud application space since it supports multiple runtimes, including Python. I had a space with HANA Native Application type. Since the Python tools extension&amp;nbsp;is not added by default, I edited the space to select the Python tools in the additional extension options.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="HANA Dev Space Python extension" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320334iFEC4E0932EFEAC15/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="HANA_DevSpace_Setting.png" alt="HANA Dev Space Python extension" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;HANA Dev Space Python extension&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;Note: For initial steps to check the Python version, Jupyter notebook and set ups refer to the blogs listed at the start.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Use Case: I attempted to achieve the following:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Establish a connection to HANA Cloud&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Execute an SQL query on a table/view&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Display the results&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the BAS, I created a project from Template: SAP HANA Database Project&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Project Template.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320351iEAE035C8FCA7C5B5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Project Template.png" alt="Project Template.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next step: Create a notebook file.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="notebook file.png" style="width: 339px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320356i8F1BB8DEF9D0E888/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="notebook file.png" alt="notebook file.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;My guide to connect to HANA Cloud:&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_HANA_CLIENT/f1b440ded6144a54ada97ff95dac7adf/d12c86af7cb442d1b9f8520e2aba7758.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Connect to HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;When I first tried importing hdbcli into my Jupyter Notebook within BAS, I ran into the same ModuleNotFoundError. Even though I had already installed hdbcli In the terminal, the notebook kernel wasn’t recognizing it. On some search and prompting with GPT( &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":beaming_face_with_smiling_eyes:"&gt;😁&lt;/span&gt;), I understood that it's a common issue because Jupyter can run in a different Python environment than the terminal. The fix was simple: I ran&lt;/P&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;import sys
!{sys.executable} -m pip install hdbcli&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;P&gt;directly in a notebook cell. This ensures that the HANA client is installed in the same environment as the notebook kernel. After this step, I could successfully import dbapi and connect to HANA Cloud without any errors. It was a small but important lesson about Python environments in BAS, especially when using Jupyter.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hdbcli Module Not found.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320378i62AF858DA44FE00C/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hdbcli Module Not found.png" alt="hdbcli Module Not found.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;With the hdbcli package installed and working in my Jupyter Notebook, I was ready to write my first Python script to connect to SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the next cell, I imported hdbcli in this notebook.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;import hdbcli
print(hdbcli.__file__)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="import hdbcli.png" style="width: 854px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320388iF426637D8D8CCB0F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="import hdbcli.png" alt="import hdbcli.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;The next step was to&amp;nbsp;gain access to the dbapi interface, which allows you to establish connections, execute SQL queries, and fetch results from your HANA Cloud instance. This simple import is the gateway to working with HANA directly from Python.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;from hdbcli import dbapi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The next step is to establish a connection to your HANA Cloud instance. This requires specifying the host, port, username, and password.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="hana cloud connection.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320408i84F10DA5613166DC/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="hana cloud connection.png" alt="hana cloud connection.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;After connecting, you can create a cursor object to execute SQL statements. An SQL statement, preferably a Select Query to test the retrieval of data from HANA Cloud. In my case, I used a Select with count on the number of records in a view. Once the variables were ready, execute the connection cursor object.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Note: in the SQL variable, use single quotes and a semicolon at the end of the query. (beginner tip&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":slightly_smiling_face:"&gt;🙂&lt;/span&gt; )&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Execution Cursor.png" style="width: 799px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320427iB0929785AAAB7257/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Execution Cursor.png" alt="Execution Cursor.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Now is the time to test the data retrieval from the script and compare it with the Database Explorer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Drum roll....&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":drum:"&gt;🥁&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-left" image-alt="Data in DB explorer.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320447i3D6BB255F8FDBF13/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Data in DB explorer.png" alt="Data in DB explorer.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-right" image-alt="Data in Script.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320448iDA977EF3358B8FF8/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Data in Script.png" alt="Data in Script.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Hurray&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":party_popper:"&gt;🎉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Completing my first Python script in SAP Business Application Studio and connecting it to HANA Cloud was an exciting milestone. From the initial curiosity to the small hurdles like installing hdbcli in the notebook and finally seeing my script return results, every step felt like a mini victory.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;That simple output from HANA Cloud made all the effort worthwhile and gave me a real sense of accomplishment.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This experience has sparked my curiosity to explore more complex queries, data analysis, and automation using Python in SAP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;I hope my journey inspires others to take that first step and discover how fun and powerful working with Python and HANA Cloud can be.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Chao.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/hello-python-my-first-script-in-sap-bas-connecting-to-hana-cloud/ba-p/14228993"/>
    <published>2025-09-26T13:05:26.454000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-september-2025/ba-p/14228564</id>
    <title>What’s New in SAP HANA Cloud – September 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T14:40:16.836000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomashammer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631992095"&gt;What’s New in SAP HANA Cloud – September 2025&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As we approach the end of the third quarter of 2025, we are thrilled to present the third release of SAP HANA Cloud for the year. Certainly, this quarterly update brings many innovative features designed to enhance your experience with SAP HANA Cloud and drive business value.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="blug_thumb.png" style="width: 546px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320206iB0DD73C97F93DD95/image-dimensions/546x284?v=v2" width="546" height="284" role="button" title="blug_thumb.png" alt="blug_thumb.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Let’s explore the exciting new capabilities and improvements that have just been made available.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1435478590"&gt;Innovations in SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Database&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368047804"&gt;Administration and Service Management&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1300617018"&gt;Bulk Alert configuration&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Starting off strong, the Q3 release introduces bulk alert configuration&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. Building on previous alert configuration methods and REST API-based bulk management, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;a&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;lert &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;r&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ule &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;s&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;ets offer a graphical interface for bulk alert configuration accessible to all administrators without API expertise.&lt;/SPAN&gt; &lt;SPAN&gt;The feature also allows to create and save alert configuration templates, making it easy to reuse them across different instances.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bulk alert configuration significantly enhances user efficiency by streamlining the alert setup process. Management of complex alert configurations becomes more scalable, while safeguarding that all instances are monitored effectively without the need for repetitive manual setup.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To learn more about this new feature, take a look at this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introduction-to-alert-rule-sets-in-sap-hana-cloud-central/ba-p/14223552" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt; by our product expert Hai Zhang.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104103513"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Partition Advisor&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Recommendation App, housing all intelligent advisors for SAP HANA Cloud, hosts a new advisor, as we introduce the partition advisor with QRC3 2025. It helps maintain manageable partition sizes by automatically analyzing potential partition keys and methods (range versus hash). It provides recommendations on how to partition your data effectively and can apply these recommendations via an “Apply” button to your tables.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Partition Advisor saves time by automating the analysis of partitioning options and delivering actionable recommendations. It helps users identify tables that may exceed the limits, suggesting optimal repartitioning strategies. This not only improves query performance but also optimizes costs, ensuring that your data management remains efficient and scalable.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Find more information about the partition advisor in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-administration-guide/about-partition-advisor?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;this help documentation&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-907590008"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support for 9 TB instances on Microsoft Azure&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;From now on, SAP HANA Cloud on Microsoft Azure supports large instances up to 9TB. Please note that the availability of these large database instances will vary depending on your selected region.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the support for 9 TB instances on Azure, businesses gain the flexibility to scale up their databases as needed. It allows them to handle increased memory requirements, while ensuring that their database can keep pace with growing data demands. This scalability is crucial for maintaining optimal performance and supporting business growth.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-711076503"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finding object dependencies in database objects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dependencies are now shown in the properties page of schema objects such as tables, views, functions, and procedures in the database objects app.&amp;nbsp; This enables you to quickly examine the dependencies between objects.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As seen below in the Database Objects app, the table CUSTOMER has an incoming referential dependency from the RESERVATION table and is referenced in a view and function.&amp;nbsp; A graphical &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-developer-guide-for-cloud-foundry-multitarget-applications-sap-business-app-studio/context-sensitive-actions-on-database-objects-in-database-explorer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;dependency viewer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is also available in the SAP HANA database explorer extension in SAP Business Application Studio or Visual Studio Code.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_0-1758873512590.png" style="width: 545px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320156iD4B5DA01FEB8C25B/image-dimensions/545x432?v=v2" width="545" height="432" role="button" title="thomashammer_0-1758873512590.png" alt="thomashammer_0-1758873512590.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-514562998"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Simplified Instance Provisioning&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The SAP HANA Cloud provisioning wizard has been enhanced to enable users to select either a preset configuration, provide a JSON configuration, or to use a manual configuration when creating new instances.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_1-1758873512602.png" style="width: 546px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320158iA0A601A49A3C8898/image-dimensions/546x389?v=v2" width="546" height="389" role="button" title="thomashammer_1-1758873512602.png" alt="thomashammer_1-1758873512602.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The preset configurations for SAP HANA databases include basic, minimum, maximum, last used, and most used, enabling a user to quickly choose a preset that closely matches their use case.&amp;nbsp; After filling in a few required fields such as instance name and password, the instance can be created.&amp;nbsp; Basic is sized to support additional features such as the document store, triple store, natural language processing, and the script and data provisioning servers.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The JSON configuration option enables a user to create instances based on a JSON document that contains the settings of the instance.&amp;nbsp; This can be helpful if you wish to create multiple instances with very similar configurations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_2-1758873512608.png" style="width: 614px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320155iD8DCC141A2798F0B/image-dimensions/614x264?v=v2" width="614" height="264" role="button" title="thomashammer_2-1758873512608.png" alt="thomashammer_2-1758873512608.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finally, the manual configuration option enables a user to explore all the possible configuration setting using the instance wizard.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_3-1758873512612.png" style="width: 610px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320162iC4733B1CEE3A4668/image-dimensions/610x151?v=v2" width="610" height="151" role="button" title="thomashammer_3-1758873512612.png" alt="thomashammer_3-1758873512612.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-318049493"&gt;SQL Console statement library&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the QRC3 release of SAP HANA Cloud, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;the statement library in the SQL Console of SAP HANA Cloud Central has the option to run and open multiple statements either in the current tab or in individual tabs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_4-1758873512616.png" style="width: 528px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320161i5F51D6B8008A4C25/image-dimensions/528x107?v=v2" width="528" height="107" role="button" title="thomashammer_4-1758873512616.png" alt="thomashammer_4-1758873512616.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Run will append the statements together and the results will be shown in separate result set tabs.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Run in Individual Tabs opens each selected statement in its own SQL Console tab and executes it.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_5-1758873512619.png" style="width: 513px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320159i7E6D77A749ACBC17/image-dimensions/513x109?v=v2" width="513" height="109" role="button" title="thomashammer_5-1758873512619.png" alt="thomashammer_5-1758873512619.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--7546731"&gt;Data Integration&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--150208886"&gt;Introducing the New Data Access Agent - connecting to Azure SQL Database &amp;amp; Snowflake&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Additionally, I am thrilled to announce that&amp;nbsp;SAP HANA smart data access (SDA)&amp;nbsp;now supports Microsoft Azure SQL database and Snowflake as remote sources via the new &lt;STRONG&gt;Data Access Agent&lt;/STRONG&gt;. This new Data Access Agent expands data federation and provides broader coverage with JDBC-based adapters as an SAP-managed service.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With a clean core strategy in mind, SDA is a core component to leverage the full potential of your data. Until recently, the limited protocol boundaries to ODBC and REST as well as restrictions on running 3rd party drivers, limited the supported scope of remote resources.&amp;nbsp;SAP HANA smart data integration (SDI)&amp;nbsp;helped to bridge this gap but required customers to deploy and operate the Data Provisioning Agent (DPAgent) in an on-premise setup.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The new Data Access Agent now supports new JDBC-based adapters. Of course, the natively available SDA adapters continue to be based on ODBC and REST. The SAP-managed Data Access Agent simplifies operations and reduces the effort to access &lt;STRONG&gt;Microsoft Azure SQL Database&lt;/STRONG&gt; and the &lt;STRONG&gt;Snowflake&lt;/STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;in SAP HANA Cloud. Users can also benefit from streamlined and user-friendly configuration and monitoring of this fully managed, secure, and cloud native product.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please note the&amp;nbsp;new&amp;nbsp;Data Access&amp;nbsp;Agent&amp;nbsp;currently only supports data federation and snapshot toggling within the virtual table interface. Real-time replication is not supported. Refer to further details of support in&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2600176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 2600176 - SAP HANA Smart Data Access Supported Remote Sources&lt;/A&gt;&lt;U&gt;.&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To learn more about SAP HANA Cloud's New Data Access Agent, take a look at&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/204092" target="_blank"&gt;@SeungjoonLee&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;'s&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/expanding-data-federation-for-broader-coverage-with-the-new-data-access/ba-p/14165135" target="_blank"&gt;blog post here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--346722391"&gt;Support a remote source to SharePoint in Microsoft 365&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moreover, with the Q3 release we introduce support for creating a remote source to SharePoint in Microsoft 365 using the data access agent of SAP HANA smart data access. This feature allows for the virtualization of data, including lists and Excel worksheets, within SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database. For further details on supported remote sources, refer to &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/2600176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 2600176&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the ability to access SharePoint data in Microsoft 365 through the SAP-managed data access agent, users can simplify operations and reduce the effort required for data integration. This eventually enhances collaboration and streamlines data management processes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--543235896"&gt;Direct SQL access to files in the Apache Iceberg open table format&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Furthermore, with the recent release we introduce direct SQL access to files in the Apache Iceberg’s open table format. This enhancement enables users to create virtual tables within SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database, allowing read-only access to Apache Iceberg data in external object storage. Supported storage types include the data lake files in SAP HANA Cloud, Amazon S3, Azure Blob Storage, Azure Data Lake Storage (ADLS) Gen2, and Google Cloud Storage.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This means users can execute SQL queries on large volumes of data without the need to load it into the memory of the SAP HANA database. The new feature thus enhances performance and efficiency, enabling seamless data analysis across diverse storage environments.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--446346394"&gt;Security&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--936262906"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Row-level data access control over fact tables based on associated dimension attributes&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Next, SAP HANA Cloud now supports row-level data access control over fact tables based on associated dimension attributes. This allows users to restrict access to fact table data without the need to join the dimension tables where the access control is applied. Restrictions are based on the availability of associated dimensional data, which is already restricted with a structured filter (=nested structured filters).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This capability enables fine-grain access control to restrict data for fact tables based on associated dimension table attribute data. This enhances security and ensures that sensitive data is accessible only to authorized users, improving overall data governance.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1132776411"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Support for X509-based dynamic user creation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Moreover, SAP HANA Cloud also supports X509-based dynamic user creation, leveraging the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP). Customers can now create user data automatically in SAP HANA Cloud based on X509 authentication and manage user data within related LDAP groups.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bridging the gap for automated user creation through X509 authentication with user authorization through LDAP, this feature allows for the automation of user creation. This strengthens operational efficiency and streamlines user management processes, ensuring a seamless integration of security protocols.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1329289916"&gt;Support for Azure Private Link&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Over the past quarters, there have already been announcements about different private IP endpoint service deliveries. From Q3 2025 on, SAP HANA Cloud now supports Azure Private Link as well, enabling users to connect applications running within an Azure landscape to SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database using private IP endpoints. These endpoints are addressable only within the Azure network and are not exposed publicly, ensuring an additional layer of security. It is important to note that services in SAP HANA Cloud already enforce strict transport layer security (TLS) and allow users to configure IP allow or disallow lists.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;With Azure Private Link support, users can significantly reduce the exposure of IP endpoints, enhancing the overall security of connections to SAP HANA Cloud. This feature complements existing IP allow or disallow list filtering, ensuring that sensitive data remains protected and secure within the Azure network.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1232400414"&gt;Multi-Model Data Processing&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1722316926"&gt;Vector Embedding SQL Function Support for Generative AI Hub&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With the recent release, SAP HANA Cloud once again expands its vector embedding support by allowing the VECTOR_EMBEDDING SQL function to directly use embedding models exposed via SAP GenAI Hub.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Previously, the function only supported SAP-provided NLP models. Now, customers can connect their own SAP GenAI Hub service instance and consume any available embedding model, for example OpenAI, Amazon Titan, or other partner models directly via SQL.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All one must do is:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Create a remote source in SAP HANA Cloud that points to your SAP GenAI Hub (AI Core) service instance&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Configure certificates and authentication controls&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Retrieve available models with GET_REMOTE_SOURCE_AI_MODELS built-in procedure&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Call VECTOR_EMBEDDING by passing the text, type (e.g. DOCUMENT), model name and version, and the remote source&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For detailed setup and examples, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-vector-engine-guide/creating-text-embeddings-with-sap-ai-core?q=genai+hub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;see here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1918830431"&gt;Support for Batch Embedding Creation using CREATE VECTOR EMBEDDINGS&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP HANA Cloud also introduces a newly built-in procedure &lt;STRONG&gt;CREATE_VECTOR_EMBEDDINGS&lt;/STRONG&gt; that makes it easier to generate vector embeddings for large volumes of text data stored in SAP HANA tables.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Instead of having to process documents row by row, this procedure lets you embed text in batches. You simply provide the table and column that contain your documents, specify the target vector column, choose the NLP model, and the procedure automatically generates embeddings where they are missing.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This new capability simplifies and accelerates the integration of AI and NLP use cases with SAP HANA Cloud, by reducing time to value for building intelligent applications with embeddings and by allowing developers to process large datasets more efficiently with built-in batch handling.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;It also &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;eliminates repetitive boilerplate code for embedding creation and storage.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To summarize, this makes SAP HANA Cloud a more powerful foundation for scenarios such as semantic search, generative AI, and intelligent text analysis. For detailed syntax and examples, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-vector-engine-guide/create-vector-embeddings-procedural?q=creat_vector_embeddings" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;see here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--1947160245"&gt;JSON as a datatype in the SAP HANA Cloud JSON Document Store&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With QRC3 2025, SAP HANA Cloud introduces JSON as a datatype in the Document Store. This is not a column data type for tables, but a return type for collections in the Document Store.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Collections can now return JSON directly instead of NVARCHAR, so queries follow JSON semantics without extra casting. This brings clearer path access with the $ root specifier, better performance through filter and function pushdown, and simpler syntax when working with JSON content.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By making JSON a first class return type, SAP HANA Cloud improves both efficiency and consistency when building applications on flexible document data. For detailed syntax and examples, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-json-document-store-guide/json-data-type" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;see here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Please note, the ‘$’ &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/hana-cloud-database/sap-hana-cloud-sap-hana-database-json-document-store-guide/document-root-specifier?state=DRAFT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;document root specifier&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; is mandatory for collections returning JSON.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Existing collections will still default to NVARCHAR unless explicitly created or altered to return JSON.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Some casts (like TO_NVARCHAR on complex types) are restricted for JSON return types.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1850270743"&gt;Graphical View Modeling&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;The third release in 2025 again brings many enhancements to SAP HANA Cloud’s graphical view modeling capabilities. Below, we are giving an overview about the innovations introduced. To get more details, you can take a closer look at Jan Zwickel's &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/calculation-view-features-of-2025-qrc3/ba-p/14192411" target="_self"&gt;blog post&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1954780041"&gt;Ability to rename multiple already mapped columns&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s start with the new ability to rename multiple columns that are already mapped, allowing users to perform this action in a single step. This feature is available for star joins and in the node mapping dialog.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This new capability simplifies the refactoring of column names and enhances model insights by enabling users to provide more-specific and meaningful column names. This increases the clarity and usability of data models, improving overall user experience.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1758266536"&gt;Flexibly maintaining labels for alias names&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, users can now flexibly maintain labels for alias names by using expressions. For example, users can generate a label that transforms the alias name to lowercase and adds a prefix.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature not only increases development efficiency and improves model quality but also provides a better analytics user experience by ensuring that labels are consistent and meaningful, eventually enhancing the readability and interpretability of data models.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1561753031"&gt;Support of semijoin functionality&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Furthermore, the semijoin functionality is now available. This feature enables users to effectively reduce records based on filter values by providing a dedicated join option for filtering in standard join nodes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The semijoin functionality optimizes resource consumption when filtering through joins, allowing users to more efficiently manage data processing tasks. It enhances performance and ensures that only relevant data is processed, leading to improved overall efficiency and resource utilization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1365239526"&gt;Switching between structured privileges and structured filters through a graphical editor&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Next, we introduced the capability to switch between structured privileges and structured filters using a graphical editor. Users can now change from one object type to another seamlessly and store the changes accordingly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This increases flexibility when creating analytic privileges, allowing users to easily switch between privilege types to meet their specific requirements. The graphical editor enhances the overall usability and efficiency of managing data insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1168726021"&gt;Improved supportability by SQL plan trace for EPM, MDS, and prepared statement caches&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Moreover, supportability for SAP HANA Cloud got improved by enabling SQL plan trace for EPM (Enterprise Performance Management) queries, MDS (Multidimensional Services) queries, and prepared statement caches.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By enabling plan trace for EPM, MDS queries, and prepared statement caches, this feature allows for better troubleshooting and performance analysis. It increases the overall supportability and reliability of these systems, ensuring that users can get the assistance they need when issues arise.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-972212516"&gt;MDS Cubes&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-482296004"&gt;Support of input parameters in multidimensional services (MDS) cubes&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;With the Q3 release, users can now select combinations of input parameter values that will be loaded and served by the MDS cube. This functionality extends the capabilities of MDS cubes, allowing for more flexible and dynamic data insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The support for input parameters in MDS cubes increases the scope of scenarios that can be handled, providing users with more comprehensive and tailored insights. Thus, this feature helps users receive insights more quickly, enhancing the overall analytics experience and improving operational efficiency of SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-285782499"&gt;Using additional currency conversion options with MDS cube&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Besides, the recent release enables the use of additional currency conversion options with MDS cubes. Users can now employ rounding, decimal shifts, and the accuracy option "retain all possible digits" in conjunction with MDS cubes.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These additional currency conversion options simplify the creation of MDS cubes from existing calculation views while providing greater flexibility and control over currency data, and ensuring accurate and consistent financial insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-257452685"&gt;Using unit conversion of MDS cube measures together with the option to convert at query execution time&lt;/H4&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, users are now able to convert units of MDS cube measures during query execution time.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;By allowing the unit conversion at query execution time, users gain increased control over when and how unit conversion happens thus enhancing the flexibility and accuracy of data analysis, while also ensuring that units are converted as needed for specific insights.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-941148201"&gt;Innovations in SAP HANA Cloud, data lake&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-451231689"&gt;Single Sign on support for SAP HANA Cloud, data lake files&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Data Lake Files app in SAP HANA Cloud Central now supports Single Sign-On (SSO) in addition to X509 credentials for authentication.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It can be enabled with the “Enable Single Sign-On for Data Lake Files” menu item from the actions menu in either the Instances or Data Lake Files app.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This feature enables users to quickly use the Data Lake Files app without having to do configuration steps required to use X509 authentication.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="thomashammer_6-1758873512624.png" style="width: 575px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/320163i20774542DDB5E0BB/image-dimensions/575x283?v=v2" width="575" height="283" role="button" title="thomashammer_6-1758873512624.png" alt="thomashammer_6-1758873512624.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-548121191"&gt;Further Innovations &amp;amp; Enhancements&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-58204679"&gt;SAP HANA Client&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Our SAP HANA Client for Python now supports Alpine Linux x64 as of the 2.25 release.&amp;nbsp; Alpine Linux is a security-oriented, lightweight Linux distribution.&amp;nbsp; Alpine Linux offers several benefits, such as faster build times due to its lightweight nature and enhanced security with fewer vulnerabilities due to its minimalism.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;However, unlike most Linux distributions, Alpine Linux uses musl libc instead of glibc. While this keeps Alpine lean, it breaks compatibility with the regular Linux x64 SAP HANA Client package and requires its own separate Python wheel release.&amp;nbsp; It can be found on PyPI at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://pypi.org/project/hdbcli/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;https://pypi.org/project/hdbcli/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For further details on the platforms that the SAP HANA Client supports, please see &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3165810" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Note 3165810 - SAP HANA Client Supported Platforms&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--138308826"&gt;Expanded Data Center Availability on SAP Cloud Infrastructure in Germany&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;With QRC3 2025, we are introducing SAP HANA Cloud on SAP Cloud Infrastructure (SCI) — SAP's own cloud infrastructure, operated in SAP data centers. This new deployment option expands the existing SAP HANA Cloud offering on leading hyperscaler infrastructure (AWS, Azure, GCP, and AliCloud) and meets the growing demand for technological independence, local compliance, and data control.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Today, SAP HANA Cloud is available on SCI in Frankfurt, Germany. With EU-Access, in-country hosting, and enterprise-grade SLAs, this region offers compliance, security, and reliability for German and European customers. Additional SCI regions are planned for upcoming releases. Check &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Data Center Availability in &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://roadmaps.sap.com/board?PRODUCT=73554900100800002881&amp;amp;range=CURRENT-LAST&amp;amp;q=data%20center" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP Roadmap Explorer&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To learn more about SAP HANA Cloud on SCI, take a look at this &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/introducing-sap-hana-cloud-on-sap-cloud-infrastructure/ba-p/14223782" target="_blank"&gt;this blog post&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--334822331"&gt;Database Application Development&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--824738843"&gt;Natural language to SQL generation in Joule using SAP Build Code&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Last but not least, we introduce the generation of SQL for SAP HANA Cloud in Joule using SAP Build Code. This feature allows users to generate SQL statements based on natural language input. Additionally, it copies the generated SQL statement to the SQL consoles of the database explorer extension for SAP HANA in SAP Build Code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This feature increases developer productivity by automating the process of generating SQL statements through natural language input. It reduces the likelihood of errors and improves the quality of the generated SQL, ultimately streamlining the development process and enhancing efficiency.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;P&gt;Great job reading through the entire Q3 2025 What's New blog post!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;To dive deeper into the technical specifics of the Q3 2025 release, be sure to check out our &lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/whats-new/2495b34492334456a49084831c2bea4e" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;What’s New Viewer&lt;/A&gt; in the Technical documentation. It offers a detailed overview of the release scope. To stay updated on the latest developments and news surrounding SAP HANA Cloud, follow the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+HANA+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800002881" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud tag&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Additionally, you can discover our latest blog posts by searching for the &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/whatsnewinsaphanacloud/tg-p" target="_blank"&gt;#whatsnewinsaphanacloud&lt;/A&gt; hashtag. If you missed the previous What’s New webinar from Q2 2025, you can find it along with past recordings and future webinars in &lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;this YouTube playlist&lt;/A&gt;. Our upcoming webcast on the Q3 innovations will be added to the same playlist soon.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Have questions about SAP HANA Cloud or want to discuss the new innovations? Feel free to post them in our &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-q-a/qa-p/technology-questions" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud Community Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/A&gt; or in the comments section below!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Cheers!&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-september-2025/ba-p/14228564"/>
    <published>2025-09-26T14:40:16.836000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/from-rest-to-datasphere-a-cap-based-integration-approach/ba-p/14218922</id>
    <title>From REST to Datasphere: A CAP-based Integration Approach</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T08:30:00.053000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>christian_willi</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/678327</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1631072292"&gt;From REST to Datasphere: A CAP-based Integration Approach&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We recently wrote a blog about how we integrate data from a REST service into SAP Datasphere. For that we deployed a small service on SAP BTP, which used the OPEN SQL schema and FastAPI to write this data directly into Datasphere. That service could also be triggered via REST endpoint from SAP Datasphere directly (&lt;A href="https://www.zpartner.eu/streamlining-rest-api-integrations-in-sap-datasphere-with-task-chains-and-fastapi-microservices-on-sap-btp/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;ZPARTNER Link&lt;/A&gt;, &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/streamlining-rest-api-integrations-in-sap-datasphere-with-task-chains-and/ba-p/14169273" target="_blank"&gt;SAP Community Link)&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog we now choose a different setup to retrieve data and consume it into SAP Dataphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We Created a CAP Application on SAP BTP.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;This CAP service connects to the SCIM API of SAP Datasphere, extracts users and roles, and makes the data consumable for analytics. It uses the following BTP services:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HDI Container&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To persist our data from the REST calls. The HDI container is deployed to the HANA Cloud instance of our Datasphere tenant, so the data can be consumed directly.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BTP Credential Store&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We store the credentials for the SCIM API in the BTP Credential Store and retrieve them in our CAP application securely.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;XSUAA Authorization and Trust Management&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;To secure our REST endpoints and enforce token-based access control.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Cloud Foundry Space&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Provides the runtime environment for deploying the CAP application.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_0-1758034031474.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315296i7682A0680123DAA5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_willi_0-1758034031474.png" alt="christian_willi_0-1758034031474.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1434558787"&gt;Use Case&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;In our use case, we extract user information from SAP Datasphere’s own SCIM API.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;We retrieve:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;the list of users,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;all available roles, and&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;the assignments between users and roles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This can be helpful for reporting on the number of users in a tenant and their corresponding roles. However, the same setup can be reused to extract and process any other REST API data into SAP Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1238045282"&gt;Credential Store&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We create a dedicated namespace in the Credential Store and store four secrets for the SCIM API authentication flow:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;dsp-scim-token-url&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;dsp-scim-base-url&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;dsp-scim-client-id&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;dsp-scim-client-secret&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;The CAP application retrieves these secrets at runtime, ensuring no credentials are hardcoded.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-1041531777"&gt;XSUAA Authorization and Trust Management Service&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We create a dedicated xsuaa service to get a Token URL and credentials. This service is bound to our CAP application so that every incoming request is authorized and protected.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-845018272"&gt;HDI Container&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;We create an HDI container where the database artifacts (tables and associations) are deployed. This container is provisioned in our SAP Datasphere tenant, making the synchronized data directly available for consumption.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-648504767"&gt;CAP Application&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The heart of the solution is the CAP service DSPUsers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;It exposes two kinds of endpoints:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-581073981"&gt;Virtual Views (live from SCIM)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/UsersVH → List of users with profile info.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/RolesVH → Roles with aggregated user counts.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/UserRolesVH → Which users have which roles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;These views are always fresh, since they query SCIM directly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-384560476"&gt;Persistent Entities (stored in HDI)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/Users → Users persisted in HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/Roles → Roles persisted in HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;GET /data/UserRoles → User-to-role assignments persisted in HANA.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-188046971"&gt;Actions (to sync SCIM → HDI)&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;POST /data/SyncUsersVHToUsers → Upserts SCIM users into the Users table.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;POST /data/SyncRolesFromSCIM → Stores aggregated roles in the Roles table.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;POST /data/SyncUserRolesFromSCIM → Refreshes both Roles and UserRoles.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;This design lets you both query SCIM data live and persist snapshots into HANA for modeling in Datasphere.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;The complete CAP service code is available here: &lt;A href="https://github.com/zpartner/cap-scim-handler-dsp" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Link to GitHub Repository&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId--137549253"&gt;SAP Datasphere&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;Once deployed, the HDI container is automatically integrated with our SAP Datasphere tenant. This allows:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Consuming the Users, Roles, and UserRoles tables directly in Datasphere,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Building reporting scenarios on top of user and role data,&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Joining with other business data to enrich analytics.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;To consume the entities, we need to add the HDI Container to a specific space. Also, we can now create a generic HTTP Connection. This enables to call the Endpoints for sync in a Task Chain.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="christian_willi_1-1758034059841.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/315297i9C02A86C7A1B379C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="christian_willi_1-1758034059841.png" alt="christian_willi_1-1758034059841.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H1 id="toc-hId-435677325"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;P&gt;The integration of a CAP-based service into SAP Datasphere showcases how SAP BTP services (HDI Container, Credential Store, XSUAA, Cloud Foundry) can be combined to securely retrieve and persist data from external REST APIs. By consuming SAP Datasphere’s own SCIM API, we demonstrated how to expose both live views for real-time insights and persistent tables for analytical modeling, all within a lightweight and extensible architecture.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Looking ahead, this framework can be reused for any REST API integration into SAP Datasphere, opening the door to richer reporting scenarios, advanced data modeling, and seamless orchestration with Task Chains. With this foundation, organizations gain a simple but powerful pattern for bridging external services with Datasphere while maintaining enterprise-grade security and governance.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-members/from-rest-to-datasphere-a-cap-based-integration-approach/ba-p/14218922"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T08:30:00.053000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-sap-build-q3-2025-release-highlights/ba-p/14231783</id>
    <title>What’s New in SAP Build – Q3 2025 Release Highlights</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T16:14:25.210000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EsmeeX</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/8621</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Zoom Webinar Banner (3) (1).png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321661i10CB0B180F5894FB/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Zoom Webinar Banner (3) (1).png" alt="Zoom Webinar Banner (3) (1).png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In Q3, we delivered several innovations across AI-powered development, ABAP project creation, modernized SAPUI5&amp;nbsp;and advanced mobile capabilities. SAP Build also reached a significant milestone with the introduction of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;MCP servers&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, allowing developers to boost productivity further with AI agents.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Check these out in our Top 10 Release Highlights from Q3 2025!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-powered development&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. Empowering developers with MCP Tools for SAP Build&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers&amp;nbsp;are now available for the following technologies: SAP Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP), SAPUI5 and SAP Fiori. This is a huge step forward for developers working with popular IDEs and coding assistants like GitHub Copilot, Cursor and more. With these MCP servers,&amp;nbsp;we’re now providing a comprehensive set of tools designed to optimize your development workflow across various SAP technologies.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-introduces-new-mcp-servers-to-enable-agentic-development-for/ba-p/14205602" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. SAP HANA Cloud SQL Statement Generation in Joule&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Directly in SAP Build Code, the Joule panel now offers the new command &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;/hana-sql-gen,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;which enables the generation of SQL statements from natural language directly in the panel. The generated statements can be reviewed and refined in the Joule panel. Suitable SQL statements can be either copied to a SQL console or directly executed inside the Joule panel after selecting a database connection on which to run the statement.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="hana cloud.png" style="width: 727px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321675i984EF7EF189C674B/image-dimensions/727x365/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="727" height="365" role="button" title="hana cloud.png" alt="hana cloud.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Expanded AI-powered capabilities in SAP Build Work Zone&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Build Work Zone continues to expand its AI capabilities, bringing new built-in features to an intelligent workspace with accelerated decision-making and improved employee experiences:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Integration of Joule in SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;By bringing Joule into SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition, users can now enjoy the power of Joule within their digital workplace. This eliminates the hassle of system-hopping, reduces time wasted on searching for information, and allows employees to focus on what is important. (Note: Available in early October)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;AI-powered text and comment generation: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This enables employees to quickly create, summarize, and engage with workplace content. For example, project managers can generate project status updates in minutes, ensuring their team members stay aligned.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-build-work-zone-gets-even-more-powerful-with-ai-powered-capabilities/ba-p/14180971" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="WZ joule.jpg" style="width: 728px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321676i619CA9786FB4BA73/image-dimensions/728x384/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="728" height="384" role="button" title="WZ joule.jpg" alt="WZ joule.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhanced App Development &amp;amp; Automation&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;4. Availability of SAPUI5 1.136.x-legacy-free with deprecated code removed&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAPUI5 1.136.x-legacy-free with deprecated code removed is now available via cloud access. This means app developers can test their UI code for compliance to SAPUI5 best practices. This helps to future-proof an SAP Fiori app for future SAPUI5 versions and work on deprecated/outdated code. Developers can also provide feedback to the UI5 team.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/explore-sapui5-openui5-1-136-x-legacy-free/ba-p/14103271" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;5. Create full-stack ABAP projects in SAP Business Application Studio&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can now create full-stack ABAP projects or open an existing ABAP CSN as a project in SAP Business Application Studio. You can also model your application using the CDS Graphical Modeler and generate ABAP development objects. By leveraging high productivity tools, this significantly accelerates time-to-market, improves collaboration and provides a standardized, compliant approach to building extensions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/bas/developing-full-stack-abap-application-in-sap-business-application-studio-40adaba361e2469493d47bf9757e87c7/developing-full-stack-abap-application-in-sap-business-application-studio?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Help Portal.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;..And stay tuned! We’ll share more about this topic at &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/events/teched/berlin/flow/sap/te25/catalog-inperson/page/catalog/session/1749110615653001ATih" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP TechEd 2025.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;6. Maintenance project for released process automation projects&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For process automation, we’ve introduced the ability to create dedicated project versions based on an existing released version. This allows process owners to maintain parallel editable versions while keeping the latest version in place, enabling teams to focus on solving a problem without redoing everything from scratch.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/build-process-automation/sap-build-process-automation/manage-business-process-projects?locale=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Help Portal.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;7. Holistic process views for requestors and participants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Now customers can benefit from dedicated, holistic views across their automated processes. The views provide information about natively running instances across multiple processes and workflows without any external configuration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;8. Outbox functionality for tasks in SAP Task Center&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Task Center, which provides a seamless user experience for&amp;nbsp;accessing open tasks, now lets you view completed tasks in an outbox. This provides a complete view of historical data while reducing support requests and efforts around process automation instances.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;New innovations for mobile&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;9. Support for new site experience in SAP Build Work Zone, advanced edition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Employees accessing their workspace content via SAP Mobile Start can now enjoy a new view mode with a more flexible structuring of content. They can quickly view workspace updates, company news or project dashboards, making it easier to organize and consume information in a personalized way. (Note: Available in early October)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mobile start document AI.png" style="width: 302px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321677iF375AB4D9A89D5E6/image-dimensions/302x302/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="302" height="302" role="button" title="mobile start document AI.png" alt="mobile start document AI.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="mobile start 2.png" style="width: 369px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321678iC54A3157B190A318/image-dimensions/369x303/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="369" height="303" role="button" title="mobile start 2.png" alt="mobile start 2.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;10. Updates to SAP Mobile Start&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;As the native mobile entry point to all SAP business apps and content, SAP Mobile Start has released several new innovations that simplify employee tasks and optimize their user experience:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;SAP Document AI integration: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Allows users to upload documents and photos for automated processing. This streamlines document handling, cuts down manual work and ensures data accuracy throughout operations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Enhanced push notifications with more detailed information: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Load and display context-specific details directly in the push notification, providing more meaningful and informative messages.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Simplified onboarding via deep link: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;IT teams can invite users to onboard to SAP Mobile Start via an email or message and provide a deep link that the users can use to initiate a simplified onboarding process.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Top news on start screen: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Shows the most important news in a larger format on top of the Start screen.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Learn more in the latest &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-mobile-start-v2-4-sap-document-ai-integration-and-much-more-release/ba-p/14170599" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;blog post&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;A href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_MOBILE_START/386859cc981742f3b6bb31f7e0d8a168?locale=en-US&amp;amp;state=PRODUCTION&amp;amp;version=2.4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Help Portal&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;I&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT size="5" color="#333399"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ready to see these in action?&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Join us for the next &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;What’s New in SAP Build Webinar&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; on October 8&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;th&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; as we dive deeper into MCP servers in CAP, SAP Mobile Start innovations, and much more!&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="whats new.jpeg" style="width: 569px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321673iBA7A6B90719D2F62/image-dimensions/569x298/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="569" height="298" role="button" title="whats new.jpeg" alt="whats new.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Sign up today for your preferred option:&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;October 8th, 9:00-10:00am CEST&lt;/STRONG&gt; (EMEA/APJ friendly):&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/3517592411496/WN_HjxF9s5sRSevFRe3kFzRDQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":globe_with_meridians:"&gt;🌐&lt;/span&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;October 8th, 5:00-6:00pm CEST&lt;/STRONG&gt; (Americas friendly):&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://sap-se.zoom.us/webinar/register/2017592412254/WN_hj7isBlESOuvEKzNL6AYdg" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;Register here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tooling-sap-build-blog-posts/what-s-new-in-sap-build-q3-2025-release-highlights/ba-p/14231783"/>
    <published>2025-09-30T16:14:25.210000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/fast-track-your-transition-to-sap-business-data-cloud-%EF%B8%8F/ba-p/14232169</id>
    <title>Fast Track Your Transition to SAP Business Data Cloud! 🌩️</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T05:54:58.129000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>JaSoN_Luo</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/1708</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P class=""&gt;Hello SAP Community! &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":waving_hand:"&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Whether you’re a seasoned data architect or just beginning your cloud journey, navigating the move to SAP Business Data Cloud is a hot topic. Inspired by our recent interactive webinar, let’s recap key insights — and invite you to share your own!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761815750"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":glowing_star:"&gt;🌟&lt;/span&gt;Why Embrace SAP Business Data Cloud?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Empower both people and AI agents with up-to-the-minute analytics and packaged data products.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Make “data as a product” — not just a byproduct — your standard, giving everyone context, semantics, and self-service.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Spark a culture of citizen data stewardship, freeing up IT to innovate!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SCR-20250930-patj.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321843i651C640C80F3DFF5/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SCR-20250930-patj.png" alt="SCR-20250930-patj.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565302245"&gt;🧭 Pillars for a Winning Transition&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Persona-Centricity: Solutions must work for technical teams, business leaders, AND the growing “citizen” analyst.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Lakehouse Architecture: Combine cost-effective storage with lightning-fast analytics — all using open formats.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Data Productization: Out-of-the-box, ready-to-consume data models to power your analytics and AI.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Open Connectivity: Break down silos and connect SAP &amp;amp; non-SAP data seamlessly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Data Harmonization: Share and exchange trusted data across domains, finally reducing friction!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SCR-20250930-pdxq.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321844i188E11D031B81C66/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SCR-20250930-pdxq.png" alt="SCR-20250930-pdxq.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368788740"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":repeat_button:"&gt;🔁&lt;/span&gt;Interactive Paths to BDC&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;BW Modernization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Still on BW 7.5? Lift-and-shift to BDC extends support and unlocks automated data product generation.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HANA Cloud Migration&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Bring your trusted HANA models forward, integrate with powerful engines, and publish new data products instantly.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Analytics Cloud “Rewire”&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Plug your Data Sphere and SAC directly into BDC. No re-engineering, just more value.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Zero-Copy Sharing (Databricks fans, this is for you!)&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Share data and semantics directly into advanced AI/ML scenarios.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="SCR-20251001-lvhl.png" style="width: 995px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/321842iF3203EE548407C59/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="SCR-20251001-lvhl.png" alt="SCR-20251001-lvhl.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172275235"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":hammer_and_wrench:"&gt;🛠&lt;/span&gt;️ Community Resources at Your Fingertips&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP Discovery Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Stay current with FAQs and technical guides.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Architecture Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Grab and customize diagrams, share your patterns, and learn from validated community posts.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Accelerator Hub&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Browse SAP data products and packages for every industry.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Roadmap Explorer&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Track features, data center rollouts, and future capabilities.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Trust Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Review compliance, security, and data residency—key for every architect!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975761730"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-779248225"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":busts_in_silhouette:"&gt;👥&lt;/span&gt;What’s Your Transition Story?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;We want your input! Which transition path is top-of-mind in your organization? Have another innovative approach? Drop your experiences, questions, or favorite resources in the comments below. Let’s shape this journey together.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-582734720"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-386221215"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":chequered_flag:"&gt;🏁&lt;/span&gt;Ready to Take Action?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL class=""&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Sign up for the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/registration/sap-bdc-modernization-assessment.html" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;free BDC assessment&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and get personalized insights.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Ask about discovery workshops and premium engagement for tailored guidance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;Bookmark this blog and join our next community session for more best practices and live demos! (&lt;A href="https://events.sap.com/eaa-bdc-apac/en_us/home.html#accordion-5d79451476-item-113b80c110" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Registration Link&lt;/A&gt;)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P class=""&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A special thank you to our guest, &lt;a href="https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/37326"&gt;@hmohammed&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;, for providing valuable insights and sharing his experiences with the participants&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/enterprise-architecture-blog-posts/fast-track-your-transition-to-sap-business-data-cloud-%EF%B8%8F/ba-p/14232169"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T05:54:58.129000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/time-series-forecasting-with-generative-ai-integrating-hana-ai-toolkit-with/ba-p/14127224</id>
    <title>Time-series Forecasting with Generative AI: Integrating HANA AI Toolkit with Joule in SAP Build Code</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T09:09:01.195000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sushil01</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/160869</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1732412865"&gt;Introduction&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In the era of AI-first development, embedding intelligence into business applications is no longer optional—it's expected. As an application developer working on SAP BTP, I was recently tasked with enhancing our&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Refunds Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;application with a&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;forecasting component&lt;/STRONG&gt;. The challenge? I’m not a data scientist.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;But thanks to the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;HANA AI Toolkit&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;and&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;, SAP Build Code’s AI co-pilot, I was able to build a robust forecasting solution—without needing deep expertise in machine learning.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog, I’ll walk you through how I used a simple slash command&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/hana-ai&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;to interact with the HANA AI Toolkit via Joule, and how this integration empowered me to build, evaluate, and deploy a forecasting model in just a few conversational steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1535899360"&gt;What is the HANA AI Toolkit?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;The&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://github.com/SAP/generative-ai-toolkit-for-sap-hana-cloud" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generative AI Toolkit for SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;is a powerful suite of tools designed to simplify the use of SAP HANA’s machine learning and vector capabilities. It includes:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Conversational agents for building forecasting models&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tools for selecting and applying ML algorithms&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SmartDataFrame interface for natural language data exploration&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Vector and embedding services&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Code generation components for SAP HANA Cloud scenarios&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1339385855"&gt;Meet Joule: Your AI Co-Pilot in SAP Build Code&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Joule&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;is SAP Build Code’s generative AI assistant, designed to help developers write, generate, and integrate code faster. With the new&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/hana-ai&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;slash command, Joule can now directly interact with the HANA AI Toolkit—bringing ML capabilities into the hands of every developer.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1142872350"&gt;My Use Case: Forecasting Sales Refunds&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Here’s how I used the integration to build a forecasting model for our Sales Refunds application:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1075441564"&gt;1.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Initiating the Forecasting Task&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai I am tasked to create a forecasting application, do you have any hana-ai tools which can help me with that?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule responded with a list of ready-to-use forecasting tools like:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;additive_model_forecast_fit_and_save&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;automatic_timeseries_fit_and_save&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;intermittent_forecast&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.42.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273954i26D3EFC4FAC08FF0/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.42.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.42.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-878928059"&gt;2.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Exploring the Data&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;!--         ScriptorStartFragment         --&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;!--         ScriptorEndFragment         --&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Show me the first 5 rows from SALES_REFUNDS table&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule fetched the data, helping me understand the structure and values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.58.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273956iB4B482548D6EB15B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.58.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.03.58.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-682414554"&gt;3.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generating a Dataset Report&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;A detailed HTML report was generated, giving me insights into data quality and structure.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.04.56.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273957i9B384B3709671D0D/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.04.56.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.04.56.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-485901049"&gt;4.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Time Series Analysis&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Please analyse and check the time series data in the table SALES_REFUNDS_TRAIN&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule analyzed the dataset and provided:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stationarity check (KPSS test)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seasonality detection&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Intermittency level&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Suggested algorithms and many more details&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.15.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273959i1EA867D03B5EFE89/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.15.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.15.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-289387544"&gt;5.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Choosing the Right Algorithm&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;!--         ScriptorStartFragment         --&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Which time series forecasting algorithm do you suggest?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Based on the data characteristics, Joule recommended the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Additive Model Forecast&lt;/STRONG&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.34.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273961iA3E744052CCB2B26/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.34.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.05.34.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-92874039"&gt;6.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Building the Forecast Model&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Build a forecast model and save it as Refunds-ForecastModel&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;The model was trained and saved with versioning support.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.06.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273963i3FBC707F6D9F8EC5/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.06.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.06.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--178870835"&gt;7.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generating Predictions&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-abap"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Apply the latest forecast model to the SALES_REFUNDS_PREDICT table&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Predictions were stored in a new table, ready for analysis.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.19.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273964iBBD7B3F337F94287/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.19.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.19.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--375384340"&gt;8.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Visualizing the Forecast&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Generate a forecast line plot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;A visual plot was generated to compare actual vs. predicted values.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.54.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273965iE869D8A99AA0916E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.54.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.06.54.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.24.31.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273967i92FBE3FA743EA91E/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.24.31.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.24.31.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--571897845"&gt;9.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Evaluating Accuracy&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Evaluate the forecast accuracy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule returned key metrics:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MAPE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;8.41%&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;MSE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;16,807,501.57&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;RMSE:&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;4,099.70&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.05.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273968i4A6C1BB4EA4CCD0C/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.05.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.05.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId--768411350"&gt;10.&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Generating CAP Artifacts&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;pre class="lia-code-sample language-bash"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/hana-ai Generate CAP artifacts for the forecast model&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;P&gt;Joule generated and offered to integrate the artifacts directly into my CAP project.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline" image-alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.13.png" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/273970iF273BD851A0C3AFD/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.13.png" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-13 at 16.07.13.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--671521848"&gt;Outcome&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;With just a few conversational commands, I was able to:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Analyze time series data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Select the right forecasting model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Train and evaluate the model&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Visualize and integrate the results into my application&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;All without writing a single line of ML code.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--868035353"&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI democratization&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Developers without ML expertise can now build intelligent features.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Conversational development&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Joule + HANA AI Toolkit enables natural language-driven workflows.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Enterprise-ready&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The integration supports versioning, evaluation, and CAP artifact generation.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId--1064548858"&gt;What’s Next?&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;This is just the beginning. With the&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;/hana-ai&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;slash command, we’re opening the door to a wide range of AI-powered development scenarios—from classification to anomaly detection and beyond.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you're building on SAP BTP and want to embed intelligence into your applications, give the HANA AI Toolkit and Joule a try. You might be surprised how far a conversation can take you.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;!--         ScriptorEndFragment         --&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/time-series-forecasting-with-generative-ai-integrating-hana-ai-toolkit-with/ba-p/14127224"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T09:09:01.195000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-5-in-the-series/ba-p/14206266</id>
    <title>Top Reasons to Modernize with SAP HANA Cloud – Blog #5 in the Series</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T18:05:36.979000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>thomashammer</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/122781</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;This is the final chapter in this &lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/forums/searchpage/tab/message?advanced=false&amp;amp;allow_punctuation=false&amp;amp;filter=location&amp;amp;location=blog-board:technology-blog-sap&amp;amp;q=whyhanacloud" target="_self"&gt;blog series&lt;/A&gt; on the benefits of migrating to SAP HANA Cloud. In each blog, I’ve described key features that offer significant benefits for your organization and can help you build your business case for SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P data-unlink="true"&gt;Although it can be difficult calculating the business value of migrating your database to the cloud, the expertise of independent organizations can be helpful. A recent IDC &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;study&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp; used a specialized business value methodology to assess the benefits of SAP HANA Cloud delivered to participating organizations. IDC concluded that the benefits were worth an annual average of US$13.7 million per organization and that the database enabled a 35% three-year reduction in total cost of ownership.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;If you don’t have time to read this report, I encourage you to complete your own organization &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt; using our free tool. In less than five minutes, you’ll receive useful insights that can help you decide your next steps.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog5-Pic1.jpg" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319507i5061DAE3E768CE7F/image-size/medium?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="Blog5-Pic1.jpg" alt="Blog5-Pic1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Let’s consider two more features of SAP HANA Cloud that can help you realize significant business value: comprehensive security and a complete application development ecosystem.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Comprehensive security&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Protecting your data and helping ensure compliance are top concerns for every organization. As business operations and workforces become more distributed, the need to provide secure data access from anywhere in the world intensifies.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud offers robust security features that cover critical data protection areas, including authentication, authorization, user management, data masking, anonymization, and encryption. Because these features are built into the database, you have little or no need for third-party security tools. These capabilities also reduce the administrative effort needed to protect data.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Support for multiple security certifications and standards, such as ISO (International Organization for Standardization) and SOC (Standard&amp;nbsp;Occupational Classification), helps ensure regulatory compliance. Configurable audit policies streamline compliance activities while helping protect your business and your customers. Automated updates to libraries and applications also boost security.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;These features help make it faster and simpler to meet your security goals. According to the IDC report, the security teams of organizations that deployed SAP HANA Cloud increased efficiency by 19%. This benefit translates into an average annual business value of $183,016 per organization.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One study participant from the agriculture industry cited the database security standards and policies of SAP HANA Cloud, considering it an extra protective layer to reinforce security. “If we had an on-premises database, we’d lack this added protection,” said the interviewee. “The entire platform has policies that prevent mistakes. For instance, SAP now requires updates to libraries and applications for security reasons. These requirements from SAP keep us updated and secure.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Another participant from the healthcare industry viewed the advanced protection as a financial advantage. “SAP HANA Cloud is a much more secure system that makes data more accessible and applications perform faster,” he said. “This has helped us meet our customers’ needs much better and has improved our revenue by about five percent.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;A complete application development ecosystem&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Time and resources are tight for your development teams. Demand from business users has never been higher, new use cases are emerging, and the need for different developer skill sets seems to continually grow.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud can help address these challenges with an integrated development ecosystem based on SAP Build solutions. SAP Build offers a comprehensive group of tools that support the full spectrum of no-code/low-code, pro-code, and generative AI development approaches. With SAP Build and SAP HANA Cloud, you can support developers at any skill level with the right tools.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Developers can build intelligent applications that use generative AI and harness their expertise and data. Applications built on SAP HANA Cloud can use intelligent algorithms to process large volumes of data and provide actionable recommendations. SAP HANA Cloud also includes machine learning libraries that help developers build sophisticated analytics applications that augment user expertise. By incorporating AI-driven insights, these applications help you anticipate future trends and predict behaviors, make business decisions faster, and improve business performance.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Blog5-Pic2.jpg" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/319509i293631EE46B5112B/image-size/large?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Blog5-Pic2.jpg" alt="Blog5-Pic2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The IDC report found that these application development capabilities deliver quantifiable business value. IDC estimates that development team productivity spiked by 30% in the surveyed organizations, creating staff time savings of $361,519 per organization.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;SAP HANA Cloud features, such as information libraries, combined with faster performance and easier integrations, helped developers build more complex applications such as those using machine learning and AI. Overall, participants developed or deployed 154% more features and applications annually than they could without SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;One study participant explained the impact of this value on the development team. “SAP HANA Cloud provides developers with more seamless integrations, and it is easy to use,” the interviewee explained. “They spend less time writing code because they can reuse code and use the libraries.”&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Explore additional SAP HANA Cloud resources&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As we’ve seen in this , the advanced features of SAP HANA Cloud offer significant value for organizations like yours. To help you make your business case for SAP HANA Cloud, check out the following resources:&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;What’s the potential value of SAP HANA Cloud for your organization? Complete a short &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.saphanacloud-businessvalue.com/campaign/bd9c2089-9aad-449a-bbab-837ceaa49a60" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;assessment&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Learn more about &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Discover how moving to SAP HANA Cloud helps you create a &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/products/data-cloud/hana/cloud-migration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;foundation for modernization&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Explore this guide on &lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/building-a-compelling-business-case-to-move-your-database-to-the-cloud/ba-p/14123254" target="_blank"&gt;building a compelling business case to move your database to the cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;[1]&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;“&lt;A href="https://www.sap.com/documents/2025/04/8262c341-007f-0010-bca6-c68f7e60039b.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;The Business Value of SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;,” IDC, sponsored by SAP, April 2025.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/top-reasons-to-modernize-with-sap-hana-cloud-blog-5-in-the-series/ba-p/14206266"/>
    <published>2025-10-01T18:05:36.979000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-release-september-2025-round-up/ba-p/14233522</id>
    <title>SAP HANA Cloud release September 2025 Round-up</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T15:59:05.349000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>andreamiranda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/135788</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Dear SAP HANA Cloud Enthusiasts,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;We are thrilled to share a comprehensive collection of the latest videos, blogposts, and resources from the SAP HANA Cloud Q3 2025 release.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="100%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50.129533678756474%" height="222px"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="teaserplay.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322310i54746DE2076CBF0B/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="teaserplay.png" alt="teaserplay.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.870466321243526%" height="222px"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-2020014692"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New Teaser&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;Explore the latest innovations in SAP HANA Cloud with Lead Product Manager Thomas Hammer! In this exciting teaser, he shares his favorite features from the newest release.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y31I9wpc_bs&amp;amp;list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN&amp;amp;index=2" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Watch it now on YouTube.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50.129533678756474%" height="250px"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1823501187"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;What’s New blogpost&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H4&gt;Intrigued by the teaser? Explore our "What’s New in SAP HANA Cloud in September 2025" blog post for an in-depth look and find valuable links for further insights.&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-september-2025/ba-p/14228564" target="_blank"&gt;Read it here!&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.870466321243526%" height="250px"&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/what-s-new-in-sap-hana-cloud-september-2025/ba-p/14228564" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="blogpostbutton.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322312iFEE962F7C6ADB24C/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="blogpostbutton.png" alt="blogpostbutton.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="50.129533678756474%" height="250px"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="webinarplaybutton.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322313i7981F26A8F0E10A7/image-size/medium/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=400" role="button" title="webinarplaybutton.png" alt="webinarplaybutton.png" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="49.870466321243526%" height="250px"&gt;&lt;H4 id="toc-hId-1626987682"&gt;What's New Webinar&lt;/H4&gt;Prefer watching over reading? Our 'What’s New' webinar is just for you! Join our Product experts for an in-depth view of the latest features. Watch anytime&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OwPFB6rzqcA&amp;amp;list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN&amp;amp;index=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;!&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301391458"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;DIV class=""&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don’t miss out on all the content and remember to&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/topics/hana" target="_blank"&gt;follow us in the SAP HANA Community.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;Remember to check our content following the # whatsnewinsaphanacloud tag:&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://community.sap.com/t5/tag/whatsnewinsaphanacloud/tg-p/board-id/technology-blog-sap" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don’t forget to subscribe and follow SAP HANA Cloud on&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL3ZRUb1AKkpTDZQgENtRcupp6vsNg8NHN" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;YouTube&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;to always stay up-to-date regarding the most recent innovations in SAP HANA Cloud.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;All the best,&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Andrea on behalf of the SAP HANA Cloud team&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+HANA+Cloud%25252C+SAP+HANA+database/pd-p/ada66f4e-5d7f-4e6d-a599-6b9a78023d84" target="_blank"&gt;#SAP HANA Cloud, SAP HANA database&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;#&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A class="" href="https://community.sap.com/t5/c-khhcw49343/SAP+HANA+Cloud/pd-p/73554900100800002881" target="_blank"&gt;SAP HANA Cloud&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;#whatsnewinsaphanacloud&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/sap-hana-cloud-release-september-2025-round-up/ba-p/14233522"/>
    <published>2025-10-02T15:59:05.349000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/open-source-apache-superset-and-sap-hana-comes-together-to-help-you/ba-p/14234973</id>
    <title>Open Source - Apache Superset™ and SAP HANA Comes together to help you</title>
    <updated>2025-10-05T12:52:29.479000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Yogananda</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/75</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://superset.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://superset.apache.org/&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;In today’s data-driven world, organizations need powerful tools to explore, visualize, and act on their data. &lt;STRONG&gt;Apache Superset™&lt;/STRONG&gt;, an open-source data visualization platform, combined with &lt;STRONG&gt;SAP HANA&lt;/STRONG&gt;, a high-performance in-memory database, offers a robust solution for modern analytics.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1890965764"&gt;Documentation&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="https://superset.apache.org/docs/6.0.0/intro" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://superset.apache.org/docs/6.0.0/intro&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1694452259"&gt;Apache Superset Highlights:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Open-source and free to use&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Rich visualization options (bar charts, pie charts, geospatial maps, etc.)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;SQL Lab for advanced querying&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Role-based access control and authentication&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Cloud-native and scalable architecture&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1497938754"&gt;SAP HANA Advantages:&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;In-memory computing for real-time analytics&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Combines transactional and analytical workloads&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Advanced analytics (predictive, spatial, text)&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;High performance with large datasets&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Seamless integration with enterprise systems&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;Together, they enable &lt;STRONG&gt;real-time, interactive dashboards&lt;/STRONG&gt; that empower business users and data analysts alike.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1172342530"&gt;Use Cases&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Sales Dashboards&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Real-time revenue tracking across regions&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Operations Monitoring&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Visualize supply chain metrics&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finance Analytics&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Profitability and cost breakdowns&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Customer Insights&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Behavioral analysis from SAP CRM data&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-975829025"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;Apache Superset and SAP HANA together form a powerful duo for enterprise-grade analytics. With Superset’s intuitive interface and HANA’s blazing-fast performance, teams can unlock insights faster and make data-driven decisions with confidence.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/data-and-analytics-blog-posts/open-source-apache-superset-and-sap-hana-comes-together-to-help-you/ba-p/14234973"/>
    <published>2025-10-05T12:52:29.479000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/partners-unveil-generative-ai-applications-to-solve-real-time-industry/ba-p/14234115</id>
    <title>Partners unveil generative AI applications to solve  real-time industry challenges with SAP and AWS</title>
    <updated>2025-10-06T11:54:48.184000+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>cvasanthk</name>
      <uri>https://community.sap.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/5485</uri>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1761875173"&gt;AWS SAP AI Co-Innovation Program&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;At SAP Sapphire 2025, SAP and Amazon Web Services (AWS) unveiled the AI co-innovation program aimed at assisting partners in developing Generative AI applications to address business challenges. This program integrates advanced GenAI technologies from SAP with Generative AI Services from AWS, complemented by SAP Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) Data, to facilitate customer implementation journeys.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;As a pivotal advancement in the SAP AI co-innovation program, AWS and SAP have established a new cohort in collaboration with SAP’s well-established Hack2Build initiative. This cohort provides support for the development, testing, and deployment of industry-specific applications. Partners are encouraged to develop industry-focused solutions utilizing AWS generative AI tools and services from Amazon Bedrock, including large language models (LLMs) such as Amazon Nova and Anthropic Claude within AI Foundation on SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP). This enables partners to swiftly develop and deploy AI applications tailored to their customers’ SAP workloads.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1565361668"&gt;Hack2Build&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Hack2Build Cohort- September 2025 with AWS" style="width: 631px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322567i8A556057517D6145/image-dimensions/631x181/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="631" height="181" role="button" title="Banner_new_SCIP.jpg" alt="Hack2Build Cohort- September 2025 with AWS" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hack2Build Cohort- September 2025 with AWS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;SPAN&gt;The new cohort of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A title="Your Highway to Business Innovation" href="https://events.sap.com/hack2build/en_us/home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Hack2Build&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, an initiative of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Excellence Center&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;SAP&lt;/STRONG&gt; &lt;STRONG&gt;Partner Ecosystem Success&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; in collaboration with &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;AI Partner Product Management, SAP Business AI and Amazon Web Services&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, brought together AI expertise from SAP and AWS and architects to expedite the development of partner Generative AI applications within a seven-day timeframe. Ten partners were selected across various regions as part of this initiative. Experts from SAP and AWS provided support and guidance to the selected ten partners on the chosen use cases. The hack phase commenced on September 22nd and concluded with an impressive demo jam on September 30th.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Partners selected for Hack2Build Cohort with AWS and SAP  - September 2025" style="width: 654px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322546iC04F8C1BAFC3A8F8/image-dimensions/654x308/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="654" height="308" role="button" title="Partner_Logos_blog.jpg" alt="Partners selected for Hack2Build Cohort with AWS and SAP  - September 2025" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Partners selected for Hack2Build Cohort with AWS and SAP  - September 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H2 id="toc-hId-1368848163"&gt;Hack2Build Cohort: &lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":party_popper:"&gt;🎉&lt;/span&gt; Winners&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;P&gt;In this blog post, we will delve into the generative AI solutions developed by the winning partners. These solutions leverage the capabilities of Generative AI Hub, a component of SAP AI Core, a service within the SAP Business Technology Platform (SAP BTP). By accessing various Large Language Models (LLMs) on Amazon Web Services (AWS) through the Amazon Bedrock platform, the partners have harnessed the power of generative AI to create innovative solutions.&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Hack2Build Cohort 2025-Winners' Podium- AWS SAP AI Co-Innovation" style="width: 541px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/322548iF614E900ADA4AF46/image-dimensions/541x298/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2" width="541" height="298" role="button" title="Winners_Blog.jpg" alt="Hack2Build Cohort 2025-Winners' Podium- AWS SAP AI Co-Innovation" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Hack2Build Cohort 2025-Winners' Podium- AWS SAP AI Co-Innovation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1301417377"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;🧑‍&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":balance_scale:"&gt;⚖️&lt;/span&gt;🧑🏻‍&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":balance_scale:"&gt;⚖️&lt;/span&gt; Judges&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;On September 30, 2025, a distinguished panel of senior leaders from SAP and AWS convened to select three winners from the demo jam.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Kamal Arora, Director of Solutions Architecture and AI Innovation at AWS USA&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Marc-Oliver Klein, Vice President and Head of Partner Product Management and Strategic AI Development Partnerships at SAP SE&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Stefan Wellner, Vice President of Technology Alliances, Platform and Incubation Partnerships at SAP Business AI Ecosystem at SAP SE&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;Tom Adams, Director of Global Business Consulting and Advisory Partners at AWS USA&amp;nbsp;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-1104903872"&gt;&lt;FONT size="4"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":1st_place_medal:"&gt;🥇&lt;/span&gt; Winner: &lt;A href="https://atos.net/en/services/smart-platforms/sap" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Atos&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Atos presented an AI-Powered Supply Chain Disruption Analysis solution that addresses external vulnerabilities in supply chains, particularly unforeseen disruptions. The solution integrates real-time hazard data with SAP metrics to enhance operational resilience. It also integrates SAP BTP services UI5 and CAP applications with AWS AI services, including the Anthropic Claude 4 Sonnet LLM model on Amazon Bedrock. Key features demonstrated include real-time disruption data collection and automated supplier prioritization integrated with SAP S/4HANA systems.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="AI-Powered Supply Chain Disruption Analysis by Atos" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323097i637EEDC9C532901F/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Atos_AI powered Supply Chain Disruption analysis.jpg" alt="AI-Powered Supply Chain Disruption Analysis by Atos" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;AI-Powered Supply Chain Disruption Analysis by Atos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-908390367"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":2nd_place_medal:"&gt;🥈&lt;/span&gt;1st Runner up - &lt;A href="https://www.capgemini.com/de-de/" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;Capgemini&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;Capgemini demonstrated a GTS smart check solution that seamlessly integrates with SAP GTS and SAP S/4HANA. This solution effectively addresses challenges in import processing, where manual document handling and compliance checks result in delays. The solution significantly reduces import processing time, thereby saving substantial hours annually. This is achieved through the automation of data extraction and comparison from multiple document sources using the Anthropic Claude 4 Sonnet LLM model from Amazon Bedrock.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Capgemini's GTS Smart Check Solution" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323201iD7FC3283EF3104A6/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="Capgemini_GTS smart check.jpg" alt="Capgemini's GTS Smart Check Solution" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Capgemini's GTS Smart Check Solution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":3rd_place_medal:"&gt;🥉&lt;/span&gt;2nd Runner up - &lt;A href="http://www.nttdata-solutions.com" target="_self" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"&gt;NTT Data&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;NTT Data unveiled its Voice Control ERP Assistant, a collaborative solution designed to alleviate the challenges associated with accessing ERP systems on the shop floor. This innovative solution addresses the inherent difficulties faced by workers in navigating unfamiliar ERP systems without disrupting their workflow. By seamlessly integrating SAPUI5 and HANA Cloud, SAP HANA Vector Engine, Generative AI Hub within SAP BTP Services, and Anthropic Claude LLM from Amazon Bedrock, including Amazon Polly for voice interaction, the solution enables hands-free access to ERP data and documentation. Specifically targeting the manufacturing industry, the solution demonstrated substantial business value by enhancing task focus and mitigating employee turnover.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-center" image-alt="Voice Controlled ERP Assistant by NTT Data" style="width: 999px;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://community.sap.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/323202iB6BFAB948DEF3D1A/image-size/large/is-moderation-mode/true?v=v2&amp;amp;px=999" role="button" title="NTT_Voice Control ERP Assistant.jpg" alt="Voice Controlled ERP Assistant by NTT Data" /&gt;&lt;span class="lia-inline-image-caption" onclick="event.preventDefault();"&gt;Voice Controlled ERP Assistant by NTT Data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-711876862"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":clapping_hands:"&gt;👏🏼&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&amp;nbsp;Finalists&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We thank all the finalist teams who successfully demonstrated the innovations to the panel of judges, as a part of this Hack2Build cohort.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;TABLE border="1" width="90%"&gt;&lt;TBODY&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48.769987699877%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Finalists&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51.230012300123%" height="30px"&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Minimal Viable Product demonstrated&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48.769987699877%" height="57px"&gt;Accenture&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51.230012300123%" height="57px"&gt;Navi , a smart delivery scheduling solution focusing on the supply chain's inefficiencies in developing countries&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48.769987699877%" height="57px"&gt;Cognizant&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51.230012300123%" height="57px"&gt;Asset Unitization AI, addresses manual asset unitization challenges in asset-intensive industries&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48.769987699877%" height="57px"&gt;Deloitte&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51.230012300123%" height="57px"&gt;Relationship Management Agent, automates the processing of email queries related to supplier and vendor management&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48.769987699877%" height="57px"&gt;IBM&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51.230012300123%" height="57px"&gt;Sustainable Buddy, addresses sustainability challenges for better operational transparency and efficiency in Oil &amp;amp; Gas&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48.769987699877%" height="84px"&gt;LTIMindtree&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51.230012300123%" height="84px"&gt;FieldSense.ai, enhances SAP Service and Asset Manager to streamline field service operations, improve safety, and ensure compliance in Utilities and Manufacturing&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48.769987699877%" height="84px"&gt;Phoenix Consulting&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51.230012300123%" height="84px"&gt;Automated Supplier Invoice Processing, addresses high manual effort and error rates in accounts payable ,supporting Arabic characters and Hindu numerals&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD width="48.769987699877%" height="84px"&gt;Tech Mahindra&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;TD width="51.230012300123%" height="84px"&gt;Improve PO extraction&amp;nbsp; and Sales Order creation process, easing the process of extracting data from challenging invoice formats like blurry or multilingual images.&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-515363357"&gt;&lt;span class="lia-unicode-emoji" title=":folded_hands:"&gt;🙏&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; Special Thanks&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We extend our appreciation to the many AWS and SAP experts , who coached the partners to successfully develop their solutions during this Hack2Build initiative.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;H3 id="toc-hId-318849852"&gt;☞ &amp;nbsp;Next Phase&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;P&gt;We anticipate that all participating partners will now proceed to finalize their comprehensive solution within a timeframe of 6 to 8 weeks. SAP and AWS will actively engage with all participating partners to provide support throughout their development process in the upcoming weeks, ensuring that their innovations are prepared for customer deployment.&lt;/P&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://community.sap.com/t5/technology-blog-posts-by-sap/partners-unveil-generative-ai-applications-to-solve-real-time-industry/ba-p/14234115"/>
    <published>2025-10-06T11:54:48.184000+02:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
